<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bug forecasting by visualizing code evolution</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/bug-forecasting-by-visualizing-code-evolution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Tommi Penttinen - Bug forecasting by visualizing code evolution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to introduce and expand the ideas presented by Adam Tornhil in his work (Your Code as a Crime Scene – applying forensics to mining software repositories - where do the bugs propbably lurch). Tornhill's main ideas are combining cyclomatic code complexity metric with repository history -calculated &amp;quot;code/knowledge ownership&amp;quot;. Adding test coverage data, replicated production-system web traffic and their call graphs adds whole new dimensions to the data available from the repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm a(n almost-university-dropout) mathemathics major, software engineer. I've worked professionally with Python (and Django) since 2009, having also had the privilege to work only with DVCS. I've worked in different organizations ranging from freelancing and small companies to multinational corporations. I enjoy automation, debuggers and meta-programming. Most of my non-programming spare time goes into a cappella singing, improvisational theatre and finding ways to express my acrobatic tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tommi Penttinen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/bug-forecasting-by-visualizing-code-evolution.html</guid></item><item><title>Building a marketplace</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/building-a-marketplace.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Elena Oat - Building a marketplace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motivation for this talk is sharing my own experience with implementing Stripe payments in a Django application. I will, specifically, touch on Stripe Connect which is meant for marketplaces. Django is still missing a package for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will include challenges faced and some of the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I've been a speaker in 2014 and 2013 at PyCon Finland. I am the founder of Helsinki PyLadies&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elena Oat</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/building-a-marketplace.html</guid></item><item><title>How to become enterprise-friendly with free software</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/how-to-become-enterprise-friendly-with-free-software.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Alexander Bokovoy - How to become enterprise-friendly with free software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to enable single sign-on in your web applications and allow Kerberos logins in an enterprise next to you to work? This talk covers recent developments in FreeIPA, SSSD, and Ipsilon projects that allow application developers to integrate with traditional corporate infrastructure with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm Principal Software Engineer at Red Hat, working on FreeIPA, Samba, SSSD, Kerberos, and many other things. FreeIPA is a free software infrastructure project doing to Linux and other POSIX-compatible operating systems what Active Directory is for Windows environment. FreeIPA is written in Python and C.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Bokovoy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/how-to-become-enterprise-friendly-with-free-software.html</guid><category>FreeIPA</category><category>SSSD</category><category>Ipsilon</category></item><item><title>Hunting Malware with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/hunting-malware-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Matteo Cafasso - Hunting Malware with Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worms, Trojans, BotNets and Ransomware. These bad guys are quite known nowadays but how do they look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am gonna show one of the approaches IT Security experts employ to study these threats using open source Python technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation would be a live demo in which I'll execute some malware in a secure environment and show how it behaves and how to detect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will show a Sandboxing technology developed within F-Secure named Sandboxed Execution Environment (SEE). SEE is a Python framework which allows to quickly build behavioural scanning engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEE will be used altogether with other open source technologies to show some recent malware to the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I am a software engineer working in F-Secure Labs. F-Secure Corporation is an IT security company based in Helsinki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among my duties, malware handling and analysis automation is one of the most interesting to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I develop and maintain the main behavioural scanning engines within F-Secure back-end and SEE is one of their core technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matteo Cafasso</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/hunting-malware-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Introducing the Asphalt framework</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/introducing-the-asphalt-framework.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Alex Grönholm - Introducing the Asphalt framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most existing server frameworks only cater to a specific network protocol, forcing developers to learn everything anew when building an app for a different protocol. Or worse, there's no framework available so they have to reinvent everything by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, meet Asphalt -- a new general purpose server microframework that not only solves these problems, but also provides strong compatibility guarantees through the use of semantic versioning and PEP 484 type hints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will hear how Asphalt compares (or doesn't) to Twisted, how to mix asynchronous code with synchronous code and how to develop multi-protocol applications that work seamlessly together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm a private contractor from Espoo, 35 years old. I'm a Jython core developer and the author of APScheduler, sqlacodegen, jython-swingutils, the concurrent.futures backport and of course the Asphalt framework. I build and maintain Enterprise Resource Planning systems for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Grönholm</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/introducing-the-asphalt-framework.html</guid><category>asphalt</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Solid data structures in Python with logs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/keynote-solid-data-structures-in-python-with-logs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Keynote: Jyrki Pulliainen - Solid data structures in Python with logs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know the classic web application that has a database connected to it. Over time the app grows and we add more bells and whistles, like a search functionality via ElasticSearch. Soon we notice that we need a cache too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have a fairly complex application and a completely new set of problems like the cache invalidation, stale data, consistency issues etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I said that using logs would help you here? This talk looks into using Kafka via Python to build solid data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of the talk outline is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are log based data structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's Kafka and why is it amazing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Kafka via Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demo time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm a content engineer at the music streaming company Spotify. I've been using Python for professional and personal projects for over 10 years now. Over the course of years I've built open-source tools for Python and even contributed to the cpython itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been a part of creating both PyCon Finland and PyCon Sweden. I'm also organising the PySthlm meetups in Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/keynote-solid-data-structures-in-python-with-logs.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Lightning talks. PyCon Finland 2015</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/lightning-talks-pycon-finland-2015.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Lightning talks&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/lightning-talks-pycon-finland-2015.html</guid><category>Lightning Talks</category></item><item><title>Nix for Python developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/nix-for-python-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Asko Soukka - Nix for Python developers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do when your python project has dependencies beyond Python? Nix is a &amp;quot;purely functional&amp;quot; package manager, which can also be used like &amp;quot;virtualenv&amp;quot;, but for everything. I would cover single user installation of Nix package manager on Linux or Mac, defining Nix based development environments, generating Nix expressions for large Python projects using buildout, and finally, building minimal Docker images from SCRATCH by using those generated expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm a system designer at University of Jyväskylä and core contributor for a Python based open source CMS called Plone. I have blogged about my topics at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://datakurre.pandala.org/"&gt;https://datakurre.pandala.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Asko Soukka</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/nix-for-python-developers.html</guid></item><item><title>Plug in with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/plug-in-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Markus Törnqvist - Plug in with Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are plugins? Why are they nice? How do you write them for applications? How do you make your application accept plugins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author: Python for about 15 years, since version 1.5 at school. Started coding Python for the web making his own frameworks before they were a thing. Since then a Django veteran who likes to take breaks writing Python in other ways, like Ripwhine the CD ripping tool. Original roots in system administration, then onto coding, being CTO at his startup for some years and currently Software Architect at Codento. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fi.linkedin.com/in/mjtorn"&gt;https://fi.linkedin.com/in/mjtorn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Törnqvist</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/plug-in-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Pragmatic Testing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/pragmatic-testing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Charlie Hornsby - Pragmatic Testing
I would like to talk about software testing from a real world point of view, explaining a healthy testing mindset for all programming skill levels. Just as programming skill is a continuum of experience, testing best practices are also not black and white. I will begin with a brief introduction to some testing concepts (unit testing, integration testing, system testing, etc) but the main focus of the presentation will be on ways for both professional developers and hobbyist programmers to improve their use of testing in everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm a junior developer working in a Django e-commerce company in Helsinki. I've worked with Python for 3 years in both the fields of web development and scientific computing. I moved to Finland from England around 10 months ago and I love talking about Python and progamming in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charlie Hornsby</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/pragmatic-testing.html</guid></item><item><title>Weaving a Search Engine around User's Workflow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/weaving-a-search-engine-around-users-workflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Priidu Kull - Weaving a Search Engine around User's Workflow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss my attempt to build a search engine for legal documents that lawyers would love to use. I tried to figure out how lawyers work with documents and to build a search engine that would best fit their workflows. I will discuss the methods that I have used for finding out about their workflows and the decisions that I had to make to best accommodate the workflows of my users. The talk will include practical advice on using Elasticsearch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I was a lawyer, then decided to become a coder because I enjoyed coding so much and I was motivated by the ability to make a difference that coders possess more than lawyers. Currently I have three years of experience in software development, including 1.5 years working for a software development firm. The project that will feature in my talk is online at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://legal.ee/"&gt;http://legal.ee/&lt;/a&gt; and I am currently putting in full time effort to develop it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Priidu Kull</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/weaving-a-search-engine-around-users-workflow.html</guid></item><item><title>Welcome and quick introduction of all talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/welcome-and-quick-introduction-of-all-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Welcome and quick introduction of all talks&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/welcome-and-quick-introduction-of-all-talks.html</guid></item><item><title>Welcome to async/await era</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/welcome-to-asyncawait-era.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Igor Davydenko - Welcome to async/await era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PEP492 accepted and Python 3.5 will have new async/await statements. Talk will introduce them to the audience and shows examples on how to and when to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk also covers how async/await helps to write better and clear asyncio web applications on top of aiohttp library and shows common patterns to use, while making backend applications on Python 3.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  Python &amp;amp; React.js developer from Kyiv, Ukraine. Love creating API for humans, open source libraries, and giving talks about the process. In Python 3 &amp;amp; asyncio I trust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Igor Davydenko</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/welcome-to-asyncawait-era.html</guid></item></channel></rss>