<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-italia-2017.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Artistic Python: Mixing Python Programming with Fashion</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/artistic-python-mixing-python-programming-with-fashion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ria Baldevia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/artistic-python-mixing-python-programming-with-fashion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are numerous ways to learn and introduce the world of programming
to new coders. One way is to embrace the world of art. Python offers an
ecosystem that can take any curious programmer to merge the world of art
and technology. Artistic Python: Mixing Programming with Fashion aims to
show how Python, some hardware, and numerous libraries can inspire
anyone to incorporate coding into their artistic endeavors and vice
versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one thinks of fashion, several things come to mind: fabric, sewing,
and fashion shows. Rarely does one think about leveraging programming
and available hardware as components in creating a final product.
Artistic Python will present the ideation, design, coding, and creation
process of an outfit that incorporated Python programming, lighting, and
small programmable computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="fashion"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="multimedia"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="Math"></category></entry><entry><title>Attack of Pythons : Gotchas and Landmines in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/attack-of-pythons-gotchas-and-landmines-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manoj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/attack-of-pythons-gotchas-and-landmines-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python may be one of the simplest and most flexible programming
languages out there, but it is still a programming language. It still
has syntax, data types, and some occasional dark corners. Python “warts”
are things for which people have criticised Python, typically aspects of
the language or mechanisms of its implementation, because such aspects
either expose certain surprising inconsistencies, are regarded as
omissions, or cause irritation for parts of the community in some sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be about common pitfalls (termed warts/landmines) that
people face using Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="features"></category><category term="warts"></category><category term="bugs"></category><category term="landmines"></category><category term="dark-corners"></category><category term="python2"></category></entry><entry><title>Awesome CLI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/awesome-cli.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Fink</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/awesome-cli.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to get user input from your command line program?
Or maybe color the output a bit? Or do you want to write an immersive
terminal application like top, or even vim? Then you need to speak a bit
of terminal! This talk describes how to talk to your terminal from
scratch and goes on to show why the Python library prompt-toolkit is so
awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terminal emulators we run so many of our programming tools in are
more powerful than we give them credit for, and the key to that power is
understanding the interface. This talk will cover terminal colors and
styles, writing to arbitrary portions of the screen, handling signals
from the terminal, determining the terminal’s dimensions and scrollback
buffer behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terminal programming can get hairy, especially if you want to support
multiple platforms like Mac, Linux and Win; along the way we’ll deal
with encoding issues, automatisation issues and look into 4 decades’ of
terminal communication. By gaining a deeper understanding of these
issues, we’ll be able to choose from the abstractions over them offered
by Python libraries like Blessings, prompt-toolkit, asciimatics etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="terminal"></category><category term="prompt-toolkit"></category><category term="cli"></category><category term="command-line"></category></entry><entry><title>Crash test of Django ORM</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/crash-test-of-django-orm.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrii Soldatenko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/crash-test-of-django-orm.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world is swimming in articles and books about Django and Django ORM
itself. All this sources cover only basic use cases of Django ORM
comparing to real world examples. This talk is dedicated to the
proposition to crash test Django ORM 80% of functionalities in 20% of
the time. Also I’m going to show the important features and capabilities
of Django ORM compare to most of SQL features. Traditionally, ORM is
presented in a “bottom-up” fashion, but I would like to propose
approach, on the other hand, is “top-down”. We begin by identifying a
rather short list of standard questions, or precisely types of
questions, that are often asked of relations databases. We then show how
these standard questions are posted in Django ORM, introducing and
motivating the use of its capabilities and features as they become
relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django-orm"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Create a serverless infrastructure for data collection with Python and AWS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/create-a-serverless-infrastructure-for-data-collection-with-python-and-aws.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Santucci</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/create-a-serverless-infrastructure-for-data-collection-with-python-and-aws.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk illustrates a real-world example of how to collect data from
your web, mobile, server and cloud apps and then send them to third
party services and tools or load them into your data warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data collection pipeline is integrated with multiple AWS services,
such as Kinesis Firehose, Lambda functions and StepFunctions; Python is
used to write each module. The data workflow is fully described pointing
out how to store backup correctly, manage the conditional routing (in
order to allow or discard data for specific services), implement a retry
strategy on failure and finally compare performance and costs for each
module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://clda.co/pycon8-data-collection-blogpost"&gt;clda.co/pycon8-data-collection-blogpost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: Basic knowledge of AWS services&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="datawarehousing"></category><category term="aws"></category></entry><entry><title>Dai dati alla visualizzazione: la mia prima data pipeline</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dai-dati-alla-visualizzazione-la-mia-prima-data-pipeline.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Riccardo Magliocchetti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/dai-dati-alla-visualizzazione-la-mia-prima-data-pipeline.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Costruire una data pipeline non deve essere per forza complicato. Nel
talk vedremo come si può realizzare una semplice data pipeline usando
Luigi per consumare dati da una API e prepararli per fare esplorazione e
visualizzazione con Superset (AKA Caravel).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DataExploration"></category><category term="superset"></category><category term="DataVisualization"></category><category term="etl"></category><category term="luigi"></category></entry><entry><title>Differential network analysis and graph classification: a glocal approach</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/differential-network-analysis-and-graph-classification-a-glocal-approach.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Jurman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/differential-network-analysis-and-graph-classification-a-glocal-approach.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We propose a novel solution in differential network analysis to both the
network comparison and the classification tasks by introducing the
glocal HIM metric for comparing graphs and a graph kernel induced by the
HIM measure. The HIM distance is defined as the one-parameter family of
product metrics linearly combining the normalised Hamming distance H and
the normalised Ipsen- Mikhailov spectral distance IM. The combination of
the two components within a single metric allows overcoming their
drawbacks and obtaining a measure which is simultaneously global and
local. Furthermore, plugging the HIM kernel into a Support Vector
Machine gives us a classification algorithm based on the HIM distance.
Here we outline the underlying theoretical details of the metric
construction, and we present several applications of the HIM distance
and the HIM kernel to datasets belonging to different areas, including
socioeconomics, neuroscience, oncogenomics and developmental genomics,
supporting the adoption of the HIM family as a general analysis tool for
information extraction based on a quantitative evaluation of the
difference among diverse instances of a complex system. We conclude
introducing the Open Source implementation of the HIM metrics provided
in the R package nettols and in its web interface ReNette.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mathematics"></category><category term="algebra"></category><category term="Network"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Explore the brain with Nilearn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/explore-the-brain-with-nilearn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Darya Chyzhyk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/explore-the-brain-with-nilearn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past recent years, the Python programming language became popular
and widely used in many science areas, that you can notes from huge
amount of high quality &lt;strong&gt;scientific&lt;/strong&gt; libraries available in GitHub.
Python has already won the confidence in neuro-imaging community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis of different &lt;strong&gt;neuroimaging&lt;/strong&gt; modalities consists of
identifying such a complex pipeline that include supporting specific
&lt;strong&gt;MRI&lt;/strong&gt; data acquisition, image processing, statistics and predictive
modeling, and visualization of the results. &lt;strong&gt;Nilearn&lt;/strong&gt; is a Python
package designed to face these challenges. It provides state-of-the-art
&lt;strong&gt;machine-learning&lt;/strong&gt; methods for analysis task fMRI, resting-state, or
anathomical data. In my talk, I would like to present general purpose of
Nilearn, focusing on &lt;strong&gt;functional connectivity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;connectome&lt;/strong&gt;
analysis in resting-state fMRI.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="computer-science"></category><category term="cognitive-science"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Facial Analysis Techniques for Pythonista (and beyond!)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/facial-analysis-techniques-for-pythonista-and-beyond.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Casalboni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/facial-analysis-techniques-for-pythonista-and-beyond.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to detect, track, and analyze faces opens up a wide range of
interesting use cases, ranging from interactive smart applications and
real- time video processing, all the way to biometric security and
augmented reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will showcase the available &lt;strong&gt;tools built by the Python
community&lt;/strong&gt; and their corresponding pros &amp;amp; cons, limitations, and
complexity. While discussing the possible scenarios and what is actually
required to &lt;strong&gt;DIY with Python&lt;/strong&gt;, I will compare such handmade solutions
with &lt;strong&gt;Cloud-based products and APIs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: basic understanding of Python’s data science stack
(especially numpy).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="CloudComputing"></category><category term="aws"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="scikit-image"></category><category term="google-cloud"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="opencv"></category><category term="scikits"></category><category term="cv"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Facial-Analysis"></category><category term="dlib"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category></entry><entry><title>Indicizzare e cercare tonnellate di dati con ElasticSearch e Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/indicizzare-e-cercare-tonnellate-di-dati-con-elasticsearch-e-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ernesto Arbitrio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/indicizzare-e-cercare-tonnellate-di-dati-con-elasticsearch-e-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cercare in maniera efficente e veloce in grandi quantità di dati risulta
essere, almeno nel mio campo e nelle mie esperienze, un problema
abbastanza diffuso. In questo talk sarà affrontato da un punto di vista
tecnico/sistemistico la parte di indicizzazione di grandi volumi di
dati, le accortenze da avere quando si indicizzano dati in un engine di
search e anlaytics e la parte di monitoring del cluster ELK. Nella
seconda parte invece verrà mostrata l’interazione di una web interface
(Django based) con elasticsearch. Conoscenze necessarie per il talk:
concetti base di serializzazione, restful web services, django&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="elasticsearch"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="Full Text Search"></category><category term="REST"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Just one Shade of OpenStack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/just-one-shade-of-openstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Polli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/just-one-shade-of-openstack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to start using openstack? Come to this talk and meet shade! Shade
is a python library that wraps the many OpenStack clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This introductory talk presents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an overview of openstack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting to openstack with shade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating and listing machines, networks &amp;amp; co&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shade usage in ansible modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contributing to shade (tox, git review, …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="OpenStack"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Keeping up with the pace of a fast growing community without dying</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Flavio Percoco</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;New open source communities are born everyday. Some of them are meant to
last long and some others aren’t. There’s a moment in every community
where it needs to outgrow itself, expand its limits and aim way higher
than ever. This is no necesarily related to its goals but the ecosystem
it needs to stay alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a community has gone beyond its limits, the community members,
consumers and leaders will have to keep up with its pace. How do we help
it to remain sane? How do we keep our goals on track while allowing for
further growth? How do we allow it to keep expanding without further
damaging the community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all questions we ask ourselves everyday in the OpenStack
community and that we’ve managed to work on without killing ourselves on
the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="open-source"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Leading an open source project as a startup.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/leading-an-open-source-project-as-a-startup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Garnier</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/leading-an-open-source-project-as-a-startup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 year after releasing MJML (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mjmlio/mjml"&gt;https://github.com/mjmlio/mjml&lt;/a&gt;), it’s time
to stand back and look at the lessons we learnt. We’ll discuss about how
to get involved into open source, why you would, and how to remain
credible as a company doing open source. We’ll also go over one of the
most important things in open source: community. How to get people
involved, how to communicate and collaborate effectively, but also how
to work with people you might not be best friends with.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Mastering Your Tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/mastering-your-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Branco Palhas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/mastering-your-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m all about efficiency. Not just code execution efficiency, but also
regarding my work tools, and my usage of them.Having been an avid
programmer and Linux user for several years now, and being obsessed with
my workflow efficiency, I’ve amassed a pretty good understanding of how
to improve productivity when it comes to writing code. From small but
powerful configurations for my text editor that took me weeks to find to
some not-so- well-known tools, I’m always thinking about how I can tweak
my environment and workflow to perfection. Have you ever considered how
many keys you hit during the day? And how can you go about minimizing
that and train your muscle memory to make you more efficient? And what
about that thing you’re not even noticing you’re spending so much time
on, and that you could improve on?This talk will focus on very practical
advice aimed at answering the above questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Open edX, soluzione per l'e-learning basata su Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/open-edx-soluzione-per-le-learning-basata-su-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Davide Corio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/open-edx-soluzione-per-le-learning-basata-su-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open edX è una soluzione open source basata (quasi) interamente su
Django per l’erogazione di Massive Open Online Courses (MOOC). La
soluzione è stata concepita dal Massachusetts Institute of Technology
(MIT) e dalla Harvard University. Anche se al team di lavoro si sono ora
uniti altri nomi illustri come la Stanford University, Microsoft e molti
altri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk approfondiremo le funzionalità offerte da Open edX, la
sua architettura e qualche cenno di sviluppo di estensioni e moduli
aggiuntivi.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="E-learning"></category><category term="MOOC"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Pilotare un braccio robotico dal cloud con GenroPy e Raspberry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/pilotare-un-braccio-robotico-dal-cloud-con-genropy-e-raspberry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michele Bertoldi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/pilotare-un-braccio-robotico-dal-cloud-con-genropy-e-raspberry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spesso con gli applicativi in cloud si pone il problema di pilotare
periferiche presenti nella rete locale o collegate direttamente al
computer come registratori di cassa, stampanti industriali o altri
dispositivi. Per superare questa difficoltà abbiamo sviluppato un client
in Python sfruttando il framework GenroPy e installandolo sul proprio
computer o su una scheda RaspberryPi possiamo pilotare le periferiche
dal software in cloud. Il software è scritto interamente in Python ed è
studiato per usare un sistema a plugin grazie al quale basta scrivere un
solo modulo Python per aggiungere le funzionalità specifiche di una
singola periferica. Nel talk mostreremo come pilotare un piccolo braccio
robotico direttamente dal web sfruttando i WebSocket per la
comunicazione con il server, le Bag di GenroPy per la messaggistica e
qualche componente elettronico per il collegamento fisico con il
braccio.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="raspberrypi"></category><category term="genropy"></category><category term="robotics"></category></entry><entry><title>Python and the Commissioning of the Advanced Virgo Gravitational Waves Detector</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-and-the-commissioning-of-the-advanced-virgo-gravitational-waves-detector.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Franco Carbognani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/python-and-the-commissioning-of-the-advanced-virgo-gravitational-waves-detector.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the announcement of the first direct detection of gravitational
waves on February 2016, the Virgo Collaboration is thriving to complete
the integration and commissioning of the Advanced Virgo detector in
order to provide, as soon as possible, its decisive contribution to the
international network of gravitational wave detectors. Having at least
three detectors working simultaneously is essential for the localization
of the sources in the sky. In this talk I will present an overview on
the status of the Advanced Virgo detector highlighting the challenges
encountered during its commissioning and how Python is helping in facing
them in particular for the detector supervisory control automation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python e swift: linguaggi a confronto</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-e-swift-linguaggi-a-confronto.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lelio Campanile</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/python-e-swift-linguaggi-a-confronto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quando Apple decise di affiancare all’objective C un altro linguaggio
per consentire lo sviluppo di app sulla piattaforma iOS, moltissime voci
di corridoio davano python per essere stato scelto per questo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come sappiamo alla fine non è andata così, ma è stato creato un
linguaggio totalmente nuovo: Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk andremo a scoprire affinità e differenze tra python e
swift.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="Swift"></category><category term="python3"></category></entry><entry><title>Python + Windows, like a boss</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-windows-like-a-boss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicola Iarocci</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/python-windows-like-a-boss.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically, Python coding on Windows has been kind of troublesome, but
not anymore. Since a couple of years ago it is possible write awesome
quality Python code with Visual Studio. This is good news for Python
developers of all levels, because Visual Studio offers and incredible
set of tools to enhance all the stages of product development: from
managing virtual environments and handling package management, to
writing and refactoring code, up to testing &amp;amp; debugging - all of that
for free. In this talk I will demo how you can use PTVS to boost your
Python development on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="windows"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="IDE"></category></entry><entry><title>Regole pratiche per testare la documentazione</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/regole-pratiche-per-testare-la-documentazione.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Buttu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/regole-pratiche-per-testare-la-documentazione.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nel lontano 1999 Tim Peters fece alcune
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/comp.lang.python/DfzH5Nrt05E/Yyd3s7fPVxwJ"&gt;considerazioni&lt;/a&gt;
in merito alla documentazione del codice. Scrisse che &lt;em&gt;gli esempi non
hanno prezzo&lt;/em&gt;, che &lt;em&gt;gli esempi che non funzionano sono peggio di quelli
inutili&lt;/em&gt;, e che &lt;em&gt;gli esempi che funzionano alla fine diventano esempi
che non funzionano&lt;/em&gt;. Queste sostanzialmente furono le motivazioni che lo
spinsero a scrivere il modulo
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/doctest.html"&gt;doctest&lt;/a&gt; della
libreria standard. Da quel momento nel mondo Python si è iniziato a
prestare particolare attenzione ai test della documentazione. Non
abbastanza però. Si pensi che attualmente (inizio 2017), la
documentazione ufficiale di Python conta circa 450 failures su 2100 test
complessivi. Questi fallimenti sono dovuti solo in minima parte ad
esempi errati. Generalmente (ma anche in questo caso specifico) le cause
sono la mancanza di isolamento tra i test, assieme alla scarsa
dimestichezza con il framework di test. Entrambe le cause possono
portare a brutte sorprese, come ad esempio dei test ballerini, che a
volte passano e a volte no, senza apparente motivo. Lo scopo di questo
talk è quindi mostrare come scrivere correttamente gli esempi ed il
codice presenti nella documentazione (doc utente, tutorial, docstring,
libri, o altro), in modo da tenere sotto controllo la situazione ed
evitare spiacevoli sorprese e perdite di tempo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materiale: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marco-buttu/pycon8"&gt;https://github.com/marco-buttu/pycon8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="documentation"></category><category term="sphinx"></category><category term="doctest"></category><category term="testing"></category></entry><entry><title>Roboto Framework for Test Code Coverage for cloud services.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/roboto-framework-for-test-code-coverage-for-cloud-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>khushbu parakh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/roboto-framework-for-test-code-coverage-for-cloud-services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test case design is an important phase of software testing life cycle
where test cases are identified. Designing test cases for cloud
solutions requires a different approach from traditional application
oriented testing. The quality which is multidimensional will include
more attributes like network resiliency, fault recovery, reliability and
availability when it comes to cloud-based solutions. If such aspects
when not encompassed through test development framework, it will lead to
high chances of defect leakage in production in an agile mode of
delivery. We propose a strategy to design the test cases which traverse
across different levels of testing to find gaps using the Roboto
framework with Python. The solution provides the teams and the product
owners to get a picture of what is getting tested and how much of
coverage is done. The data can be used in team release discussions to
build confidence in the tests that gets executed as part of that
release. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/robotframework/robotframework"&gt;https://github.com/robotframework/robotframework&lt;/a&gt; Testing
performed for features in a product is diverse and can be widely
categorized into functional, non-functional like reliability, fault
injections etc. Though developing test cases for functional changes is
achievable, arriving at test cases for non-functional requirements is
challenging in the given two-week sprint cycle of agile, and so leads to
defect leakage. Some vital modules in a project would have been running
in production for years and would have different sets of teams working
at different periods. Quantifying test code coverage and quality only by
a number of test cases per feature does not suffice as testing is
multidimensional and has to span across different levels. Measuring and
improving the test code coverage is the challenge generally faced by
product teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="quality-assurance"></category><category term="Functional Testing"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="robustness"></category><category term="integration"></category><category term="automation"></category><category term="framework"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="google-cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Taiga e l’agile project management: join the Oompa Loompas’ Army!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/taiga-e-lagile-project-management-join-the-oompa-loompas-army.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriele Giaccari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/taiga-e-lagile-project-management-join-the-oompa-loompas-army.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Taiga is a project management platform for agile developers &amp;amp; designers
and project managers who want a beautiful tool that makes work truly
enjoyable”. Nominato “best agile tool” nel 2015, Taiga si dimostra
semplice, versatile e sopratutto fedele ai framework agili. Durante il
talk si presenteranno le principali funzionalità e i modi di utilizzo
relazionandoli alle relative pratiche agili e confrontandoli con il suo
concorrente diretto: Jira.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="project-management-platform"></category><category term="agile"></category><category term="kanban"></category><category term="taiga"></category><category term="scrum"></category></entry><entry><title>Tensor decomposition with Python: Learning structures from multidimensional data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/tensor-decomposition-with-python-learning-structures-from-multidimensional-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>André Panisson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/tensor-decomposition-with-python-learning-structures-from-multidimensional-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many problems in signal processing and machine learning generate massive
amounts of multidimensional data. Data sources from sensor networks and
Internet-of-Things applications promise a wealth of interaction data
that can be naturally represented as tensors. Tensor decompositions have
gained a steadily increasing popularity in data mining and machine
learning, with applications in psychometrics, chemometrics, signal
processing, computer vision, neuroscience, graph analysis, and more. For
example, time-varying social networks collected from wearable proximity
sensors can be represented as 3-way tensors, and tensor decomposition
can be used to extract community structures with their structural and
temporal signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current standard framework for working with tensors, however, is
Matlab. We will show how tensor decompositions can be carried out using
Python, how to obtain latent components and how they can be interpreted,
and what are some applications of this technique in the academy and
industry. We will see a use case where a Python implementation of tensor
decomposition is applied to a dataset that describes face-to-face social
interactions of people, collected using the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sociopatterns.org/"&gt;SocioPatterns&lt;/a&gt; platform. This
platform was deployed in different settings such as conferences, schools
and hospitals, in order to support mathematical modelling and simulation
of airborne infectious diseases. Tensor decomposition has been used in
these scenarios to solve different types of problems: it is used for
data cleaning, where time-varying graph anomalies can be identified and
removed from data; it have been also used to assess the impact of
face-to-face interactions in the spreading of diseases. These examples
show the potential of this technique in data mining and machine learning
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mathematical-modelling"></category><category term="datamining"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I still develop synchronous web in the asyncIO era</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/why-i-still-develop-synchronous-web-in-the-asyncio-era.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giovanni Barillari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/why-i-still-develop-synchronous-web-in-the-asyncio-era.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since python 3.4 the introduction of the asyncIO module produced a new
way of building web applications and tons of new frameworks. With
asyncIO we take advantage of large throughput over the network, but is
it really everything about web development?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="web"></category><category term="asyncio"></category><category term="web-development"></category><category term="backend"></category></entry><entry><title>ZimboPy: Empowering Zimbabwean Girls As Change Makers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marlene Mhangami</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZimboPy is an organic, on-the-ground effort by a local non-profit
organization and Python developers in the Harare software development
community to advance the cause of women in technology in Zimbabwe. The
program operates in community centers, universities, high schools and
tech hubs to make programming accessible to girls regardless of their
socio-economic status. Upon initially joining a ZimboPy club, many of
the girls would have never used a computer before, let alone code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Zimbabwe, only 17% of computer science undergraduate majors are
women, and in the developing world, women make up less than 20% of the
information and technology workforce. ZimboPy exists to empower
Zimbabwean girls with the skills and confidence necessary to not only
enter the local tech industry, but to lead it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to learning to code, ZimboPy club members also join a global
network of women in technology that are working to tackle social
challenges through human-centered design and computer science. ZimboPy’s
mentorship program invites experienced women developers, mainly from the
United States and Europe, to help Zimbabwean girls address local
problems which can be solved with technology, such as clean water and
e-commerce solutions for small shops in towns and villages. Mentors will
travel to Zimbabwe and work with girls as they develop a plan for their
applications and pair-program with them, answering questions and
providing feedback along the way. To ensure that the girls are
successful, mentors will continue to work with their groups even after
leaving the country through weekly video conferences and email feedback.
Overall, ZimboPy looks forward to changing Zimbabwe’s future through
creativity, collaboration and the power of Python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="internationalization"></category><category term="School"></category><category term="Learning"></category><category term="problem solving"></category></entry><entry><title>42 PyCharm Tips and Tricks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/42-pycharm-tips-and-tricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dmitry Trofimov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/42-pycharm-tips-and-tricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCharm, a Python IDE with its free and open-source community edition,
in last several years has become a tool of choice for more and more
Python developers. But not everybody uses its full power. Moreover, most
only use a fraction of the functionality it provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is that an IDE is not just about a set of integrated tools,
but an environment that understands the semantics of your project, of
what you’re doing. It can leverage this to provide you with
functionality that can make repetitive mundane tasks become
frictionless, as well as give insight into potential problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will go through 42 the most powerful features the
IDE offers and whether you do web development or work with data using
Python, you will benefit knowing how the IDE can leverage your
programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="text-editors"></category><category term="Pycharm"></category><category term="IDE"></category></entry><entry><title>Affrontare le sfide del cambiamento climatico con Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/affrontare-le-sfide-del-cambiamento-climatico-con-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessandro Amici</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/affrontare-le-sfide-del-cambiamento-climatico-con-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Che si intenda pianificare una attività industriale di lungo periodo,
come costruire un complesso sciistico, o semplicemente scegliere il
periodo ideale per le vacanze ai tropici è essenziale avere previsioni
affidabili sulle condizioni climatiche che si incontreranno. Cosa non
banale in un mondo in cui il clima sta cambiando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://climate.copernicus.eu"&gt;servizio per il monitoraggio del cambiamento climatico del programma
europeo Copernicus&lt;/a&gt; si avvia a
diventare la principale piattaforma per l’accesso e l’analisi dei dati
climatici in Europa il cui cuore, il Climate Data Store Toolbox, è
interamente basato su Python 3 e sullo stack di tecnologie del PyData
con l’aggiunta di tool specifici per trattare dati che riguardano
l’atmosfera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk presenterò i dati e gli strumenti di accesso e analisi
già disponibili e la roadmap verso il sistema completo attraverso
l’implementazione di vari casi d’uso.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="climate-change"></category><category term="notebook"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>AI, Machine Learning e Deep Learning: cosa cambia?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/ai-machine-learning-e-deep-learning-cosa-cambia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Antonio Spadaro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/ai-machine-learning-e-deep-learning-cosa-cambia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt; e &lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;:
cosa sono e qual’è la loro storia? Ma soprattutto quali sono le
differenze tra questi tre?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questo talk è orientato a coloro che non hanno alcuna base su nessuno di
questi argomenti&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Ansible roles, private git repos and the Ansible Galaxy tool</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/ansible-roles-private-git-repos-and-the-ansible-galaxy-tool.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>serena lorenzini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/ansible-roles-private-git-repos-and-the-ansible-galaxy-tool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a python tool that automates the management of an IT
infrastructure. It is easy to learn but rushing to use it with a limited
knowledge of its best practices leads to not reusable code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating reusable Ansible roles is a strongly encouraged practice, in
fact there is a tool designed just for this purpose: Ansible Galaxy. It
comes bundled with Ansible and its purpose is to download roles from the
Galaxy hub and other sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk wants to show how we manage our Ansible roles and their
dependencies in a consistent way by means of Ansible Galaxy. It will
also offer an overview of how Ansible roles can be tested.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="config-ninja"></category><category term="continuous-integration"></category><category term="command-line"></category><category term="gitlab"></category><category term="ansible"></category><category term="best-practices"></category></entry><entry><title>Applying the unix philosophy to django projects: a report from the real world</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/applying-the-unix-philosophy-to-django-projects-a-report-from-the-real-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Federico Capoano</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/applying-the-unix-philosophy-to-django-projects-a-report-from-the-real-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software architecture is often overlooked: pushed by deadlines and
hurry, we tend to make our applications a giant ball of mud. Here is
where the unix philosophy comes to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will give an overview of the unix philosophy and I will
explain how I have applied it to django development for the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://openwisp.org"&gt;OpenWISP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://netjson.org/"&gt;NetJSON&lt;/a&gt;
projects (a set of software modules and standard formats that can be
used to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://openwisp.org/whatis.html"&gt;deploy wireless networks and implement a public wifi
service&lt;/a&gt;) with encouraging results.
In this talk I will cover the benefits and the downside of such
approach, showing example implementations that are being tested in the
real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/FedericoCapoano/applying-the-unix-%20philosophy-to-django-projects-a-report-from-the-real-world"&gt;Slides are available on
slideshare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building Serverless applications with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/building-serverless-applications-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrii Soldatenko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/building-serverless-applications-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serverless applications in Python sounds, strange isn’t? In this talk
I’ll explain how to build not only crop images or select data from
DynamoDB, but build real application, what kind of troubles are we
should expect, how to make decision is your task fit into serverless
architecture in Python or may be you should use, general approach. How
fast serverless applications written in Python, and more important how
to scale it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="serverless"></category><category term="aws"></category><category term="lambda-functions"></category><category term="python3"></category></entry><entry><title>ByteCode al supporto dei test per protocolli ed enforcing di best practices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/bytecode-al-supporto-dei-test-per-protocolli-ed-enforcing-di-best-practices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessandro Molina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/bytecode-al-supporto-dei-test-per-protocolli-ed-enforcing-di-best-practices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python è un linguaggio interpretato con efficaci strumenti di
introspezione, fino a permetterci di accedere al suo bytecode e vedere
cosa la virtual machine sta per eseguire. Per quanto questa esigenza sia
solitamente molto limitata in ambito di produzione ed uso del software
può venirci utile all’interno delle test suite per verificare che il
codice scritto da terzi o dal noi stessi del domani rispetti ancora dei
protocolli o delle best practices che avevamo presupposto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La maggior parte di queste esigenze possono essere soddisfatte anche
tramite l’uso di metaclassi o monkeypatching, ma in alcuni casi è
possibile saltare i check preposti involontariamente (ad esempio
ereditando dalla classe sbagliata nel caso delle metaclassi), mentre la
verifica del byte code ci consente di controllare cosa effettivamente
sarà eseguito, non cosa ci aspettiamo sia eseguito.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="quality-assurance"></category><category term="CPython"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="robustness"></category><category term="static-typing"></category><category term="bytecode"></category><category term="hacking"></category><category term="compiler"></category></entry><entry><title>Digital Analytics Data Aggregation: un case study dal mondo reale utilizzando SQL, NoSQL e Pandas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/digital-analytics-data-aggregation-un-case-study-dal-mondo-reale-utilizzando-sql-nosql-e-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessandro Pelliciari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/digital-analytics-data-aggregation-un-case-study-dal-mondo-reale-utilizzando-sql-nosql-e-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I clienti enterprise si trovano sempre più spesso ad avere difficoltà
nel recuperare informazioni essenziali per capire nel complesso dove il
brand sta funzionando e dove invece serve un intervento tempestivo,
perchè sono inondati di dati di dettaglio che spesso non sono facilmente
aggregabili e visualizzabili insieme con frequenza giornaliera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per rispondere a questa esigenza, in azienda, nel nostro reparto R&amp;amp;D,
abbiamo sviluppato una dashboard che permette a clienti con diversi
brand e properties (siti) di aggregare i principali KPI da monitorare
(sia KPI standard che KPI personalizzati). I KPI sono i key performance
indicators, ovvero metriche che aiutano a valutare le performance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ma i dati da visualizzare e aggregare, provenienti da diverse fonti
(Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, tools SEO), hanno strutture diverse
e non è possibile a priori prevedere quali sono le strutture
disponibili.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perciò, in questo talk vedremo insieme come abbiamo gestito questo caso
reale attraverso un mix di tecnologie SQL (MySQL attraverso Django) e
NoSQL (MongoDb), utilizzando i dataframe di Pandas come layer intermedio
attraverso il quale lavorare il dato velocemente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La soluzione realizzata ci ha permesso di integrare rapidamente nuove
fonti e nuovi KPI, e di gestire volumi elevati di dati (attualmente 200+
siti contemporaneamente) con ottime performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vedremo poi (se rimane tempo) come questi dati vengono forniti
attraverso API Rest (grazie a Django Rest Framework) e consumati
attraverso AngularJS sul client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vorremmo infine coinvolgervi chiedendovi come avreste gestito questa
difficoltà - non è assolutamente detto che la nostra soluzione sia per
forza quella ottimale!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django-rest-framework"></category><category term="mongodb"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="API Design"></category><category term="web-development"></category><category term="angularjs"></category><category term="mysql"></category><category term="google-analytics"></category><category term="pandas"></category></entry><entry><title>Disaster recovery: una serie di sfortunati eventi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/disaster-recovery-una-serie-di-sfortunati-eventi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giulio Calacoci</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/disaster-recovery-una-serie-di-sfortunati-eventi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scambio di storie, esperienze, domande e risposte riguardo a
piccoli/medi/grandi disastri quotidiani (forse) realmente accaduti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durante l’esposizione il pubblico sarà legittimato a interrompere (nei
limiti del sensato) la narrazione dei relatori, al fine di sapere tutto
cioè che avrebbero sempre voluto sulla disaster recovery (su PostgreSQL)
e non hanno mai osato chiedere.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="#Horror"></category><category term="#PostrgreSQL"></category><category term="#DisasterRcovery"></category><category term="#Barman"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Rest Framework - Tips&amp;Tricks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/django-rest-framework-tipstricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca Zacchetti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/django-rest-framework-tipstricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing Web APIs for Django websites have never been so easy.
Starting from a real world use case, I’ll explain why DRF became our
weapon of choice to develop in a fast and easy way all the APIs we need
at Cloud Academy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start talking about the main benefits that DRF brings to Django
projects, then we’ll use our real world use case to describe the best
practices we use to build fast, secure and maintainable APIs diving into
DRF main features and functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of this talk is to explain in a very practical way how DRF can
be integrated into Django projects to build beautiful web APIs. We’ll
use a lot of code examples and performance benchmarks to describe the
various features explored during the talk. No prior experience on DRF is
required but at least some basic knowledge of Django is suggested for
attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django-rest-framework"></category><category term="REST API Frameworks"></category><category term="API Design"></category><category term="REST"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="performance"></category></entry><entry><title>E.T. chiama Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/et-chiama-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Davide Corio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/et-chiama-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All’osservatorio astronomico della Val Pellice in provincia di Torino,
le attività amministrative, didattiche, divulgative e scientifiche non
mancano di certo. L’osservatorio, gestito dall’&lt;a class="reference external" href="http:/osservatoriourania.it"&gt;Associazione Astrofili
Urania&lt;/a&gt;, dispone di diversi telescopi
ottici, di un planetario, di una biblioteca, di una sala
corsi/conferenze e di un radio telescopio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python è spesso un filo conduttore nel mondo scientifico e non solo, e a
prova di questo fatto vogliamo mostrarvi come lo usiamo noi
all’osservatorio. Mostreremo come Python viene usato per l’elaborazione
dei dati provenienti dal radio telescopio, che scruta il cielo alla
ricerca di segnali provenienti da esopianeti ed inviati potenzialmente
da altre forme di vita intelligente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altri cenni riguarderanno l’utilizzo di software basati su Python (come
Odoo) per la gestione di associazioni come la nostra.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pydata"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="data-logging"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="Odoo"></category><category term="astronomy"></category></entry><entry><title>Growing a Python community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about people, not tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share one recipe of building a community from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reveals hands-on experience about the organisational journey,
including insider details and financial questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is packed into the story, how one year ago a tempting
idea of making a little Python conference in Munich was born. Six month
later, with poor German skills, no business network and mostly foreign
crew a little idea was converted into PyCon.DE. This conference had a
noticeable Italian flavour, and it’s time to tell why.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="humor"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="beer"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>How to turn Wikipedia into a Quiz Game</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/how-to-turn-wikipedia-into-a-quiz-game.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Cappelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/how-to-turn-wikipedia-into-a-quiz-game.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiz games let people test their knowledge through multi-choice
questions. Unfortunately, generating such questions can be very
time-consuming and it is typically done manually. In this talk we
will present a pipeline to automatically generate quiz games starting
from generic knowledge (e.g. Wikipedia). The pipeline consists of the
following components: (i) a parser to retrieve text from Wikipedia
pages, (ii) a Natural Language Processing module (based on the Google
Natural Language API) to extract information about syntax, entities
and relations, (iii) a Natural Language Generation module to generate
test questions and correct answers, and finally (iv) a domain-aware
module that uses domain-specific knowledge to generate wrong answers
(i.e. distractors). Every module is written in Python and it is based
on either available libraries or Cloud services (e.g., Google Natural
Language).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: basic knowledge of python, minimal understanding
of text syntactic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="nlp"></category><category term="AI"></category><category term="games"></category><category term="computational-linguistics"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="text-analysis"></category><category term="google-cloud"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="linked-data"></category></entry><entry><title>How to use pandas the wrong way</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/how-to-use-pandas-the-wrong-way.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pietro Battiston</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/how-to-use-pandas-the-wrong-way.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pandas&lt;/strong&gt; library represents a very efficient and convenient tool
for data manipulation, but sometimes hides unexpected pitfalls which can
arise in various and sometimes unintelligible ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By briefly referring to some aspects of the internals, I will review
specific situations in which a change of approach can, for instance,
make a difference in terms of performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (April 12, 2017) - SLIDES:&lt;/strong&gt; the talk had very few slides;
still, you can find those few, together with the notebooks I used live,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pietrobattiston.it/python:pycon"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="data-science"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>Infrastructure as Code with Terraform</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/infrastructure-as-code-with-terraform.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justyna Janczyszyn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/infrastructure-as-code-with-terraform.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is infrastructure as code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introduction to terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practical demo for a sample flask application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tramwaj29/iac-with-terraform"&gt;https://github.com/tramwaj29/iac-with-terraform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="provisioning"></category><category term="terraform"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="infrastructure-as-code"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Data-Analysis with Pandas / Time Series Analysis with Pandas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/introduction-to-data-analysis-with-pandas-time-series-analysis-with-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Hendorf</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/introduction-to-data-analysis-with-pandas-time-series-analysis-with-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is the &lt;em&gt;Swiss-Multipurpose Knife&lt;/em&gt; for Data Analysis in Python.
With Pandas dealing with data-analysis is easy and simple but there are
some things you need to get your head around first as Data-Frames and
Data-Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;first part&lt;/strong&gt; of talk with provide an &lt;strong&gt;introduction to Pandas&lt;/strong&gt;
for beginners, while the &lt;strong&gt;second part&lt;/strong&gt; will focus on &lt;strong&gt;Time Series
Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; with Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; (~40&amp;quot;) &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Pandas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading and writing data across multiple formats (CSV, Excel, JSON,
SQL, HTML,…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;statistical data analysis and aggregation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work with built-in data visualisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inner-mechanics of Pandas: Data-Frames, Data-Series &amp;amp; Numpy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; (~20&amp;quot;) &lt;em&gt;Time Series Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to analyse periodical data with pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to mangle, reshape and pivot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caveats when working with timed data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visualize your data on the fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bonus (if we have time left)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gain insights with statsmodels (e.g. seasonality)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="computer-science"></category><category term="statistics"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>Is it too late to learn how to program and how being a developer changed my life</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/is-it-too-late-to-learn-how-to-program-and-how-being-a-developer-changed-my-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alicia Carr</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/is-it-too-late-to-learn-how-to-program-and-how-being-a-developer-changed-my-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How I became a developer in my 50th. the challenges, the assumption and
the victories and how women are not being recognized as an important
part of the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How and why I wanted to be an iOS mobile developer at the age of 51.
Some people want to believe that people my age are out of touch with
technology and as a woman, I have seen the best and the worst in the
tech community but I also now that there is a solution at the end of the
rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the boom in use of smartphones, we have seen a corresponding growth
in numbers of available apps, some of which are being leveraged for
social change. What people don’t know is 70% of women are more active on
our mobile device than men, women are more active with social media,
shopping, photo apps, are more connected to entertainers and play more
games on their smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said we the tech community need to open up our arm and
embrace the change and think about how women in tech can change the way
we see and create apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="android"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Jupyter: if you don't use it yet you're doing wrong</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/jupyter-if-you-dont-use-it-yet-youre-doing-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Barra</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/jupyter-if-you-dont-use-it-yet-youre-doing-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard about Jupyter Notebook ? It’s like Python REPL on
steroids !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce the Jupyter project, the libraries behind
this project and how you can use Jupyter Notebook for a lot of
activities like fast prototyping, data science, education and so on !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be an introduction, Beginners are welcome !&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="iPython"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>L'Italia, Python e la chimera dell'Agile</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/litalia-python-e-la-chimera-dellagile.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Iacopo Spalletti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/litalia-python-e-la-chimera-dellagile.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sono quasi certo che il proverbio “tra il dire e il fare c’è di mezzo
il mare” lo abbiano inventato pensando alle metodologie agili. Forse
in USA o in Svezia ci riescono davvero, ma in Italia? Possiamo dire
di essere agili quando di test ne facciamo “ un po’ “, i task degli
sprint li decide il cliente e il contratto prevede un budget fissato
e una deadline prestabilita? E com’è la situazione tra i pythonisti?
Ne parliamo con Marco Beri, Iacopo Spalletti, Roberto Bettazzoni e
Peter Bittner in un panel dove siete tutti invitati a partecipare e
condividere casi di successo e scheletri nell’armadio.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning con Python: algoritmi NILM e real-time processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-algoritmi-nilm-e-real-time-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felice Tuosto</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-algoritmi-nilm-e-real-time-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le tecniche di Machine Learning sono sempre più pervasive nelle
applicazioni analitiche odierne. In questo talk l’attenzione verte sul
problema del &lt;strong&gt;NILM&lt;/strong&gt; (Not Intrusive Load Monitoring) per cui
l’obiettivo è la disaggregazione real-time dei consumi di energia
elettrica. Gli algoritmi, permettono di riconoscere in realtime i
dispositivi attivi in base alle sole caratteristiche del segnale
aggregato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’obiettivo del talk è dimostrare come sia possibile implementare
rapidamente un prototipo hardware e software grazie alle potenzialità di
Arduino e Python rispettivamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Con degli &lt;em&gt;esempi hardware e software pratici&lt;/em&gt; (4 devices collegati ad
una multipresa), verrà dimostrata la capacità di Arduino di acquisire le
misura di corrente elettrica e la capacità di Python di riconoscere i
dispositivi attivi. Verranno fornite informazioni sulle logiche alla
base di tali algoritmi, con riferimento all’ecosistema Python e alle
relative librerie utilizzate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per la comprensione del talk non sono necessari particolari requisiti se
non una conoscenza di base di programmazione in Python e di Machine
Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="signal-processing"></category><category term="arduino"></category><category term="nilm"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="realtime"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning con Python: previsione in real-time della richiesta di energia elettrica</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-previsione-in-real-time-della-richiesta-di-energia-elettrica.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felice Tuosto</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-previsione-in-real-time-della-richiesta-di-energia-elettrica.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nel talk si parlerà di come attraverso il linguaggio Python sia
possibile risolvere un problema reale e complesso relativamente alla
trasmissione di energia elettrica. Verrà spiegato il progetto
&lt;strong&gt;RealtimeLoadForecast&lt;/strong&gt; che è stato sviluppato per un importante TSO
(Transmission System Operator). Si tratta di sistema predittivo che
permette di fornire in tempo reale ogni 15 minuti ed entro 5 minuti, le
previsioni delle serie storiche dei consumi di energia elettrica
relativi a circa 500 nodi elettrici.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si parlerà dei passi che occorre seguire per ottenere da un semplice
prototipo, un sistema &lt;em&gt;ingegnerizzato&lt;/em&gt; che lavori in tempo reale e di
come sono state utilizzate le librerie di Python per l’acquisizione,
manipolazione e processamento dei dati elettrici ed ambientali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saranno descritte alcune tecniche algoritmiche e di Machine Learning per
ottenere dei modelli predittivi capaci di fornire previsioni accurate ma
con tempi di risposta sfidanti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrà mostrato un &lt;em&gt;esempio concreto&lt;/em&gt; di implementazione di un algoritmo
predittivo basato sulla libreria Deep Learning &lt;strong&gt;Keras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per la comprensione del talk non sono necessari particolari requisiti se
non una conoscenza di base di programmazione in Python e di Machine
Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Forecasting"></category><category term="Genetic Algorithms"></category><category term="Keras"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="programming-paradigms"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="threading"></category><category term="realtime"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="mysql"></category><category term="signal-processing"></category><category term="LoadForecasting"></category><category term="cassandra"></category></entry><entry><title>Nipy on functional brain MRI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/nipy-on-functional-brain-mri.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexandre Savio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/nipy-on-functional-brain-mri.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you seen the Kaggle competition on brain functional MRI (fMRI)? It
was called: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/mlsp-2014-mri"&gt;MLSP 2014 Schizophrenia Classification
Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The number of
public databases of neuroimaging data is increasing and with them, the
number of scientific open questions regarding its pre- and
post-processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They offered 2 types of features: Functional Network Connectivity (FNC)
and Source-Based Morphometry (SBM) loadings. These features are obtained
through a pre-processing pipeline that can be rather complex and still
presents many open scientific questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will show in this talk some tools on how to deal with this type of
data, how to use Python to do most of the pre-processing of one
subject’s fMRI data, and one way to create a functional connectivity
matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find the slides
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alexsavio/pydata2017-florence-talk"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Source: Pathway to Development Freedom</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/open-source-pathway-to-development-freedom.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Perkins</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/open-source-pathway-to-development-freedom.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris Perkins - Open Source: Pathway to Development Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Overcoming Cognitive Bias</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/overcoming-cognitive-bias.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Ravenscroft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/overcoming-cognitive-bias.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be expanding on previous talks to describe how built-in
mechanisms in our brains lead to cognitive bias, how cognitive biases
manifest in the Python and tech community, and how to overcome these
biases.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Panel: Microsoft Azure integration with Open Technologies</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/panel-microsoft-azure-integration-with-open-technologies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicola Iarocci</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/panel-microsoft-azure-integration-with-open-technologies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La posizione di Microsoft verso tecnologie Open Source si basa su quattro pilastri:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abilitazione di numerosissime tecnologie Open Source sulla piattaforma Cloud di Microsoft, che prende il nome di Microsoft Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrazione nativa di diverse tecnologie Open Source con prodotti Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rilascio di diverse tecnologie Microsoft in modalità Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributo alla realizzazione di progetti Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racconto e dimostrazione della integrazione della piattaforma cloud di Microsoft con il mondo non-Microsoft&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Performant Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/performant-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>George Berhnard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/performant-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a great language. Easy to learn, friendly to use, widely used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not, however, renowned for being fast. In a lot of situations
that does not matter. Sometimes it really does. This talk will
introduce you to some tools and techniques for making sure your
Python code becomes fast enough – without turning into a maintenance
nightmare. Fast code does not have to be unreadable - and when you’re
writing Python, it really pays of to think “pythonically”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That does mean using the included batteries, and utilising the
ecosystem of tools around the language, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: may contain small bits of other languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PostgreSQL su NFS: miti e verità</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/postgresql-su-nfs-miti-e-verita.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Battiato</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/postgresql-su-nfs-miti-e-verita.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abbiamo avuto l’occasione di lavorare alla richiesta di un cliente, di
valutare in maniera obiettiva la possibilità di basare un database
PostgreSQL su Network File System. Sono stati scritti molti articoli a
riguardo, ma quando si ha l’opportunità di mettere in pratica questa
configurazione in prima persona, ci si rende conto che ancora molto non
è stato documentato. Le prestazioni di NFS possono essere molto buone,
ma si abbassano notevolmente quando si inseriscono vincoli di
affidabilità. Una soluzione può essere quella di basare PostreSQL su 2
partizioni NFS, una per i dati e una per gli xlog, in modo distinguere
una configurazione per un rapido accesso ai dati e una con maggiore
affidabilità per le scritture consistenti dei WAL. In questo talk vorrei
sottoporre la mia personale esperienza esponendo quali sono stati i test
effettuati per considerare PostgreSQL su NFS un’opzione molto
interessante, sfatando miti e constatando fatti.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="nfs"></category><category term="postgresql"></category></entry><entry><title>Python e PostgreSQL, un connubio perfetto</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-e-postgresql-un-connubio-perfetto.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Nenciarini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/python-e-postgresql-un-connubio-perfetto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL ha come obiettivi primari l’integrità dei dati,
l’affidabilità e le caratteristiche integrate orientate agli
sviluppatori. Per questo molti progetti lo scelgono fin dall’inizio. In
questo talk vedremo come PostgreSQL e Python si integrano su più
livelli, e come sia possibile sfruttare in Python le caratteristiche
avanzate di questo database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://prezi.com/5kvmyfmqp1mt/"&gt;http://prezi.com/5kvmyfmqp1mt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django-orm"></category><category term="psycopg2"></category><category term="pl/python"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="database"></category></entry><entry><title>Ricerca full text in Django con PostgreSQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/ricerca-full-text-in-django-con-postgresql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paolo Melchiorre</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/ricerca-full-text-in-django-con-postgresql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dalla versione 1.10 di &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt; è presente il modulo che facilita
l’utilizzo del motore di &lt;strong&gt;ricerca full text&lt;/strong&gt; di PostgreSQL. Dal
momento che &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; è utilizzato in molti progetti Django,
sfruttare il suo motore di ricerca full text permette di avere questa
funzionalità molto facilmente, senza dover configurare prodotti esterni
e senza doversi preoccupare di mantenere sincronizzati i dati tra
differenti sistemi. Vedremo come abbiamo sfruttato questa funzionalità
di ricerca full text in un &lt;strong&gt;progetto reale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Full Text Search"></category><category term="search"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Serverless computing con Python e AWS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/serverless-computing-con-python-e-aws.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Federico Caboni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/serverless-computing-con-python-e-aws.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Il paradigma serverless è una delle innovazioni più recenti e
interessanti negli ultimi anni: l’idea di base è quella di poter
pubblicare, nel Cloud, funzioni e pezzi di codice che vengono invocati
automaticamente al verificarsi di certi eventi, con scalabilità
potenzialmente infinita e senza doversi preoccupare della gestione dello
stack tecnologico sottostante.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel corso di questo talk vi mostrerò:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;la più breve introduzione al Cloud Computing del mondo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cosa sono i microservizi e come funzione il paradigma serverless;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quali sono i casi d’uso che beneficiano di più da questo paradigma;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;come costruire un’applicazione serverless in Python con i componenti
di Amazon Web Services (Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB, S3…);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;come coordinare l’esecuzione del nostro codice Python (AWS Step
Functions);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;come rendere tutto ancora più semplice con l’uso di framework
specifici (Chalice, Serverless)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e, se avanza tempo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;il senso della vita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="serverless"></category><category term="microservices"></category><category term="CloudComputing"></category><category term="aws"></category><category term="chalice"></category><category term="Amazon"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Solving the web most popular code shortening competition with Python 3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/solving-the-web-most-popular-code-shortening-competition-with-python-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessandro Amici</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/solving-the-web-most-popular-code-shortening-competition-with-python-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Code shortening” is the “sport” where participants strive to achieve
the shortest possible source code that solves a programming problem by
exploiting all the tricks and quirks of the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoj.com/problems/SIZECON"&gt;SIZECON problem&lt;/a&gt; on SPOJ
is one of the oldest and most popular code shortening problems on the
web with a bizarre twist, only character above ASCII value 32 are
counted for the penalty. During the talk we will take a journey into
some frightening depths of the Python language in order to write shorter
and shorter solutions to SIZECON until, exploiting a number of
mind-blowing tricks, we will reach the current record solution for
Python 3 of 31 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise I’ll show you the most obfuscated, contrived and sick python
code you have ever seen and (hopefully!) will ever see. I invite
participants to give &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoj.com/problems/SIZECON"&gt;SIZECON&lt;/a&gt;
a try and check their score against the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoj.com/ranks/SIZECON/lang=PYTH%203.2.3"&gt;Python3
rankings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an updated version of a talk I presented during Europython 2015
and that had an unexpected success both on-site and on social media. The
talk is now centred on Python 3 shorting tricks and is has been reworked
to be much more easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="coding-competitions"></category><category term="fun-and-humor"></category><category term="python3"></category></entry><entry><title>Taking care of PostgreSQL with Ansible</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/taking-care-of-postgresql-with-ansible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rubens Souza</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/taking-care-of-postgresql-with-ansible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful automation tool written in &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;. With
its modules already built for &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt;, we can easily manage the
most advanced open source database, making sure the configuration is
exact in every detail and repeatable as many times as it is needed. In
this talk we will understand how &lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; works, see some of its main
modules for system/cloud administration, and learn how it can be used to
orchestrate &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; deployments, managing all parts of the
process at ease. A &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; test environment configuration, using
&lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Vagrant&lt;/strong&gt;, will be shown as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="automation"></category><category term="ansible"></category></entry><entry><title>Validazione e decodifica di file XML con Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/validazione-e-decodifica-di-file-xml-con-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Davide Brunato</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/validazione-e-decodifica-di-file-xml-con-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Per la schematizzazione di documenti XML sono disponibili diversi
standard, tra questi XML Schema. La prima problematica è quella di poter
validare file XML secondo il loro rispettivo schema. Un’altra esigenza è
la conversione dell’XML in strutture dati in cui siano valorizzati i
tipi base definiti nello schema e la struttura nidificata in cui sono
inseriti, similmente a quello che è già reso disponibile per JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ambito scientifico, nell’ambito delle attività del progetto europeo
MaX (Materials design at the Exascale), per semplificare l’interscambio
di dati dati XML tra diversi software di simulazione, si è deciso di
adottare un approccio unitario e sistematico alla validazione e alla
decodifica dei dati XML prodotti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pertanto è in fase di sviluppo una nuova libreria (xmlschema), basata
sulla libreria standard ElementTree di Python, che permette di validare
e decodificare dati XML con schemi XSD. La decodifica di un documento
XML produce un dizionario nidificato con i valori terminali appartenenti
ai corrispondenti tipi elementari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nella presentazione parlerei delle problematiche degli schemi XSD,
dell’ambito scientifico in cui è stata sviluppata la libreria e della
struttura della libreria stessa, illustrando e magari raccogliendo
qualche idea per migliorarla.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="xml"></category><category term="mathematical-modelling"></category><category term="encoding"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="simulation"></category><category term="validation"></category><category term="physics"></category><category term="metadata"></category></entry><entry><title>Word Embedding: come codificare il linguaggio naturale per algoritmi di previsione e classificazione</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/word-embedding-come-codificare-il-linguaggio-naturale-per-algoritmi-di-previsione-e-classificazione.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felice Tuosto</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/word-embedding-come-codificare-il-linguaggio-naturale-per-algoritmi-di-previsione-e-classificazione.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Da qualche anno si parla sempre più insistentemente di &lt;em&gt;Word Embedding&lt;/em&gt;,
identificando così quell’insieme di tecniche che tentano di modellare il
linguaggio umano creando una mappatura delle parole nel campo
vettoriale. Come spesso accade per ambiti in rapido sviluppo, si è
assistito alla nascita di diversi approcci algoritmici tra i quali a
volte è difficile districarsi. Da questo punto di vista un linguaggio di
propotipazione rapida come Python consente l’implementazione e
l’utilizzo di una serie di librerie al fine di scegliere di volta in
volta quelle che meglio modellano il problema in esame. Il talk mostra
la potenzialità del word embedding entrando nel merito di due
applicazioni reali relative a due contesti lontani fra loro, quali
quelli della pubblica amministrazione e del privato. In ambito PA viene
mostrato come, analizzando le descrizioni progettuali presentate da un
insieme di aziende ad un importante istituto italiano, è possibile
prevedere l’esito delle rispettive richieste di finanziamento,
consentendo di aumentare in modo sostanziale il numero degli
investimenti. Nella seconda parte ci spostiamo invece nel privato e
mostriamo come codificare un’informazione naturalmente non strutturata,
come la descrizione di un intervento in una officina meccanica,
rendendola così gestibile al pari di quella strutturata.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="word_embedding"></category><category term="embedding"></category><category term="text_mining"></category></entry><entry><title>Word Embeddings for Natural Language Processing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/word-embeddings-for-natural-language-processing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Bonzanini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/word-embeddings-for-natural-language-processing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Word embeddings are a family of Natural Language Processing (NLP)
algorithms where words are mapped to vectors in low-dimensional space.
The interest around word embeddings has been on the rise in the past few
years, because these techniques have been driving important improvements
in many NLP applications like text classification, sentiment analysis or
machine translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll describe the intuitions behind this family of
algorithms, we’ll explore some of the Python tools that allow us to
implement modern NLP applications and we’ll conclude with some practical
considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="nlp"></category><category term="text-analysis"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>A Gentle Introduction to Neural Networks (with Python)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/a-gentle-introduction-to-neural-networks-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tariq Rashid</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/a-gentle-introduction-to-neural-networks-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A gentle introduction to neural networks, and making your own with
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session is especially designed to be accessible to everyone,
including anyone with no expertise in mathematics, computer science or
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this session you will have an intuitive understanding of what
neural networks are and how they work. If you are more technically
capable, you will see how you could make your own with Python and numpy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 1 - Ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the search for AI, hard problems for computers easy for humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning from examples (simple classifier)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;biologically inspired neurons and networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;training a neural network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the back propagation breakthrough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matrix ways of working (good for computers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 - Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python is easy, and everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python notebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MNIST data set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a very simple neural network class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus on concise and efficient matrix calculations with numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;97.5% accuracy recognising handwritten numbers - with just a few lines of code!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 3 - Live Demo! … and Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="image-processing"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="neural network"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>A year of Genropy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/a-year-of-genropy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Muhammad Hassan Khurshid</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/a-year-of-genropy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The presentation focuses on the use of Genropy in a year,from the first
difficulties to first successes, analyzing the pros and cons of its use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the talk there will be a small presentation of two projects made
with Genropy. The first project is the one I have worked on in the last
year, a platform that analyzes energy data. The second one is Genrello,
a Trello made with Genropy, developed in spare time as a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk does not require any preconditions for the comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="genropy"></category><category term="framework"></category></entry><entry><title>Amazon Web Services for dummies - tips and tricks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/amazon-web-services-for-dummies-tips-and-tricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justyna Janczyszyn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/amazon-web-services-for-dummies-tips-and-tricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Amazon Web Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical demo including the use of EC2, S3, RDS, CloudFront, IAM,
CloudFormation and command line tools for a sample Django application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tramwaj29/aws-for-dummies"&gt;https://github.com/tramwaj29/aws-for-dummies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Amazon"></category><category term="monitoring"></category><category term="EC2"></category></entry><entry><title>An Introduction to web scraping using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/an-introduction-to-web-scraping-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manoj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/an-introduction-to-web-scraping-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web scraping is a technique for gathering data or information on web
pages. You could revisit your favorite web site every time it updates
for new information. Or you could write a web scraper to have it do it
for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to scrape the web (and / or organized data sets and
APIs) for content? This talk will give you the building blocks (and
code) to begin your own scraping adventures. We will review basic data
scraping, API usage, form submission as well as how to scrape pesky bits
like Javascript-usage for DOM manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides looking at how websites are put together, we will also discuss
the ethics of scraping. What is legal? How can you be a friendly
scraper, so that the administrator of the website you are scraping won’t
try to shut you down?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="information-retrieval"></category><category term="regex"></category><category term="web-scraping"></category><category term="lxml"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="beautifulsoup"></category></entry><entry><title>Analisi dati e grafici con Genropy e Pandas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/analisi-dati-e-grafici-con-genropy-e-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Francesco Porcari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/analisi-dati-e-grafici-con-genropy-e-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
offre ad utenti e sviluppatori un ambiente di lavoro molto comodo per il
caricamento e la gestione dei dati. In questo talk parleremo degli
strumenti messi a disposizione per l’analisi dei dati e la
rappresentazione grafica, tabellare e in dashboard. Parleremo in
particolare dell’integrazione con Pandas e di come sia facile anche per
un utente non particolarmente esperto generare pivot table, e creare
colonne calcolate e mostrare i risultati come grafici.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="genropy"></category><category term="webapp"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="web-development"></category><category term="graph"></category></entry><entry><title>Basic principles of scientific data visualization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/basic-principles-of-scientific-data-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Jurman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/basic-principles-of-scientific-data-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific data visualization has its rules, and they are essential to
warrant effectiveness of the desired message one wants to convey. In
this talk, following the guidelines of Edward Tufte, a master of data
visualization, we show why these rules are important, and what happens
if some of them are not properly followed and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DataVisualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Be(come) a Mentor! Help Others Succeed!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/become-a-mentor-help-others-succeed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Ossowski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/become-a-mentor-help-others-succeed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of us are lifelong learners. Especially in technology there is
always something new to learn so we are always experts in one and
beginners in another field. In order to learn, make progress, and
succeed, it’s really helpful to have a mentor. But it’s equally
important to learn how to be a good mentor to others. All of us started
out as beginners and if it wasn’t for the help of others, who shared
their knowledge with us, lent a hand, and guided us, we probably
wouldn’t be where we are today. Let’s start giving back! Let’s help
others succeed! Mentorship can be super fun and rewarding, you will
learn a ton by helping others, and you don’t need to be an expert in
order to mentor someone. In my talk we’ll explore what a mentor is and
why you should become a mentor. I’ll also give you mentorship advice and
tips and we’ll learn about the Do’s and Don’ts of mentorship. Finally,
I’ll present some concrete ways you can help as a mentor and which
projects you can get involved in. PS: There will be Star Wars involved ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction - Who am I? What is this talk about? (2 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a mentor? (3 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why you should be(come) a mentor (3 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to be a good mentor - Mentorship tips (9 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concrete ways you can help as a mentor&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What projects to get involved in (5 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion (3 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A (5 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Catching Neutrinos with Python and KM3NeT</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/catching-neutrinos-with-python-and-km3net.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Moritz Lotze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/catching-neutrinos-with-python-and-km3net.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;KM3NeT is the next generation underwater neutrino telescope located in
the deepest seas of the Mediterranean. Once completed, it will have an
instrumented volume of several cubic kilometres. One of the technical
challenges in such a huge project is providing software tools, which can
be rapidly developed and maintained while keeping a focus on
portability, compatibility and usability. The area of application ranges
from live monitoring over offline processing and analysis to data
visualisation and 3D event displays. Python with it’s wonderful standard
library combined with extraordinary open source frameworks proves to be
able to handle all these different tasks with ease. This talk covers
some of the projects used in our collaboration to make our lives easier,
featuring technologies such as Cython, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
Jupyter, Tornado, PyOpenGL, urwid and more, and focusses on one of our
key ingredients: a framework called KM3Pipe, which provides a
pipeline-based workflow to allow us building complex analysis chains by
stitching together modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="physics"></category><category term="pipeline"></category><category term="neutrinos"></category><category term="hephysiscs"></category></entry><entry><title>Continuous Delivery for Iot with Python and Iottly</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/continuous-delivery-for-iot-with-python-and-iottly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefano Terna</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/continuous-delivery-for-iot-with-python-and-iottly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know, continuous delivery is one of the current buzzwords (much like
IoT was a couple of years ago). But think of an industrial IoT project
connecting thousands of remote and inaccessible devices which should be
kept secure and updated over time. Now, imagine you can just write
Python code for your devices, test it over-the-internet both locally in
the lab, and in a real test environment simply by pushing your code to
specific branches and finally just pushing to master to update the
entire fleet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the talk we will use Iottly to showcase this continuous delivery
pattern for the internet of things, with live code and connected devices
(Raspberry Pi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iottly is a Development and Management Cloud Service for IoT Projects,
built by TomorrowData. Iottly is written in Python and is open source
(github). It features a Python sandbox for the devices, an online editor
to program the devices over-the-internet, and the integration with git
as the base for continuous delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="raspberrypi"></category><category term="git"></category><category term="continuous-delivery"></category><category term="iot"></category><category term="over-the-air firmware upgrade"></category><category term="InternetOfThings"></category><category term="InternetDelleCose"></category><category term="github"></category><category term="IDE"></category></entry><entry><title>Continuous Delivery for Python Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/continuous-delivery-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Bittner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/continuous-delivery-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery sounds easy in theory, but it’s hard to do in
practice. There are myriads of things you can and should do to get your
code delivered faster, reliably. We look at what we can do as Python
developers, or as a small or mid-sized team to make the industrialized
software development production chain come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Continuous Delivery?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should we do it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We explain a hands-on process and show tools and platforms that can
be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may have time to try the demonstrated tools and setups in a hands-on
demo. Bring your own notebook and get an immediate feeling of CD.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Creazione ed evoluzione di un framework per interfacce grafiche Multi-Touch con OpenGL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/creazione-ed-evoluzione-di-un-framework-per-interfacce-grafiche-multi-touch-con-opengl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tiziano Carotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/creazione-ed-evoluzione-di-un-framework-per-interfacce-grafiche-multi-touch-con-opengl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obiettivo del talk è descrivere la progettazione ed evoluzione di un
framework interattivo per interfacce grafiche 2D/3D interattive
multi-touch basato sulle recenti API OpenGL 4.5. Saranno introdotti
anche i concetti di computer grafica presenti all’interno del framework,
descrivendo l’evoluzione delle componenti dalla fase di protipazione in
puro Python all’implementazione e messa in produzione in C++ con API
Python. Infine, sarà presentata una descrizione del workflow di lavoro
per i progetti interni realizzati dai nostri team sottolineando gli
aspetti peculiari che Python fornisce agli sviluppatori.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I requisiti necessari per una piena comprensione, oltre ad una buona
conoscenza di Python, sono una buona confidenza con le tecnologie comuni
per la realizzazione di interfacce Web &amp;amp; Desktop: HTML, CSS, e almeno
uno dei framework comunemente usati per le GUI (Qt, GTK, .NET WPF,
ecc…). Inoltre è preferibile (ma non necessario) avere delle nozioni
basi di Computer Grafica e OpenGL.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="computer-graphics"></category><category term="ui"></category><category term="graphic-design"></category><category term="opengl"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploy automatizzato di un progetto Python 3/Django con Ansible</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/deploy-automatizzato-di-un-progetto-python-3django-con-ansible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Santamaria</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/deploy-automatizzato-di-un-progetto-python-3django-con-ansible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La mia applicazione è pronta e funziona senza problemi sulla mia
macchina con il server di sviluppo, ma non ho chiaro come portarla in un
ambiente di produzione. Ci sono parecchi servizi che permettono il
deploy con un solo click, adatti soprattutto a semplici siti, ma essi
non sono pienamente configurabili e nascondono il modo in cui il server
è effettivamente organizzato. Anche se molti usano ingegnose soluzioni
PaaS, vale ancora la pena capire come costruire da zero un ambiente di
produzione con Linux, Python 3, Django e uWSGI. Nel talk questo classico
stack verrà brevemente introdotto e si mostrerà poi come automatizzare
la configurazione e la procedura di deploy con un &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marco-santamaria/django-%20ansible-deploy"&gt;playbook
Ansible&lt;/a&gt;
che verrà messo a disposizione. Una particolare enfasi verrà data
all’uso di variabili d’ambiente per la configurazione del progetto
seguendo l’approccio delle twelve-factor-app. Inoltre verranno spiegati
i concetti più importanti di Ansible (playbook, ruoli, template, moduli,
inventari).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deploy"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="automation"></category><category term="nginx"></category><category term="ansible"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="uwsgi"></category></entry><entry><title>Dial M For Mentor</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta Wijaya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about Python community, is the availability of
mentors willing to help you. Various mentors have helped me navigate the
open source community and help advanced my skills. I realized finding a
mentor is not as easy as it seems, and it takes a lot of courage to
reach out in the first place. And then, there is impostor syndrome,
where one may feel like they don’t deserve the help.In this talk, I will
provide advice about working with mentor.Asking for help is not a
failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Diversity Panel: experience and discussion from all over the world</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alicia Carr</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion table about Diversity in all its hues with organizers and
experts from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="panel"></category></entry><entry><title>Don't try to look smart. Be smart</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Flavio Percoco</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The technology industry is growing and already huge. The number of
humans in this industry and the number of areas they can work on are
overwhelming. The number of opportunities often don’t seem as many for
an industry that big, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how long you’ve been in this industry, you often feel
overwhelmed, unfocused, demotivated by the size of the industry, the
uncertainty it generates and the urge of doing something others consider
important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this talk, the audience will learn how to grow in an industry
that is often blasted with intellectual appearances, quantity over
quality and unstoppable, constant, changes. The talk provides tips to
cope with large communities and fields as well as experiences and
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Growth"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>ENVIFATE: plugin per QGIS per la valutazione del rischio di inquinamento ambientale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/envifate-plugin-per-qgis-per-la-valutazione-del-rischio-di-inquinamento-ambientale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Francesco Geri</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/envifate-plugin-per-qgis-per-la-valutazione-del-rischio-di-inquinamento-ambientale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Negli ultimi anni è cresciuto in maniera considerevole l’interesse per i
fenomeni di inquinamento ambientale causati da sostanze tossiche e altre
fonti di disturbo. La pericolosità di ciascuna di tali sostanze si
manifesta laddove sia superata una certa soglia di concentrazione che la
rende tossica. Per proteggere la salute pubblica e gli ecosistemi
occorre mantenere le concentrazioni di tali inquinanti al di sotto di
una soglia di sicurezza e risulta di particolare importanza essere in
grado di prevedere in maniera sufficientemente attendibile le
concentrazioni che si vengono a stabilire nei diversi comparti
ambientali. In questo contesto, sia per le PA che per gli operatori
privati, sta diventando sempre più importante poter disporre di
strumenti semplici ma efficaci che consentano di effettuare analisi di
screening tali da individuare le possibili criticità in quest’ambito. Il
software ENVIFATE viene sviluppato nell’ambito di un progetto di ricerca
ancora in corso finanziato al DICAM (Università di Trento) dalla Regione
Veneto proprio per operare analisi di screening per valutare la
possibilità di rischi di inquinamento ambientale nelle aree protette a
seguito di pianificazione di potenziali sorgenti inquinanti. Il progetto
ha previsto lo sviluppo di un’applicazione con i seguenti requisiti: i)
open-source ii) multipiattaforma iii) user friendly iv) GIS oriented. Si
è scelto di sviluppare una famiglia di plugin di QGIS, utilizzando un
linguaggio python multipiattaforma e realizzando un modulo per ciascuna
matrice ambientale considerata: fiumi, laghi, dispersione atmosferica,
dispersione in falda, rumore. I plugin sono stati sviluppati a partire
da una libreria di moduli lanciabili da linea di comando o da
applicazioni di terze parti con un elevato livello di modularità e
scalabilità. E’ così anche possibile concatenare i diversi moduli in
flussi di dati personalizzati. Tutti i plugin forniscono risultati di
tipo numerico e cartografico. In particolare i tool da linea di comando
forniscono un risultato “statico”, ovvero collegato ad un particolare
stato spaziale e temporale, mentre all’interno dei plugin il modulo
viene reiterato nello spazio e nel tempo allo scopo di fornire mappe
georiferite e risultati relazionati temporalmente, propedeutici alle
diverse valutazioni ambientali. I futuri sviluppi del plugin ne
estenderanno le funzionalità affinché verifichi quando gli effetti
calcolati causino scostamenti significativi e misurabili dello status
delle matrici ambientali in relazione a ciò che è tutelato. Questo in
prima istanza rispetto agli habitat e alle specie della rete Natura 2000
all’interno di valutazioni di incidenza, ma anche con la prospettiva di
estendere tali analisi a VIA e VAS o ad una integrazione con i Life
Cycle Inventories (LCI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autori: Francesco Geri, Oscar Cainelli, Paolo Zatelli, Gianluca Salogni,
Marco Ciolli&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="risk-management"></category><category term="open-source"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="environment"></category><category term="Qgis"></category><category term="gis"></category><category term="impact-assessment"></category><category term="gdal"></category><category term="pollution"></category></entry><entry><title>Genropy: 10 anni di sviluppo di un framework italiano</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giovanni Porcari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
consente allo sviluppatore di scrivere applicazioni complesse in tempi
brevissimi. Lo scopo del framework è di mettere a disposizione un
potente costruttore di GUI web, un ORM molto facile, veloce ed intivo ed
una serie di component che rendono possibile costruire la propria
applicazione in poche righe di codice. A questo si aggiungono tools di
amministrazione per la gestione di permessi, grafici, gestione del
workflow, gestore di stampe e molti altri che fanno di Genropy
un’ambiente usabile immediatamente in produzione anche in situazioni
complesse e critiche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abbiamo cominciato a scrivere Genropy nel 2005 e durante il primo Pycon
qui a Firenze nel 2007, abbiamo ne abbiamo mostrato la primissima
versione. Da allora, ogni edizione di Pycon è stata l’occasione per
presentare le nuove features e cercare di diffondere la copnoscenza di
questo framework . A distanza di 10 anni possiamo dire che esiste una
minuscola ma molto attiva community che utilizza Genropy come strumento
quotidiano per scrivere le proprie applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk vorremmo raccontarvi questa avventura, e darvi modo di
conoscere meglio Genropy e di capire se può essere anche per voi il
vostro nuovo modo di scriverre applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="genropy"></category><category term="gui"></category><category term="web-development"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Genropy - Caso d'uso: gestione di una infrastruttura telefonica VoIP di medie/grandi dimensioni</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/genropy-caso-duso-gestione-di-una-infrastruttura-telefonica-voip-di-mediegrandi-dimensioni.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mauro Zanardi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/genropy-caso-duso-gestione-di-una-infrastruttura-telefonica-voip-di-mediegrandi-dimensioni.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La gestione delle configurazioni VOIP per realtà di grandi dimensioni
può essere un problema non indifferente quando ci sia la necessità di
frequenti cambiamenti. Per questa ragione, in occasione della migrazione
del sistema telefonico passando dall’attuale sistema telefonico digitale
vecchio stile con centrale locale a sistema digitale VoIP con gestione
delocalizzata, abbiamo pensato di costruire un gestionale che
facilitasse tale migrazione e che ci consentisse di gestire poi nel
tempo tutte le richieste di attivazioni e modifiche che, per la
tipologia di azienda, sono assai frequenti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In realtà avevamo già un sistema precedente basato su PHP, ma la
manutenzione del codice era ormai un problema. Per questa ragione
abbiamo pensato di ripartire da zero e abbiamo deciso di utilizzare il
framework Genropy, che ci dava modo di raggiungere in tempi molto rapidi
dei risultati in grado di risolvere i nostri problemi attuali, lasciando
lo spazio, data la modularità del sistema, ad ulteriori implementazioni
per coprire anche aree nuove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel talk vi racconterò la mia esperienza e vi mostrerò i risultati
ottenuti.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="genropy"></category><category term="gestionali"></category><category term="VoIP"></category><category term="framework"></category></entry><entry><title>Geospatial three amigos: Python, Leaflet, and ElasticSearch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/geospatial-three-amigos-python-leaflet-and-elasticsearch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Rosario</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/geospatial-three-amigos-python-leaflet-and-elasticsearch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the many jobs we do at our company is custom spatial solutions.
Over time we’ve narrowed down the stack of products that are best suited
for their jobs. Crime maps, construction zone mapping, public routes,
and real state, we’ve done it all using these three components and this
talk shows you how can do it too.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="OpenStreetMap"></category><category term="maps"></category><category term="geospatial"></category><category term="elasticsearch"></category><category term="javascript"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting started with requests HTTP library</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/getting-started-with-requests-http-library.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Grandi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/getting-started-with-requests-http-library.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;requests is one of the most advanced and simple to use HTTP libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentations is going to show how to get started with it, how to
consume REST APIs and last but not least how to properly mock and test
our code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="requests"></category><category term="api"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="REST"></category></entry><entry><title>iCond: GenroPy per amministratori di condomini</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/icond-genropy-per-amministratori-di-condomini.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Busanelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/icond-genropy-per-amministratori-di-condomini.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I software verticali costituiscono da sempre un grosso problema. Quello
della nostra azienda - che si occupa di condomini - ideato, pensato e
realizzato da noi in tempi eroici quando i S.O. stavano sui floppy,
aveva bisogno di un pesante refresh. Obiettivo del talk é quello di
illustrare l’esperienza della nostra azienda, appassionata da sempre di
tecnologia che, pur non sviluppando software, é riuscita ad utilizzare
le potenzialità, la flessibilità e gli strumenti disponibili in GenroPy,
grazie anche al supporto di tutto il suo team, per realizzare iCond, un
software completamente nuovo che va oltre il mero programma contabile e
che gestisce a 360 gradi l’attività dell’amministratore condominiale.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="In-house software"></category><category term="genropy"></category><category term="Condomini"></category></entry><entry><title>La GUI di Genropy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/la-gui-di-genropy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giovanni Porcari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/la-gui-di-genropy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lo scopo di quersto talk è di offrire una panoramica della GUI di
Genropy e del suo meccanismo di funzionamento. In particolare verra
mostrato come sia possibile, scrivendo solo codice python, usare genropy
come interfaccia grafica al di fuori del classico uso del gestionale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proveremo a vedere come dare un’ interfaccia grafica ad alcuni comandi
di shell e a mostrare come tramite i widget di genropy sia possibile
gestire con poche righe di codice python widget complessi come griglie,
griglie editabili e alberi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi mostreremo l’utilizzo sia in versione classica nel browser, che con
electron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostreremo anche l’uso di RPC classiche e di websocket.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="genropy"></category><category term="gui"></category><category term="websockets"></category></entry><entry><title>Let the music play! Recommendation Systems in Banking</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/let-the-music-play-recommendation-systems-in-banking.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Gigli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/let-the-music-play-recommendation-systems-in-banking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robot advisory is a hot topic in Banking and Finance nowadays. The
quality of any Robot relies on its ability to anticipate the choices of
customers and engage them toward an action. For this reason
recommendation systems are gaining ground in banking sector as an
alternative or supplementary approach to classical Portfolio Selection
models. In this talk I show how to build recommendation systems in
Python using two different ideas, one inspired by graph theory, and the
other by item embedding.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Out of Sight, Out of Mind: Survival tricks and tools for remote developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/out-of-sight-out-of-mind-survival-tricks-and-tools-for-remote-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessio Bragadini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/out-of-sight-out-of-mind-survival-tricks-and-tools-for-remote-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remote working and “smart working” is very much in fashion these days,
but what does it entail for the daily routing of a distributed
development team? We will talk about tools, the disputed use of email,
Skype, Slack but more specifically about time management, what you can
expect from yourself and from other members of the remote team. Is your
company “remote-friendly” or rather “remote-first”? When it’s time to
spend a few days in physical proximity with your colleagues? We will
share some examples out of the experience of a distributed team actively
working with Python and Django on a daily basis, and show how you can
make it all work, if you work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Planet friendly web development with Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Adams</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the quote “Software is eating the world” to describe
how services like Airbnb, Uber, Slack and Skype are replacing the likes
of hotels, taxis and the office commute. As software engineers, part of
our job is accelerating this shift.And it’s easy to think that a shift
from moving atoms, to moving bits, is a net win for the planet.However,
moving all those bits for our sites around takes servers. And these
servers run on electricity. And most of this electricity powering our
servers comes from burning fossil fuels. And burning these is a key
driver of climate change - the kind of disruption we don’t want.So, what
can we do? We’re not going to stop sharing cat pics anytime soon, but we
can change how we build online services to make them greener, load
faster, and convert better, by borrowing techniques from web performance
optimisation and containerisation, as well as good old common sense.
This talk will show how we can start on the journey to more planet-
friendly, sustainable django web development.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Presenting pysftpserver: OpenSSH SFTP service with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/presenting-pysftpserver-openssh-sftp-service-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Filippo Morelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/presenting-pysftpserver-openssh-sftp-service-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever needed to connect to an OpenSSH SFTP server and keep track
of the user activities? Or maybe limit user permissions? Or define
specific callbacks to react to user actions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pysftpserver&lt;/em&gt; is an OpenSSH SFTP wrapper, written purely in Python. It
is yet another cool example of what you might already know: how powerful
Python can be while staying extremely simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims at presenting the tool and a few use cases in which it
was harnessed, including one with Django and Django REST Framework. It
requires a good knowledge of Python and Django and understanding the
basics of a SFTP service.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="SFTP"></category><category term="command-line"></category><category term="django-rest-framework"></category><category term="storage"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="ssh"></category><category term="servers"></category></entry><entry><title>PyPy Status Update</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/pypy-status-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Antonio Cuni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/pypy-status-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to present the latest news in the PyPy world.
In particular, I will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the current status of PyPy, including performance and compatibility
w.r.t CPython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the status of NumPy and in general of the scientific stack: what
works, what doesn’t, the speed and compatibility tradeoffs, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the status Python 3 on PyPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="performance"></category><category term="JIT"></category><category term="pypy"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="numpy"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Africa</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Makarudze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="startup"></category><category term="beginner"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="women"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="pyladies"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="Learning environment"></category><category term="user-groups"></category></entry><entry><title>Python, Locales and Writing Systems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-locales-and-writing-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rae Knowler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-locales-and-writing-systems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3 removes a lot of the confusion around Unicode handling in
Python, but that by no means fixes everything. Different locales and
writing systems have unique behaviours that can trip you up. Here’s some
of the worst ones and how to handle them correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Realizzare stampe HTML e PDF usando solo Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/realizzare-stampe-html-e-pdf-usando-solo-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Saverio Porcari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/realizzare-stampe-html-e-pdf-usando-solo-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uno dei compiti più noiosi per chi fa software orientato al business ma
non solo, è quello di generare stampe con layout complessi e specifici
sulle esigenze del committente. Creare documenti come fatture, moduli
d’ordine, bolle di lavorazione e trasporto, schede prodotto o qualsiasi
cosa il cliente abbia il desiderio di vedere sulla stramaledetta carta è
una cosa che di norma comporta diverse criticità. Infatti ci troviamo a
dover ingabbiare dati, che solitamente rappresentiamo a video con layout
elastici e responsivi, in strutture grafiche rigide che devono risultare
sempre uguali, misurate in millimetri e ben leggibili una volta
stampate. Per rispondere a questa necessità &lt;strong&gt;Genropy&lt;/strong&gt; mette a
disposizione la libreria &lt;em&gt;gnrhtml&lt;/em&gt; che permette di descrivere in Python
layout complessi ed annidati, ottenendo come risultato un documento HTML
ed eventualmente PDF tramite il comando &lt;em&gt;wkhtmltopdf&lt;/em&gt;. La libreria
&lt;em&gt;gnrhtml&lt;/em&gt; è perfettamente integrata con il framework &lt;strong&gt;Genropy&lt;/strong&gt;, ma può
essere facilmente utilizzata anche al di fuori da questo ambiente.
Durante il talk spiegheremo il funzionamento della libreria e ne
mosteremo l’utilizzo con un caso d’esempio realizzato sia &lt;strong&gt;Genropy&lt;/strong&gt;
che in &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pdf"></category><category term="prints"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="genropy"></category></entry><entry><title>Rusty Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/rusty-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matteo Bertini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/rusty-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python è un linguaggio “colla”, esistono librerie per creare estensioni
nei linguaggi più vari, da C/C++ a Fortran con poche righe di codice
abbiamo il nostro wrapper bello funzionante.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Da qualche tempo un nuovo linguaggio di aggiunge alla lista: Rust!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ci sono due strade, la prima è quella di fare in modo che la libreria
Rust esponga una API C, e per poi usarla con &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ctypes&lt;/tt&gt; o &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;cffi&lt;/tt&gt;.
L’altra strada passa per &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;rust-cpython&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;, un wrapper Rust per le API C
di Python, con cui è possibile sia chiamare Python da Rust che estendere
Python con moduli in puro Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk vedremo come è possibile esporre delle strutture Rust in
modo da offrire una interfaccia Pythonica senza venire a compromessi con
le prestazioni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisiti:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conoscenza base di Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conoscenza minima di Rust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Si può fare!!” un modulo Python in Rust, con setup e test su Travis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="extensions"></category><category term="Rust"></category></entry><entry><title>Scientific Hooliganism: lessons from the first hack in history</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/scientific-hooliganism-lessons-from-the-first-hack-in-history.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lilly Ryan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/scientific-hooliganism-lessons-from-the-first-hack-in-history.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1903, Guglielmo Marconi prepared to unveil his world-first,
long-distance wireless communication technology to the Royal Institution
in London. He was looking forward to roaring success, scientific
acclaim, and a string of wealthy new customers - but he didn’t count
upon falling victim to the first hack in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a tale of business secrets, flame wars, stage magic, and
magnificent sideburns, direct from the records of Edwardian England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk highlights several of the lessons that the FLOSS and
information security communities can still learn from the fateful events
of 1903. Marconi’s tale is a master class in the necessity of open
source technology, as well as being a delightful introduction to the art
of vulnerability reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="infosec"></category><category term="FLOSS"></category><category term="radio"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="hacking"></category><category term="history"></category></entry><entry><title>Sparking Pandas: an experiment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/sparking-pandas-an-experiment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Francesco Bruni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/sparking-pandas-an-experiment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is a good library to deal with tabular data. What if you need to
manage an amount of data that doesn’t fit into memory? What if you want
to “distribute” your computations among multiple machines?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from a real scenario, Apache Spark will be presented as the
main tool to read and process collected data. It will be shown how a
Pandas-like syntax will come in handy to run aggregations, filtering and
grouping using a Spark Dataframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A previous knowledge of Docker and Docker Compose will be very useful
while knowing MongoDB (where data will be fetched from) is not
mandatory. Basics of functional programming will help to understand
Spark inner logic.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="microservices"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="mongodb"></category><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="spark"></category><category term="docker"></category></entry><entry><title>Svilluppare con python sull'iPad</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/svilluppare-con-python-sullipad.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lelio Campanile</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/svilluppare-con-python-sullipad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Da quando è stato introdotto l’iPad, questo si è evoluto velocemente,
trasformandosi da un iPhone agli steroidi ad un surrogato di computer
ultraportatile. Questo mi ha spinto ad esplorare la piattaforma per
vedere fino a che punto ci si poteva spingere nell’utilizzo di un iPad
come sostituto di un ultra portatile: volevo poter sviluppare con python
anche su un iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finalmente dopo molte ricerche scopro l’app Pythonista che consente di
sviluppare in python sull’iPad e senza alcun jailbreak, secondo le
regole della Apple!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi voglio far conoscere questo strumento con il quale potrete sviluppare
script python per automatizzare il vostro lavoro sull’iPad, fare test al
volo di codici anche quando non avete un pc, utilizzare l’iPad per le
vostre ricerche scientifiche (grazie al supporto di numpy e matplotlib)
ad adirittura scrivere app con una gui che potrete pubblicare sull’app
store!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="IDE"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>Sviluppo lato client con Odoo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/sviluppo-lato-client-con-odoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Davide Corio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/sviluppo-lato-client-con-odoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://odoo.com"&gt;Odoo&lt;/a&gt; è un framework utilizzato prevalentemente per
lo sviluppo di soluzioni business, dall’ambito all’ERP all’e-commerce.
E’ famoso per essere estremamente malleabile e scritto interamente in
Python. Linguaggio con il quale può essere facilmente personalizzato ed
esteso. Ma lo sviluppo di componenti client-side si fa sempre più
sentire (hey, siamo nel 2017, non lamentarti) ed è ormai necessario
comprendere come arricchire i nostri moduli Odoo scritti in Python con
qualche riga di codice JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="javascript"></category><category term="ecommerce"></category><category term="Odoo"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing in Layers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/testing-in-layers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Martelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/testing-in-layers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to code tests in modular ways suitable for multiple
arrangements and layers, arrange and deploy tests as unit tests,
intermediate integration tests, end-to-end tests, and load-tests, and
enrich code and tests with appropriate use and analysis of logging.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The unconventional Introduction to Deep Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/the-unconventional-introduction-to-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valerio Maggio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/the-unconventional-introduction-to-deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are into Deep Learning, sooner or later, it inevitbly happens
that you’re asked at least once to explain what actually means &lt;strong&gt;Deep
Learning&lt;/strong&gt; , and what’s all the fuss about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, answering this question in a proper way, may vary (and it has
to) depending on the kind of audience you’ve been talking to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are talking to a machine learning experts, you have to
concentrate on what &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; means, for the multiple learning models you
can come up with. Most importarly, you have to convince them that a deep
learning model would work by far better than a more standard and robust
Random Forest or Support Vector Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if your audience is made up of engineers, they
[STRIKEOUT:don’t give a damn..] are definitely more interested in how
you implement your Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) rather than
understanding what are the implications of different &lt;em&gt;activations&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;optimizers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if your audience is made up of data scientists - who are a good
mixture of the previous two, according to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://drewconway.com/zia/2013/3/26/the-data-science-venn-diagram"&gt;Drew
Conway&lt;/a&gt;
- they are more or less interested in both the two aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way, that is the &lt;em&gt;unconventional way&lt;/em&gt;, to explain what Deep
Learning means, is from the perspective of the computational model it
requires to be properly effective. Therefore, you may want to talk about
ANN in terms of matrix multiplications algorithms, running on a (series
of) GPUs in parallel. And this is &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;/strong&gt; the perspecitve I intend
to pursue in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for PyData scientists who are interested in understanding
Deep Learning models from this unconventional perspective, learning what
are the libraries and tools they may leverage for their experiments on
GPUs. Experienced engineers may likely benefit from this talk as well,
learning how they can make their models run fast(er).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Keras"></category><category term="rumba"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="Theano"></category><category term="GPU"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry><entry><title>Unreal Engine 4 e Python: Ora si Puo'</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/unreal-engine-4-e-python-ora-si-puo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto De Ioris</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/unreal-engine-4-e-python-ora-si-puo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unreal Engine e’ la piattaforma per lo sviluppo di videogiochi tripla A
piu’ apprezzata nell’industria del settore. Da Agosto 2016 ho avuto
l’onore di integrare il supporto Python sia nel runtime che nell’editor
stesso, permettendo di sviluppare i propri giochi usando esclusivamente
Python o fare scripting dell’editor per automatizzare la pipeline di
lavoro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk mostrera’ quali sono stati i passaggi salienti
dell’integrazione, come l’industria videoludica (ma anche quella
cinematografica) stanno utilizzando il plugin e quali saranno i futuri
sviluppi. Il tutto sara’ condito da un paio di demo interattive
realizzate in python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="game-development"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Python in Cosmology</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/using-python-in-cosmology.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valeria Pettorino</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/using-python-in-cosmology.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cosmology is the study of the Universe, its evolution and forms of
energy within it. The Planck satellite has been able to detect light
from the early stages of the Universe, 13 billion years ago,
confirming the scientific puzzle of Dark Energy and providing us with
a big data challenge. I will describe the context and how python is
used for the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>weppy: the web framework for humans</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/weppy-the-web-framework-for-humans.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giovanni Barillari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/weppy-the-web-framework-for-humans.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why another python web framework? Do we really need to innovate the
Django and Flask scene? Could we? This talk will address all these
questions, introducing weppy: the full stack python web framework
designed with simplicity in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="web"></category><category term="orm"></category><category term="webservices"></category><category term="sql"></category><category term="webapp"></category><category term="web-development"></category></entry></feed>