<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bringing Research to Real Life</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/bringing-research-to-real-life.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is a fascinating field with numerous applications in
data science. New research is always emerging in the field of machine
learning but it can take years for this research to be converted into
usable software libraries. In this talk, I'll be providing a technique
for reading (actually reading) research papers and using the powerful
syntax and data-focused libraries of Python to write up quick and dirty
implementations of techniques written out in research papers. This talk
is relevant to any practical professional who occasionally strays into
the field of academics to discover new techniques that are applicable to
the data problems that they are attempting to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Safia Abdalla</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/bringing-research-to-real-life.html</guid></item><item><title>Classification using Pandas and Scikit-Learn</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/classification-using-pandas-and-scikit-learn.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will be a tutorial-style talk demonstrating how to use pandas and
scikit-learn to do classification tasks. We will do some data munging
and visualization using pandas and matplotlib. Then we will introduce
some of the different classifiers in scikit-learn and show how to
include them into a classification pipeline to produce the best
predictive model. Interactive IPython/Jupyter notebooks will be
provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Skipper Seabold</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/classification-using-pandas-and-scikit-learn.html</guid></item><item><title>Document Classification with Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/document-classification-with-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The presentation will discuss how Python was used to implement a
machine-learning algorithm that accepts a training set of documents and
then classifies documents based on word vector similarity. This project
inspired by faculty at DePaul is now a fully-fledged start-up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jordan "Vladimir'' Myers</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/document-classification-with-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Eight years of web2py</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/eight-years-of-web2py.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a compressed tutorial about web2py taking an historical
prospective, going from its older features to some of the most recent
ones. No previous experience required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Massimo Di Pierro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/eight-years-of-web2py.html</guid></item><item><title>Extending versatility of Python to nonprogrammers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/extending-versatility-of-python-to-nonprogrammers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The explosive availability of data is creating unprecedented
opportunities in the analytics space. However, not everyone performing
analytics is a data scientist and has the appropriate technical
expertise for creating, debugging and running code. This so-called
business analyst brings a broad understanding of data analysis and the
business problem at hand and does best with user-friendly tools. What
happens, however, if the business user needs to run a non-standard or
unique analysis that is not available natively in their analytics
software? Join our session to learn how python code can be integrated
with IBM SPSS and how business users can employ the versatility and
power of python without the need to run code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Armand Ruiz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/extending-versatility-of-python-to-nonprogrammers.html</guid></item><item><title>Getting Started with Cassandra and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/getting-started-with-cassandra-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will covers why to use Cassandra, basic Cassandra
architecture, setting up Cassandra, and basic crud operations with a
python web framework. The Apache Cassandra database is the right choice
when you need scalability and high availability without compromising
performance. Linear scalability and proven fault-tolerance on commodity
hardware or cloud infrastructure make it the perfect platform for
mission-critical data. Cassandra's support for replicating across
multiple datacenters is best-in-class, providing lower latency for your
users and the peace of mind of knowing that you can survive regional
outages. Cassandra's data model offers the convenience of column indexes
with the performance of log-structured updates, strong support for
denormalization and materialized views, and powerful built-in caching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amber Doctor</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/getting-started-with-cassandra-and-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Jupyter Project: Interacting between Python and R Libraries for Data Mining</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/jupyter-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover using ipython (Jupyter Project) for python and
non-python projects, and how to interact Python and R through rmagic
(rpy2) package.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Myles Gartland</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/jupyter-project.html</guid></item><item><title>Learning by doing: Predicting West Nile Virus in Chicago.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/learning-by-doing-predicting-west-nile-virus-in.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Challenging students with interesting projects is an effective way to
motivate them. In this talk we will first discuss Kaggle, a platform for
predictive modelling and analytics competitions on which companies and
researchers post their data and statisticians and data miners from all
over the world compete to produce the best models. In particular, we
will discuss the West Nile Virus Prediction challenge and how it is
being used in the classroom. Finally, this talk will get interested
competitors started with some sample code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jonathan Gemmell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/learning-by-doing-predicting-west-nile-virus-in.html</guid></item><item><title>Python in Computer Security - Student's Perspective</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/python-in-computer-security-students-perspecti.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As students of computer security, we are often the subject of academic
discussion regarding the best topics to study. We hope to show how we
have utilized python to within our area of study and why it is important
for future students. Our goal is to encourage future classes of students
to enjoy scripting. We will introduce how we as security students
utilize Python as an everyday tool with specific examples of how we used
Python in various security competitions and gave us a noticeable
advantage over other teams. This will include scripts used as defenders
against various red team attacks&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Li-Wey Lu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/python-in-computer-security-students-perspecti.html</guid></item><item><title>Python-Powered Machine Learning in the Cloud</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/python-powered-machine-learning-in-the-cloud.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a powerful, easy-to-use language which now has a wide range of
numerical and machine-learning open source libraries. At Civis
Analytics, we've built a cloud-based platform for data science which
empowers analysts to extract insights from their data with less effort.
The platform itself runs on Amazon Web Services, and the machine
learning workflows at the core of the platform are coded in Python.
Open-source Python libraries such as pandas, numpy, statsmodels, and
scikit-learn let our data scientists focus on high-level workflows and
greatly accelerate our development process. In this talk, I'll give an
overview of Civis's new data science platform, focusing on the
machine-learning aspects. I'll talk about how we use Python open-source
libraries to help with data analysis, and some of the challenges we've
overcome along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Hoover</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/python-powered-machine-learning-in-the-cloud.html</guid></item><item><title>The Use of Web Games to Train Data Analysts</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/the-use-of-web-games-to-train-data-analysts.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been recent work on the taxonomy of games which are based, one
way or another, on real world data. Typically these games help people
learn that data or how to cope with it. The traditional examples are
simulation games (flight, driving, etc.), while other games incorporate
data in such a way that it is beneficial to learn the real world data in
the game play (trivia). These types of data-games commonly have a domain
specific focus. We intend to explore the possibility of interactive
games which help people to learn data analysis, in general, implementing
some such games in python using web2py.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Casey Schroeder</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/the-use-of-web-games-to-train-data-analysts.html</guid></item><item><title>Work work money money</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/work-work-money-money.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public census and economics data are combined with job board postings to
paint a portrait of industry growth and salary differences across the
United States. Apache Spark's Python shell is used for analytics; Heroku
hosts the visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tanya Schlusser</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/work-work-money-money.html</guid></item><item><title>Cloudmesh Virtual Cluster Management for Data Intensive Applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/cloudmesh-virtual-cluster-management-for-data-int.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cloudmesh is an important component to deliver a software-defined system
encompassing virtualized and bare-metal infrastructure, networks,
application, systems and platform software with a unifying goal of
providing Cloud Testbeds as a Service (CTaaS). Cloudmesh federates a
number of resources from academia and industry. This includes existing
FutureSystems, Amazon Web Services, Azure, HP Cloud, Karlsruhe using
various technologies. An high level architectural image is provided at
{&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cloudmesh.github.io/introduction_to_cloud_computing/_images/cloudmesh-arch-2013.png"&gt;http://cloudmesh.github.io/introduction_to_cloud_computing/_images/cloudmesh-arch-2013.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gregor von Laszewski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/cloudmesh-virtual-cluster-management-for-data-int.html</guid></item><item><title>Having Fun with Recommender Systems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/having-fun-with-recommender-systems.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bamshad Mobasher</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/having-fun-with-recommender-systems.html</guid></item><item><title>Maximum Viable Integrity with web2py</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/maximum-viable-integrity-with-web2py.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating an enterprise grade application to meet static business
specifications is an easy task for a developer using web2py. Keeping up
with ever changing needs of a business, while maintaining core
application logic can be more difficult. At Suits + Tables, we have
found this process facilitated using a combination of Unit Testing,
Behavior Driven Development, and Continuous Integration. Best practices
for maintaining Maximum Viable Integrity during iteration and deployment
of web2py applications will be discussed in the context of Suits +
Tables and other case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Graves</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/maximum-viable-integrity-with-web2py.html</guid></item><item><title>pyDAL: a pure python Database Abstraction Layer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/pydal-a-pure-python-database-abstraction-layer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview and quick demonstration of the
features and the APIs of pyDAL, the python Database Abstraction Layer.
It dynamically generates the SQL in real time using the specified
dialect for the database back end, so that you do not have to write SQL
code or learn different SQL dialects (the term SQL is used generically),
and your code will be portable among different types of databases. pyDAL
comes from the original web2py's DAL, with the aim of being
wide-compatible. pyDAL doesn't require web2py and can be used in any
Python context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giovanni Barillari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/pydal-a-pure-python-database-abstraction-layer.html</guid></item><item><title>PyHSPF: Data integration software for hydrologic and water quality modeling</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/pyhspf-data-integration-software-for-hydrologic.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hydrological Simulation Program in Fortran (HSPF) is used
extensively for the assessment of water quantity and water quality
issues. This presentation will discuss the development of an open-source
Python package (PyHSPF) for gathering necessary data from the internet
and using it to build HSPF input files, performing HSPF simulations,
postprocess results and calibrate parameters. An example application of
the software will be presented for a model of the North Skunk River
Basin, Iowa, that simulates monthly flows over a 30-year time period
with a high degree of explanatory power (R squared = 0.85).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Lampert</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/pyhspf-data-integration-software-for-hydrologic.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and Data Processing and Visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/python-and-data-processing-and-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Argonne National Laboratory's Leadership Computing Facility uses Python
in many ways from developing tools, testing supercomputers, completing
real science, and much more all using Python. We will dive into a few of
these systems and how Python has benefited us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Pershey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/python-and-data-processing-and-visualization.html</guid></item><item><title>Realtor Search: Elasticsearch and Python in Practice</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/realtor-member-search.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of our Master Member Profile project, the REALTOR search is a
Web2py-based application, leveraging Elasticsearch, that aims to provide
users (staff and members) with a means to query comprehensive member
profiles. With relevant data gathered and presented via an easy-to-use
centralized platform, staff can leverage information to enhance services
provided to members and members to enhance productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aleksandar Velkoski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/realtor-member-search.html</guid></item><item><title>Speeding Up Python Data Analysis Using Cython</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/speeding-up-python-data-analysis-using-cython.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an ideal language for developing software for the analysis of
scientific data. Although packages such as NumPy, SciPy, and pandas can
offer execution speeds similar to those possible using statically typed,
compiled languages, oftentimes Python code is too slow for the task at
hand. Cython is a static compiler for Python which, with the addition of
a few type declarations, allows Python code to execute at significantly
faster speeds. This talk will detail how to use Cython to optimize the
run time of Python code for analysis of scientific data with examples
taken from the development of algorithms in the Python ARM Radar Toolkit
(Py-ART), an open source library for working with weather radar data in
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jonathan Helmus</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/speeding-up-python-data-analysis-using-cython.html</guid></item><item><title>Teaching web app development with web2py and crowdsourced grading</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/teaching-web-app-development-with-web2py-and-crow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we describe how web2py together with crowdsourced grading
enable teaching web applications at scale. Web2py is unique in allowing
the easy packaging and sharing of applications. A student can write a
web app, package it into a single file, then share it; other students
can with the click of a mouse unpack and load the application, and use
it. This allows teaching web development in a peer-driven fashion:
students submit solutions to homework assignments, then review and grade
each other's work, in the process learning from studying the solutions
that other students submitted for the same problem. We have successfully
used this approach at UC Santa Cruz for three years now, in the process
building a tool, CrowdGrader, for the peer review and grading of the
applications. The talk will describe the peer-driven approach and the
tool, and present results on tool accuracy and student satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luca de Alfaro</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/teaching-web-app-development-with-web2py-and-crow.html</guid></item><item><title>Tuning Machine Learning Parameters using scikit-learn Gridsearch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/tuning-machine-learning-parameters-using-scikit-l.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Braintree we rely on scikit-learn's Pipeline and Gridsearch concepts
to build and tune our predictive models. I'll talk through how this
looks, the benefits, and the custom classes we've built out to augment
this process to integrate Pandas dataframes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Goetsch</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/tuning-machine-learning-parameters-using-scikit-l.html</guid></item></channel></rss>