<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - PyCon Korea 2024</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-korea-2024.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A Hacker's Perspective on Django Framework</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/a-hackers-perspective-on-django-framework.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Seokchan Yoon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/a-hackers-perspective-on-django-framework.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we analyze the Django Framework from a hacker's perspective, exploring how real-world hacking techniques could be applied to Django. We also share practical methods to use Django more securely. This talk will be valuable not only for developers using Django but also for anyone interested in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we analyze the Django Framework from a hacker's perspective, exploring how real-world hacking techniques could be applied to Django. We also share practical methods to use Django more securely. This talk will be valuable not only for developers using Django but also for anyone interested in security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seokchan Yoon
Hello! I am an active developer and security professional, deeply involved in various tech communities. Currently, I am focusing on development productivity and security, with a special interest in researching Django. Nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Adding Cloud to Python Backend</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/adding-cloud-to-python-backend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jungsik Hwang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/adding-cloud-to-python-backend.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would like to share the limitations I experienced while developing Python web services and how I overcame them using AWS infrastructure. Based on my experiences with significant server overhead, I will present two case studies and share specific solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="Cloud"></category><category term="AWS"></category><category term="Backend"></category></entry><entry><title>AI and Python for Financial Data Analysis with NLP</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/ai-and-python-for-financial-data-analysis-with-nlp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Daehyun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/ai-and-python-for-financial-data-analysis-with-nlp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will dive into analyzing financial data using Python and Artificial Intelligence (AI), focusing on Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques. This session will cover various methods to process and analyze financial data, along with how NLP can be leveraged to improve financial data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Daehyun …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will dive into analyzing financial data using Python and Artificial Intelligence (AI), focusing on Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques. This session will cover various methods to process and analyze financial data, along with how NLP can be leveraged to improve financial data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Daehyun
Hello, I am a data scientist with a focus on AI and NLP. I have experience working with various types of data, including financial datasets. I hope this session helps you understand how to apply Python and AI to financial data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Automating Assignment Grading with pytest &amp; GitHub Actions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/automating-assignment-grading-with-pytest-github-actions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kangwon Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/automating-assignment-grading-with-pytest-github-actions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Kangwon Lee shares his journey of automating assignment grading workflows using pytest and GitHub Actions. The talk covers the motivations for automation, the technical setup process, challenges faced during implementation, and best practices for using continuous integration tools to streamline grading tasks. This session is valuable …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Kangwon Lee shares his journey of automating assignment grading workflows using pytest and GitHub Actions. The talk covers the motivations for automation, the technical setup process, challenges faced during implementation, and best practices for using continuous integration tools to streamline grading tasks. This session is valuable for educators and developers interested in educational automation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="automation"></category></entry><entry><title>CPython 인터프리터 구조 파헤치기</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/cpython-inteopeuriteo-gujo-pahecigi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>한성민</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/cpython-inteopeuriteo-gujo-pahecigi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session is designed for advanced users and delves into the internal structure of CPython, the primary interpreter of Python. It provides insights into building the interpreter and understanding its core functionalities. It is particularly suited for those who wish to gain a deeper understanding of Python's internal architecture …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session is designed for advanced users and delves into the internal structure of CPython, the primary interpreter of Python. It provides insights into building the interpreter and understanding its core functionalities. It is particularly suited for those who wish to gain a deeper understanding of Python's internal architecture or the core system of the Python language itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Cracking PDF with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/cracking-pdf-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kangmin Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/cracking-pdf-with-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this PyCon Korea 2024 session, Kangmin Kim, a data journalist at Newstapa , demonstrates practical techniques for extracting and processing data from government and public PDF documents using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="PDF"></category></entry><entry><title>함수 추적 도구를 만들며 알아보는 파이썬 고성능 event-monitoring</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/hamsu-cujeog-dogureul-mandeulmyeo-alaboneun-paisseon-goseongneung-event-monitoring.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>강민철</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/hamsu-cujeog-dogureul-mandeulmyeo-alaboneun-paisseon-goseongneung-event-monitoring.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will explore event monitoring, which provides the capability to trace Python code execution. There are various situations where understanding the flow of function execution is essential during development, such as debugging, profiling, and coverage testing. These capabilities can be implemented based on Python’s event …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will explore event monitoring, which provides the capability to trace Python code execution. There are various situations where understanding the flow of function execution is essential during development, such as debugging, profiling, and coverage testing. These capabilities can be implemented based on Python’s event system. We will first review how these features have been traditionally implemented, and then explain how, in more recent versions of Python (3.12 and above), they can be implemented with improved performance. Throughout the session, we will demonstrate this by building a simple Python function tracing tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>험난한 암호화폐 세상을 여행하려는 Python 유저를 위한 안내서</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/heomnanhan-amhohwapye-sesangeul-yeohaengharyeoneun-python-yujeoreul-wihan-annaeseo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>이왕원</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/heomnanhan-amhohwapye-sesangeul-yeohaengharyeoneun-python-yujeoreul-wihan-annaeseo.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will briefly discuss the following topics: How the cryptocurrency ecosystem operates, Cryptocurrency airdrops and various incidents related to them, On-chain data analysis based on real-world data using Python, Other ways to contribute to the cryptocurrency ecosystem with Python&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>자동화된 파이썬 웹 프레임워크 API Schema 제작기: The long way around</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/jadonghwadoen-paisseon-web-peureimweokeu-api-schema-jejaggi-the-long-way-around.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>조규진</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/jadonghwadoen-paisseon-web-peureimweokeu-api-schema-jejaggi-the-long-way-around.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will share the journey of overcoming the challenges encountered while trying to automate API documentation using aiohttp. Through real-world examples of understanding the limitations of aiohttp and how they were addressed, attendees will gain a clearer understanding of the necessity of API documentation automation and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will share the journey of overcoming the challenges encountered while trying to automate API documentation using aiohttp. Through real-world examples of understanding the limitations of aiohttp and how they were addressed, attendees will gain a clearer understanding of the necessity of API documentation automation and the technical challenges involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote] Python, PyCon, the Age of Dinosaurs, and the Planet of Chickens</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/keynote-python-pycon-the-age-of-dinosaurs-and-the-planet-of-chickens.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jung-kyu Shin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/keynote-python-pycon-the-age-of-dinosaurs-and-the-planet-of-chickens.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sharing thoughts on the growth of Python and the future of AI and computing, intertwined with personal experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Playing games in the browser with WASM</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/playing-games-in-the-browser-with-wasm.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/playing-games-in-the-browser-with-wasm.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>PyPencil for Fair-Scoring</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/pypencil-for-fair-scoring.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Inah Hwang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/pypencil-for-fair-scoring.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Inah Hwang introduces PyPencil, a tool designed to promote fairness in scoring and evaluation processes. The talk covers the motivations behind creating PyPencil, its core features, and how it can be applied in educational or assessment contexts to reduce bias and enhance objectivity. This session will …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Inah Hwang introduces PyPencil, a tool designed to promote fairness in scoring and evaluation processes. The talk covers the motivations behind creating PyPencil, its core features, and how it can be applied in educational or assessment contexts to reduce bias and enhance objectivity. This session will be valuable for anyone interested in fair-scoring systems and educational technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="everyday-life"></category><category term="society"></category></entry><entry><title>Python ASGI 서버 구현기 with PyO3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/python-asgi-seobeo-guhyeongi-with-pyo3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>민태인</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/python-asgi-seobeo-guhyeongi-with-pyo3.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ASGI is an asynchronous communication standard protocol between frameworks and servers in Python. In this session, I share my experiences and insights gained while implementing an ASGI protocol server using Rust and PyO3.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Engineering for Enterprise Deployment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/python-engineering-for-enterprise-deployment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Joon-ki</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/python-engineering-for-enterprise-deployment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What kind of engineering is required to deploy Python applications to enterprise customers with high security requirements? This session examines the characteristics of such enterprise environments and shares how we solved these challenges using standalone builds and pex/scie open source projects. Additionally, we introduce how we developed a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What kind of engineering is required to deploy Python applications to enterprise customers with high security requirements? This session examines the characteristics of such enterprise environments and shares how we solved these challenges using standalone builds and pex/scie open source projects. Additionally, we introduce how we developed a TUI installer using the textual library to make complex installation and configuration processes accessible not only to developers but also to partner technical support engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Python on the Browser: Past, Present, and Future</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/python-on-the-browser-past-present-and-future.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Choi Kyung-jae</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/python-on-the-browser-past-present-and-future.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session will introduce the technology of running Python on top of the browser using WebAssembly, how it has evolved, where it is being used, and where it is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Starting ML Quant Strategies with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/starting-ml-quant-strategies-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hanjin Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/starting-ml-quant-strategies-with-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session briefly explores how to easily create quant strategies using Python's powerful ML packages, and discusses the real-world challenges faced by professional quants.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="quant"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>SUN vs Me: Quest to Outwit the Blinding Sun with MQTT and micropython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/sun-vs-me-quest-to-outwit-the-blinding-sun-with-mqtt-and-micropython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vishrut Kohli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/sun-vs-me-quest-to-outwit-the-blinding-sun-with-mqtt-and-micropython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vishrut Kohli, a Principal Engineer at battery Smart, shares his journey of battling the sun to optimize his sleep schedule. He discusses how he built an automated curtain system using micropython, MQTT, a VOS D1 mini, and a Raspberry Pi to control his blinds based on sunrise and sunset …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vishrut Kohli, a Principal Engineer at battery Smart, shares his journey of battling the sun to optimize his sleep schedule. He discusses how he built an automated curtain system using micropython, MQTT, a VOS D1 mini, and a Raspberry Pi to control his blinds based on sunrise and sunset times.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="MQTT"></category><category term="IoT"></category><category term="home automation"></category><category term="Raspberry Pi"></category></entry><entry><title>Upgrading to Django 4.2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/upgrading-to-django-42.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Kwang-hyun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/upgrading-to-django-42.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Kim Kwang-hyun shares practical tips and lessons learned from upgrading a Django project to version 4.2. The talk covers challenges encountered during the upgrade process, how to handle deprecated features, and strategies to ensure a smooth migration for production services. This session will be valuable …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Kim Kwang-hyun shares practical tips and lessons learned from upgrading a Django project to version 4.2. The talk covers challenges encountered during the upgrade process, how to handle deprecated features, and strategies to ensure a smooth migration for production services. This session will be valuable for developers planning a Django version upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="web service"></category></entry><entry><title>web3.py: Ethereum Interaction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/web3py-ethereum-interaction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sanghyeon Choi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/web3py-ethereum-interaction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we explore how to interact with the Ethereum blockchain using web3.py. We will cover the basics of web3.py, key use cases, and practical examples for Python developers interested in blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanghyeon Choi
Hello! I am an active developer with a deep interest in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we explore how to interact with the Ethereum blockchain using web3.py. We will cover the basics of web3.py, key use cases, and practical examples for Python developers interested in blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanghyeon Choi
Hello! I am an active developer with a deep interest in blockchain and Ethereum. Currently, I am researching how Python can be used effectively in Web3 development. Nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Automating CLI commands execution with LLM and LangGraph</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/automating-cli-commands-execution-with-llm-and-langgraph.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leksikov Sergey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/automating-cli-commands-execution-with-llm-and-langgraph.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full Title: Automating CLI commands execution with LLM and LangGraph: A new frontier in Python automation&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Django DB Connection and Transaction Management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/django-db-connection-and-transaction-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Myeongsegyo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/django-db-connection-and-transaction-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we explore Django's database connection and transaction management system. We will discuss how to optimize database performance and handle transactions efficiently in Django applications. This session is designed for developers working with Django who want to deepen their understanding of database interactions and transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myeongsegyo
Hello …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we explore Django's database connection and transaction management system. We will discuss how to optimize database performance and handle transactions efficiently in Django applications. This session is designed for developers working with Django who want to deepen their understanding of database interactions and transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myeongsegyo
Hello! I am a Django enthusiast with a focus on backend development. I have experience working with databases and optimizing Django applications. I look forward to sharing insights into database connections and transaction management in Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>EAV Modeling and CQRS with Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/eav-modeling-and-cqrs-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sang-hun Moon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/eav-modeling-and-cqrs-with-django.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk explains how EAV modeling was implemented using Django and MySQL to build a no-code tool. It also discusses the performance limitations of EAV and how improvements were achieved by applying ideas from CQRS, sharing modeling experiences for complex services.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="web service"></category></entry><entry><title>FastAPI with Dependency Injector</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/fastapi-with-dependency-injector.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Han Barum</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/fastapi-with-dependency-injector.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session introduces how to use the FastAPI framework together with Dependency Injector. It explains how dependency injection can enhance code maintainability and ease of testing through practical examples, providing valuable insights for developers interested in backend architecture design using FastAPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han Barum
Hello, I am Han Barum. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session introduces how to use the FastAPI framework together with Dependency Injector. It explains how dependency injection can enhance code maintainability and ease of testing through practical examples, providing valuable insights for developers interested in backend architecture design using FastAPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han Barum
Hello, I am Han Barum. I focus on Python-based backend development, and I aim to share my experience using FastAPI and dependency injection patterns. My goal is to contribute to the Python ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Fun with Python in Math Class and Classroom Management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/fun-with-python-in-math-class-and-classroom-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cha Min-gyeong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/fun-with-python-in-math-class-and-classroom-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Cha Min-gyeong shares her experience of using Python in creative ways to support classroom management and math instruction. By incorporating small Python programs into daily teaching, she was able to make concepts more engaging and practical for students. This talk will walk you through how she …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, Cha Min-gyeong shares her experience of using Python in creative ways to support classroom management and math instruction. By incorporating small Python programs into daily teaching, she was able to make concepts more engaging and practical for students. This talk will walk you through how she introduced Python to students and applied it in real classroom scenarios to improve both learning and classroom operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="everyday-life"></category><category term="society"></category></entry><entry><title>I am an elementary school teacher teaching Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/i-am-an-elementary-school-teacher-teaching-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ko Hak-neung</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/i-am-an-elementary-school-teacher-teaching-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programming (SW education) has become mandatory in elementary and middle schools. So what does learning programming look like in school education? Students who enjoy and excel at it easily understand and quickly solve given tasks. In contrast, struggling students find it difficult to complete the same assignments. This disparity …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programming (SW education) has become mandatory in elementary and middle schools. So what does learning programming look like in school education? Students who enjoy and excel at it easily understand and quickly solve given tasks. In contrast, struggling students find it difficult to complete the same assignments. This disparity appears greater than in other subjects. So which students should teachers focus on during class? This was the concern I had while teaching programming at school and majoring in computer education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, I made choices regarding programming language selection and learning tool development. First, considering the growing social importance of programming and the needs of advanced students, I decided to teach Python. Next, I developed a Colab-based automatic program evaluation system and problems so that both advanced and struggling students could learn at their own pace. This allowed advanced students to minimize teacher feedback and learn according to the automatic evaluation system. Struggling students learned through both the feedback provided by the automatic evaluation system and focused feedback from the teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation demonstrates the process of developing and refining the automatic program evaluation system in Colab.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>Looking Back on 10 Years with PyCon</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/looking-back-on-10-years-with-pycon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jun-ki Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/looking-back-on-10-years-with-pycon.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk looks back on 10 years of presenting at PyCon, reflecting on various experiences including company growth, Python and asyncio evolution, and participation in international PyCons, while sharing insights and future directions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Monorepo with Rye</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/monorepo-with-rye.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Soo-bin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/monorepo-with-rye.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the approach of operating a monorepo for various libraries and services in a Python project.
In the process, the team adopted Rye as their package manager, and the presentation will also cover the features of Rye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply approaching a monorepo might unnecessarily increase complexity, so the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the approach of operating a monorepo for various libraries and services in a Python project.
In the process, the team adopted Rye as their package manager, and the presentation will also cover the features of Rye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply approaching a monorepo might unnecessarily increase complexity, so the speaker will share methods the team considered and implemented to prevent this while maximizing the benefits. The speaker will also introduce their personal experience in building and operating monorepos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is recommended for those who need to build shared libraries using Python or operate multiple services in an MSA environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="library"></category><category term="core"></category></entry><entry><title>print("Hello, python!")</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/printhello-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Byun Do-jin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/printhello-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploring the Structure of Functions in CPython and I/O Modules through the print Function&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="library"></category><category term="core"></category></entry><entry><title>『S』SDLC - Integrating AI for Proactive Security in Python Development</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/s-sdlc-integrating-ai-for-proactive-security-in-python-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Noflag(심의팅)</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/s-sdlc-integrating-ai-for-proactive-security-in-python-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will explore the significance of integrating AI into the Secure Software Development Life Cycle (SSDLC) to proactively address security vulnerabilities in Python code. I will discuss the OWASP Top 10 2021 security risks, demonstrate common insecure coding practices in Python, and showcase how to leverage the AI …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will explore the significance of integrating AI into the Secure Software Development Life Cycle (SSDLC) to proactively address security vulnerabilities in Python code. I will discuss the OWASP Top 10 2021 security risks, demonstrate common insecure coding practices in Python, and showcase how to leverage the AI model to detect and mitigate these vulnerabilities. The session is designed to provide both a managerial and technical perspective on improving software security through AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>SpringBoot to Django: My Adaptation Story</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/springboot-to-django-my-adaptation-story.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jihoon Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/springboot-to-django-my-adaptation-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I share my experience transitioning from SpringBoot to Django. As a developer accustomed to the Java ecosystem, I will talk about the challenges, differences, and fun moments encountered while adapting to Django. This session will be helpful for those curious about switching between frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jihoon Lee …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I share my experience transitioning from SpringBoot to Django. As a developer accustomed to the Java ecosystem, I will talk about the challenges, differences, and fun moments encountered while adapting to Django. This session will be helpful for those curious about switching between frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jihoon Lee
Hello! I am an active developer with a background in Java and SpringBoot. Recently, I have started exploring Django and am passionate about sharing my learning journey. Nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Utilizing Large Language Models for Almost Every Python User</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/utilizing-large-language-models-for-almost-every-python-user.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Park Sang-hyun / David</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/utilizing-large-language-models-for-almost-every-python-user.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is the most suitable language for leveraging large language models. It offers various tools and has a well-established ecosystem for this purpose. We hope this session provides an opportunity to share useful applications of language models that would appeal to any Python user.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="AI"></category></entry><entry><title>What If We Apply Python to Coloring?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/what-if-we-apply-python-to-coloring.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gu Min-gu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/what-if-we-apply-python-to-coloring.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing technology that automatically converts images into PIPO painting canvases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing technology that automatically converts images into PIPO painting canvases.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="computer vision"></category></entry><entry><title>[Keynote] 파이콘과 나의 10년 돌아보기</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/keynote-paikongwa-nayi-10nyeon-dolabogi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Junki Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-25:/pycon-korea-2024/keynote-paikongwa-nayi-10nyeon-dolabogi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the keynote session for PyCon Korea 2024 where Junki Kim reflects on the past 10 years of PyCon, the growth of the Python community, and its influence on the developer ecosystem. Join this insightful talk as he shares his journey and experience with the Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junki …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the keynote session for PyCon Korea 2024 where Junki Kim reflects on the past 10 years of PyCon, the growth of the Python community, and its influence on the developer ecosystem. Join this insightful talk as he shares his journey and experience with the Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junki Kim
Hi, I'm Junki Kim, one of the core members of PyCon Korea. I've had the privilege of being part of this community for the past decade, and it's been amazing to see how much we've all grown together. Nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>PyCon Korea 2024 Q&amp;A</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/pycon-korea-2024-qa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>PyCon Korea Team</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-28:/pycon-korea-2024/pycon-korea-2024-qa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Q&amp;amp;A session for PyCon Korea 2024. In this session, the organizers and speakers answer a wide range of questions from participants about Python, conference planning, programming careers, and more. We hope this Q&amp;amp;A provides useful insights for both current and aspiring Python developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Q&amp;amp;A session for PyCon Korea 2024. In this session, the organizers and speakers answer a wide range of questions from participants about Python, conference planning, programming careers, and more. We hope this Q&amp;amp;A provides useful insights for both current and aspiring Python developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon Korea Team
Welcome! We are the organizing team behind PyCon Korea 2024, dedicated to fostering the Python community and sharing knowledge through conferences and events. Nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>[Keynote] Community, Python, and Us</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/keynote-community-python-and-us.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joon-beom Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-15:/pycon-korea-2024/keynote-community-python-and-us.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From print &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; to today. This talk shares the journey of growth with Python and the community, discusses life, and explores what Python and the community mean to each of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry></feed>