<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - EuroSciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_euroscipy-2023.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Accelerating your Python code - a systematic overview</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/accelerating-your-python-code-a-systematic-overview.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Hoffmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/accelerating-your-python-code-a-systematic-overview.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is slow. We feel the performance limitations when doing computationally intensive work. There are many libraries and methods to accelerate your computations, but which way to go? This talk serves as a navigation guide through the world of speeding up Python. At the end, you should have a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is slow. We feel the performance limitations when doing computationally intensive work. There are many libraries and methods to accelerate your computations, but which way to go? This talk serves as a navigation guide through the world of speeding up Python. At the end, you should have a high-level understanding of performance aspects and know which way to go when you want to speed up your code next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series: Techniques, Tools and Tricks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/anomaly-detection-in-time-series-techniques-tools-and-tricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vadim Nelidov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/anomaly-detection-in-time-series-techniques-tools-and-tricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From sensor data to epidemic outbreaks, particle dynamics to environmental monitoring, much of crucial real world data has temporal nature. Fundamental challenges facing data specialist dealing with time series include not only predicting the future values, but also determining when these values are alarming. Standard anomaly detection algorithms and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From sensor data to epidemic outbreaks, particle dynamics to environmental monitoring, much of crucial real world data has temporal nature. Fundamental challenges facing data specialist dealing with time series include not only predicting the future values, but also determining when these values are alarming. Standard anomaly detection algorithms and common rule-based heuristics often fall short in addressing this problem effectively. In this talk, we will closely examine this domain, exploring its unique characteristics and challenges. You will learn to apply some of the most promising techniques for detecting time series anomalies as well as relevant scientific Python tools that can help you with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Build Drug Discovery web applications with PyScript, Ketcher and rdkit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/build-drug-discovery-web-applications-with-pyscript-ketcher-and-rdkit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nikita Churikov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/build-drug-discovery-web-applications-with-pyscript-ketcher-and-rdkit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you don't know JavaScript but know how to use python? Do you want to build an app where you can draw molecules for some application like properties prediction? Then come to this talk where I'll show you how to use Ketcher, EPAM tool for small molecule drawing, PyScirpt …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you don't know JavaScript but know how to use python? Do you want to build an app where you can draw molecules for some application like properties prediction? Then come to this talk where I'll show you how to use Ketcher, EPAM tool for small molecule drawing, PyScirpt and rdkit for your next drug discovery app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Building diverse open source communities</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/building-diverse-open-source-communities.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maren Westermann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/building-diverse-open-source-communities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today state of the art scientific research as well as industrial software development strongly depend on open source libraries. The demographic of the contributors to these libraries is predominantly white and male. In order to increase participation of groups who have been historically underrepresented in this domain PyLadies Berlin …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today state of the art scientific research as well as industrial software development strongly depend on open source libraries. The demographic of the contributors to these libraries is predominantly white and male. In order to increase participation of groups who have been historically underrepresented in this domain PyLadies Berlin, a volunteer run community group focussed on helping marginalised people to professionally establish themselves in tech, has been running hands on monthly open source hack nights for more than a year. After some initial challenges the initiative yielded encouraging results. This talk summarises the learnings and teaches how they can be applied in the wider open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Chalk’it: an open-source framework for rapid web applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/chalkit-an-open-source-framework-for-rapid-web-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mongi Ben Gaid</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/chalkit-an-open-source-framework-for-rapid-web-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chalk'it is an open-source framework that transforms Python scripts into distributable web app dashboards. It utilizes drag-and-drop widgets to establish an interface linked to a dataflow connecting Python code and various data sources. Chalk'it supports multiple Python graphics libraries, including Plotly, Matplotlib and Folium for interactive mapping and visualization …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chalk'it is an open-source framework that transforms Python scripts into distributable web app dashboards. It utilizes drag-and-drop widgets to establish an interface linked to a dataflow connecting Python code and various data sources. Chalk'it supports multiple Python graphics libraries, including Plotly, Matplotlib and Folium for interactive mapping and visualization. The framework operates entirely in web browsers using Pyodide. In our presentation, we will showcase Chalk'it, emphasizing its primary features, software architecture, and key applications, with a special focus on geospatial data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Content-based recommendation-system for the examples in sphinx-gallery</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/content-based-recommendation-system-for-the-examples-in-sphinx-gallery.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Arturo Amor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/content-based-recommendation-system-for-the-examples-in-sphinx-gallery.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gallery of your project might group the examples by module, by use case, or some other logic. But as examples grow in complexity, they may be relevant for several groups. In this talk we discuss some possible solutions and their drawbacks to motivate the introduction of a new …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gallery of your project might group the examples by module, by use case, or some other logic. But as examples grow in complexity, they may be relevant for several groups. In this talk we discuss some possible solutions and their drawbacks to motivate the introduction of a new feature to sphinx-gallery: a content-based recommendation system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>DataFrame-agnostic code: are we there yet?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/dataframe-agnostic-code-are-we-there-yet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Gorelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/dataframe-agnostic-code-are-we-there-yet.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to write a DataFrame-agnostic function, which should perform the same operation regardless of whether the input is pandas / polars / something else? Did you get stuck with special-casing to handle all the different APIs? All is good, the DataFrame Standard is here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploying multi-GPU workloads on Kubernetes in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/deploying-multi-gpu-workloads-on-kubernetes-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacob Tomlinson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/deploying-multi-gpu-workloads-on-kubernetes-in-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By using Dask to scale out RAPIDS workloads on Kubernetes you can accelerate your workloads across many GPUs on many machines. In this talk, we will discuss how to install and configure Dask on your Kubernetes cluster and use it to run accelerated GPU workloads on your cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Developing pandas extensions in Rust</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/developing-pandas-extensions-in-rust.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc Garia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/developing-pandas-extensions-in-rust.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pandas is a batteries included dataframe library, implementing hundreds of generic operations for tabular data, such as math or string operations, aggregations and window functions... In some case, domain specific code may benefit from user defined functions (UDFs) that implement some particular logic. These functions can sometimes be implemented …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pandas is a batteries included dataframe library, implementing hundreds of generic operations for tabular data, such as math or string operations, aggregations and window functions... In some case, domain specific code may benefit from user defined functions (UDFs) that implement some particular logic. These functions can sometimes be implemented using more basic pandas vectorized operations, and they will be reasonably fast, but in some others a Python function working with the individual values needs to be implemented, and those will execute orders of magnitude slower than their equivalent vectorized versions. In this tutorial we will see how to implement functions in Rust that can be used with dataframe values at the individual level, but run at the speed of vectorized code, and in some cases faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Estimagic: A library to solve challenging numerical optimization problems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/estimagic-a-library-to-solve-challenging-numerical-optimization-problems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Janos gabler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/estimagic-a-library-to-solve-challenging-numerical-optimization-problems.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we give a tour through estimagic's most notable features and explain its position in the ecosystem of Python libraries for numerical optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Exploring Geospatial data for Machine Learning using Google Earth Engine</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/exploring-geospatial-data-for-machine-learning-using-google-earth-engine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Duarte Carmo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/exploring-geospatial-data-for-machine-learning-using-google-earth-engine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered what type of data you can get about a certain location on the globe? What if I told you that you can access an enormous amount of information while sitting right there at your laptop? In this talk, I'll show you how to use Google …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered what type of data you can get about a certain location on the globe? What if I told you that you can access an enormous amount of information while sitting right there at your laptop? In this talk, I'll show you how to use Google Earth Engine to enrich your dataset. Either your exploring, or planning your next ML project, Geospatial data can provide you with a lot of information you did not know you had access to. Let me show you how!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Exploring GPU-powered backends for scikit-learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/exploring-gpu-powered-backends-for-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Franck Charras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/exploring-gpu-powered-backends-for-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Could scikit-learn future be GPU-powered ? This talk will discuss the performance improvements that GPU computing could bring to existing scikit-learn algorithms, and will describe a plugin-based design that is being foresighted to open-up scikit-learn compatibility to faster compute backends, with special concern for user-friendliness, ease of installation, and interoperability …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Could scikit-learn future be GPU-powered ? This talk will discuss the performance improvements that GPU computing could bring to existing scikit-learn algorithms, and will describe a plugin-based design that is being foresighted to open-up scikit-learn compatibility to faster compute backends, with special concern for user-friendliness, ease of installation, and interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>From Complex Scientific Notebook to User-Friendly Web Application</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/from-complex-scientific-notebook-to-user-friendly-web-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Piotr Płoński</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/from-complex-scientific-notebook-to-user-friendly-web-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to show your work with the MERCURY framework. This open-source tool perfectly matches your computed notebook (e.g., written in Jupyter Notebook). Without knowledge of frontend technologies, you can present your results as a web app (with interactive widgets), report, dashboard, or report. Learn how to improve …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to show your work with the MERCURY framework. This open-source tool perfectly matches your computed notebook (e.g., written in Jupyter Notebook). Without knowledge of frontend technologies, you can present your results as a web app (with interactive widgets), report, dashboard, or report. Learn how to improve your notebook and make your work understandable for non-technical mates. Python only!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>From Implementation to Ecosystem: The Journey of Zarr</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/from-implementation-to-ecosystem-the-journey-of-zarr.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Striebel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/from-implementation-to-ecosystem-the-journey-of-zarr.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zarr is an API and cloud-optimized data storage format for large, N-dimensional, typed arrays, based on an open-source technical specification. In the last 4 years it grew from a Python implementation to a large ecosystem. In this talk, we want to share how this transformation happened and our lessons …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zarr is an API and cloud-optimized data storage format for large, N-dimensional, typed arrays, based on an open-source technical specification. In the last 4 years it grew from a Python implementation to a large ecosystem. In this talk, we want to share how this transformation happened and our lessons learned from this journey. Today, Zarr is driven by an active community, defined by an extensible specification, has implementations in C++, C, Java, Javascript, Julia, and Python, and is used across domains such as Geospatial, Bio-imaging, Genomics and other Data Science domains.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Generating Data Frames for your test - using Pandas strategies in Hypothesis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/generating-data-frames-for-your-test-using-pandas-strategies-in-hypothesis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cheuk Ting Ho</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/generating-data-frames-for-your-test-using-pandas-strategies-in-hypothesis.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you test your data pipeline? Do you use Hypothesis? In this workshop, we will use Hypothesis - a property-based testing framework to generate Pandas DataFrame for your tests, without involving any real data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Get the best from your scikit-learn classifier</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/get-the-best-from-your-scikit-learn-classifier.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillaume Lemaitre</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/get-the-best-from-your-scikit-learn-classifier.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will provide some insights regarding the way to obtain accurate probabilities and predictions and also illustrate how to use in practice this model on different use cases: cost-sensitive problems and imbalanced classification problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting started with JupyterLab</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/getting-started-with-jupyterlab.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Müller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/getting-started-with-jupyterlab.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab is very widely used in the Python scientific community. Most, if not all, of the other tutorials will use Jupyter as a tool. Therefore, a solid understanding of the basics is very helpful for the rest of the conference as well as for your later daily work.
This …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab is very widely used in the Python scientific community. Most, if not all, of the other tutorials will use Jupyter as a tool. Therefore, a solid understanding of the basics is very helpful for the rest of the conference as well as for your later daily work.
This tutorial provides an overview of important basic Jupyter features.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>GPT generated text detection: problems and solution in the scientific publishing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/gpt-generated-text-detection-problems-and-solution-in-the-scientific-publishing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Milos Cuculovic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/gpt-generated-text-detection-problems-and-solution-in-the-scientific-publishing.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within this talk, we are discussing on how to detect AI-generated text and how to create a scalable architecture integrating this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Ibis: A fast, flexible, and portable tool for data analytics</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ibis-a-fast-flexible-and-portable-tool-for-data-analytics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ibis-a-fast-flexible-and-portable-tool-for-data-analytics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ibis provides a common dataframe-like interface to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without ever having to learn SQL. No more pains rewriting pandas code to something …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ibis provides a common dataframe-like interface to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without ever having to learn SQL. No more pains rewriting pandas code to something else when you run into performance issues; write your code once using Ibis and run it on any supported backend. In this tutorial users will get experience writing queries using Ibis on a number of local and remote database engines.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Ibis: Because SQL is everywhere but you don't want to use it</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-but-you-dont-want-to-use-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-but-you-dont-want-to-use-it.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, come and learn about Ibis! It offers a dataframe-like interface to construct concise and composable queries and then executes them against a wide variety of backends (Postgres, DuckDB, Spark, Snowflake, BigQuery, you name it.).&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Incidents management using Hawkes processes and other Tech AIOps projects in ING</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/incidents-management-using-hawkes-processes-and-other-tech-aiops-projects-in-ing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Arkadiusz P. Trawiński</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/incidents-management-using-hawkes-processes-and-other-tech-aiops-projects-in-ing.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will discuss incident management using Hawkes processes within an IT infrastructure. We show how a model previously applied for earthquake predictions can help answer the question ‘what caused what’ in a major European bank.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Integrating Ethics in ML</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/integrating-ethics-in-ml.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giada Pistilli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/integrating-ethics-in-ml.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving landscape of Machine Learning (ML), significant advancements like Large Language Models (LLMs) are gaining critical importance in both industrial and academic spheres. However, the rush towards deploying advanced models harbors inherent ethical tensions and potential adverse societal impacts. The keynote will start with a brief …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving landscape of Machine Learning (ML), significant advancements like Large Language Models (LLMs) are gaining critical importance in both industrial and academic spheres. However, the rush towards deploying advanced models harbors inherent ethical tensions and potential adverse societal impacts. The keynote will start with a brief introduction to the principles of ethics, viewed through the lens of philosophy, emphasizing how these fundamental concepts find application within ML. Grounding our discussion in tangible realities, we will delve into pertinent case studies, including the BigScience open science initiative, elucidating the practical application of ethical considerations. Additionally, the keynote will touch upon findings from my recent research, which investigates the synergy between ethical charters, legal tools, and technical documentation in the context of ML development and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to AI Safety</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-ai-safety.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michele De Simoni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-ai-safety.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI is poised to be &amp;quot;Our final invention,&amp;quot; either the key to a never-ending utopia or a direct road to dystopia (or apocalypse). Even without the eschatological framing, it's still a revolutionary technology increasingly embedded in every aspect of our life, from smartphones to smart cities, from autonomous agents …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI is poised to be &amp;quot;Our final invention,&amp;quot; either the key to a never-ending utopia or a direct road to dystopia (or apocalypse). Even without the eschatological framing, it's still a revolutionary technology increasingly embedded in every aspect of our life, from smartphones to smart cities, from autonomous agents to autonomous weapons. In the face of acceleration, there can be no delay: if we want AI to shape a better tomorrow, we must discuss safety today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Geospatial Machine Learning with SRAI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-geospatial-machine-learning-with-srai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Szymon Woźniak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-geospatial-machine-learning-with-srai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial offers a thorough introduction to the srai library for Geospatial Artificial Intelligence. Participants will learn how to use this library for geospatial tasks like downloading and processing OpenStreetMap data, extracting features from GTFS data, dividing an area into smaller regions, and representing regions in a vector space …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial offers a thorough introduction to the srai library for Geospatial Artificial Intelligence. Participants will learn how to use this library for geospatial tasks like downloading and processing OpenStreetMap data, extracting features from GTFS data, dividing an area into smaller regions, and representing regions in a vector space using various spatial features. Additionally, participants will learn to pre-train embedding models and train predictive models for downstream tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to matplotlib for visualization in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-matplotlib-for-visualization-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Hoffmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-matplotlib-for-visualization-in-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial explains the fundamental ideas and concepts of matplotlib. It's suited for complete beginners to get started as well as existing users who want to improve their plotting abilities and learn about best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to numerical optimization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-numerical-optimization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Mensinger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-numerical-optimization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this hands-on tutorial, participants will delve into numerical optimization fundamentals and engage with the optimization libraries scipy.optimize and estimagic. estimagic provides a unified interface to many popular libraries such as nlopt or pygmo and provides additional diagnostic tools and convenience features. Throughout the tutorial, participants will get …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this hands-on tutorial, participants will delve into numerical optimization fundamentals and engage with the optimization libraries scipy.optimize and estimagic. estimagic provides a unified interface to many popular libraries such as nlopt or pygmo and provides additional diagnostic tools and convenience features. Throughout the tutorial, participants will get the opportunity to solve problems, enabling the immediate application of acquired knowledge. Topics covered include core optimization concepts, running an optimization with scipy.optimize and estimagic, diagnostic tools, algorithm selection, and advanced features of estimagic, such as bounds, constraints, and global optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to NumPy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-numpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Geir Arne Hjelle</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-numpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NumPy is one of the foundational packages for doing data science with Python. It enables numerical computing by providing powerful N-dimensional arrays and a suite of numerical computing tools. In this tutorial, you'll be introduced to NumPy arrays and learn how to create and manipulate them. Then, you'll see …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NumPy is one of the foundational packages for doing data science with Python. It enables numerical computing by providing powerful N-dimensional arrays and a suite of numerical computing tools. In this tutorial, you'll be introduced to NumPy arrays and learn how to create and manipulate them. Then, you'll see some of the tools that NumPy provides, including random number generators and linear algebra routines.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Python for scientific programming</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-python-for-scientific-programming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Milton Gomez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-python-for-scientific-programming.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built-in types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;controls flow (i.e. conditions, loops, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built-in functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic Python class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Let’s exploit pickle, and `skops` to the rescue!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/lets-exploit-pickle-and-skops-to-the-rescue.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adrin Jalali</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/lets-exploit-pickle-and-skops-to-the-rescue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pickle files can be evil and simply loading them can run arbitrary code on your system. This talk presents why that is, how it can be exploited, and how skops is tackling the issue for scikit-learn/statistical ML models. We go through some lower level pickle related machinery, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pickle files can be evil and simply loading them can run arbitrary code on your system. This talk presents why that is, how it can be exploited, and how skops is tackling the issue for scikit-learn/statistical ML models. We go through some lower level pickle related machinery, and go in detail how the new format works.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk Day 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talk-day-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cheuk Ting Ho</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talk-day-2.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks of the second conference day at EuroSciPy 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks Day 1</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mridul Seth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-1.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First-day lightning talk taking place at EuroSciPy 2023 conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>My foray from Scientific Python into the Pyodide / WebAssembly universe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/my-foray-from-scientific-python-into-the-pyodide-webassembly-universe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Loic Esteve</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/my-foray-from-scientific-python-into-the-pyodide-webassembly-universe.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will also mention some of the Pyodide sharp bits and conclude with some of the ideas we have to use it even more widely.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>MyST &amp; Thebe: Community-driven tools for awesome open science communication with Jupyter[lite] backed computation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/myst-thebe-community-driven-tools-for-awesome-open-science-communication-with-jupyterlite-backed-computation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steve Purves</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/myst-thebe-community-driven-tools-for-awesome-open-science-communication-with-jupyterlite-backed-computation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a powerful authoring framework that supports blogs, online books, scientific papers, preprints, reports and journals articles. It includes thebe a minimal connector library for Jupyter, and thebe-lite that bundles a JupyterLite server with pyodide into any web page for in-browser python. It also provides publication-ready tex and pdf …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a powerful authoring framework that supports blogs, online books, scientific papers, preprints, reports and journals articles. It includes thebe a minimal connector library for Jupyter, and thebe-lite that bundles a JupyterLite server with pyodide into any web page for in-browser python. It also provides publication-ready tex and pdf generation from the same content base, minimising the rework of publishing to the web and traditional services.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Network Analysis Made Simple (and fast!)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/network-analysis-made-simple-and-fast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mridul Seth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/network-analysis-made-simple-and-fast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the use of NetworkX's API, tutorial participants will learn about the basics of graph theory and its use in applied network science. Starting with a computationally-oriented definition of a graph and its associated methods, we will build out into progressively more advanced concepts (path and structure finding). We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the use of NetworkX's API, tutorial participants will learn about the basics of graph theory and its use in applied network science. Starting with a computationally-oriented definition of a graph and its associated methods, we will build out into progressively more advanced concepts (path and structure finding). We will also discuss new advances to speed up NetworkX Code with dispatching to alternate computation backends like GraphBLAS. This will be a hands-on tutorial, so stretch your muscles and get ready to go through the exercises!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Pandas 2.0 and beyond</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/pandas-20-and-beyond.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joris Van den Bossche</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/pandas-20-and-beyond.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has reached a 2.0 milestone in 2023. But what does that mean? And what is coming after 2.0? This talk will give an overview of what happened in the latest releases of pandas and highlight some topics and major new features the pandas project is working …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has reached a 2.0 milestone in 2023. But what does that mean? And what is coming after 2.0? This talk will give an overview of what happened in the latest releases of pandas and highlight some topics and major new features the pandas project is working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Polars</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/polars.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ritchie Vink</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/polars.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polars is the &amp;quot;relatively&amp;quot; new fast dataframe implementation that redefines what DataFrames are able to do on a single machine, both in regard to performance and dataset size.
In this talk, we will dive into polars and see what makes them so efficient. It will touch on technologies like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polars is the &amp;quot;relatively&amp;quot; new fast dataframe implementation that redefines what DataFrames are able to do on a single machine, both in regard to performance and dataset size.
In this talk, we will dive into polars and see what makes them so efficient. It will touch on technologies like Arrow, Rust, parallelism, data structures, query optimization and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Posters Spotlight</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/posters-spotlight.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Piotr Płoński</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/posters-spotlight.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Posters Spotlight from the EuroSciPy 2023 conference held in Basel.
Abstract and link to the posters: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.euroscipy.org/2023/poster_session.html"&gt;https://www.euroscipy.org/2023/poster_session.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>PPML: Machine Learning on data you cannot see</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ppml-machine-learning-on-data-you-cannot-see.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valerio Maggio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ppml-machine-learning-on-data-you-cannot-see.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Privacy guarantee is the most crucial requirement when it comes to analyse sensitive data. However, data anonymisation techniques alone do not always provide complete privacy protection; moreover Machine Learning models could also be exploited to leak sensitive data when attacked, and no counter-measure is applied. Privacy-preserving machine learning (PPML …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Privacy guarantee is the most crucial requirement when it comes to analyse sensitive data. However, data anonymisation techniques alone do not always provide complete privacy protection; moreover Machine Learning models could also be exploited to leak sensitive data when attacked, and no counter-measure is applied. Privacy-preserving machine learning (PPML) methods hold the promise to overcome all these issues, allowing to train machine learning models with full privacy guarantees. In this tutorial we will explore several methods for privacy-preserving data analysis, and how these techniques can be used to safely train ML models without actually seeing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Python versioning in a changing world</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/python-versioning-in-a-changing-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wolf Vollprecht</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/python-versioning-in-a-changing-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python versioning is a critical aspect of maintaining a consistent ecosystem of packages, yet it can be challenging to get right. In this talk, we will explore the difficulties of Python versioning, including the need for upper bounds, and discuss mitigation strategies such as lockfiles in the Python packaging …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python versioning is a critical aspect of maintaining a consistent ecosystem of packages, yet it can be challenging to get right. In this talk, we will explore the difficulties of Python versioning, including the need for upper bounds, and discuss mitigation strategies such as lockfiles in the Python packaging ecosystem (pip, poetry, and conda / mamba). We will also highlight a new community effort to analyze Python libraries dynamically and statically to detect the symbols (or libraries) they are using. By analyzing symbol usage, we can predict when package combinations will start breaking with each other, achieving a high rate of correct predictions. Our goal is to gather more community inputs to create a robust compatibility matrix. Additionally, we are doing similar work in C/C++ using libabigail to address ABI problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling pandas to any size with PySpark</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/scaling-pandas-to-any-size-with-pyspark.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hyukjin Kwon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/scaling-pandas-to-any-size-with-pyspark.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses using the pandas API on Apache Spark to handle big data, and the introduction of Pandas Function APIs. Presented by an Apache Spark committer and a product manager, it offers technical and managerial insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Solara: A Pure Python, React-style Framework for Scaling Your Data Apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/solara-a-pure-python-react-style-framework-for-scaling-your-data-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maarten Breddels</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/solara-a-pure-python-react-style-framework-for-scaling-your-data-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solara is a pure Python web framework designed to scale complex applications. Leveraging a React-like API, Solara offers the scalability, component-based coding, and simple state management that have made React a standard for large web applications. Solara uses a pure Python implementation of React, Reacton, to create ipywidgets-based applications …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solara is a pure Python web framework designed to scale complex applications. Leveraging a React-like API, Solara offers the scalability, component-based coding, and simple state management that have made React a standard for large web applications. Solara uses a pure Python implementation of React, Reacton, to create ipywidgets-based applications that work both in the Jupyter Notebook environment and as standalone web apps with frameworks like FastAPI. This talk will explore the design principles of Solara, illustrate its potential with case studies and live examples, and provide resources for attendees to incorporate Solara into their own projects. Whether you're a researcher developing interactive visualizations or a data scientist building complex web applications, Solara provides a Python-centric solution for scaling your projects effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>The Helmholtz Analytics Toolkit for massively-parallel scientific Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/the-helmholtz-analytics-toolkit-for-massively-parallel-scientific-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Fabian Hoppe</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/the-helmholtz-analytics-toolkit-for-massively-parallel-scientific-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we will provide an overview of Heat's current features and capabilities and discuss its role in the ecosystem of distributed array computing and machine learning in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Timing and Benchmarking Scientific Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/timing-and-benchmarking-scientific-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kai Striega</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/timing-and-benchmarking-scientific-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific code is often complex, resource-intensive, and sensitive to performance issues, making accurate timing and benchmarking critical for optimising performance and ensuring reproducibility. However, benchmarking scientific code presents several challenges, including variability in input data, hardware and software dependencies, and optimisation trade-offs. In this talk, I discuss the importance …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific code is often complex, resource-intensive, and sensitive to performance issues, making accurate timing and benchmarking critical for optimising performance and ensuring reproducibility. However, benchmarking scientific code presents several challenges, including variability in input data, hardware and software dependencies, and optimisation trade-offs. In this talk, I discuss the importance of timing and benchmarking for scientific code and outline strategies for addressing these challenges. Specifically, I emphasise the need for representative input data, controlled benchmarking environments, appropriate metrics, and careful documentation of the benchmarking process. By following these strategies, developers can effectively optimise code performance, select efficient algorithms and data structures, and ensure the reliability and reproducibility of scientific computations.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Transformations in Three Dimensions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/transformations-in-three-dimensions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Fabisch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/transformations-in-three-dimensions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rigid transformation in 3D are complicated due to the multitude of different conventions and because they often form complex graphs that are difficult to manage. In this talk I will give a brief introduction to the topic and present the library pytransform3d as a set of tools that can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rigid transformation in 3D are complicated due to the multitude of different conventions and because they often form complex graphs that are difficult to manage. In this talk I will give a brief introduction to the topic and present the library pytransform3d as a set of tools that can help you to tame the complexity. Throughout the talk I will use examples from robotics (imitation learning, collision detection, state estimation, kinematics) to motivate the discussed features, even though presented solutions are useful beyond robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Where is the flock? The use of graph neural networks for bird identification with meteorological radar</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/where-is-the-flock-the-use-of-graph-neural-networks-for-bird-identification-with-meteorological-radar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olga Lyashevska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/where-is-the-flock-the-use-of-graph-neural-networks-for-bird-identification-with-meteorological-radar.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this project we generate tools to identify birds within the spatial extent of a meteorological radar. Using the opportunities created by modern dual-polarization radars we build graph neural networks to identify bird flocks. For this, the original point cloud data is converted to multiple undirected graphs following a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this project we generate tools to identify birds within the spatial extent of a meteorological radar. Using the opportunities created by modern dual-polarization radars we build graph neural networks to identify bird flocks. For this, the original point cloud data is converted to multiple undirected graphs following a set of predefined rules, which are then used as an input in graph convolutional neural network (Kipf and Welling, 2017, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1609.02907"&gt;https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1609.02907&lt;/a&gt;). Each node has a set of features such as range, x, y, z coordinates and several radar specific parameters e.g. differential reflectivity and phase shift which are used to build model and conduct graph-level classification. This tool will alleviate problem of manual identification and labelling which is tedious and time intensive. Going forward we also focus on using the temporal information in the radar data. Repeated radar measurements enable us to track these movements across space and time. This makes it possible for regional movement studies to bridge the methodological gap between fine-scale, individual-based tracking studies and continental-scale monitoring of bird migration. In particular, it enables novel studies of the roles of habitat, topography and environmental stressors on movements that are not feasible with current methodology. Ultimately, we want to apply the methodology to data from continental radar networks to study movement across scales.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I Follow CI/CD Principles When Writing Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/why-i-follow-cicd-principles-when-writing-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Artem Kislovskiy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/why-i-follow-cicd-principles-when-writing-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss the importance of Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) principles in the development of scientific applications, with a focus on creating robust and reproducible code that can withstand rigorous testing and scrutiny. The presentation will cover best practices for project structure and code organization …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss the importance of Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) principles in the development of scientific applications, with a focus on creating robust and reproducible code that can withstand rigorous testing and scrutiny. The presentation will cover best practices for project structure and code organization, as well as strategies for ensuring reproducibility, collaboration, and managing dependencies. By implementing CI/CD principles in scientific application development processes, researchers can improve efficiency, reliability, and maintainability, ultimately accelerating research.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>