<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pydata-amsterdam-2018.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Are You Ready for GDPR?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/are-you-ready-for-gdpr.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michele Appello</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/are-you-ready-for-gdpr.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michele will share her story and intro to the GDPR, breaking down the regulation in a digestible format. She will discuss the background of GDPR in terms of data privacy, the core points and key definitions in the regulation, the list of steps companies need to take and show some examples of what the industry is doing to prepare for the May 25th implementation date. She hopes that audience members will walk away from the keynote with a better understanding of the GDPR and how it can affect them and their companies – as well as gain insights on how their day to day work can be impacted by the regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category><category term="gdpr"></category></entry><entry><title>Asyncio, websockets, and BTC sitting in a tree</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/asyncio-websockets-and-btc-sitting-in-a-tree.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giovanni Lanzani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/asyncio-websockets-and-btc-sitting-in-a-tree.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asyncio is a different way to think about how you program. In this talk we will talk about using asyncio to consume data from a bitcoin exchange offering a websocket endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="asyncio"></category></entry><entry><title>Bayesian Deep learning with 10% of the weights</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/bayesian-deep-learning-with-10-of-the-weights.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Romijnders</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/bayesian-deep-learning-with-10-of-the-weights.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep learning grows in popularity and use, but it has two problems. Neural networks have millions of parameters and provide no uncertainty. In this talk, we solve both problems with one simple trick: Bayesian deep learning. We show how to prune 90% of the parameters while maintaining performance. As a bonus, we get the uncertainty over our predictions, which is useful for critical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building customer-visible data science dashboards with Altair / Vega / Vue</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/building-customer-visible-data-science-dashboards-with-altair-vega-vue.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Uwe L  Korn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/building-customer-visible-data-science-dashboards-with-altair-vega-vue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several tools to build ML dashboards and visulisations. Their focus is often on making it as simple as possible for a (Python) data scientist. Shipp ing them as part of our product means that other roles like frontend developers get involved. Aspects that ease development for one role, create pains for oth ers. We want to show how balance this using Altair, Vega and Vue.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Case Study in Travel Business - Time Series Analysis with Seasonal Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cheuk Ting Ho</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For time series analysis, everyone's talking about ARIMA or Holt-Winters. But there's other models which could also break down a seasonal series into trend, seasonality and noise. We will use an open source Python library called Seasonal to analyse B2B worldwide travel data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Challenges in building Machine Learning models in production</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/challenges-in-building-machine-learning-models-in-production.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elena Sokolova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/challenges-in-building-machine-learning-models-in-production.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk Elena will describe challenges that arise when building machine learning models that should run in production to personalize user's search. She will present biases that can be hidden in your observational data and can destroy your model completely and will explain several options on how you can correct for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Computer-aided design of advertisement product compositions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/computer-aided-design-of-advertisement-product-compositions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kay Hoogland</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/computer-aided-design-of-advertisement-product-compositions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to apply data science to a creative task? In my talk, I will cover my research to the (semi-)automated creation of advertisement product compositions. The resulting application co-creates compositions with graphic designers by making use of an evolutionary algorithm with user input. The algorithm is built in DEAP and runs on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Conversational AI with Rasa Core &amp; NLU</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/conversational-ai-with-rasa-core-nlu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Bocklisch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/conversational-ai-with-rasa-core-nlu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rasa NLU &amp;amp; Rasa Core are open source libraries for building machine learning-based chatbots and voice assistants. In this live-coding workshop you will learn the fundamentals of conversational AI and how to build your own using these open source libraries. In this workshop we will live-code a useful, engaging conversational AI bot based entirely on machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Creating correct and capable classifiers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/creating-correct-and-capable-classifiers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Ozsvald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/creating-correct-and-capable-classifiers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iteratively building a classifier requires a mix of skill, diagnostic ability and guesswork. I'll lay out a framework that helps you build reliable classifiers with greater confidence and less random guesswork. Tools demonstrated will include sklearn, YellowBrick, Shapley and pandas_profiling.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>DataFrames: scaling up and out</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/dataframes-scaling-up-and-out.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ondrej Kokes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/dataframes-scaling-up-and-out.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DataFrames of all sorts have become very popular for tabular data analytics for their nifty APIs and ease of use. But as they usually operate as in-memory engines, they can be hard to scale. In my talk, I'd like to outline several ways one can scale their compute platform to handle larger datasets without incurring much cost.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Deploying JupyterHub with Kubernetes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/deploying-jupyterhub-with-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Camilla Montonen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/deploying-jupyterhub-with-kubernetes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterHub is a great way to provide a data analytics environment for a class, a research group or a team of data scientists. In this talk, we will go through JupyterHub: what it is and how it works and how to setup a production ready deployment on a cloud provider using Kubernetes as the underlying infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Detecting Pikachu on Android using Tensorflow Object Detection</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/detecting-pikachu-on-android-using-tensorflow-object-detection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan De Dios Sanos Rivera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/detecting-pikachu-on-android-using-tensorflow-object-detection.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TensorFlow has a component named TensorFlow Object Detection, whose purpose is to train a system capable of recognizing objects in a frame. Usually, this technology is used to detect real-life objects, until I took on the challenge of building a detection system to detect everybody's favorite Pokemon, Pikachu. What is object detection, and how I built my model? That's what this talk is about.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dynamic Code Instrumentation with Hacked Interpreters</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/dynamic-code-instrumentation-with-hacked-interpreters.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Powell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/dynamic-code-instrumentation-with-hacked-interpreters.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've seen how easy it is to modify CPython—it's a C program after all, and one written to be understood and extended by normal human beings. But beyond the slow, deliberative process of adding features to the core language, what is the value of hacking your interpreter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk presents a practical example of dynamic code instrumentation using hacked interpreters.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Elegant data pipelining with Apache Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/elegant-data-pipelining-with-apache-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bolke de Bruin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/elegant-data-pipelining-with-apache-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Batch data processing, historically known as ETL,  is extremely challenging. It’s time-consuming, brittle, and often unrewarding. Not only that, it’s hard to operate, evolve, and troubleshoot. As ETL pipelines grow in complexity, and as data teams grow in numbers, using methodologies that provide clarity isn’t a luxury, it’s a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Forecasting airline passengers using designer machine learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/forecasting-airline-passengers-using-designer-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Backus</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/forecasting-airline-passengers-using-designer-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to accurately forecast the amount of passengers that will board a particular flight is crucial for airline operations. But how do we design a machine learning algorithm for this use case and in what ways can we improve it? In this talk, we start with a simple linear model, evolving to increasingly complex deep learning neural network architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>From cells to drug responses - machine learning in cancer research</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/from-cells-to-drug-responses-machine-learning-in-cancer-research.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Julian de Ruiter</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/from-cells-to-drug-responses-machine-learning-in-cancer-research.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning plays an important role in cancer research. In this talk, we’ll tackle the challenge of predicting which patients are likely to respond to given anti-cancer treatments. In doing so, we’ll show how tools such as Snakemake/Bioconda can be used to create reproducible workflows and illustrate the challenges of interpreting predictive models in large, highly-correlated feature spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Half Hour of Flower: Planting the seeds for great Image Quality</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/half-hour-of-flower-planting-the-seeds-for-great-image-quality.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dirk Guijt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/half-hour-of-flower-planting-the-seeds-for-great-image-quality.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Royal FloraHolland is the biggest flower auction in the world. And next to handling a lot of plants and flowers, we also handle a lot of pictures of plants and flowers. Pictures that need to be of a certain quality. We built a fully automized self-improving system to check the image quality by using deep learning models, asynchronous API technologies and Docker/AWS/Gitlab.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hands-on introduction to Deep Learning with Keras and Tensorflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/hands-on-introduction-to-deep-learning-with-keras-and-tensorflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Agundez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/hands-on-introduction-to-deep-learning-with-keras-and-tensorflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning has already conquered areas such as image recognition, NLP, voice recognition, and is a must-know tool for every Data Practitioner. This tutorial for aspiring Deep Learners will consist of a quick blunt Deep Learning overview followed by a hands-on tutorial that will teach you how to get started using Keras and Tesorflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="keras"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry><entry><title>Improve classification accuracy for customer contact transcriptions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/improve-classification-accuracy-for-customer-contact-transcriptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Vechtomova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/improve-classification-accuracy-for-customer-contact-transcriptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The correct classification of customer service calls/chat transcription is crucial to identify bottlenecks in customer facing business processes and in improving customers satisfaction. In this talk we discuss the technical and even harder business challenges we had to overcome at KPN in applying multiple Text Analytics techniques in order to achieve a workable classification accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Pentesting ChatOps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/keynote-pentesting-chatops.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Melanie Rieback</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/keynote-pentesting-chatops.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ChatOps, a concept originating from Github, is chatroom-driven DevOps for distributed teams, using chatbots (like Hubot) to execute custom scripts and plugins. We, at Radically Open Security, have applied the concept of ChatOps to the penetration testing workflow, and found that it fits outstandingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Learning credit networks with applications in financial industry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/learning-credit-networks-with-applications-in-financial-industry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sumit Sourabh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/learning-credit-networks-with-applications-in-financial-industry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to illustrate the importance of network-based models in financial industry since the 2007-08 crisis. I will present our novel method to learn a (Bayesian) network using default dependence of financial institutions and show how financial distress can propagate via such a network. I will share some examples where we extensively use NetworkX and bnlearn packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="networkx"></category><category term="bnlearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Monitoring models in production</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/monitoring-models-in-production.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jannes Klaas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/monitoring-models-in-production.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Data Scientists work is not done once machine learning models are in production. In this talk, Jannes will explain ways of monitoring Keras neural network models in production, how to track model decay and set up alerting using Flask, Docker and a range of self-built tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyData Amsterdam 2018 Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/pydata-amsterdam-2018-lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/pydata-amsterdam-2018-lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2018&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>PyData Amsterdam 2018 overview</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/pydata-amsterdam-2018-overview.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/pydata-amsterdam-2018-overview.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Promotional video for PyData Amsterdam 2018&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python and the Holy Grail of Causal Inference</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/python-and-the-holy-grail-of-causal-inference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dennis Ramondt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/python-and-the-holy-grail-of-causal-inference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Causal Inference, AKA how effective is your new product, policy or feature? Inspired by AB testing in tech, organizations have turned to randomized testing. However, randomization often fails, leaving us in a biased reality. Join us on our quest to dispel myths about randomized testing and build practical models for effect measurement in business situations, in this Eneco-Heineken joint talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>(Re)training word embeddings for a specific domain</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/retraining-word-embeddings-for-a-specific-domain.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jetze Schuurmans</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/retraining-word-embeddings-for-a-specific-domain.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Word embeddings (like GloVe, fastText and word2vec) are very powerful for capturing general word semantics. What if your use case is domain specific? Will your embeddings still work? If they don’t, how do you retrain them?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>SAMENVATTR, or, How to Make a Text Summarization Tool for your Language of Choice</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/samenvattr-or-how-to-make-a-text-summarization-tool-for-your-language-of-choice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Rodger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/samenvattr-or-how-to-make-a-text-summarization-tool-for-your-language-of-choice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how the autotldr bot on Reddit works? Ever want to build &amp;quot;tl;dr&amp;quot; functionality into your text processing system? Ever try to do so, only to find that all of the good out-of-the-box options are coded to work with English text and not your desired input language? If you answered &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; to any of the above questions, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Scaling Machine Learning jobs with Kubernetes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/scaling-machine-learning-jobs-with-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tarek Mehrez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/scaling-machine-learning-jobs-with-kubernetes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running Machine learning jobs at scale places painful demands on infrastructure from an operational perspective. As the number of jobs increase, having an easy-to-use infrastructure becomes a necessity. In this talk we will cover how we use Kubernetes at Textkernel as a job manager to scale our Tensorflow-based jobs. We will also explore other solutions such as distributed Tensorflow and Kubeflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Selection bias: The elephant in the room</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/selection-bias-the-elephant-in-the-room.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lucas Bernardi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/selection-bias-the-elephant-in-the-room.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll introduce the problem of selection bias in the context of machine learning, illustrate its consequences and present some solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Structured Streaming with PySpark and Azure Databricks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/structured-streaming-with-pyspark-and-azure-databricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrei Varanovich</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/structured-streaming-with-pyspark-and-azure-databricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;IoT adoption is raising, together with the number of other types of scenarios, where high-performance streaming analytics becomes a critical component. In this tutorial we focus on the capabilities of structured streaming in Apache Spark, for building so-called continuous applications in the cloud. Microsoft Azure is used as the running platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Super Donkey Cars</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/super-donkey-cars.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Niels Zeilemaker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/super-donkey-cars.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Donkey car is an open source DIY self driving platform powered by a Raspberry Pi running a Deep Learning network. In this talk we'll go into how we modified the platform to retrain the Deep Learning network on a AWS GPU instance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Data I Breathe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/the-data-i-breathe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gorjan Jovanovski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/the-data-i-breathe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in a age of technology, with enormous amounts of data being created and collected all around us. But, are we putting all of it to good use? Gorjan, a 25 year old software engineer, uses open data and a mobile app to lead a 3000 strong community of eco-activists in his home country of Macedonia, with the goal of saving 2.000.000 of his fellow citizens from a horrific air pollution problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Thompson Sampling for Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/thompson-sampling-for-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ruben Mak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/thompson-sampling-for-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I hope to give a clear overview of the opportunities for applying Thompson Sampling in machine learning. I will share some technical examples in recent developments (for example Bayesian Neural Networks using Edward) but more importantly I hope to trigger the audience to start thinking strategically about how we want our machine learning models to learn from new data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bayesian neural networks"></category><category term="edward"></category></entry><entry><title>Tricks, tips and topics in Text Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/tricks-tips-and-topics-in-text-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bhargav Srinivasa Desikan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/tricks-tips-and-topics-in-text-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an abundance of easily mineable text data (Whatsapp, twitter, and even our own e-mails!), and we have no excuse to not analyze it. In this workshop, we will learn some tips and tricks to deal with messy text data, before moving on to some lesser looked at text analysis techniques, such as text summarization, working with distance metrics, and an old personal favorite - topic models.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Unit Testing Data with Marbles</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/unit-testing-data-with-marbles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jane Stewart Adams</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/unit-testing-data-with-marbles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the same way that we need to make assertions about how code functions, we need to make assertions about data, and unit testing is a promising framework. In this talk, we'll explore what is unique about unit testing data, and see how Two Sigma's open source library Marbles addresses these unique challenges in several real-world scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="marbles"></category></entry><entry><title>Why AI in the Medical Field Both Sucks and Rocks...</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/why-ai-in-the-medical-field-both-sucks-and-rocks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kicky van Leeuwen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/why-ai-in-the-medical-field-both-sucks-and-rocks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep learning is hot and happening, also in the medical field, however implementation is slow. Why is that? How do you approach such problems and how to make this a success? Where do you get the privacy-sensitive data from? Do pre-trained networks work? Can we make it scalable in the cloud? I will address these issues with a case study: segmentation of 4D heart MRI for heart function analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>“Why Should I Trust You?” - Debugging black-box text classifiers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/why-should-i-trust-you-debugging-black-box-text-classifiers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tobias Sterbak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/why-should-i-trust-you-debugging-black-box-text-classifiers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classifying text is a common use case for machine learning algorithms. But despite widespread adoption, machine learning models remain mostly black boxes. Understanding the reasons behind predictions is, however, quite important in assessing trust, which is fundamental if one plans to take action based on a prediction. We will use eli5 and the LIME algorithm to explain text classifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="eli5"></category><category term="lime"></category></entry><entry><title>Winning (Some) Churners Back</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/winning-some-churners-back.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ferran Elias</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/winning-some-churners-back.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our presentation we will discuss our experience at Booking.com creating a marketing channel using incentive offers to bring churners back. The main elements of our strategy are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A model predicting the probability of churning for each customer in a given timeframe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimentation framework to incentivize customers based on the churn model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>