<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Developments of Super Resolution</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/developments-of-super-resolution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction of super resolution with deep learning techniques. Super
resolution is a technique which serve low- resolution image as input and
outputs high-resolution images. How to preserve edges and restore detail
information in the high-resolution image is very important. In this
talk, we will discuss the developments of super resolution, especially
methods using deep learning where pytorch is used during training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">GUAN Jingwei</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-hk-2018/developments-of-super-resolution.html</guid></item><item><title>Exploiting Emotional Knowledge from Emojis and #Hashtags</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/exploiting-emotional-knowledge-from-emojis-and-hashtags.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grasping other person’s emotions or sentiments through texts is
challenging even for humans sometimes. I bet you also have an experience
that once you were reading someone’s message multiple times to figure
out, “Is he/she upset? Or am I too sensitive?” Despite the difficulties,
figuring out emotion or sentiment in texts is crucial nowadays, due to
our daily habit of using emails, mobile messengers, social media, chats.
An interesting question is, “can we teach machines to understand
sentiment and emotions inside our texts?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce how to build a sentiment/emotion analysis system by
training deep learning models with a huge amount of tweets. We exploit
the emotional knowledge inside those texts by using emojis and hashtags
as weakly supevised label. Our system ranked Top 3 in SemEval 2018:
Affect in Tweets, a well-known competition in the NLP research
community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;blog:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/park-ji-%20ho/teaching-machines-to-read-emotions-in-texts-with-emojis-and-%20hashtags-%20a50b7e93384f"&gt;https://medium.com/park-ji-ho/teaching-machines-to-read-emotions-in-
texts-with-emojis-and-hashtags-
a50b7e93384f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;paper: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1804.08280"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1804.08280&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ji Ho Park</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-hk-2018/exploiting-emotional-knowledge-from-emojis-and-hashtags.html</guid></item><item><title>IoT in Home – Building a Toilet Vacancy Indicator</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/iot-in-home-building-a-toilet-vacancy-indicator.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is to encourage audiences start solving problems in their
everyday’s life by building IoT systems with Python, Raspberry Pi and
sensors. The technologies being used in the project of this talk is not
difficult, but when every pieces of technology comes together, we can
create something that actually helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Agenda:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. Demo video showing the problem, and how we are going to solve it&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. Real setup demo&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3. How the system was initiated, designed and implemented&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– System design overview&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– Hardware – sender and receiver&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– Python code&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– How sender and receiver links together&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4. Where to buy the hardware needed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;5. Q &amp;amp; A&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Arnold Chan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-hk-2018/iot-in-home-building-a-toilet-vacancy-indicator.html</guid></item><item><title>Neural network image recognition: A “Kong girl” approach to DIY photo sorting</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/neural-network-image-recognition-a-kong-girl-approach-to-diy-photo-sorting.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever felt fed up with digging photos out from thousands of images?
Should you group them by time or content? Want to tag not just your
friends, but also your pets? You know about some paid online services,
but they are not as tailor-made, and you want to keep the photos to
yourselves? Why not DIY? With image recognition by deep learning neural
networks, tedious photo tagging and searching steps can be much
simplified. Amidst the sea of selfies, skies, and food of a “Kong
girl”‘s collection, you’ll find a better way to ease your life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Claire Chung</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-hk-2018/neural-network-image-recognition-a-kong-girl-approach-to-diy-photo-sorting.html</guid></item><item><title>NoSQL Development for MySQL Document Store using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/nosql-development-for-mysql-document-store-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MySQL 8.0 introduced the MySQL Document Store, allowing developers to
work with SQL relational tables and schema-less JSON collections through
the use of the X DevAPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Join us to better understand how MySQL Connector/Python implements and
makes use of the X DevAPI along with a quick demo showcasing its most
relevant features.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Additionally, concepts such as the X Protocol, NoSQL and the
aforementioned X DevAPI are reviewed to get better understanding on
the MySQL Document Store&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan Ma</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-hk-2018/nosql-development-for-mysql-document-store-using-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Thumbor: a smart image processing pipeline</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/thumbor-a-smart-image-processing-pipeline.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thumbor is a smart imaging service, which enables on-demand crop,
resizing and flipping of images. With built-in state-of-the-art face and
feature detection algorithms, it delivers a very smart content-aware
image cropping and resizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will deliver an short introduction to thumbor and
discuss how HK01 leverages thumbor to build its next generation image
processing pipeline, serving thumbnails and responsive images to its 9M+
audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dick Tang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-hk-2018/thumbor-a-smart-image-processing-pipeline.html</guid></item><item><title>Big Data Journey in HK01</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/big-data-journey-in-hk01.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data is the foundation of everything in our business, including data reports, analytics dashboards, machine learning algorithms as well as artificial intelligent products. In HK01, we manage our own data. We feed our M.L. algorithms from our data silos. We enrich users’ reading experience through A.I. products. Python is at the center of the above processes. In this talk, we guide you through the usage of Python in HK01 Data Team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Mole T.Y. WONG</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/big-data-journey-in-hk01.html</guid></item><item><title>Breast cancer classification in digital pathology using Python and Deep Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/breast-cancer-classification-in-digital-pathology-using-python-and-deep-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is one of the leading cancer-related death causes
worldwide, specially for women. In this talk, we will talk about how
Deep Learning &amp;amp; Python could help pathologists to classify breast cancer
microscopic images. The speaker will share his approach that won the
“&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://iciar2018-challenge.grand-challenge.org/Legacy-results/"&gt;ICIAR 2018 Grand Challenge on Breast Cancer Histology
images&lt;/a&gt;”,
which was implemented in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to the papers for more details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1808.04277"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1808.04277&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-93000-8_106"&gt;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-93000-8_106&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scotty Kwok</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/breast-cancer-classification-in-digital-pathology-using-python-and-deep-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Collaboration hack with slackbot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/collaboration-hack-with-slackbot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know that Slack knows that Integration and API are easy to use
and are hackable collaboration platform? Even Python is able to easily
make chatbot by using slackbot ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/lins05/slackbot"&gt;https://github.com/lins05/slackbot&lt;/a&gt; ) .
With using this framework, you are able to let slackbot perform a Python
process triggered by a mention or a keyword in a conversation on Slack.
This is means that anything you can do with Python can be run on Slack!!
(For example, it is acquiring information from the database, acquiring
data using Web scraping, and deploying applications and so on.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this Talk Session, I’m going to introduce the points of utilization
of slackbot,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;with a talk on SQUEEZE’s efforts to improve the workflow,
communication and work realized by using slackbot.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Examples of Improve In SQUEEZE Inc (I Companies to which I belong ):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– slackbot make a primary response of request work beyond department&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– example of request are that inquiries about the system from business
team, Customer support etc. – slackbot receives request for products
and notifies them collectively at a fixed time.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kei Iwasaki</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/collaboration-hack-with-slackbot.html</guid></item><item><title>Current use cases for machine learning in the industry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/current-use-cases-for-machine-learning-in-the-industry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our speaker, Delon Yau, is currently a Software Engineer from the
Commercial Software Engineering Division at Microsoft Asia. He works
with key strategic customers in Asia to envision and build next
generation cloud solutions on artificial intelligence, big data
analytics, blockchain and IoT, on both the Microsoft and OSS stacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining Microsoft, Delon cofounded a number of startups and
solution companies in the UK and Hong Kong with broad technology
experience. He is also a hardware engineer with experience in sensors,
micro-controllers and wearable devices, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delon holds a Bachelor’s degree in Electrical and Electronic Engineering
from Imperial College and a Master’s degree in Computer Science from
UCL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Delon Yau</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/current-use-cases-for-machine-learning-in-the-industry.html</guid></item><item><title>Deep Learning in Python: Image Recognition for Anime Characters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/deep-learning-in-python-image-recognition-for-anime-characters.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep learning is a booming machine-learning technique which we often
read in a lot of articles nowadays. Deep learning sounds like an
intimidating concept for a lot of people, but everyone believes that
deep learning is a cutting- edge tool to solve a lot of problems. In
this talk, we will see how Python and various open-source tools are very
easy to use and very powerful for solving deep learning problems. For
the study case, we will have a 30-minute journey in revisiting image
recognition problem with anime characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will briefly explain how traditional machine learning works with
TensorFlow and introduces some alternatives tools out there. After that,
we will see how deep learning enhances our knowledge in the traditional
machine learning and how we can get more benefits from it. All of these
examples will be presented in the context of image recognition problem,
and while on it, we will also see the use cases of other tools, such as
OpenCV, OpenFace, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the main part of the talk, we will see that images of anime
characters are limited by nature, since it totally depends on number of
existing fan arts. In addition, 3D model (human face) cannot be applied
directly in solving this problem since 2D model (anime character face)
totally depends on the illustrator. Therefore, we will explore how we
can utilize transfer learning for model training with small amount of
dataset. Finally, we will build our own simple app with Sanic to serve
our ready-built model for other users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the concept of deep learning, transfer
learning, and how we can apply it to our own existing problems. In
addition, we will present some alternative PaaS as a comparison to build
a model from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iskandar Setiadi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/deep-learning-in-python-image-recognition-for-anime-characters.html</guid></item><item><title>Demystifying speech recognition with Project DeepSpeech</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/demystifying-speech-recognition-with-project-deepspeech.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our voices are no longer a mystery to speech recognition (SR) software,
the technology powering these services has amazed the humanity with its
ability to understand us. This talk aims to cover the intrinsic details
of advanced state of art SR algorithms with live demos of Project
DeepSpeech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A research says that “50% of all searches will be voice searches by
2020”. World’s technology giants have placed big bets with their
investments in services providing voice search, personal digital
assistant, IoT devices etc. Solving the problem of speech recognition is
a herculean task, given the complexity involved with data like human
voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover a brief history of speech recognition algorithms,
the challenges associated with building these systems and then explain
how one can build an advance speech recognition system using the power
of deep learning and for illustration, we will deep dive into Project
DeepSpeech. Project DeepSpeech is an open source Speech-To-Text engine
developed by Mozilla Research based on Baidu’s Deep Speech research
paper and implemented using Google’s TensorFlow library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speech recognition is not all about the technology, there are a lot more
concerns, challenges around how these AI models are being part of our
day to day life, its biases etc. The bigger question revolves around
centralization of these AI services, projects like Common Voice
addresses these problems by enabling all to be part of this revolution,
a part of the talk will focus on how people need to approach these type
of research keeping in mind the community and humanitarian benefits as
first priority.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vigneshwer Dhinakaran</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/demystifying-speech-recognition-with-project-deepspeech.html</guid></item><item><title>Deploying Django App On AWS Lambda</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/deploying-django-app-on-aws-lambda.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to run your application on cloud is one of most challenging tasks in
the full development cycle. With the latest serverless technology, we
can deploy our application easily on cloud, with much more affordable
cost, but with more server processing power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will also discuss on how to archive asynchronous function call
on serverless architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/deploying-django-app-on-aws-lambda.html</guid></item><item><title>Deploying Machine Learning Models in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/deploying-machine-learning-models-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is now widely used in different applications. In some
cases, it is sufficient to generate batch results using machine learning
models in an offline manner. However, in other cases, models must be
deployed online in a production environment, such that end users or
other system components can benefit from the real-time outputs of these
models. Serving machine learning models involves mostly engineering
challenges, including designing the interface, optimizing the time
required to generate predictions and the computing resources required to
run the models, etc. In this talk, I will discuss different ways of
serving machine learning models in Python, and introduce several useful
Python packages that would make deploying machine learning models much
easier. I will also share some experience in deploying different kinds
of machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Albert Au Yeung</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/deploying-machine-learning-models-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Distributed System in Deep Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/distributed-system-in-deep-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent trends in distributed Deep Learning and how distributed
system can both massively reduce training time and enable
parallelisation. I will introduce different distributed deep learning
paradigms, including model-level parallelism and data-level parallelism,
and demonstrate how data parallelism can be used for distributed
training.In next iteration phase of deep learning there will be need of
distributed GPU computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As data volumes increase, GPU clusters will be needed for the new
distributed methods that already produce produce the state-of-the-art
results for ImageNet and Cifar-10, such as neural architecture search.
Auto-ml is also predicated on the availability of GPU clusters. Deep
Learning systems at hyper-scale AI companies attack the toughest
problems with distributed deep learning. Distributed Deep Learning
enables both AI researchers and practitioners to be more productive and
the training of models that would be intractable on a single GPU server.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ashutosh Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/distributed-system-in-deep-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Enjoy type hinting and its benefits</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/enjoy-type-hinting-and-its-benefits.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Python 3, type hinting was prompted. Thanks to this, static type
analysis is now available in Python’s world. It is possible to use this
mechanism with mypy, intellij etc. In this session we will learn about
type hinting in Python 3.5 / 3.6/ 3.7. Next, learn how to use static
type analysis using mypy. It is also possible to use mypy not only in
Python 3 but also in Python 2. In other words, it is said to demonstrate
great power to port Python 2 code to Python 3. In fact there are already
successes like the following projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this session, I am pleased that you can think about writing
python code and writing tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.zulip.org/2016/10/13/static-types-in-python-oh-mypy/"&gt;http://blog.zulip.org/2016/10/13/static-types-in-python-oh-mypy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Masato Nakamura</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/enjoy-type-hinting-and-its-benefits.html</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneous Job processing with Apache Kafka</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/heterogeneous-job-processing-with-apache-kafka.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apache Kafka is widely used in large scale message processing
applications. However, build a (job|task|work) processing system with
Kafka is not straightforward. The talk will share experience on building
a heterogeneous Job processing with Kafka and Python. The mentioned job
processing mechanism can be made use of to several scenarios, e.g.,
cloud resource provisioning, tiering storage system and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chu, Hua-Rong</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/heterogeneous-job-processing-with-apache-kafka.html</guid></item><item><title>Honey, there is a Python in my Android Phone!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple scripting, such as Python, Bash, PHP, Perl are all embedded in
modern operating system. Since Android is also a linux-based operating
system, with some techniques, it is also possible for us to write a
script. Unfortunately before SL4A arrives (Scripting Language 4
Android), it is not possible for us to script on Android phone. SL4A
provides rich APIs that allow user to access Android intents such as GPS
location, Accelerometer, Camera, Battery status, and etc. through
scripting. Hence with the rich APIs, the user can build a very simple
script to interact with those APIs, without building a complex app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks shows how we can interact with android intents and APIs via
RPC using python client embedded inside the android app, through SL4A
app. First the speaker introduces various python related apps available
for android OS. Next the speaker will show the relationship and
interaction between Android API and Python API inside SL4A, and how RPC
is used as communication between two APIs, hence demonstrate how a new
different service/intent can be built based on the provided Android API,
by doing some hacking on Python API inside SL4A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker will begin his talk with introduction on the basic of RPC,
and illustrate the relationship between Android APIs and Python APIs in
SL4A, by comparing both Android and Python code. The speaker will then
demonstrate how different android intents can be accessed on the android
devices, through various demo, such as reading GPS coordinate and x, y,
z position from the accelerometer, together with making a phone call
through python client on android phone. In the end, the speaker will
demonstrate how a flask application that allows user to send SMS
messages through Rest APIs, can be built on top on the android.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ing Wei, Tang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html</guid></item><item><title>How I battle with HK open data in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/how-i-battle-with-hk-open-data-in-python.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ho Wa Wong</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/how-i-battle-with-hk-open-data-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>How to Evolve Life using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/how-to-evolve-life-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will demonstrate how to create Artificial Life in a
computer using Python and its wonderful libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python program, called “Lenia”, is developed to discover/evolve new
life species, using its interactive UI to facilitate Evolutionary
Algorithms (EA). A video recorded from the program won the Virtual
Creatures Contest in GECCO conference 2018, Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;It utilizes the following libraries:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– NumPy for matrix calculation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– PyOpenCL/PyCUDA and Reikna for GPU acceleration – SciPy and
PIL/Pillow for image processing&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;– Tkinter (and potentially Matplotlib) for interactive UI – Subprocess
and FFmpeg for real-time video&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenia is now open source at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Chakazul/Lenia"&gt;https://github.com/Chakazul/Lenia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bert Chan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/how-to-evolve-life-using-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Industrial Machine Learning Pipelines with Python &amp; Airflow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning and data pipelines in Python. I will
cover practical presentation that will build from the basics of Airflow,
and show how it is possible to build scalable and distributed machine
learning data pipelines using a distributed architecture with a
producer- consumer backend using Celery. I will provide insights on some
of the key learnings I have obtained throughout my career building
machine learning systems, as well as caveats and best practices
deploying scalable data pipelines systems in production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alejandro Saucedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/lightning-talks.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/lightning-talks.html</guid></item><item><title>Python Community and PyCon in Hong Kong and APAC</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/python-community-and-pycon-in-hong-kong-and-apac.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sammy and Noah will introduce Python Community and PyCon in Hong Kong and APAC, and status of these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noah Chen</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/python-community-and-pycon-in-hong-kong-and-apac.html</guid></item><item><title>Quant Trading with artificial intelligence</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/quant-trading-with-artificial-intelligence.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The objective of the talk is to provide an introduction of how
artificial intelligence could be applied in stock trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will introduce how to use Python to extract historical
open-high- low-close (OHLC) data, perform data processing, recognise
patterns in the stock market with artificial intelligence algorithms and
eventually backtest the strategy. The talk will also touch on further
work that could be done, including the scraping and feature engineering
of alternative data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Lee</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/quant-trading-with-artificial-intelligence.html</guid></item><item><title>Ready, Get Set, Go! Development Sprints in Python community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/ready-get-set-go-development-sprints-in-python-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk would cover all about the development sprint which has been
hidden weapon of Python community that helps us to have a healthy
ecosystem. In this talk, I’ll show the history of development sprint,
how it helps us become a strong and diverse community, and how can you
host your own development sprint along with what you need to become a
good participant. Also I’ll share PyCon Korea’s development sprint cases
as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Younggun Kim</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/ready-get-set-go-development-sprints-in-python-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Secure yourself (&amp; your apps) with Secretless</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/secure-yourself-your-apps-with-secretless.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All apps need secrets – it could be passwords, API key or cert. We need
tons of secrets to do our Dev job, and at the same time, make us as
potential suspects during data breaches or cyberattacks. It is totally
unavoidable, until now. In this session, 2 open source projects, Conjur
&amp;amp; Secretless, will be introduced. The speaker will explain how to enable
your apps to work without secrets, such that you &amp;amp; your apps are both
secured.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Quincy Cheng</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/secure-yourself-your-apps-with-secretless.html</guid></item><item><title>Train and optimize your models with automated machine learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/train-and-optimize-your-models-with-automated-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Train and optimize your models with automated machine learning&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Delon Yau</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/train-and-optimize-your-models-with-automated-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Unlock the power of insurtech! A case study of digitizing the risk assessment in insurance using powerful python libraries and optimise performance with advanced machine learning models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/unlock-the-power-of-insurtech-a-case-study-of-digitizing-the-risk-assessment-in-insurance-using-powerful-python-libraries-and-optimise-performance-with-advanced-machine-learning-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Part 1 – Digitizing documents with powerful python libraries&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;So.. in the digital era you suddenly realise that until very recently
not all valuable information kept is/was machine friendly, there are
tons of word and pdf documents with reports, meetings minutes,
contracts and so-on waiting to be re-discovered. With python libraries
PdfMiner, PyPDF2 among others, we will unlock the power of text data
in pdf format.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 – Optimise risk assessment with advanced machine learning models
Traditional risk assessment in insurance process can be based on
creating a set of rules to classify cases that are likely to default.
With powerful machine learning libraries such as SCIKIT-LEARN and
XGBOOST, a probability of default model is trained using historical data
to predict the future cases. In order to understand the decision making
process, we can evaluate the output using Eli5 libraries and create
visualisation tools for the end users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Calvin Cheung</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/unlock-the-power-of-insurtech-a-case-study-of-digitizing-the-risk-assessment-in-insurance-using-powerful-python-libraries-and-optimise-performance-with-advanced-machine-learning-models.html</guid></item></channel></rss>