<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-russia-2013.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building Public Infrastructure with Autosustainble Services</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/building-public-infrastructure-with-autosustainble-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Lindsay</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/building-public-infrastructure-with-autosustainble-services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, I realized we needed a vehicle other than startups to build sustainable open source services. This need came from my own problem of building lots and lots of simple services (usually in Python) and not having the time or desire to build a business around them. These services include Localtunnel, RequestBin, Airscript, and others. Here I'll show these projects, their place in the ecosystem, and what I plan to do about making them sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Celery for internal API in SOA infrastructure</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/celery-for-internal-api-in-soa-infrastructure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roman Imankulov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/celery-for-internal-api-in-soa-infrastructure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of Celery is to execute background tasks. As a rule, Celery processes use the same code base as the main application. I suggest to have a look at Celery from the other side and try to use in as a transport for linking the dispersed application components.  The report will show the particular examples of API realization on Celery, take a good look at questions connected with the routing of demands to workers. Also there will be told why exactly Celery is so good for inside API building, in what situations the usage can be excess. The audience will learn how to connect the components of dispersed application in the whole thing  fast and without extra consumptions, get rid of coherence, and possibly to look at your application from the other side. It’s taken that listeners know the queue messengers concept and conceive why Celery or analogous solutions  can be used&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Distributed execution Python code on 1000+ servers.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/distributed-execution-python-code-on-1000-servers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexandr Budkar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/distributed-execution-python-code-on-1000-servers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll talk about created in Yandex infrastructure for administration a lot of servers, about problems which arise in work with many computers and about the used technologies. Report will be interest those, who develop distributed systems, high loaded services, encounter with processing a lot of data in real time. Also system administrators, who exploit 10+ servers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Django 1.6 and beyond: The Django Roadmap</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/django-16-and-beyond-the-django-roadmap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Russell Keith-Magee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/django-16-and-beyond-the-django-roadmap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the impending release of Django 1.5, now is a good time to reflect on the roadmap for Django 1.6 and beyond. In this talk, Django Core Developer Russell Keith-Magee will gaze into his crystal ball and speculate about what the future may hold for Django -- both in the short term, and possibilities for the long term.
Audience: Existing Django users interested in what the future holds for their web framework of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2013-02-25</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/lightning-talks-2013-02-25.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/lightning-talks-2013-02-25.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks February 25 2013&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Re-inventing Python packaging and testing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/re-inventing-python-packaging-and-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Holger Krekel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/re-inventing-python-packaging-and-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python still does not have a built-in installer that can install dependencies.  You have to first install setuptools/distribute and then use easy_install/pip.  Installation of packages is slow and depends on reachability of  pypi.python.org and other servers.  There is no quality control where you could e. g. see on which platforms the package successfully installs, let alone has its automated tests passing.  There is not really a standard way to run tests.  This talk outlines my plans for improving the situation, including a demo of a new (in-development) PyPI server that speeds up installation by an order of magnitude for many packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Redis, the hacker's database</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/redis-the-hackers-database.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Amir Salihefendic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/redis-the-hackers-database.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple_queue: feature set, comparison with Celery and Rq&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;redis_graph: available options, integration with other tools, and the big-O performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bitmapist, idea, architecture, reports based on cohorts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optionally: tagged-logger / ormist (lightweight Object-to-Redis mapper)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optionally: scripting possibility of Lua, Lua-jit (almost as fast as C)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>System of data synchronization between services evolution</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/system-of-data-synchronization-between-services-evolution.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dmitry Prokofjev</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/system-of-data-synchronization-between-services-evolution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report will explain why Yandex needed the data synchronization and what we had to meet with in the process: why we synchronize in the application level. Update log vs Insert log. Problems related with DB. Types of data, transactions absence. Problems related with Django. Problems related with the changings below the application level. For instance, mass update.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Tornado – not only web-sites</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/tornado-not-only-web-sites.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valentin Sinisyn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-25:pycon-russia-2013/tornado-not-only-web-sites.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In «Ideco» we don’t do web-developing, we create solutions for web infrastructure which make complicated things easier. There is Linux and other system instruments laid in the depths of these solutions and there’s a good web-interface shown on the surface. Tornado takes the middle  and provides the connection between “top” and “bottom”. Why does it go this way and is why web-framework a successful decision for system programming? You will learn all of these issues from the report. Report will be helpful for Python-programmers, who want to learn the possibilities of Tornado, and also for developers of dispersed systems solving the problems of connection organization between components.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Advanced Flask patterns</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/advanced-flask-patterns.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Armin Ronacher</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/advanced-flask-patterns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk shows some interesting patterns for large scale Flask applications and how Flask extension should be structured. It also dives into some of the more unknown helpers in the Werkzeug and Jinja2 base libraries. The goal of this talk is to share some of the things that the documentation can’t explain well by itself. Required prerequisites: basic knowledge of how Flask operates.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>An approach to versioning in relational database</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/an-approach-to-versioning-in-relational-database.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Konstantin Lopukhin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/an-approach-to-versioning-in-relational-database.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to tell about data versioning  in relational database – where this problem comes from, possible ways of statement and solution. Particularly I will tell about interval based approach which allows working with the system at any moment in the past, do the whole system back-off or back-off of its separate parts. This approach realized in a small library “documents” for Django, but the concept is easy movable. I will take the usage of this approach for traditional applications and for versioned EAV database building, showing data like a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building a development community: Lessons and challenges</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/building-a-development-community-lessons-and-challenges.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Russell Keith-Magee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/building-a-development-community-lessons-and-challenges.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 7 years, Django has grown from an in-house project in an obscure Kansas newsroom, to a project with global reach, in use on all 7 continents, with contributors and users all over the planet. How has the Django project managed this process of growth? What lessons can other projects learn from Django's successes and failures? And how can Django protect it's long term survival? In this talk, Django Core Developer Russell Keith-Magee will reflect on the history of the Django project, and look at how Django -- and other open source projects -- can build, grow and sustain their communities. Audience: Anyone involved in open source.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Construction distributed caching system and messaging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/construction-distributed-caching-system-and-messaging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ilya Biin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/construction-distributed-caching-system-and-messaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the methods optimization speed and quality of work your website is caching. Within the framework of presentation I want share practical experience in the creation, setting and tuning of distributed caching system. Emphasis will be paid features of work such system in conditions changeability network environment and instability of hardware. As well it will be about the exchange of messages through such system, its advantages and disadvantages. Presentation aimed on architects and developers of systems, who works with &amp;quot;heavy&amp;quot; data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to transition to Python 3?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/how-to-transition-to-python-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Korobov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/how-to-transition-to-python-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll tell how do matters stand with transition to Python 3, why should it transition and how (on my mind) transition to it. Knowledge can be applied on practice at the same day. We'll be porting several libraries on evening workshop/sprint. I hope that after the report and the workshop everyone's skill of porting code on Python 3 is systematized. This skill will become necessary soon for reading majority popular project's code for example and for benefit of the World Civilization, why not?:-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2013-02-24</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/lightning-talks-2013-02-24.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/lightning-talks-2013-02-24.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks February 24 2013&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Low-latency and soft-realtime на Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/low-latency-and-soft-realtime-na-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Denis Kolodin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/low-latency-and-soft-realtime-na-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report will tell about software developing working on high speeds and having the predictable reaction time. Also there will be presented the Python integration ways with ctypes and cython with the high-speed services of the operation system. It will touch upon the questions  of  memory, processes, streams, fibers and GIL managingcontrol. The audience will learn how to build systems with the expected reaction time. The knowledge can be used for servers’ development servicing a lot of clients simultaneously or executing high-speed data processing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>MongoEngine: NoORM for NoSQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/mongoengine-noorm-for-nosql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sergey Matveyenko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/mongoengine-noorm-for-nosql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowdays non relational databases become more popular than relational, in particular, MongoDB. However, even experienced developers, who are familiar with relational databases, their experience don't help them and sometimes it interfere. I'll tell about using MongoEngine, which allows you to bring methods of application development by Python with using MongoDB to more traditional approaches. This will be useful all Python developers who have an interest in MongoDB and non relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PEP 3156 — Standard of asynchronous IO Support Rebooted in Python.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/pep-3156-standard-of-asynchronous-io-support-rebooted-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Svetlov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/pep-3156-standard-of-asynchronous-io-support-rebooted-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python already has a lot of libraries for network programming. The most famous are twisted, tornado, gevent, medusa/asyncore. These systems are not compatible with each other, that does not give a possibility to write cross-platform libraries working in any event loop. PEP 3156 proposes new general standart, that will be able to support all developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Round table: Do you need to switch from Python 2 to Python 3?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/round-table-do-you-need-to-switch-from-python-2-to-python-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/round-table-do-you-need-to-switch-from-python-2-to-python-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Round table&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>SaltStack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/saltstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mihail Yumatov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/saltstack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SaltStack – is an instrument for parallel commands execution on servers where commands are functions on Python. In my report I will try to explain why you should pay attention to SaltStack even if you are actually using Chef or Puppet, why – how it can be helpful. I will speak about the usage of how we use SaltStack for the projects deployment automation and take into consideration the additional good possibilities like notification system between services, system of users’ rights and some other things.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Scaling for Success: How to build proper scalable web apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/scaling-for-success-how-to-build-proper-scalable-web-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Cramer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/scaling-for-success-how-to-build-proper-scalable-web-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll talk about what I see as a successful scaling strategy for growing companies. Specifically it will focus on things you should avoid early on, and where you can get easy wins. Additionally I'll cover various high level components of an early scaling strategy such as database sharding, CDN caching, and overall architecture to simplify the growing pains.
- How to approach sharding (architecture)
- Horizontal vs vertical, which solution is right and when
- How we sharded the Django ORM
- Materialized views using Redis
- Buffered counters using Redis&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Static analysis of Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/static-analysis-of-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Vlasovskih</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/static-analysis-of-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Static analysis provides the information of the source code without executing it. We'll consider available means of static analysis code by Python (PyLint, PyFlakes, Pep8, inspection IDE) and will talk about problems that they can find automatically in code. I'll talk about the approaches that are based static analysis in these tools and about the specifics of the analysis of Python as dynamic language. Report introduces you whith tools of static analysis, using that in daily practice you can reduce quantity of problems in Python code (errors, exceptions, and stylistic differences).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Test Driven Development in Python and Django.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/test-driven-development-in-python-and-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ilya Shalyapin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/test-driven-development-in-python-and-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In books, articles and videos most test examples are simplified to much. So it's very hard to apply these examples to real work. Real projects are not so simple. In real project we depend on internet connection, databases and filesystems. It's not obvious how to test such things. We will show test examples and tools that we use every day in our practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Test optimization in terms of Django and Postgres</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/test-optimization-in-terms-of-django-and-postgres.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Grisha Kostjuk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/test-optimization-in-terms-of-django-and-postgres.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test execution speed is important not only in TDD but also for Continuous Integration. I will tell you how we organized test environment in Ostrovok.ru: how we isolate the base and cash, how solved the problem with of  launching in to several streams, about the advantages of our runner pluses…In general, I will share the experience how we do it and why the report will especially be helpful for projects which have the real base in tests used, because sqlite in the memory doesn’t fit. And for those who think  about tests’ acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What happens inside of asynchronous code?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2013/what-happens-inside-of-asynchronous-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Koshelev</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-02-24:pycon-russia-2013/what-happens-inside-of-asynchronous-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What happens inside asynchronous code? What to do if logic becomes cpu-bound? Is it possible to create the hybrid synchronous- asynchronous architecture? I will try to answer these questions in terms of Tornado application. I will make the visualization of application and suggest the ways to solve some problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>