<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Decoupling Django with Django REST (and a sprinkle of React)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/decoupling-django-with-django-rest-and-a-sprinkle-of-react.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="abstract"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of JavaScript as the lingua-franca of the web and the
steady growth of libraries like React, today’s web developers can build
rich and well structured frontend experiences. Pair that with Django and
Django REST framework and you get the perfect combination. But it’s not
all bells and whistles. What challenges are we going to face when
decoupling Django with Django REST? What are the best practices? How to
structure such a project? In this talk I’ll guide Django developers
(both beginners and intermediate) from 0 to structuring a decoupled
Django project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="description"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to give Django developers an overview of a
Django REST project, paired with React, as well as the tradeoffs of the
decoupled approach. By the end of the talk the developer should be able
to configure a new Django REST project and use a frontend library for
interacting with the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-and-when-to-decouple-django"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;1. Why and when to decouple Django&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways for decoupling a Django application and each one
depends on the use case. In this section we’ll outline what decoupling
is, why decoupling is a great approach and why sometimes it is not the
right thing to do. We’ll see what the challenges of such approach are
and how to deal with authentication in a decoupled context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-rest-fundamentals"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;2. Django REST fundamentals&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django REST framework is a Django application for exposing API endpoints
from a Django project. It this section we’ll see the building blocks of
a Django API app: the model, the serializer and the view. Models should
not be a surprise for the audience, they come from Django. Serializers
instead are provided by Django REST. We’ll also see how a Django REST
view looks like and how to leverage both function based views and
generic views within the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="setting-up-the-frontend"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;3. Setting up the frontend&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key for a truly decoupled experience is a frontend for consuming and
interacting with the API. In this section we’ll see how to structure a
Django REST project alongside with React. We will explore two
approaches: fully decoupled frontend and mixed frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-note-on-testing-and-closing-words"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;4. A note on testing and closing words&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of a decoupled Django site we move from the typical
Django tests to testing the API’s response instead. We will see how a
simple API test looks like. And for the JavaScript frontend we’ll take a
look at the current available tooling for functional testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1735"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1735&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valentino Gagliardi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/decoupling-django-with-django-rest-and-a-sprinkle-of-react.html</guid><category>javascript</category><category>django-rest-framework</category><category>REST</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning for brain MRI segmentation: Big Data, AI and HPC meet together</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-for-brain-mri-segmentation-big-data-ai-and-hpc-meet-together.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With ever-increasing advancements in technology, neuroscientists are
able to collect data in greater volumes and with finer resolution. There
has been a growing interest in leveraging this vast volume of data
across levels of analysis, measurement techniques, and experimental
paradigms to gain more insight into brain function. At multiple stages
and levels of neuroscience investigation, ML holds great promise as an
addition to the arsenal of analysis tools for discovering how the brain
works. As quantitative analysis of brain MRI is routine for many
neurological diseases and conditions, deep learning-based segmentation
approaches for brain Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) are gaining
interest due to their self-learning and generalisation ability over
large amounts of data. On the other hand, High Performance Computing
(HPC) and AI will increasingly intertwine as we transition to an
exascale future using new computing, storage, and communications
technologies. In this talk I will walk you through fundamentals of
generating high- performance deep-learning models in TensorFlow platform
using Python on large computing system (e.g NVIDIA® Tesla® GPUs powered
by Tensor Cores), in order to infer and segment thousands of cell
centroids out of the brain objects of interest. From a more
technological perspective, although astonishing results have been
achieved concerning the distribution of training large convolutional
neural networks on big data, to date the Python scientific ecosystem is
still missing tools for an optimised and, above all, distributed
inference of deep learning models. In this talk I will show you how a
tiling-based inferencing approach could be a good solution to remedy the
problem. The talk is intended for intermediate PyData researchers and
practitioners. Basic to intermediate level experience in image
recognition/object detection deep learning applications is assumed.
Overall, a good proficiency with the Python language and with scientific
python libraries (e.g. numpy, TensorFlow, Keras) are required for the
entire talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1794"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1794&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giuseppe Di Bernardo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-for-brain-mri-segmentation-big-data-ai-and-hpc-meet-together.html</guid><category>GPUComputing</category><category>parallelization</category><category>bio-informatics</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>ComputerVision</category><category>optimization</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category></item><item><title>Immagino: un racconto di serverless e codeless (più o meno).</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/immagino-un-racconto-di-serverless-e-codeless-piu-o-meno.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gs1it.org/"&gt;GS1 Italy&lt;/a&gt; abbiamo realizzato il servizio
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://immagino.biz/"&gt;Immagino&lt;/a&gt;, dove vengono digitalizzati prodotti
merceologici. La parte interessante è come ci portiamo in casa le
immagini e le descrizioni: abbiamo creato una pipeline di elaborazione
con &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://aws.amazon.com/"&gt;aws&lt;/a&gt;, vedremo insieme il disegno
dell’applicazione, i servizi (sqs, sns, lambda, s3) e package (zappa,
asyncio, boto3) utilizzati. Non servono partiolari conoscenze di aws e
Python, l’obiettivo è mostrare un caso d’uso in produzione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1690"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1690&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Strappazzon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/immagino-un-racconto-di-serverless-e-codeless-piu-o-meno.html</guid><category>aws</category><category>boto3</category><category>zappa</category><category>lambda-functions</category><category>packages</category><category>tools</category><category>pythonscripts</category></item><item><title>Introduzione a Zerynth: Python per Microcontrollori e Applicazioni IoT</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/introduzione-a-zerynth-python-per-microcontrollori-e-applicazioni-iot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Durante il talk verrà presentato Zerynth
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.zerynth.com/"&gt;www.zerynth.com&lt;/a&gt;), un software per la
programmazione di &lt;strong&gt;microcontrollori&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; e la realizzazione
di applicazioni &lt;strong&gt;IoT&lt;/strong&gt; e per l’ &lt;strong&gt;Industria 4.0&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I principali argomenti trattati saranno:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perchè utilizzare Zerynth (e quindi Python) per programmare
dispositivi IoT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differenza tra Zerynth e il Python tradizionale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differenza tra Zerynth ed altre piattaforme di programmazione
&lt;strong&gt;“embedded”&lt;/strong&gt; come &lt;strong&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong&gt; , &lt;strong&gt;Micropython&lt;/strong&gt; e &lt;strong&gt;Arduino&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panoramica delle schede elettroniche supportate e dei servizi
&lt;strong&gt;Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; compatibili. In particolare verrà presentata la board
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://4zerobox.com/"&gt;4zerobox&lt;/a&gt;, una delle schede elettroniche
ufficialmente supportate da Zerynth, mostrandone le caratteristiche
principali e le applicazioni in &lt;strong&gt;campo industriale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target ideale&lt;/strong&gt; : sviluppatori Python, professionisti dell’IoT,
designers, studenti e insegnanti, makers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Per approfondire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La suite di sviluppo Zerynth è composta da:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zerynth Studio&lt;/strong&gt; , un IDE professionale per la programmazione in
Python su schede elettroniche a microcontrollore. Zerynth Studio è
free e cross-platform. Scaricabile da qui:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.zerynth.com/zerynth-studio/"&gt;https://www.zerynth.com/zerynth-studio/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zerynth Virtual Machine&lt;/strong&gt; , un sistema operativo real-time
multithreaded che fornisce una reale indipendenza dall’hardware e che
permette il riutilizzo del codice su qualsiasi architettura MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zerynth App&lt;/strong&gt; , una App generica per smartphone con cui
visualizzare i dati e/o controllare i dispositivi programmati con
Zerynth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1488"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1488&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luigi Francesco Cerfeda</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/introduzione-a-zerynth-python-per-microcontrollori-e-applicazioni-iot.html</guid><category>micropython</category><category>iot</category><category>embedded</category><category>industry applications</category><category>microcontroller</category><category>aws</category><category>InternetOfThings</category><category>InternetDelleCose</category><category>industry4.0</category><category>google-cloud</category></item><item><title>Let the AI Do the Talk: Adventures with Natural Language Generation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/let-the-ai-do-the-talk-adventures-with-natural-language-generation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in Artificial Intelligence have shown how computers can
compete with humans in a variety of mundane tasks, but what happens when
creativity is required?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the concept of Natural Language Generation, the
task of automatically generating text, for examples articles on a
particular topic, poems that follow a particular style, or speech
transcripts that express some attitude. Specifically, we’ll discuss the
case for Recurrent Neural Networks, a family of algorithms that can be
trained on sequential data, and how they improve on traditional language
models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is for beginners, we’ll focus more on the intuitions behind the
algorithms and their practical implications, and less on the
mathematical details. Practical examples with Python will showcase
Keras, a library to quickly prototype deep learning architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brief outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Natural Language Generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Modelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recurrent Neural Networks and Long Short Term Memory for NLG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RNN examples with Keras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1574"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1574&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Bonzanini</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/let-the-ai-do-the-talk-adventures-with-natural-language-generation.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>Keras</category><category>natural-language-processing</category><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>Python Standard Library, the hidden gems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/python-standard-library-the-hidden-gems.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La standard library di Python è ricca di strumenti, al punto che si dice
che Python arrivi “con le batterie incluse”. Ma con così tanti strumenti
e librarie a disposizione è facile perdersi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk mira ad esporre alcune ricette, snippet e modi di usare parti
della standard library che possono essere meno note o che non sono
trattati in rete o nei più comuni libri su Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk mira ad esporre un insieme di brevi esempi che possano far
pensare ai programmatori presenti “oh, non ci avevo mai pensato” o che
possano dimostrare come in molti casi non è necessario appoggiarsi a
librerie esterne per ottenere quello che si vuole in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcune degli esempi esposti sono tratti ed approfonditi dal libro
“Modern Python Standard Library Cookbook”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1532"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1532&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Molina</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/python-standard-library-the-hidden-gems.html</guid><category>libraries</category><category>best-practices</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Python Website is Slow? Think Again!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/python-website-is-slow-think-again.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a Python avid user, we read a lot of articles that describe Python as
a slow, interpreted language. At a certain point, some people start to
blame the language itself for performance problems and consider to
migrate their codebase to other languages. However, the success story of
Instagram in handling four hundred million users has shown us that
Python is not the bottleneck, but our codebase is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, the speaker will share a tale of improving Python website
performances in medium-sized enterprise (serving million users) that I’m
currently working at. In a year, we finally achieved speed improvement
from the average response time of 400 ms to 150 ms per request and we
could save around $100k per year in AWS EC2 instance provisioning, which
is around 60% of total cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several key points that we have learned from our development process
includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking database queries with Python decorator will reduce number of
unnecessary queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using an async framework does not guarantee your codebase is
implementing it correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default configured third-party library is not always suitable for all
use cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizing memory profiler and pdb properly will help you in
pinpointing application bottleneck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python for-loops vs generators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And several other common pitfalls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected level of audience: This talk is mainly targeted for beginner to
intermediate web developer who are interested in improving the cost-
performance of their web applications. After listening to this talk, the
audiences are expected to understand that good coding practices (e.g.:
implement asyncio correctly, track number of DB queries with decorators,
etc) will make their web application a lot faster and cut down
operational costs by a large margin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1592"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1592&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iskandar Setiadi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/python-website-is-slow-think-again.html</guid><category>tornado</category><category>best-practices</category><category>aws</category><category>web-development</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Real world Graphene - lessons learned from building a GraphQL API on top of a large Django project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-on-top-of-a-large-django-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphene is currently the most popular framework for building a GraphQL
in Python and it’s also an obvious choice for adding a GraphQL layer to
Django applications. Over the course of a year, we successfully built an
API with about 50 queries and over 100 mutations on top of existing
Django project (Saleor), but we also learned some hard lessons and had
to overcome several shortcomings of the framework along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’d like to share some practical tips to overcome the most
common problems that a Django developer might face when building an
optimized and maintainable API with Graphene, such as: - using useful
abstractions to build queries and mutations faster - optimizing database
queries in a graph - structuring a large Graphene project - unified
error handling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to bring up a few limitations of the framework that we
discovered as we were working on the project and then end the talk with
the most important benefits that adoption of GraphQL brings to modern
web applications development - both for the backend and frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: - Intermediate knowledge of Django - Familiarity with API
design and concepts in terms of web development - Basic knowledge of
GraphQL or interest in it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the talk would be of great value to anyone working with a
Graphene framework and those who want to know more about building
GraphQL in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All code examples in the presentation would be based on Saleor
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mirumee/saleor"&gt;https://github.com/mirumee/saleor&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1644"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1644&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marcin Gębala</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-on-top-of-a-large-django-project.html</guid><category>API Design</category><category>e-commerce</category><category>graphql</category><category>open-source</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>RedisAI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/redisai.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking deep learning models to production and doing so reliably is one
of the next frontiers of DevOps. With the advent of Redis modules and
the availability of C APIs for the major deep learning frameworks, it is
now possible to turn Redis into a reliable runtime for deep learning
workloads, providing a simple solution for a model serving microservice.
In this talk we will introduce RedisAI, a joint effort by Orobix and
RedisLabs that introduces tensors and graphs as new Redis data types and
allows to execute graphs over tensors using multiple backends (PyTorch,
TensorFlow, and ONNXRuntime), both on the CPU and GPU. The module also
supports scripting with TorchScript, which provides a Python-like tensor
language that can be used to facilitate pre- and post-processing
operations, like input shaping or output ensambling. In addition, thanks
to its support for the ONNX standard, including ONNX-ML, RedisAI is not
strictly limited to deep learning, but it offers support for general
machine learning algorithms. In this talk, we will demonstrate a full,
Python-powered journey from fine tuning a model to a scalable Flask +
RedisAI deployment. Last, we will lay down the roadmap for the future,
like automated batching, sharding, integration with Redis data types
(e.g. streams) and advanced monitoring. The talk will include sample
code, best practices and a live demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1756"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luca Antiga</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/redisai.html</guid><category>database</category><category>redis</category><category>devops</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>deployment</category><category>neural network</category></item><item><title>Service discovery: sai dov'è il mio microservice?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/service-discovery-sai-dove-il-mio-microservice.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quello del discovery dei servizi è un problema che sembra banale fino a
quando non ne hai bisogno. Non serve essere (metti qui grossa azienda)
per doverlo fare: già con un paio di servizi deployati in maniera
dinamica (leggi cloud e/o container) bisogna inventarsi qualcosa.
Kubernetes offre la sua visione, ma se non lo usiamo o abbiamo un
ibrido, dobbiamo trovare un’alternativa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk analizzeremo il problema, la soluzione che adottiamo a
SpazioDati (basata su Consul e HAProxy) e le novità in questo campo
(Envoy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1788"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1788&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Davide Setti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/service-discovery-sai-dove-il-mio-microservice.html</guid><category>Consul</category><category>devops</category><category>SRE</category></item><item><title>Sharing is Caring! - how to free the CPU from message passing hell - shared memory saved the day</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/sharing-is-caring-how-to-free-the-cpu-from-message-passing-hell-shared-memory-saved-the-day.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When dealing with a real time application in which you are required to
process a lot of data from multiple sources in parallel, system
resources disappear quickly. Add some CPU intensive processing and you
are set to fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will illustrate a solution to solve a CPU bound problem with a
data stream of tens of megabytes. I will talk about how easy it is to
fail and how to obtain a working solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following arguments will be discussed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;threading and its limitations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiprocessing and its limitations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serialization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a solution: multiprocessing + shared memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code will be provided and shown during the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1656"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1656&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrei Neagu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/sharing-is-caring-how-to-free-the-cpu-from-message-passing-hell-shared-memory-saved-the-day.html</guid><category>threading</category><category>SharedMemory</category><category>#Python</category><category>python3</category><category>multiprocessing</category></item><item><title>Source; deploying unbiased models effortlessly.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/source-deploying-unbiased-models-effortlessly.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many organizations rapid machine learning deployment is often an
oxymoron. BCG Source provides a one-stop shop for data lineage and model
development. We will demonstrate how easy deployment enables quick
diagnoses that a model is biased. Since it is essential to deploy
unbiased machine learning, we will show how to remove this bias. You
will learn about common machine-learning and data-science pitfalls, how
to easily deploy a machine learning model, how to spot bias and how to
remove bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1808"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1808&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anton Bossenbroek</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/source-deploying-unbiased-models-effortlessly.html</guid></item><item><title>Subwoofler: Create Your Own Musical Instrument</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/subwoofler-create-your-own-musical-instrument.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you, like me, started your musical encounters with toys that made
animal sounds? Has the teenage you wondered how your favorite beat
makers turned field recordings into playable sounds? What would happen
if you combined the two? Let me take you on a journey through the world
of sampling instruments which inspired Subwoofler - a barking sampler
written completely in Python. We’ll go through all of its components and
learn a few concepts commonly used in music applications. Finally, we’ll
compare the performance of processing real-time audio on different
implementations of Python; the language which is not the most typical
choice for such a use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1801"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1801&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Wszeborowska</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/subwoofler-create-your-own-musical-instrument.html</guid></item><item><title>TemPy! Una alternativa al templating tradizionale usando solo Python.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/tempy-una-alternativa-al-templating-tradizionale-usando-solo-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TemPy è un modo di fare pagine HTML senza usare HTML. E’ un modo per
avere, nel templating di pagine web, tutta la libertà offerta da Python,
senza dover sottostare a un linguaggio simil-python con limitazioni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk sarà una introduzione a un modo alternativo di produrre l’output
web attraverso TemPy, sia per un veloce prototyping che per un complesso
sistema di template da semplificare… o potenziare. Coprirà esempi di
utilizzo del modulo, la filosofia alla sua base ed alcuni esempi di ciò
che può fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1516"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1516&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Federico Cerchiari</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/tempy-una-alternativa-al-templating-tradizionale-usando-solo-python.html</guid><category>templates</category><category>html5</category><category>oop</category><category>python3</category><category>web development</category></item><item><title>Ternary CPUs: how they work and how Python helps designing one</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/ternary-cpus-how-they-work-and-how-python-helps-designing-one.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;0/1, False/True, off/on, etc.: the computers which we’re working on are
based, from very long time, on the so called binary arithmetic/logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Two states to rule them all&amp;quot;: with these we built a complete ecosystem
which goes from the hardware to the software… showing even this text
that you’re reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However the possibility to use the ternary logic instead, that started
just a joke some years ago, generated recent papers and researches about
it, with interesting features exploited and documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An FPGA project is in development to implement a “ternary CPU” and an
ISA (Instruction Set Architecture) draft was roughly defined (and
evolving).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a CPU without code to execute is useless and here comes Python,
which allows to quickly implement (and test) some simple, primitive
assembler to generate executables (&amp;quot;ternaries”?), which can then be
transferred to the FPGA board and run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A basic emulator with a minimal set of instructions is implemented, in
order to test the code even without the physical board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk provides a short overview of the ternary logic, some
challenges, and how the basic assembler and emulator are written,
tested, and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1793"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1793&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cesare Di Mauro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/ternary-cpus-how-they-work-and-how-python-helps-designing-one.html</guid><category>TernaryLogic</category><category>Assembler</category><category>emulator</category><category>CPU</category></item><item><title>Text Extraction from PDFs made Easy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/text-extraction-from-pdfs-made-easy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Overview:*&lt;/strong&gt; PDFs are one of the widely used digital media formats
and are used to present and exchange information reliably, independent
of the software, hardware and operating system. Extracting data from PDF
files can be a tricky task. This is because of the complicated formats,
fonts, and layouts that are stored in PDF files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text Extraction from PDFs is one of the most common problems that is
prevalent in every industry. I shall be showing you how to extract data
directly from n number of PDF files using just one Python Library -
Regex. I encountered a similar problem while working with my company and
utilized Regular Expressions to automate an otherwise strenuous task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*1. Who is this talk for?*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone who is dealing with the problem of extracting data from
unstructured data at their workplace/ university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone who wants to learn Regular Expression in a fun and easy
manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*2. What background knowledge or experience should the audience
have?*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will be a beginner’s talk. The basis of Regex will be built from
the ground up during the talk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*3. What will the audience learn after attending the talk?*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The audience will get a crisp overview of Regular Expressions, that
can assist them in a wide spectrum of tasks, from wrangling data to
qualifying and categorizing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ll be showing them a use-case/demo of a problem statement that I
encountered at my workplace, giving the attendees more clarity about
the extent of usage of Regex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1632"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aakriti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/text-extraction-from-pdfs-made-easy.html</guid><category>textextraction</category><category>datawrangling</category><category>datamining</category></item><item><title>Uno sguardo alle Dataclasses: quando una namedtuple non basta</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/uno-sguardo-alle-dataclasses-quando-una-namedtuple-non-basta.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hanno fatto la loro prima apparizione in Python 3.7, sono la moda del
momento. Sto parlando delle DataClasses, definite nella PEP557 come
“mutable namedtuples with defaults”. Inizieremo facendo un ripasso
veloce sulla bellezza, ma anche sui limiti, delle namedtuple,
continuando poi con un tour alla scoperta di questo nuovo strumento
regalatoci da Eric V. Smith (Python Core Developer) e di come può
esserci d’aiuto nello scrivere nuove classi con minimo sforzo. Oltre
alla definizione come Standard Library suggerisce, verranno proposti
degli esempi di codice per far capire in maniera semplice ai
programmatori che si avvicinano per la prima volta a questo modulo le
caratteristiche, le differenze rispetto ad altri strumenti, e i vantaggi
nell’usare le dataclasses nei loro programmi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1534"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1534&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Cucci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/uno-sguardo-alle-dataclasses-quando-una-namedtuple-non-basta.html</guid><category>data-structures</category><category>object-oriented-programming</category><category>Python</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Usa lo Zen, Luke!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/usa-lo-zen-luke.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nel nostro lavoro ci troviamo spesso di fronte a scelte difficili da
prendere, compromessi che possono compromettere il nostro codice o altre
scelte future. Per fortuna abbiamo una guida che ci può aiutare a
compiere queste scelte un po’ più facilmente: lo Zen di Python. In
questo talk voglio mostrare alcuni casi reali in cui lo zen ci può
aiutare a scrivere codice migliore, più manutenibile e più bello.
Impossibile parlare di tutto lo zen, prenderò quattro o cinque consigli
e proporrò un caso reale, cioè un pezzo di codice in produzione, per
mostrarne la veridicità.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non sono richiesti pre-requisiti, si parlerà di concetti generali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentazione:`link &amp;lt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1GUdMd7VCQqyHHgWxSq2mf2Ot370ERWVsCwN5ln7EfEc/edit?usp=sharing&amp;gt;`__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:https://python.it/feedback-1664&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorenzo Mele</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/usa-lo-zen-luke.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>Zen</category></item><item><title>Using OpenAPI (and Python) to standardize a Country's API Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/using-openapi-and-python-to-standardize-a-countrys-api-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating an &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://teamdigitale.governo.it/en/projects/api.htm"&gt;API
Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; is
one of the goal of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://teamdigitale.governo.it/en/"&gt;Italian Government Digital Transformation
Team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk shows how OpenAPI (formerly known as Swagger) is a cornerstone
for standardizing the behavior of the APIs created by thousands of
Public Administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief introduction to OpenAPI, we’ll show the current work on
documenting service management semantics (eg. circuit breaker) and
standardizing API elements and schemas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code samples are based on
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;`connexion&lt;/tt&gt; &amp;lt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://connexion.readthedocs.io/en/latest/quickstart.html#running-%20it"&gt;https://connexion.readthedocs.io/en/latest/quickstart.html#running-%20it&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;`__:
a python framework based on flask which makes trivial creating REST APIs
and sandboxes useful for testing and interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1681"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1681&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto Polli</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/using-openapi-and-python-to-standardize-a-countrys-api-ecosystem.html</guid><category>web</category><category>REST API Frameworks</category><category>openapi</category></item><item><title>Using Vault to better protect your secrets.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/using-vault-to-better-protect-your-secrets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All developers have seen it and few will admit to doing it. Putting
unprotected authentication credentials like usernames and passwords or
cloud service authentication keys into application code, scripts or
Ansible playbooks. We do this because it saves us time and effort. Add
in external source control tools, like Github, and the risks of these
credentials being publicly exposed increases. While most developers
agree on the importance of automated testing and syntax checking, its
time to add protecting application secrets, to the list of best
practices. In this talk, we will explore how to use Hashicorp Vault, a
secure storage and encryption tool, to help manage authentication in a
way that is safe and secure. Time will be spent on learning how to setup
a Vault server, migrate secrets into the service, and modify python
scripts and Ansible playbooks to take advantage of Vault. This talk is
for developers of all levels who are interested in a better way to
manage their secrets and become the next hero with their security
department. (Your results may vary.) Presenter has no affiliation with
Hashicorp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1657"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1657&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bryce Verdier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/using-vault-to-better-protect-your-secrets.html</guid><category>identity-management</category><category>configuration-management</category><category>Hashicorp-Vault</category></item><item><title>White Mars: living far away from any form of life</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/white-mars-living-far-away-from-any-form-of-life.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concordia Station is a French/Italian facility located inside
Antarctica, in a plateau called Dome-C, in the middle of nowhere. A dark
and cold place: no Sun from May to August, temperatures around -80
Celsius degress, no life. In this weird place there is a lack of oxygen,
extremely dry air and no way to go back to the “normal world” between
February and November. I lived in Concordia for 13 months, performing
scientific research with other 12 collegues from Italy, France and
Austria. We were the most isolated people on Earth, more than the
austronauts on the International Space Station. It was like living on
another planet, and that is why the European Space Agency was making
bio-medical research on us, in order to understand how the human body
behaves in a such extraterrestrial environment. In this talk I will
introduce our studies, describe Concordia and our life there, and of
course also speak about Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://marco-buttu.github.io/white_mars/"&gt;https://marco-buttu.github.io/white_mars/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1802"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1802&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Buttu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/white-mars-living-far-away-from-any-form-of-life.html</guid></item><item><title>You don't need n dimensions when you have pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/you-dont-need-n-dimensions-when-you-have-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pietrobattiston.it/wiki/python:pycon#talk_you_don_t_need_n_dimensions_when_you_have_pandas"&gt;Click here for slides and material
used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a (very) quick general introduction to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt;, and in
particular to pandas &lt;strong&gt;indexes&lt;/strong&gt; , this talk will focus on particular
types of indexes, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;MultiIndex&lt;/tt&gt;es, and on the many &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt;
features allowing us to use them to store and analyze multidimensional
data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discover together &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt; does not have (any more) data
structures with more than 2 dimensions, and why we should not regret
them. We will then look at further ways to “restructure” data, including
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;groupby&lt;/tt&gt; e &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;window&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1771"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1771&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pietro Battiston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/you-dont-need-n-dimensions-when-you-have-pandas.html</guid><category>data-structures</category><category>numpy</category><category>pandas</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>A Worked Intro to Scikit-learn</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/a-worked-intro-to-scikit-learn.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A talk introducing the audience to Scikit-learn as a library aimed at
people who know Python at a beginner/intermediate level but are new to
machine learning concepts. The goal of the talk is for the audience to
leave with an understanding of the foundations of machine learning while
respecting how easy it is to make a wrong choice that invalidates your
model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be a short background on scikit-learn followed by a livecoding
demo where I demonstrate how scikit-learn works and detail common
pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will demonstrate ways of coping with problems such as data leakage,
the importance of train-test splits, choosing metrics wisely, and
explain how cross-validation works and why we use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1596"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1596&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anders Bogsnes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/a-worked-intro-to-scikit-learn.html</guid><category>pydata</category><category>Python</category><category>scikit-learn</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>analytics</category><category>data</category><category>sklearn</category></item><item><title>Artisanal Async Adventures</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/artisanal-async-adventures.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to write an efficient server, asynchronous networking is an
excellent strategy to do so. To build a production ready system, you
would use asyncio, tornado, twisted, trio or another popular
implementation. However, to fully understand how and why it works, I
will ignore these solutions and instead craft an artisanal asynchronous
implementation in front of your very eyes. Step by step we will turn a
blocking socket server, only capable of handling a single connection at
a time, into a beautiful non blocking server that has no trouble dealing
with many connections at once. By the end, you should see that
asynchronous code is not magical at all, but nevertheless incredibly
useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1742"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1742&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jonas Obrist</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/artisanal-async-adventures.html</guid><category>async</category><category>event-driven-architecture</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Basta problemi con tensorflow usando Docker &amp; Nvidia Docker</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/basta-problemi-con-tensorflow-usando-docker-nvidia-docker.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Di sicuro vi sarà capitato che condividendo o effettuando un progetto
tensorflow questo non funzioni correttamente. Soprattutto non riesco a
far scalare la mia app perchè non ho abbastanza macchine con GPU e
eseguire lo scale su macchine con solo CPU è costoso per poi ottenere
scarsi benefici. La soluzione è utilizzare Docker e Nvidia Docker.
Vedremo perchè Docker è migliore di una macchina virtuale e come
cambiano le prestazioni rispetto ad andare direttamente sulla macchina.
Vedremo trucchi su come strutturare dei docker-compose file senza
duplicazione per poter sviluppare agilmente sia con GPU che senza, poter
effettuare un deploy con tranquillità e poter scalare facilmente anche
senza GPU. Slide Link: &amp;lt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/NicolaLandro/basta"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/NicolaLandro/basta&lt;/a&gt;-
problemicontensorflowusandodockernvidiadocker&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1528"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Landro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/basta-problemi-con-tensorflow-usando-docker-nvidia-docker.html</guid><category>OSX</category><category>windows</category><category>devops</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>GNU/Linux</category><category>cuda</category><category>tensorflow</category><category>docker</category></item><item><title>Come aiutare i cani con Genropy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/come-aiutare-i-cani-con-genropy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Se il solo strumento che possedete è un martello, vedrete in ogni
problema un chiodo” (Abraham Maslow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corollario: se cominci ad usare Genropy vedrai in ogni problema un caso
d’uso per fare una WebApp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel tempo libero mi sono ritrovato a fare volontariato presso
un’associazione che prende i cani randagi fa un processo di rieducazione
e li rende adottabili.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date le mie limitate competenze cinofile, ho pensato bene, vedendo come
era organizzato il lavoro dei volontari (fogli di carta, e tanta
disorganizzazione) di usare le mie competenze Pythoniche e mettere su un
gestionale per questa realtà nel mio tempo libero. È venuto fuori
qualcosa di bello e sicuramente un caso interessante di uso del
framework Genropy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk verranno presentati 3 livelli per ogni problema
affrontato: - il mondo reale - come viene schematizzato in termini di
base di dati e model - la ui, con esempi di codice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il focus del talk è mostrare come sia semplice passare da una realtà di
fogli di carta e file excel disorganizzati ad una webapp moderna in
costante evoluzione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grazie a Python e Genropy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1809"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1809&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/come-aiutare-i-cani-con-genropy.html</guid></item><item><title>Communicating Between Microservices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/communicating-between-microservices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microservices are not just a bunch of little apps, it’s a connected
ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a monolith, code modules invoke each other simply by using
language- level function calls, but in a microservice architecture,
communication between components does not come for free anymore.
Choosing not just a protocol, but a paradigm for communication between
endpoints is considered the most tricky issue of microservice approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing microservices in Python is a joy, but when you decide on it,
there is often no way back. Therefore it is always an advantage to know
what to expect in advance, not just from inspiring blog posts but also
from the harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a bunch of smooth as well as tricky microservice migrations in
the past, I would like to share typical pitfalls of choosing a framework
stack, communication protocol, conventions, and deployment process — all
covered by real projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1638"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anton Caceres</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/communicating-between-microservices.html</guid><category>MessageQueues</category><category>microservices</category><category>HTTP</category><category>communication</category><category>architecture</category><category>websockets</category></item><item><title>Darkweb + Python: discover, analyze and extract information from hidden services</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/darkweb-python-discover-analyze-and-extract-information-from-hidden-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will start explaining how Tor project can help us to the
research and development of tools for online anonymity and privacy of
its users while surfing the Internet, by establishing virtual circuits
between the different nodes that make up the Tor network. In addition,
we will review how Tor works from anonymity point of view, preventing
websites from tracking you. Python help us to automate the process to
search an discover hidden services thanks to packages like
requests,requesocks and sockspy. At this point we will review the
crawling process and show tools in python ecosystem available for this
task such as Deep Explorer(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/blueudp/deep-explorer"&gt;https://github.com/blueudp/deep-explorer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These could be the talking points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Tor project and hidden services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovering hidden services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modules and packages we can use in python for connecting with Tor
network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools that allow search hidden services and atomate the crawling
process in Tor network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1563"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1563&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jose Manuel Ortega</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/darkweb-python-discover-analyze-and-extract-information-from-hidden-services.html</guid><category>tor</category><category>security</category><category>privacy</category><category>hacking</category><category>crawler</category></item><item><title>Defence Against the Dark Arts: Adversarial ML</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/defence-against-the-dark-arts-adversarial-ml.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security and Privacy issues need no introduction. But how exactly is
this affecting the field of Machine Learning? This is what this talk
will cover. We first expose the attack surface of systems deploying
machine learning. We then describe how an attacker may force models to
make wrong predictions with very little information about the victim.
One such attack can be biometric recognition where fake biometric traits
may be exploited to impersonate a legitimate user. We demonstrate that
these attacks are practical against existing machine learning as a
service platform. Towards the end, we will discuss current research to
defend models from such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1700"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1700&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amit Kushwaha</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/defence-against-the-dark-arts-adversarial-ml.html</guid><category>security</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>privacy</category></item><item><title>From Science with (Data) Love: make others love data the way you do.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/from-science-with-data-love-make-others-love-data-the-way-you-do.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists that become Data Scientists in companies bring with them a
particular academic baggage that defines the way they think, work and
communicate in the new environment. In this talk, I will talk about pros
and cons associated with this baggage, drawing from my personal story of
transitioning to Data Science with a focus on how we love data and how
we can improve communication with stakeholders through better data
visualization and storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1800"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1800&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paula Gonzales</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/from-science-with-data-love-make-others-love-data-the-way-you-do.html</guid></item><item><title>How software can feed the world</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/how-software-can-feed-the-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infarm is a FaaS, Farming as a Service, and whether you believe it or
not, our business is in-house farming at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We design and build our farms, grow vegetables and sell them, and the
backbone of our infrastructure is based on Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 10 million observations recorded from our farms, rapidly
increasing given our expansion to new markets, feed our farm management
system that allows the operators, plant scientists, and supervisors to
monitor each farm in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk I will introduce our IoT infrastructure, how we use
Python and how we plan to improve the capabilities of our farms by
adding edge machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1785"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1785&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Barra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/how-software-can-feed-the-world.html</guid><category>microservices</category><category>iot</category><category>CloudComputing</category><category>microcontroller</category><category>influxdb</category><category>raspberrypi</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>social-impact</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>How to write a JIT compiler in 30 minutes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/how-to-write-a-jit-compiler-in-30-minutes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Real-world JIT compilers like PyPy and Numba are complex and advanced.
However, the basic ideas behind JIT compilers are easy to understand, as
this talk aim to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be a live-coding exercise: we will write a working (albeit
simple and limited) JIT compiler from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1675"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1675&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonio Cuni</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/how-to-write-a-jit-compiler-in-30-minutes.html</guid><category>performance</category><category>JIT</category><category>assembly</category><category>live-coding</category><category>compilers</category></item><item><title>In Codice Ratio: Machine Transcription in the Vatican Secret Archive</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/in-codice-ratio-machine-transcription-in-the-vatican-secret-archive.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Codice Ratio is a research project to study tools and techniques for
analyzing the contents of digitized historical documents from the
Vatican Secret Archives (VSA). Being digitized as images, their text
content is still unaccessible without expert human intervention:
transcription is therefore a key enabler for search and automation of
knowledge discovery on such large collections. Handwritten documents are
particularly challenging, as traditional OCR does not apply, and state
of the art handwritten text recognition systems require very large and
expensive to obtain datasets. ICR’s transcription system is based on
convolutional neural networks and statistical language models, and
requires minimal dataset collection effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1797"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1797&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elena Nieddu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/in-codice-ratio-machine-transcription-in-the-vatican-secret-archive.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/lightning-talks.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/lightning-talks.html</guid></item><item><title>Machine Learning for Inventory Management</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-for-inventory-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Material forecast is the process of deciding which items to stock in the
inventory, how much, and when. Aim of the forecast is to increase parts
availability with the less possible impact on inventory, having enough
stock in the warehouse to ensure the business keeps moving but not
enough stock to drain its limited cash reserves. This decision process
is being profoundly revised in its foundational concepts, thanks to new
classification methodologies enabled by Machine Learning. We integrated
domain knowledge and ML to create a new classification and level setting
process, leveraging on 6 years of data and new statistical indicators
for demand patter. These new features are used to run the machine
learning algorithm that classify Make To Stock / Make To Order items in
a single flow approach. The validation phase is reduced at each
iteration as ML model can be re-trained to incorporate past validations,
increasing efficiency and performances. Level setting problem is
addressed benchmarking ML methods (Reinforcement Learning), Montecarlo
simulations and traditional statistical methodologies. Regarding RL and
Montecarlo we established punishments for letting an particular
inventory item run out of stock and we also punish the model for stock
too higher value for too long. For rewards, we primarily focus on
ordering items within a safe window before the demand. First application
of this new methodology brings a 20% reduction of inventory, without
impact on sales, and a workload reduction of about 70%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1554"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1554&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laura De Stefanis</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-for-inventory-management.html</guid><category>logistics</category><category>clustering</category><category>statistics</category><category>Python</category><category>Big-Data</category><category>gestionali</category><category>django</category><category>supplychain</category><category>sql</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category></item><item><title>Multi-modal classification with PyTorch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/multi-modal-classification-with-pytorch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent work by Kiela et al. (2018) reveals that image and text
multi-modal classification models far outperform both text- and
image-only models. This talk will review work that extends Kiela et
al.’s (2018) research by determining if accuracy in classification may
be increased by the implementation of transfer learning in language
processing. The performance of the model over a MM-IMDb (Arevalo et al.
2017) dataset is analyzed and compared to the baseline provided by Kiela
et al. (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is implemented with PyTorch and the goal of the talk will be to
review details of the implementation, and performance of the model as
compared to that recorded in Kiela et al. (2018). Attendees of this talk
should have a basic familiarity with neural nets developed in PyTorch
for the purposes of NLP and computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References: Arevalo, J., Solorio, T., Montes-y-Gómez, M., &amp;amp; González, F.
A. 2017. Gated multimodal units for information fusion. arXiv preprint
arXiv:1702.01992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiela, Douwe, Edouard Grave, Armand Joulin, and Tomas Mikolov. 2018.
Efficient large-scale multi-modal classification. arXiv preprint
arXiv:1802.02892.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1754"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1754&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jennifer Seale</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/multi-modal-classification-with-pytorch.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>computer-vision</category></item><item><title>Orobix: AI gets to work!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/orobix-ai-gets-to-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orobix is an engineering company focused on delivering AI-based
solutions to businesses, in multiple domains including life-science and
manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application of deep learning to real world problems and mission
critical contexts is laden with potential pitfalls, involving project
execution all the way to the deployment of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;models in production. Orobix has engineered systems with deep learning
at their core, ranging from medical image segmentation to industrial
quality inspection. In its operations, Orobix has devised strategies to
cope with the cost of collecting data, gathering annotations from
experts, training data- efficient models, deploying models in
production, monitoring and communicating results back to experts. This
talk represents an opportunity for us to share where we started from and
where we’re at, what worked and what didn’t, and what we think is laying
ahead of us, both individually and collectively in the applied AI
community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1807"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1807&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luca Antiga</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/orobix-ai-gets-to-work.html</guid></item><item><title>Pipenv per la gestione delle dipendenze negli ambienti di sviluppo e di produzione</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/pipenv-per-la-gestione-delle-dipendenze-negli-ambienti-di-sviluppo-e-di-produzione.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pipenv permette la creazione automatica di un virtual environment e
l’installazione di pacchetti Python attraveso una elegante interfaccia a
riga di comando che riunisce in un unico strumento le funzionalità di
PIP e virtualenv. Allo stesso tempo permette di tracciare in modo facile
ed affidabile le dipendenze di un’applicazione attraverso i file Pipfile
e Pipfile.lock, mettendo fine ai problemi derivanti dall’uso dei file
requirements.txt e permettendo build deterministici.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inizialmente verranno presentate le motivazioni principali che
giustificano l’uso di pipenv: 1. dipendenze astratte e concrete
(setup.py vs requirements.txt) 2. problemi nell’uso di file
requirements.txt 3. librerie vs applicazioni 4. necessità di build
deterministici&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In seguito verranno descritte le funzionalità principali di pipenv per
la gestione dei pacchetti e virtual environment nell’ambiente di
sviluppo: 5. Installazione di pipenv nelle principali distribuzioni
Linux e in Windows 6. I comandi “pipenv install”, “pipenv shell”,
“pipenv run” 7. I file Pipfile e Pipfile.lock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poi si introdurranno alcune funzionalità avanzate di pipenv: 8. “pipenv
graph” per la visualizzazione del grafo delle dipendenze 9. “pipenv
check” per controllare vulnerabilità di sicurezza 10. configurazione
tramite variabili d’ambiente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infine verranno prese in esame alcune utili funzionalità che permettono
a pipenv di entrare a pieno titolo nel processo di deploy di
un’applicazione Python: 11. i comandi “pipenv install –deploy” e “pipenv
sync” 12. il supporto di file dot-env&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1714"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1714&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Santamaria</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/pipenv-per-la-gestione-delle-dipendenze-negli-ambienti-di-sviluppo-e-di-produzione.html</guid><category>dependency-management</category><category>virtualenv</category><category>pipenv</category><category>Python</category><category>pip</category><category>packages</category></item><item><title>Please tell me why?! Explaining Machine Learning predictions in Python with Shap</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/please-tell-me-why-explaining-machine-learning-predictions-in-python-with-shap.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will discuss the problem of making results coming from
machine learning models understandable to both the data scientists and
the final users. While most machine learning frameworks already include
metrics that measure the importance of different features during
training, fewer allow us to understand which features were most
important for a specific prediction at runtime. We will describe our use
case, discuss a few options and finally present Shap, an open-source
python library able to interpret many different models. Shap comes with
both general purpose tools and specialized tools for families of machine
learning models and with integrations for Jupyter and Matplotlib for
easy use during exploration and testing of a model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1601"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1601&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessio Guerrieri</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/please-tell-me-why-explaining-machine-learning-predictions-in-python-with-shap.html</guid><category>scikit-learn</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>data-analysis</category></item><item><title>Predicting Human Activity using Time Series Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/predicting-human-activity-using-time-series-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time series is referred to as sequence of data points measured over
successive intervals of time. Time series analysis is performed to
extract meaningful statistics and characteristics of the data. For
example, this analysis can be used to predict future based on the past
events. Such use cases of this analysis are stock market prediction,
weather prediction and web traffic prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll be understanding the basics and how to perform time
series analysis and machine learning for a given dataset. For this talk,
we’ll be using the UCI Human Activity Recognition (HAR) Data Set to
classify a given activity performed by the human as one of the following
activities: Walking, Sitting, Standing or Laying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk would be intermediate level and basics of Python and Pandas are
required. Understanding of Machine Learning algorithms and signal
processing would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1576"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1576&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Akul Mehra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/predicting-human-activity-using-time-series-analysis.html</guid><category>TimeSeriesAnalysis</category><category>data-science</category><category>machine-language</category><category>Python</category><category>data-exploration</category><category>Data-Scientist</category><category>MachineLearning</category><category>TimeSeries</category><category>pandas</category><category>DataEngineering</category></item><item><title>Quando la tua applicazione Django non va abbastanza veloce</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/quando-la-tua-applicazione-django-non-va-abbastanza-veloce.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django mette molta enfasi nel creare applicazioni velocemente. Questo è
grandioso! Sviluppare applicazioni velocemente però non sempre significa
sviluppare applicazioni veloci.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk mostrerò alcuni problemi di performance che ho incontrato
(o introdotto) nella mia esperienza di sviluppatore. Vedremo esempi in
diversi punti dell’applicazione: dai modelli, passando per le viste fino
ai serializzatori. Alcuni di questi si sono rivelati facili da trovare e
risolvere, altri subdoli o addirittura imbarazzanti. Tutti
fortunatamente risolti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1611"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1611&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Riccardo Magliocchetti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/quando-la-tua-applicazione-django-non-va-abbastanza-veloce.html</guid><category>performance</category><category>django</category><category>django-rest-framework</category><category>databases</category></item><item><title>Ravioli vs Pelmeni software architecture (microservices vs services)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/ravioli-vs-pelmeni-software-architecture-microservices-vs-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microservice architecture is trending now, everyone wants to use it, not
matter if it’s needed or not. But what if you could know all the pros
and cons, possible examples and success stories… What if you could
choose by your considered and mature choice. This short talk will guide
through best practices of using service and microservice architecture,
so you could choose wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1515"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1515&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anastasiia Tymoshchuk</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/ravioli-vs-pelmeni-software-architecture-microservices-vs-services.html</guid><category>best-practices</category><category>examples</category><category>clean-architecture</category></item><item><title>Scrivere i primi test frontend con python? Si Può!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/scrivere-i-primi-test-frontend-con-python-si-puo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://splinter.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;Splinter&lt;/a&gt; è uno
strumento open source per testare le applicazioni web usando Python. Ti
consente di automatizzare le azioni del browser, come visitare URL e
interagire con i loro elementi. Vi parlerò di come realizzare i test
frontend utilizzando Splinter, perché usarlo per il frontend, cosa
differenzia Splinter dagli altri tool ma sopratutto come integrarlo nei
nostri progetti Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo scopo di questo talk è di presentare le potenzialità di Splinter,
inoltre verranno mostrati dei casi d’uso e le informazioni necessarie
per poterlo installare e utilizzare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk è rivolto a sviluppatori web con esperienza in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1730"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1730&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fiorella De Luca</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/scrivere-i-primi-test-frontend-con-python-si-puo.html</guid><category>#splinter</category><category>#selenium</category><category>#Python</category></item><item><title>Serverless computing con Python e AWS - Endgame Edition</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/serverless-computing-con-python-e-aws-endgame-edition.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
La più breve introduzione al Cloud Computing del mondo: dalle valvole termoioniche al FaaS in 15 minuti!
Dal monolite ai microservizi: l’arte di smembrare un’applicazione senza farsi (troppo) male
Lambda e i suoi fratelli: come usare Python per costruire un sistema scalabile senza installare nemmeno un server
Chalice, Layers, Step Functions.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1806"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1806&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Federico Caboni</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/serverless-computing-con-python-e-aws-endgame-edition.html</guid></item><item><title>Sviluppare per Alexa in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/sviluppare-per-alexa-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In questo talk verrà mostrato come sviluppare una Skill per Amazon Alexa
in italiano. Verranno presentati i concetti e le metodologie utili allo
sviluppo di un’interfaccia vocale, le risorse e gli strumenti a
disposizione dello sviluppatore ed infine i requisiti qualitativi da
rispettare affinché la Skill sviluppata venga pubblicata sullo store. La
Skill fornirà insight sul traffico del sito web, interfacciandosi con
Google Analytics attraverso autenticazione dell’utente. Requisiti:
serverless (AWS Lambda), Oauth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1676"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alberto Anceschi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/sviluppare-per-alexa-in-python.html</guid><category>#assistant</category><category>#Python</category><category>#google</category><category>#api</category><category>#voice</category><category>#alexa</category><category>#analytics</category></item><item><title>Why you should pursue public speaking and how to get there</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/why-you-should-pursue-public-speaking-and-how-to-get-there.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear of public speaking is the most common of all phobias. Want to speak
confidently in front of the crowd? This talk shares tips on how to
overcome the fear, and ways to get started. You will be prepared to
brace presenting from a team meeting to a conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1803"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1803&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yenny Cheung</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/why-you-should-pursue-public-speaking-and-how-to-get-there.html</guid></item><item><title>AI and algorithmic art</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/ai-and-algorithmic-art.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people think of neural networks as magic boxes, using them as such
is similar to allowing the computer or the machine to have a mind of
their own. Classification and prediction are the best-known applications
of these algorithms. But it has been demonstrated that they can also be
used in multiple creative or artistic ways such as generating pictures,
musical pieces, humour based dialogues or jokes and plays or literary
pieces. Leading to the following question: can these black boxes express
true creativity? A trait commonly associated with humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic Art (or computer generated art) refers to the use of
computer algorithms to create artistic pieces. Algorithmic art has been
around from the early 1960s, when artists used a plotter controlled by a
computer to create some visual artwork pieces. In the 80s when computer
graphics became more accessible, digital fractal artworks dominated to
become the mainstream of algorithmic art. By the end of the 80s, genetic
algorithms had matured enough to have a major influence in the
algorithmic composition of music. At the same time, the artificial
neural networks were used to explore the creation of musical
compositions. Most recently, thanks to the blooming of neural network
frameworks (e.g. tensorflow), availability of GPUs and development in
sophisticated neural network architecture, they play an important part
in academic research and data science business applications. Besides
that, these enhanced resources and frameworks have enabled the neural
networks to make significant contributions in the area of Algorithmic
Arts. Examples of this are the Deep Dream and artistic style transfer
and GANs (generative adversarial network) which can generate highly
deceptive pictures. A specially trained neural network is also capable
of composing music mimicking the style of Beethoven or generating a
modern music piece. In the same way, a neural network can be used to
generate poems or literary pieces in the true style of Shakespeare or
Hamilton. In this talk, we will go through a gallery of art and music
created by algorithms, showcasing what roles computers took in different
algorithmic art forms. From the earliest fractal art to the music and
pictures generated by the state of the art neural networks and GANs.
This talk is suitable for everyone, from the curious general public to
experts in the field of neural networks, both will find this talk
inspiring and amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide for this talk:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slides.com/cheukting_ho/ai-and-algorithmic-art/live#/"&gt;https://slides.com/cheukting_ho/ai-and-algorithmic-art/live#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1778"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1778&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/ai-and-algorithmic-art.html</guid><category>art</category><category>pydata</category><category>AI</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>algorithmicart</category><category>neural network</category></item><item><title>Alex Martelli - Ask Me Anything</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/alex-martelli-ask-me-anything.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/alex-martelli-ask-me-anything.html</guid></item><item><title>Algoritmo di Routing Multi-Obiettivo di Veicoli Elettrici con vincoli di ricarica lungo il percorso</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/algoritmo-di-routing-multi-obiettivo-di-veicoli-elettrici-con-vincoli-di-ricarica-lungo-il-percorso.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In questa presentazione affronteremo alcune delle fasi più importanti, e
le problematiche ad esse correlate, per lo sviluppo di un modello di
routing multi-obiettivo di un veicolo elettrico con vincoli di ricarica
lungo il percorso. In particolare analizzeremo le principali sorgenti
Open di dati geografici della rete stradale e relativi a stazioni di
ricarica (Open Street Map, Open Charge Map, etc.), nonchè alcune delle
principali librerie Python che espongono API utili alla costruzione di
una rete per scenari urbani ed extra-urbani (Pandana, OSMnx, etc). Nella
presentazione si descriveranno inoltre brevemente algoritmi quali
Dijkstra e A* utili come punto di partenza per il design di un tale
modello e lo speed-up del tempo di processamento. Infine si mostreranno
alcuni casi studio legati al tema mobilità elettrica, mostrando alcune
mappe interattive realizzate con la potente libreria Folium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esperienza consigliata del pubblico: Beginner/Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1552"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1552&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Betti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/algoritmo-di-routing-multi-obiettivo-di-veicoli-elettrici-con-vincoli-di-ricarica-lungo-il-percorso.html</guid><category>OpenStreetMap</category><category>visualization</category><category>Network</category><category>maps</category><category>Dijkstra</category><category>performance</category></item><item><title>An insight into Python Garbage Collection</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/an-insight-into-python-garbage-collection.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will describe Python garbage collection, specifically the
CPython strategy. Various examples will demonstrate its peculiarities
and the related impact in term of performance. Whenever feasible, the
relevant piece of the actual CPython source code will be presented and
explained. Finally, the talk will focus on some comparisons with
alternative language implementation (such as PyPy) or other languages
garbage collectors (Golang). A mid-level experience with the Python
language is required. A very basic knowledge of both C and GO
programming languages will help to understand some examples regarding
CPython and Go, but it is not essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1767"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1767&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fabio Falzoi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/an-insight-into-python-garbage-collection.html</guid><category>performance</category><category>optimization</category></item><item><title>Building a Celery alternative in Django on Kubernetes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/building-a-celery-alternative-in-django-on-kubernetes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every used Celery and been frustrated by the complexity of RabbitMQ, the
Redis visibility timeout, or the deprecated Postgres support? Wish there
was better support for composing tasks into workflows and a web UI for
viewing status and logs? I’ve been working with Celery for years; it is
a great tool but I wanted to build something that fit my use cases
better so I started a new task execution framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk isn’t about that framework, however. It is about how to use
Django and React together, how to take advantage of more advanced
Postgres features like recursive queries and select-for-update row
locking, and how to deploy the resulting application onto Google Cloud
Platform’s hosted Kubernetes solution. I hope it is valuable as a how-to
guide covering many current best practices, from CLI and API design to
high-availability and continuous deployment. Everything is open-sourced
on GitHub at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/aclowes/yawn"&gt;https://github.com/aclowes/yawn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1568"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1568&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alec Clowes</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/building-a-celery-alternative-in-django-on-kubernetes.html</guid><category>celery</category><category>reactjs</category><category>postgresql</category><category>kubernetes</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Costruire un sito e-commerce con Odoo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/costruire-un-sito-e-commerce-con-odoo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In questa presentazione vedremo come costruire un sito e-commerce con
Odoo in pochi passi. Parleremo brevemente dell’installazione del
framework e della sua configurazione di base per arrivare alle modalità
di personalizzazione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il focus sarà ovviamente la vendita online, ma mostreremo come un
ambiente integrato come Odoo ci permette di gestire tutti i flussi
legati all’e-commerce nella loro interezza. Partendo quindi dalla
registrazione dei clienti fino alla spedizione del materiale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per quanto riguarda le personalizzazioni, parleremo dei vari market
place dove è possibile trovare funzionalità aggiuntive, ma tratteremo
anche le basi del SDK di Odoo che richiedono conoscenze sia di Python
che di Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1762"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1762&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Davide Corio</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/costruire-un-sito-e-commerce-con-odoo.html</guid><category>ERP</category><category>javascript</category><category>enterprise</category><category>sales</category><category>payments</category><category>Odoo</category><category>ecommerce</category></item><item><title>Deep learning: the final frontier for time series analysis and signal processing?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-the-final-frontier-for-time-series-analysis-and-signal-processing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep neural networks are becoming irreplaceable for analyzing most kinds
of data that humans supposed to exceed in - images, video, sounds,
texts. They can not only predict something based on some input but also
generate new images or sounds. Meanwhile, we are forgetting about
another very important source of data - signals (or time series, which
will be interchangeably here), that gets less hype in public but
benefits a lot from applying deep learning comparing to classical
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will review what are sources of time series and what
business goals are we solving while analyzing them, what are “old” tools
for analysis and how deep neural nets overcome them, we will learn the
latest trends and ruin some myths and, moreover, we will see how
generative models can be applied to the signal processing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, you’ll be able to boost your current solutions in
signal processing or time series analysis with deep learning. It will be
also interesting for practitioners in other areas, like computer vision
or NLP since we will discuss some concepts that are widely applicable.
Previous experience with time series is not required, but some
theoretical or practical experience with machine learning and/or neural
networks is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1716"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexandr Honchar</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-the-final-frontier-for-time-series-analysis-and-signal-processing.html</guid><category>machine-learning</category><category>deep learning</category><category>biomedical-data-science</category><category>TimeSeries</category><category>signal-processing</category><category>neural network</category><category>finance</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning with PyTorch for Fun and Profit (Part III / Italian Edition: Divina Commedia)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-with-pytorch-for-fun-and-profit-part-iii-italian-edition-divina-commedia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are all these great articles and blog posts about Deep Learning
describing all that awesome stuff. - Is it all that easy? Let’s check!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll look into: style transfer (making a picture look like painting),
speech generation (like Siri or Alexa) and text generation (writing a
story). In this talk I’ll describe the whole journey: A fun ride from
the idea to the very end including all the struggles, failures and
successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ongoing talk on how far we can get creating a full &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_drama"&gt;radio
drama (Hörspiel)&lt;/a&gt; with
deep learning and the resources required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps, we’ll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data challenge: get the data ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a character-level language models with an Recurrent Neural
Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a text generator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating artwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthesising speech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making it sound like a real person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this special PyCon X edition we will also try to recreate text in the
style of Dante’ Divina Commedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1687"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1687&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Hendorf</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-with-pytorch-for-fun-and-profit-part-iii-italian-edition-divina-commedia.html</guid><category>deep learning</category><category>Pytorch</category><category>art</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>nlp</category></item><item><title>From Machine Learning to Deep Learning and Applying AI to real-world enterprise challenges</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/from-machine-learning-to-deep-learning-and-applying-ai-to-real-world-enterprise-challenges.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence has been expanding across several areas of our
daily lives by getting embedded into billions of smart objects and IoT
devices. Securing such devices presents a number of unique challenges,
since they are deployed in uncontrolled, complex, and often hostile
environments. Smart devices currently apply Machine Learning techniques
to detect and mitigate security issues as they occur. The
ever-increasing number of new security challenges however, requires them
to predict and proactively protect against potential threats that may
occur in the future by utilising Deep Learning techniques. In this talk,
we will discuss the security challenges facing the IoT networks, as well
as desires and requirements for making the journey from Machine Learning
to Deep Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1810"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1810&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mo Haghighi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/from-machine-learning-to-deep-learning-and-applying-ai-to-real-world-enterprise-challenges.html</guid></item><item><title>Genropy e lo storage di file in cloud</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/genropy-e-lo-storage-di-file-in-cloud.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Con la transizione dagli applicativi su server proprietari agli
applicativi in cloud nasce l’esigenza di separare i dati dal loro
storage fisico sul server dove risiede l’applicazione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per soddisfare questa esigenza abbiamo provveduto a implementare in
Genropy delle API per rendere trasparente l’accesso al filesystem e
consentire quindi di scrivere procedure che possano funzionare
indifferentemente appoggiandosi in locale o in cloud
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://aws.amazon.com/it/s3/"&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; o simili)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esamineremo brevemente la gestione dei servizi di Genropy e parleremo in
particolare del servizio di Storage che consente di astrarre delle
directory logiche su cui operare nell’applicativo, potendo decidere
durante l’istallazione la corrispondenza con una directory locale o nel
cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel talk vedremo come rimpiazzare tutte le chiamate al FileSystem con le
corrispondenti chiamate alle API del servizio di Storage. Ci
soffermeremo sulla classe StorageNode che implementa sia i metodi
necessari per le operazioni di scrittura, lettura e cancellazione di
File e Directory indipendentemente dalla loro collocazione locale o in
cloud sia un metodo che fornisce l’URL da servire per vedere o scaricare
il contenuto statico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel caso di servizi S3 o simili viene gestita automaticamente la
gestione di un token di autorizzazione temporaneo basato sui privilegi
dell’utente che effettua la richiesta. Questo consente di servire
direttamente i file statici direttamente dal cloud invece di farli
transitare dal server applicativo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1761"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1761&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/genropy-e-lo-storage-di-file-in-cloud.html</guid><category>S3</category><category>genropy</category><category>cloud</category><category>deploy</category></item><item><title>Geospatial analysis with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/geospatial-analysis-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to its effectiveness and simplicity, Python is spreading as a choice
for handling geospatial data. From running algorithms capable of
extracting geo- referred insights or processing geo archives, Python
could represent a powerful tool to handle geo-related problems thanks to
an extensive set of libraries. The training will give an overview about
processing geospatial data with Python. An approximate agenda will
include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting up the the environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an introduction to geospatial world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with geospatial data&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;playing with geo archives (vector/rasters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extracting geo analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vector tiles big vector data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Spark for geospatial raster analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python for Earth observation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classifying earth observation images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracting insights from Copernicus products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use SNAP from Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No tools are required for attending this training. Bring your PC with
Docker installed. Further instructions will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1674"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1674&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt; in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4
May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Bruni</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/geospatial-analysis-with-python.html</guid><category>Jupyter</category><category>pyspark</category><category>geospatial</category><category>geopynotebook</category><category>spark</category><category>docker</category></item><item><title>Good features beat algorithms</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/good-features-beat-algorithms.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Machine Learning and Data Science in general, understanding the data
is paramount. This understanding can come from many different sources
and techniques: domain expertise, exploratory analysis, SMEs, some
specific Machine Learning techniques, and feature engineering. As a
matter of fact, most Machine Learning and Statistical analysis strongly
depends on how the data is prepared, thus making feature engineering
very important for any serious Machine Learning enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Feature engineering is the process of transforming raw data into
features that better represent the underlying problem to the predictive
models, resulting in improved model accuracy on unseen data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will discuss what feature engineering and feature
selection are; how to select important features in a real-world dataset
and how to develop a simple, but powerful ensemble to measure feature
importance and perform feature selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Familiarity with intermediate concepts of the Python programming
language is required to follow the implementation steps. General
knowledge of the basic concepts of Machine Learning and data cleaning
will be useful, but not strictly necessary, to follow the discussion on
feature selection and feature engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1529"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1529&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pietro Mascolo</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/good-features-beat-algorithms.html</guid><category>scikit-learn</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>Hearing Colours and Seeing Sounds using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/hearing-colours-and-seeing-sounds-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We humans are the masterpieces. We are born with awesome capabilities
and applaudable talents making us different from one another. As an
individual , nobody thinks the way others do , they have their own
intriguing ways to look at this world. Few of us have this exceptional
quality to be able to visualise sounds and map colours with the words.
It is termed as Synesthesia. It is fascinating to know how human brain
can see sounds and hear colours, how it thinks of a word, and sees
blocks of colours, and then these blocks get translated into letters.
There are few who see the letters with a halo-effect. The letters
give- off almost a glow of a certain colour.It is a striking fact that
the synesthetic brains are wired a little differently from the ones of
non-synesthetes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk will cover the interesting applications of python
programming by harnessing simple mathematical techniques to simulate
the synesthetic ( bridging modalities) behaviour of brain. It is
really appealing to be able to look at the world wearing colourful
shades and building an AI that does bridge these modalities (vision ,
hearing ,etc ) is truly astounding. The talk covers an interesting
viewpoint on how python can be used widely to analyse some of the
really complex human brain behaviours ,in addition to solving
comparatively trivial real world problems.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the slides :
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/aakanksha07/hearing-colours-and"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/aakanksha07/hearing-colours-and&lt;/a&gt;-
seeing-sounds-using-python?slide=28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1776"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1776&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aakanksha Chouhan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/hearing-colours-and-seeing-sounds-using-python.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>High Performance and Scalability Made Easy For Data-Analytics/Machine-Learning Codes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/high-performance-and-scalability-made-easy-for-data-analyticsmachine-learning-codes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is your data-analysis code running for too long with Scikit-Learn,
Numpy, Scipy and/or Pandas? Does your data-set blow your memory? Are
spark/dask/… not giving you the scalability and/or ease-of-use your
need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel implemented optimizations in Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Scipy and Pandas
which achieve up to orders of magnitude better performance for many
functionalities compared to standard implementations. The optimized
packages are drop-in replacements which do not require any code changes
and allow processing more data in less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, two new tools allow you to easily bring your full data
analytics pipeline to unprecedented scales: daal4py and HPAT. Daal4py is
a convenient Python API to Intel® DAAL (Intel® Data Analytics
Acceleration Library). While its interface is scikit-learn-like, its
MPI-based engine under the hood allows scaling machine learning
algorithms to bare-metal cluster performance with only little code
changes. HPAT (High Performance Analytics Toolkit) scales analytics
codes using Pandas/Python to bare-metal cluster performance. It
automatically compiles a subset of Python (Pandas/Numpy/Daal4py) to
efficient parallel binaries with MPI, also requiring only minimal code
changes. With these tools your code can be orders of magnitude faster
than alternatives like Apache Spark - without the pain of dealing
directly with lower-level languages and/or tools like C and/or message
passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1805"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1805&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Frank Schlimbach</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/high-performance-and-scalability-made-easy-for-data-analyticsmachine-learning-codes.html</guid></item><item><title>How to Become a Kickass Team Lead 101</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/how-to-become-a-kickass-team-lead-101.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Title: How to Become a Kickass Team Lead 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience Level: Beginner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SUMMARY&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most engineers who get promoted to the role of a team lead, tech lead or
lead developer (regardless of the wording of the title) feel like they
were thrown in cold waters as they, most probably, lack prior training
or education on the subject matter. Most of us that survive and actually
get to like the new role and arrive at really good results, manage to
educate themselves on the skills and habits required to become an
effective team leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will cover the most important lessons about being an
effective team lead without any previous knowledge about the subject.
This is a practical talk and the audience will walk away with a lot of
material and advice to upgrade their engineering leadership game, as
well as a recommended set of resources for further study. The talk is
primarily focused on developing leadership skills and is tailored
towards engineers and software teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals are: - How to develop practical leadership skills for
your day-to-day job - Understand the core components of leadership: ATM
(Ability, Team, Mission) - How to build teamwork on a foundation of
trust - How to overcome the main dysfunctions to look in order to
tighten up your team - Increase your awareness of the main anti-patterns
that team leads end up doing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1668"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1668&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ahmad Alhour</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/how-to-become-a-kickass-team-lead-101.html</guid><category>management</category><category>community</category><category>leadership</category><category>teamwork</category><category>tech-lead</category><category>education</category></item><item><title>Internet delle cose con Redis e django-channels</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/internet-delle-cose-con-redis-e-django-channels.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/morlandi/sinewave"&gt;https://github.com/morlandi/sinewave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’esempio proposto ha lo scopo di esaminare alcuni possibili paradigmi
di comunicazione fra dispositivi periferici e un server centrale, con
particolare riferimento al protocollo PUB/SUB reso disponibile da Redis.
L’invio di informazioni da parte del dispositivo può essere
concretizzato sia utilizzando una delle tante librerie client
disponibili (Python o altri linguaggi), sia mediante una funzione
“publish” minimale (per es. scritta in C); questa seconda opzione può
essere convenientemente utilizzata in contesti limitati quali Arduino o
altre schede embedded. Le informazioni ricevute sul server possono
essere ulteriormente propagate ad eventuali clients web che avessero
manifestato il proprio interesse, predisponendo sul server un processo
“listener” incaricato di raccogliere i dati come subscriber, per poi
eseguirne il broadcast via WebSocket; l’esempio proposto illustra una
semplice implementazione basata su django-channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1726"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1726&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Orlandi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/internet-delle-cose-con-redis-e-django-channels.html</guid><category>pub/sub</category><category>redis</category><category>arduino</category></item><item><title>Machine learning approaches for road scene video analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-approaches-for-road-scene-video-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dashboard cameras (dashcams), inward or front-facing cameras installed
in personal or commercial vehicles, are becoming increasingly popular
due to the pervasiveness of their applications: driver safety,
autonomous driving, fleet management systems, insurance, theft detection
are some examples. Focusing on safety, one of the main problems is to
analyze videos and automatically detect dangerous situations occurring
in them, such as the risk of a near crash with another vehicle or
pedestrian. In this talk, we show how we tackle this real- world problem
at Verizon Connect, using a mix of state-of-the-art deep learning
methods and traditional computer vision / machine learning techniques,
leveraging libraries such as scikit-learn, scipy/numpy, pandas, openCV,
and keras/tensorflow. We also describe how we use AWS and docker to
deploy, serve and scale the application to customers all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1603"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1603&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrea Benericetti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-approaches-for-road-scene-video-analysis.html</guid><category>ComputerVision</category><category>analytics</category><category>scikit-learn</category><category>opencv</category><category>video</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>optical-flow</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Mappe 🗺️ con GeoDjango 🌎, PostGIS 🐘 e Leaflet 🍃</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/mappe-con-geodjango-postgis-e-leaflet.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Una &lt;em&gt;mappa&lt;/em&gt; permette agli utenti di visualizzare e ricercare i dati in
maniera spaziale ed è comune l’esigenza di aggiungerne una al proprio
progetto web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
In questo talk vedremo come abbiamo integrato una &lt;em&gt;mappa&lt;/em&gt; in un
progetto web già in produzione usando &lt;strong&gt;GeoDjango&lt;/strong&gt; , &lt;strong&gt;PostGIS&lt;/strong&gt; e
&lt;strong&gt;Leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; ed eseguiremo una dimostrazione di integrazione da zero
di una mappa in un progetto &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GeoDjango&lt;/strong&gt; è un modulo incluso in &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt; che lo trasforma in un
&lt;em&gt;framework&lt;/em&gt; Web geografico di classe mondiale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PostGIS&lt;/strong&gt; è un estensione del &lt;em&gt;database&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; che aggiunge
il supporto per gli oggetti geografici consentendo di eseguire query
spaziali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; è la principale libreria &lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; per
mappe web interattive ottimizzate per dispositivi mobili.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durante il primo meetup &lt;strong&gt;#PyRoma&lt;/strong&gt; del 2019 abbiamo presentato una
versione ridotta di questo talk limitandoci al solo &lt;strong&gt;caso d’uso&lt;/strong&gt;. Info
qui:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.paulox.net/2019/01/21/pyroma-2019/"&gt;www.paulox.net/2019/01/21/pyroma-2019/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1608"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1608&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paolo Melchiorre</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/mappe-con-geodjango-postgis-e-leaflet.html</guid><category>web</category><category>postgresql</category><category>javascript</category><category>postgis</category><category>django</category><category>leaflet</category><category>maps</category><category>geospatial</category><category>gis</category><category>geodjango</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Meet dask and distributed: the unsung heroes of Python scientific data ecosystem.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/meet-dask-and-distributed-the-unsung-heroes-of-python-scientific-data-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to its world-class data tools and libraries, like Numpy, Pandas,
Jupyter, Matplotlib and xarray, Python is becoming the language of
choice in many scientific communities from Physics to Climate Science,
from Earth Observation to Economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A turn-key but less-know component of the scientific ecosystem is the
dask library that enable seamless parallel, distributed and GPU
computing in most cases without code changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use climate science as an typical example of a discipline where
simple tasks become easily big data problems and where mastering xarray,
dask and dask.distributed is the key to turn them back into simple
tasks, possibly on a large cluster of VMs (that you can easily provision
from your preferred cloud provider).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitpitch.com/alexamici/talks/master?p=PyConX-2019"&gt;https://gitpitch.com/alexamici/talks/master?p=PyConX-2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1704"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1704&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Amici</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/meet-dask-and-distributed-the-unsung-heroes-of-python-scientific-data-ecosystem.html</guid><category>Jupyter</category><category>dask.distributed</category><category>Big-Data</category><category>xarray</category><category>dask</category><category>climate-change</category><category>earth-obeservation</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Pandas ecosystem 2019</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/pandas-ecosystem-2019.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pandas is more than 10 years old now. In this time, it became almost a
standard for building data pipelines and perform data analysis in
Python. As the popularity of the project grows, it also grows the number
of projects that depend or interact with pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover this ecosystem of projects around pandas, mainly in
the prespective of scalability and performance. Discussing for example
how projects like Arrow are key for the future of pandas, or how Dask is
overcoming pandas limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first part, the talk will focus on pandas itself, its components,
and its architecture. This will give the required context for a second
part, that will explain related projects, how they interact with pandas,
and what the whole ecosystem can offer to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1613"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1613&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marc Garcia</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/pandas-ecosystem-2019.html</guid><category>pydata</category><category>analytics</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>Data Mining</category><category>data</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Porting your Python web app to serverless in 30 minutes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/porting-your-python-web-app-to-serverless-in-30-minutes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This live-coding session will guide you through the process of migrating
an existing Flask application to AWS Lambda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will analyze the existing application, decompose it into individual
microservices, adapt authentication, frontend, tests, and data model,
and finally deploy it to the Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this step-by-step process, you will learn the benefits of
serverless and how it will change the way you think of scalability,
availability, security, infrastructure management, and cost
optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1620"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1620&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Casalboni</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/porting-your-python-web-app-to-serverless-in-30-minutes.html</guid><category>serverless</category><category>web</category><category>flask</category><category>aws</category><category>live-coding</category><category>cloud</category></item><item><title>PostgreSQL on the kube</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/postgresql-on-the-kube.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes è un sistema di orchestrazione di container che permette di
gestire il deploy, lo scaling e l’aggiornamento di una applicazione e di
tutti i suoi componenti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk parleremo di quali strumenti sono a disposizione per
effettuare un deploy di un database PostgreSQL in un cluster Kubernetes.
Inoltre vedremo come sia implementabile l’alta disponibilità e la
disaster recovery, in maniera da avere i propri dati al sicuro e sempre
accessibili.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1784"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1784&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Nenciarini</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/postgresql-on-the-kube.html</guid><category>postgresql</category><category>postgres</category><category>kubernetes</category><category>storage</category><category>containers</category><category>docker</category><category>k8s</category><category>cloud</category></item><item><title>PyConX Conference Goodbye</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/pyconx-conference-goodbye.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/pyconx-conference-goodbye.html</guid></item><item><title>PyConX Conference Welcome and Introduction</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/pyconx-conference-welcome-and-introduction.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/pyconx-conference-welcome-and-introduction.html</guid></item><item><title>Python e MySQL 8.0 Document Store</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/python-e-mysql-80-document-store.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MySQL Document Store è l’implementazione di MySQL di un Document Store
JSON. Permette di memorizzare dati non strutturati sfruttando le
proprietà transazionali già disponibili in MySQL. Per poter usare
pienamente il MySQL Document Store, il nuovo X DevAPI è stato sviluppato
ed è disponibile per diversi linguaggi di programmazione, anche in
Python attraverso MySQL Connector/Python 8.0. Questa presentazione vi
guida attraverso le basi del MySQL Document Store e come utilizzare l’X
DevAPI in MySQL Connector/Python 8.0 per gestire le raccolte di
documenti e utilizzare i metodi CRUD per lavorare con questi documenti.
Partecipate a questa sessione se siete interessati a MySQL Document
Store e MySQL Connector/Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1544"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1544&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Frédéric Descamps</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/python-e-mysql-80-document-store.html</guid><category>database</category><category>json</category><category>DocumentStore</category><category>mysql</category></item><item><title>Python &amp; Serverless: Refactor your monolith piece by piece</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/python-serverless-refactor-your-monolith-piece-by-piece.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python &amp;amp; Serverless: Refactor your monolith piece by piece&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the Function as a Service (Serverless) technologies
is facilitating the adoption of a microservices based architecture. In
this talk we will discuss why this might be useful (scalability / cost
opportunities / choosing the right tool for the job) and what strategies
we can follow to either extract independent services or add new
capabilities using an event driven architecture style to a django web
application. We will end up our discussion talking about testing and
monitoring of our freshly baked services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serverless/FaaS concepts brief intro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking up the monolith rationale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracting some modules into independent services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding more capabilities using events as a trigger for our FaaS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing &amp;amp; Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;References&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intended audience should be familiar with the concepts related to
web applications, web apis and a smattering of serverless concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1591"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1591&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giuseppe Vallarelli</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/python-serverless-refactor-your-monolith-piece-by-piece.html</guid><category>serverless</category><category>microservices</category><category>pyweb</category><category>aws</category><category>devops</category><category>django</category><category>lambda-functions</category><category>event-driven-architecture</category><category>cloud</category><category>faas</category></item><item><title>The Secret Society of Happiness</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/the-secret-society-of-happiness.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happiness and our search for it is important but complicated. However,
we can learn much from each other. Being our authentic selves and
allowing ourselves to grow, gains us skills to help others too. In this
talk, we’ll learn about helping ourselves and guiding others towards
happiness for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness and our own search for it have deep impacts on our entire
lives. But important as it is, it’s also incredibly complicated. We each
carry our own baggage, and the things that make us happy are not
constants. However, we can learn so much from each other in a community,
and can have a tremendous impact on each other’s happiness in how we
shape our communities and interactions - though not always in the most
obvious ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the barriers to our happiness are actually created by ourselves,
and those can be the hardest the overcome. But by being our authentic
selves and facing up to our fears, we can gain the confidence to do what
is needed. And growing in this process ourselves, we gain so many skills
in helping others in their journeys as well. Embracing those journeys
and skills in our community will make it a happier and more inclusive
space for all, which fosters growth in ourselves and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently put literally every aspect of my life upside down in my own
search for happiness, and will share from my personal story and stories
of others about the lessons learned, in a way that many of us will
recognise. We’ll also talk about how each of us in a community has
opportunities to bring happiness to others, which in the end will
contribute to our own happiness too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous responses to this talk included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Took me a decade to understand what this speaker is presenting
gracefully and meaningfully in a handful of minutes.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Been waiting for this talk for months and it has not disappointed.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Such a strong, emotional and impactful opening keynote.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“This speaker is like the purest person ever!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Thank you for being inspiring and honest.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Hard truth. Touching chords.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I should have worn waterproof makeup.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1799"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1799&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sasha Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/the-secret-society-of-happiness.html</guid></item><item><title>Traversing the land of graph computing and databases</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/traversing-the-land-of-graph-computing-and-databases.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphs have long held a special place in the computer science’s history
(and codebases). With the advent of a new wave of the information age
characterized by a greater emphasis on linked data, graph computing and
databases have risen to prominence. Be it enterprise knowledge graphs or
graph-based analytics, there are a great number of potential
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reap the benefits of graph databases and computing, one needs to
understand the basics as well as current technical landscape and
offerings. Also, it’s important to understand if a graph-based approach
suits your problem. This talk will touch upon these points. Be prepared
to learn some graph fundamentals and witness a live demo using Neo4j, a
popular graph database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soft pre-requisites include familiarity with Python and experience
working with a SQL or NoSQL database. There are no hard pre-requisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1682"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1682&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Akash Tandon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/traversing-the-land-of-graph-computing-and-databases.html</guid><category>nosql</category><category>graph</category><category>analytics</category><category>databases</category><category>neo4j</category><category>datascience</category><category>graphdatabase</category></item><item><title>Using Python to create political acts</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/using-python-to-create-political-acts.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Pycon Italia I showed how my team has using Python and Data Science
to fight corruption - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiJ5a4CXRF8&amp;amp;t=8s"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiJ5a4CXRF8&amp;amp;t=8s&lt;/a&gt;
This time I want to show something that can be replicated in Italy right
after we finish the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &amp;#64;participatory (World Bank Internet impact researcher) says, every
country has a good response for public pressure across the internet, and
this response is even better within autocratic governments because they
want to keep healthy international relations. But how we can keep a
record of all the drafts of legislation that are happening right now?
How we can use this information and create an action for the public to
show their agreement or not for every change that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Scrapy, Python, Django, and Open source! Let me show you how has
been done in Brazil and the Pipeline that makes possible to replicated
here in Italy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1702"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1702&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe Cabral</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/using-python-to-create-political-acts.html</guid><category>web-scraping</category><category>Python</category><category>programming</category><category>scrapy</category><category>api</category><category>open-data</category><category>opendata</category><category>hacking</category></item></channel></rss>