<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - PyBay 2025</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pybay-2025.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>AI, IP, and Your Code: What Developers Need to Know</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/ai-ip-and-your-code-what-developers-need-to-know.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alla Barbalat</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/ai-ip-and-your-code-what-developers-need-to-know.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world where AI-generated code is becoming more prevalent, who owns the output? Can AI companies freely use your open-source code as training data? What are the legal ramifications when an AI system infringes upon existing intellectual property rights?Alla will address these critical questions focused on code …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world where AI-generated code is becoming more prevalent, who owns the output? Can AI companies freely use your open-source code as training data? What are the legal ramifications when an AI system infringes upon existing intellectual property rights?Alla will address these critical questions focused on code and IP law. The talk aims to demystify the complex legal landscape developers may find themselves navigating when using AI-generated code.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Architecting Real-World Complex Systems in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/architecting-real-world-complex-systems-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Hulse</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/architecting-real-world-complex-systems-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply understanding--let alone designing--complex systems can be tricky. Traditionally, systems engineering approaches have relied on clunky, proprietary, opaque tools to model, analyze, and design system structure and behavior. Python's core features--openness, simplicity, and object-oriented paradigm make it a very attractive replacement, if used correctly. With this in mind, this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply understanding--let alone designing--complex systems can be tricky. Traditionally, systems engineering approaches have relied on clunky, proprietary, opaque tools to model, analyze, and design system structure and behavior. Python's core features--openness, simplicity, and object-oriented paradigm make it a very attractive replacement, if used correctly. With this in mind, this presentation will give the case for using Python as an environment for model-based systems engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Beyond the Black Box: Interpreting ML models with SHAP</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/beyond-the-black-box-interpreting-ml-models-with-shap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Avik Basu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/beyond-the-black-box-interpreting-ml-models-with-shap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ML models often act as black boxes, making it hard to extract actionable insights. SHAP helps explain predictions by attributing importance to input features using concepts from game theory. In this talk, we’ll cover the need for explainability, introduce the intuition behind Shapley values, and walk through a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ML models often act as black boxes, making it hard to extract actionable insights. SHAP helps explain predictions by attributing importance to input features using concepts from game theory. In this talk, we’ll cover the need for explainability, introduce the intuition behind Shapley values, and walk through a couple of case studies using boosted tree-based and neural network based models. We’ll also discuss SHAP plots, best practices, challenges, and pitfalls when working with large datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Closing Remarks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/closing-remarks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Brousseau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/closing-remarks.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us to wrap up the PyBay 2025 Conference, hear about the day and important messages from a few guest speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Context Managers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/context-managers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Colin Chan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/context-managers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the 20th anniversary of PEP 343! Context managers have been part of Python since 2005, but they're still as useful as ever. In this entertaining talk, we'll explore why context managers exist, how they work, when to reach for them, and how they synergize with the contextvars module …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the 20th anniversary of PEP 343! Context managers have been part of Python since 2005, but they're still as useful as ever. In this entertaining talk, we'll explore why context managers exist, how they work, when to reach for them, and how they synergize with the contextvars module. Whether you're a beginner or a veteran Pythonista, you're sure to learn something new. And, thanks to context managers, you can rest assured that this talk won't leak any open file handles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Do It Yourself: Demystifying the Magic of Dataclasses</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/do-it-yourself-demystifying-the-magic-of-dataclasses.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brett Slatkin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/do-it-yourself-demystifying-the-magic-of-dataclasses.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's built-in &lt;cite&gt;dataclasses&lt;/cite&gt; module provides an enormous amount of leverage when defining classes: minimal code can enable maximal capabilities. However, inevitably, the &lt;cite&gt;&amp;#64;dataclass&lt;/cite&gt; decorator will fall short of your needs as a program grows over time and gains complexity. This talk will walk through how to build the most …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's built-in &lt;cite&gt;dataclasses&lt;/cite&gt; module provides an enormous amount of leverage when defining classes: minimal code can enable maximal capabilities. However, inevitably, the &lt;cite&gt;&amp;#64;dataclass&lt;/cite&gt; decorator will fall short of your needs as a program grows over time and gains complexity. This talk will walk through how to build the most important features of &lt;cite&gt;dataclasses&lt;/cite&gt; yourself so you'll know what to do. It will also investigate the advanced techniques &lt;cite&gt;dataclasses&lt;/cite&gt; uses under the hood to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Don’t Make Assertion Assumptions w/AI you still have to write unit tests</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/dont-make-assertion-assumptions-wai-you-still-have-to-write-unit-tests.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liz Acosta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/dont-make-assertion-assumptions-wai-you-still-have-to-write-unit-tests.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been inundated with opinions, takes (both hot and cold), thought leadership, and rants and raves about the merits, misfortunes, and malevolence of AI in coding. Wherever you fall on the spectrum, as a developer, you likely won’t be able to avoid AI.And yes, you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been inundated with opinions, takes (both hot and cold), thought leadership, and rants and raves about the merits, misfortunes, and malevolence of AI in coding. Wherever you fall on the spectrum, as a developer, you likely won’t be able to avoid AI.And yes, you still have to write your unit tests – more so now than ever.This talk hopes to help you strike the right balance between leveraging and leaning on AI by stepping through different strategies for approaching unit testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Events are the Wrong Abstraction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/events-are-the-wrong-abstraction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mason Egger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/events-are-the-wrong-abstraction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern software applications are distributed systems. They need to connect and communicate with other application across a network. Event-Driven Architecture is a common pattern for facilitating this connectivity, using Events as the communication abstraction. However, this pattern introduces complexities as well, such as fragmented logic, increased latency, decreased observability …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern software applications are distributed systems. They need to connect and communicate with other application across a network. Event-Driven Architecture is a common pattern for facilitating this connectivity, using Events as the communication abstraction. However, this pattern introduces complexities as well, such as fragmented logic, increased latency, decreased observability, and more. But what if there were a way to get the benefits of Event-Driven Architecture without the complexities?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Guardrails: An alternative view of safely working in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/guardrails-an-alternative-view-of-safely-working-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Neugebauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/guardrails-an-alternative-view-of-safely-working-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python – like many languages – lets you do dangerous things. Many of features that allow you to do inadvisable things were used to achieve things that since became defining features of Python.Python – unlike many languages – discovered that leaving these features lying next to dangerous things was a bad idea …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python – like many languages – lets you do dangerous things. Many of features that allow you to do inadvisable things were used to achieve things that since became defining features of Python.Python – unlike many languages – discovered that leaving these features lying next to dangerous things was a bad idea, and built guardrails around them.In this talk, we’ll explore this design philosophy, and use that to explain Python’s attitude to safely working with the language and its internals.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>How our Context Engineering reduced bugs by 50% in Python code review</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/how-our-context-engineering-reduced-bugs-by-50-in-python-code-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Cassion</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/how-our-context-engineering-reduced-bugs-by-50-in-python-code-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of AI coding agents has led to a surge in PRs awaiting review. Code reviews are critical but tedious to do manually. This is why we built a context-engineering approach at CodeRabbit that mimics how senior engineers review Python code. We feed context to LLMs from multiple …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of AI coding agents has led to a surge in PRs awaiting review. Code reviews are critical but tedious to do manually. This is why we built a context-engineering approach at CodeRabbit that mimics how senior engineers review Python code. We feed context to LLMs from multiple sources including issue tickets, dependency graphs, MCP servers (Notion, Confluence), Linters/SAST, and your AI coding agent guidelines. This approach helps LLMs catch hidden bugs and edge cases that would otherwise slip through.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Increasing Types in Large Codebases with Pyrefly and AI Tooling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/increasing-types-in-large-codebases-with-pyrefly-and-ai-tooling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maggie Moss</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/increasing-types-in-large-codebases-with-pyrefly-and-ai-tooling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta has some of the largest typed Python codebases in the world. That’s why we built Pyre and now Pyrefly. Despite this, Meta has lots of untyped code and we have been building tooling to help add types at scale. This talk will explore the benefits of typed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta has some of the largest typed Python codebases in the world. That’s why we built Pyre and now Pyrefly. Despite this, Meta has lots of untyped code and we have been building tooling to help add types at scale. This talk will explore the benefits of typed Python, how to increase types in your codebase and leverage new tools like Pyrefly to improve developer experience in large Python codebases.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Just because AI can write your tests... should it?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/just-because-ai-can-write-your-tests-should-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pamela Fox</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/just-because-ai-can-write-your-tests-should-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a big fan of AI-assisted coding tools—they’re making programming more accessible than ever! But as developers, we risk using LLMs to write everything, including our tests, and forgetting the powerful tools in our Python testing toolbox.In this talk, I’ll explore where AI-generated tests can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a big fan of AI-assisted coding tools—they’re making programming more accessible than ever! But as developers, we risk using LLMs to write everything, including our tests, and forgetting the powerful tools in our Python testing toolbox.In this talk, I’ll explore where AI-generated tests can fall short—and show how writing your own tests leads to more robust, meaningful coverage.You’ll leave with a sharper instinct for when to lean on AI—and when to reach for more specialized tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Mentor Today, Lead Tomorrow. Why Interns Are Your Next Best Investment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/mentor-today-lead-tomorrow-why-interns-are-your-next-best-investment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johannan Hjersman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/mentor-today-lead-tomorrow-why-interns-are-your-next-best-investment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late May, the Federal Reserve Bank of New York announced CS majors ranked 7th in unemployment at 6.1%. With the scarcity of openings for interns and new grads relative to previous years, internships are now more important than ever. Join me in highlighting the value of interns …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late May, the Federal Reserve Bank of New York announced CS majors ranked 7th in unemployment at 6.1%. With the scarcity of openings for interns and new grads relative to previous years, internships are now more important than ever. Join me in highlighting the value of interns to the company, mentor, mentee, and industry as a whole with an example using Python with Pandas and Matplotlib. The talk will also show the benefits of interns both immediate and after the internship experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>No, seriously, why don't we use better testing tools?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/no-seriously-why-dont-we-use-better-testing-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zac Hatfield-Dodds</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/no-seriously-why-dont-we-use-better-testing-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even powerful testing tools go unused. Drawing from years maintaining Python testing infrastructure, this talk explores why adoption is a social problem needing technical solutions.We'll examine the gap between what's possible (property-based testing, coverage-guided fuzzing) and what developers actually use. The challenge isn't building better tools – it's making …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even powerful testing tools go unused. Drawing from years maintaining Python testing infrastructure, this talk explores why adoption is a social problem needing technical solutions.We'll examine the gap between what's possible (property-based testing, coverage-guided fuzzing) and what developers actually use. The challenge isn't building better tools – it's making them accessible.For developers who want advanced testing to be not just possible, but practical.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Out of the Frying Pan/Into the Fire</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/out-of-the-frying-paninto-the-fire.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Multiprocessed code to Free Threading — Lisa Roach</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/out-of-the-frying-paninto-the-fire.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a global interpreter locked CPython, multiprocessing was often used as a tool to improve performance. Let’s discuss how to use free-threaded Python to workaround some of the pitfalls of multiprocessed code, as well as highlight the new challenges that free-threading brings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Powering up with t-strings in Python 3.14</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/powering-up-with-t-strings-in-python-314.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jim Baker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/powering-up-with-t-strings-in-python-314.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Template strings are a new language feature in Python 3.14. You use t-strings by building on what you already know about f-strings. But t-strings unlock new superpowers: preventing code injection attacks, supporting structured output, and simplifying working with other languages like HTML and SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Template strings are a new language feature in Python 3.14. You use t-strings by building on what you already know about f-strings. But t-strings unlock new superpowers: preventing code injection attacks, supporting structured output, and simplifying working with other languages like HTML and SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Resilient Network Infra</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/python-in-resilient-network-infra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Automation to Validation — Munachimso (Muna)  Nwaiwu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/python-in-resilient-network-infra.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern network infrastructure demands reliable automation. This session explores Python's role in building resilient automation and testing frameworks for complex network systems. We'll cover practical strategies and patterns for effective network automation and automated testing. Discover how to leverage powerful Python libraries and tools like Netmiko, Nornir, pyATS, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern network infrastructure demands reliable automation. This session explores Python's role in building resilient automation and testing frameworks for complex network systems. We'll cover practical strategies and patterns for effective network automation and automated testing. Discover how to leverage powerful Python libraries and tools like Netmiko, Nornir, pyATS, and pytest. You'll learn practical techniques to build more robust, maintainable, and verifiable automated systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling Open Source Up and Down</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/scaling-open-source-up-and-down.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Glyph</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/scaling-open-source-up-and-down.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've maintained a variety of open source libraries for 25 years now. Some of these libraries are extremely popular. Some are downloaded millions of times per month; some thousands of times, some tens of times. The experience at these different scales is very different. Some skills are seamlessly transferrable …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've maintained a variety of open source libraries for 25 years now. Some of these libraries are extremely popular. Some are downloaded millions of times per month; some thousands of times, some tens of times. The experience at these different scales is very different. Some skills are seamlessly transferrable, but other habits need to be opposite at different extremes of the spectrum.What do you need to start a project? And how should it change as your audience grows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Structured RAG is better than RAG!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/structured-rag-is-better-than-rag.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guido van Rossum</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/structured-rag-is-better-than-rag.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft I've been contributing to an open source project demonstrating what we call Structured RAG. This is an improvement over the popular AI tactic named RAG (look it up) that can answer questions over large collections of text or images better and faster than RAG. We use this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft I've been contributing to an open source project demonstrating what we call Structured RAG. This is an improvement over the popular AI tactic named RAG (look it up) that can answer questions over large collections of text or images better and faster than RAG. We use this as the basis for long-term AI memory.I will explain the Structured RAG algorithm and show some demos with real-world data. I will also discuss the Python library we are releasing this summer and its API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Talk to Your Chess Games with Python + LLMs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/talk-to-your-chess-games-with-python-llms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indrajit Rajtilak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/talk-to-your-chess-games-with-python-llms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you could chat with your chess games&amp;nbsp;— about strategy, tactics, weaknesses, and more!In this talk, we’ll build a Python-based chat coach: analyze your Chess games with python-chess + Stockfish, then pair positions and engine insights with an LLM.You’ll learn how to ask why is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you could chat with your chess games&amp;nbsp;— about strategy, tactics, weaknesses, and more!In this talk, we’ll build a Python-based chat coach: analyze your Chess games with python-chess + Stockfish, then pair positions and engine insights with an LLM.You’ll learn how to ask why is the eval bar tilting?, what’s the strategic plan here?, or why is this opening line dangerous?You’ll leave with a template to create your own interactive chess tutor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Taming LLMs with Pydantic: Parsing, Validating, and Guarding output</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/taming-llms-with-pydantic-parsing-validating-and-guarding-output.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manish Sinha</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/taming-llms-with-pydantic-parsing-validating-and-guarding-output.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LLMs can be unpredictable, fragile, and tricky to scale responsibly. In this talk, you’ll learn how to use Pydantic to transform that chaos into clean, typed, validated Python objects you can safely rely on in production.Based on our own real world experience with it, we'll explore how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LLMs can be unpredictable, fragile, and tricky to scale responsibly. In this talk, you’ll learn how to use Pydantic to transform that chaos into clean, typed, validated Python objects you can safely rely on in production.Based on our own real world experience with it, we'll explore how to define schemas, coerce LLM output into those schemas, and add guardrails through validation and structured prompting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>The Long Hello World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/the-long-hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Noah Kantrowitz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/the-long-hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello World is often used as a stand-in for &amp;quot;the simplest program&amp;quot;, great for teaching and getting people started on their coding journey. But what _really_ happens in that one line? This talk will be a deep dive into the Python interpreter, C libraries, Linux kernel, and beyond. We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello World is often used as a stand-in for &amp;quot;the simplest program&amp;quot;, great for teaching and getting people started on their coding journey. But what _really_ happens in that one line? This talk will be a deep dive into the Python interpreter, C libraries, Linux kernel, and beyond. We will poke holes in every abstraction and learn about our computers like never before, both to aid in debugging and to pick the best level of tooling for future development projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>The Zen of the Bronze Layer: Ingestion of Data with Unstable Schema</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/the-zen-of-the-bronze-layer-ingestion-of-data-with-unstable-schema.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Wiegel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/the-zen-of-the-bronze-layer-ingestion-of-data-with-unstable-schema.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the medallion data architecture, the bronze layer is for staging incoming raw data before further transformation and cleaning. Ideally, tabular CSV data undergoes minimal transformations and is queryable upon ingestion; however, third party data sources can contain unstable schema that make this challenging even using pandas. With native …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the medallion data architecture, the bronze layer is for staging incoming raw data before further transformation and cleaning. Ideally, tabular CSV data undergoes minimal transformations and is queryable upon ingestion; however, third party data sources can contain unstable schema that make this challenging even using pandas. With native Python data structures and a more flexible data schema, such this messy data can more reliably be ingested for cleaning and monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Visualizing large graphs and AI embeddings with ease</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/visualizing-large-graphs-and-ai-embeddings-with-ease.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nikita Rokotyan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/visualizing-large-graphs-and-ai-embeddings-with-ease.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cosmograph, a high-performance web framework for creating interactive graph visualizations, is now accessible to Python engineers directly from their notebooks!Powered by cosmos.gl (the fastest and open source JavaScript library for Network Graph visualizations library) and DuckDB, Cosmograph handles millions of points with GPU-accelerated, force-directed layouts, enabling real-time …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cosmograph, a high-performance web framework for creating interactive graph visualizations, is now accessible to Python engineers directly from their notebooks!Powered by cosmos.gl (the fastest and open source JavaScript library for Network Graph visualizations library) and DuckDB, Cosmograph handles millions of points with GPU-accelerated, force-directed layouts, enabling real-time exploration of massive multidimensional and graph data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome &amp; Opening Remarks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/welcome-opening-remarks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Brousseau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/welcome-opening-remarks.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us to kick off PyBay 2025 with Chris Brousseau the Conference Chair.  Hear about the day and important messages from a few guest speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Your Async Code Might Be Slower — and How to Fix It</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/why-your-async-code-might-be-slower-and-how-to-fix-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aastha</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/why-your-async-code-might-be-slower-and-how-to-fix-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asyncio has become one of Python’s most popular libraries for writing fast, scalable applications. But sometimes, using async can actually make programs slower.This talk explores common asyncio mistakes, how misunderstanding I/O-bound vs. CPU-bound tasks hurts performance, and practical patterns for writing efficient async code.Through real-world …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asyncio has become one of Python’s most popular libraries for writing fast, scalable applications. But sometimes, using async can actually make programs slower.This talk explores common asyncio mistakes, how misunderstanding I/O-bound vs. CPU-bound tasks hurts performance, and practical patterns for writing efficient async code.Through real-world examples and live demos, you’ll leave with a clear model for using asyncio effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.org/"&gt;https://pybay.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pybay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry></feed>