<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Advanced Software Testing for Data Scientists</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/advanced-software-testing-for-data-scientists.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The journey to deploy a model to production starts with testing it rigorously, including its code implementation. In this tutorial, you will learn about state of the art software testing approach. You will learn how to write unit tests with enhanced diagnostics, leverage validation tools from numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, apply test doubles and generate test cases using property-based testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raoul-Gabriel Urma</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/advanced-software-testing-for-data-scientists.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>An Introduction to Probability and Statistics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/an-introduction-to-probability-and-statistics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will offer a quick overview of many of the essentials of statistics used to solve real world problems. We'll start by looking at how to build a simple hypothesis test based on a practical e-commerce problem. Then we'll see how we can expand on this simple test using one of the most powerful tools in statistics: the linear model. No previous experience with statistics required!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will Kurt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/an-introduction-to-probability-and-statistics.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>How to Prove You’re Right: A/B Testing with SciPy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/how-to-prove-youre-right-ab-testing-with-scipy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you want to run an A/B test! How long should you run it for? How will you know if an observed difference is real? Does it matter what my A/B test is measuring? All of these questions and more can be answered by learning about Hypothesis Testing in SciPy. You might have heard of T-Tests, Chi Squared, and ANOVA in your high school stats class, but you've never heard them explained like this!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hillary Green-Lerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/how-to-prove-youre-right-ab-testing-with-scipy.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Language Modeling</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/introduction-to-language-modeling.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this two part tutorial we will start with introduction of language models, how they are used and why they are important in the domain of Natural Language Processing. In the second half we will be taking the attendees through a hands-on workshop where they will develop a language model based on a sample dataset and talk through some of the results and gotchas of working with language models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aditi Khullar</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/introduction-to-language-modeling.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Introduction to NLP</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/introduction-to-nlp.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curious about Natural Language Processing (NLP) but don't know where to start? This tutorial is for you! This tutorial will provide an overview of what NLP is, why it's useful, as well as several major NLP libraries and topics. You'll also have the opportunity to get hands-on with some basic NLP methods using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariel Frank</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/introduction-to-nlp.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Introduction to pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/introduction-to-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is a hands on introduction to pandas. pandas is a fast, powerful, flexible and easy to use data analysis and manipulation tool, built on top of the Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marc Garcia</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/introduction-to-pandas.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Visualizing the 2019 Measles Outbreak in NYC (with Python)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/visualizing-the-2019-measles-outbreak-in-nyc-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US is amid its largest measles outbreak since 1992, with 1,250 cases as of Oct 3, 2019. Most cases (649) were in NYC, where the outbreak was declared over on Sep 3, 2019. This tutorial creates data visualizations to help understand the measles outbreak in NYC. Bubble maps and bar charts are created using Python (bokeh, matplotlib) and following principles of clarity and context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlos Afonso</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-06:pydata-new-york-city-2019/visualizing-the-2019-measles-outbreak-in-nyc-with-python.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>A How-to guide for migrating legacy data applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-how-to-guide-for-migrating-legacy-data-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Migrating legacy applications can be daunting. They are frequently large, poorly tested, undermaintained, yet business critical. Over time they may end up relying on deprecated technology and unprepared for changing business needs. We’ll cover lessons learned in migrating such an application to something maintainable, sharing details on how to go about it in a safe and systematic manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marius van Niekerk</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-how-to-guide-for-migrating-legacy-data-applications.html</guid></item><item><title>Building a maintainable plotting library</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/building-a-maintainable-plotting-library.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fluid data visualization needs to be aware of the explicit and implicit structure of the data you want to visualize. Whether you are working on a personal project, or want to have a consistent set of figures for your company or lab, we will share tips on how to build a custom library using matplotlib that is easy to use, easy to maintain, easy to extend, and customized to your use case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Colin Carroll</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/building-a-maintainable-plotting-library.html</guid></item><item><title>Building Software and Communities With Peer Review</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/building-software-and-communities-with-peer-review.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software peer review can improve software quality, accelerate the adoption of best practices and community standards, and build communities of practice. I will present lessons from over four years of software peer review at rOpenSci, and new initiatives such as pyOpenSci that are expanding software peer review into new fields and languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noam Ross</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/building-software-and-communities-with-peer-review.html</guid></item><item><title>Clean Machine Learning Code: Practical Software Engineering Principles for ML Craftsmanship</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/clean-machine-learning-code-practical-software-engineering-principles-for-ml-craftsmanship.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning pipelines are software pipelines after all. Their complexity and design viscosity lead to spectacular, costly and even deadly ML failures. This talk describes the most important Clean Code and Clean Architecture design principles, applied to machine learning applications. It aims to help the audience reduce machine learning technical debt, and to design robust ML architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Moussa Taifi</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/clean-machine-learning-code-practical-software-engineering-principles-for-ml-craftsmanship.html</guid></item><item><title>Colorism in High Fashion (featuring: K-Means Clustering)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/colorism-in-high-fashion-featuring-k-means-clustering.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will go into the technical details of transforming twenty years of Vogue cover photos into a numeric dataset that measures skin tone lightness, which, when visualized, showcases the striking lack of diversity on the cover of Vogue magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Malaika Handa</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/colorism-in-high-fashion-featuring-k-means-clustering.html</guid></item><item><title>Data-centric exploration using intake, dask, hvplot, datashader, panel, and binder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-centric-exploration-using-intake-dask-hvplot-datashader-panel-and-binder.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discovering a new dataset is exciting, but it can also be daunting. How will you read it? Will it fit in memory? What meaning can be derived? Can you share that with others? This talk describes an opinionated method of data exploration going from data ingestion to dashboard deployment and showing how everything comes together into a complete and repeatable workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julia Signell</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-centric-exploration-using-intake-dask-hvplot-datashader-panel-and-binder.html</guid></item><item><title>Data science at The New York Times: a mission-driven approach to personalizing the customer journey</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-science-at-the-new-york-times-a-mission-driven-approach-to-personalizing-the-customer-journey.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does The New York Times use data science to further its mission? We'll talk about the use of machine learning throughout the company, from social media promotion to targeted advertising to content recommendations, and the cross-team collaborations that make it possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Wiggins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-science-at-the-new-york-times-a-mission-driven-approach-to-personalizing-the-customer-journey.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Dealing With Imbalanced Classes in Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/dealing-with-imbalanced-classes-in-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skewed datasets are not uncommon. And they are tough to handle. Usual classification models and techniques often fail miserably when presented with such a problem. We discuss right from the basics of what class imbalance means to how we can overcome it, using various algorithms and some subtle techniques. We discuss details of evaluating our efforts and some small but crucial things that are vital&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aditya Lahiri</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/dealing-with-imbalanced-classes-in-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Deep Dive into scikit-learn's HistGradientBoosting Classifier and Regressor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/deep-dive-into-scikit-learns-histgradientboosting-classifier-and-regressor.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gradient boosting decision trees (GBDT) is a powerful machine-learning technique known for its high predictive power with heterogeneous data. In this talk, we will explore scikit-learn's implementation of histogram-based GBDT called HistGradientBoostingClassifier/Regressor and how it compares to other GBDT libraries such as XGBoost, CatBoost, and LightGBM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas J Fan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/deep-dive-into-scikit-learns-histgradientboosting-classifier-and-regressor.html</guid></item><item><title>Discover your latent food graph with this 1 weird trick</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/discover-your-latent-food-graph-with-this-1-weird-trick.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Grubhub we leverage recent advances in Representation Learning to gain an automated and scalable understanding of our vast restaurant and menu catalog. We use these techniques to learn a latent food knowledge graph in order to drive better search and personalization. Particularly, we hope to share some of our advances in using: language modeling and knowledge graphs in the e-commerce setting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Egg</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/discover-your-latent-food-graph-with-this-1-weird-trick.html</guid></item><item><title>Every ML Model Deserves To Be A Full Micro-service</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/every-ml-model-deserves-to-be-a-full-micro-service.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best ML model has little business value if it operates in a vacuum. The infrastructure used at Netflix enables data-scientists to quickly deploy their model as a microservice to perform inference or integrate with other systems. We demonstrate how we leverage a Python environment, familiar to data-scientists, as well as FaaS to remove infrastructure considerations and increase productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Cledat</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/every-ml-model-deserves-to-be-a-full-micro-service.html</guid></item><item><title>Free Your Esoteric Data Using Apache Arrow and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/free-your-esoteric-data-using-apache-arrow-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you work with esoteric data that has no schema, no human-readable output, and/or inconsistent interfaces? Is your data only readable from C++ classes with a secret encoding? Let me demonstrate how to use Python and Apache Arrow to quickly read your data into pandas and elegantly analyze the data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maciej Wojton</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/free-your-esoteric-data-using-apache-arrow-and-python.html</guid></item><item><title>High-Performance Data Science at Scale with RAPIDS, Dask, and GPUs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/high-performance-data-science-at-scale-with-rapids-dask-and-gpus.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore the performance of RAPIDS, an open-source platform for accelerating data science with GPUs. The audience will learn the necessary background to leverage RAPIDS at scale in a real-world problem and get a glimpse of our roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Keith Kraus</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/high-performance-data-science-at-scale-with-rapids-dask-and-gpus.html</guid></item><item><title>How and why to put your Jupyter notebooks in Docker containers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/how-and-why-to-put-your-jupyter-notebooks-in-docker-containers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks are a key part of a data scientist's professional output. Learn how to go from a notebook that shows a report to a reproducible service with the help of Docker. In this short walkthrough, you'll learn how to write a Dockerfile that packages your work effectively and consistently, so that it can be shared with any audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Austin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/how-and-why-to-put-your-jupyter-notebooks-in-docker-containers.html</guid></item><item><title>Implementing Lightweight Random Indexing for Polylingual Text Classification</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/implementing-lightweight-random-indexing-for-polylingual-text-classification.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most NLP tasks offer a simple setup: one language and a target. In the real world, we may face with the fact that people speak different languages when building models. This talk will motivate the use of lightweight random indexing (see paper here) to combine data sets across multiple languages and walk through a working implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ian Whalen</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/implementing-lightweight-random-indexing-for-polylingual-text-classification.html</guid></item><item><title>Improve the efficiency of your Big Data application</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/improve-the-efficiency-of-your-big-data-application.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you're using NumPy and your data uses too much memory or requires too much computational resources this talk is for you! We'll introduce Caterva and IronArray, two libraries that, when used together, can greatly improve the efficiency and reduce the cost of your big data applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesc Alted</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/improve-the-efficiency-of-your-big-data-application.html</guid></item><item><title>Julia for Pythonistas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/julia-for-pythonistas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce the audience to Julia and show you how seamless it is to start programing in Julia from a Python background. I will talk about my experience using Julia in a few different projects and why I’ve found Julia an accessible yet special language with a lot of potential. I will also share what I love about the Julia community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kelly Shen</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/julia-for-pythonistas.html</guid></item><item><title>Painting a Picture of Public Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/painting-a-picture-of-public-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data powers society, information that changes situations. How can we use data to help people understand the world they live in? With the use of the publicly available data, this talk aims to see past our external identities of our jobs, physical traits, and even geographical origin. This talk is a story of New York, narrated by data science, written in code, illustrated with art.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kamal Abdelrahman</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/painting-a-picture-of-public-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Production Code in Data Science Consulting</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/production-code-in-data-science-consulting.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;BCG Gamma offers custom Data Science solutions to industry leaders worldwide. During its projects, code must quickly and seamlessly transition from a Proof of Concept to Production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Akos Furton</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/production-code-in-data-science-consulting.html</guid></item><item><title>Reproducibility in ML Systems: A Netflix Original</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/reproducibility-in-ml-systems-a-netflix-original.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we focus on the importance and benefits of effortless reproducibility as a first-class construct in machine learning infrastructure. From practices around capturing inputs and outputs to code versioning and transitive dependency management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ferras Hamad</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/reproducibility-in-ml-systems-a-netflix-original.html</guid></item><item><title>Should I develop my own DS library? Maybe.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/should-i-develop-my-own-ds-library-maybe.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever entertained the idea of developing your own library for data science related tasks to be used among your team or organization? If so, phrases like 'don't recreate the wheel' also probably came to mind. This talk will address compelling arguments on both sides of the topic while telling the story of why we at Aetna ultimately decided to do just that and what we learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piero Ferrante</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/should-i-develop-my-own-ds-library-maybe.html</guid></item><item><title>Sloth &amp; ENVy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/sloth-envy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;'Don't show up to this talk, it's going to be stupid. You won't learn anything, and if you do learn something, I promise it will be dumb.' - Diego Torres Quintanilla, PyData NYC Executive Chair&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Powell</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/sloth-envy.html</guid></item><item><title>Stars, Planets, and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/stars-planets-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For thousands of years people have wondered, “Are there planets like Earth?” “Are such planets common?” “Do any have signs of life?” Today astronomers are poised to answer these ancient questions, having recently found thousands of planets that orbit nearby Sun-like stars, called “exoplanets”. Professor Sara Seager, one of the world’s leading experts on this search for Earth-like planets, will share the latest advances in this revolutionary field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sara Seager</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/stars-planets-and-python.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>tf-explain: Interpretability for Tensorflow 2.0</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/tf-explain-interpretability-for-tensorflow-20.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep learning models now emerge in multiple domains. The question data scientists and users always ask is 'Why does it work?'. Explaining decisions from neural networks is vital for model improvements and analysis, and users' adoption. In this talk, I will explain interpretability methods implementations with TF2.0 and introduce tf-explain, a TF2.0 library for interpretability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raphaël Meudec</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/tf-explain-interpretability-for-tensorflow-20.html</guid></item><item><title>The Echo-Chamber of Your Social Media Feed</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-echo-chamber-of-your-social-media-feed.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data algorithms that anticipate what users want to see create an echo chamber of articles expressing a singular opinion. Journalist are inclined to use strong rhetoric that will be consistently favored by these ML programs and at the expense of complexity. This filtering process has bolstered polarized politics, especially on college campuses where more students turn to social media for news.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tamar Yastrab</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-echo-chamber-of-your-social-media-feed.html</guid></item><item><title>The Inspection Paradox is Everywhere</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-inspection-paradox-is-everywhere.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inspection paradox is a statistical illusion you’ve probably never heard of. It’s a common source of confusion, an occasional cause of error, and an opportunity for clever experimental design. And once you know about it, you see it everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Allen Downey</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-inspection-paradox-is-everywhere.html</guid></item><item><title>The Secret Life of Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-secret-life-of-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3.8 includes new features for security engineers to allow greater insight and awareness when your network is under attack (which is every day). This session will investigate the need for these hooks and how they are used to protect your production servers and your users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steve Dower</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-secret-life-of-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Type-Driven Automated Learning with Lale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/type-driven-automated-learning-with-lale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents Lale, an open-source Python library for semi-automated data science. Lale is compatible with scikit-learn, adding a simple interface to existing machine-learning automation tools. Lale lets you search over possible pipelines in just a few lines of code while remaining in control of your work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martin Hirzel</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/type-driven-automated-learning-with-lale.html</guid></item><item><title>A Crash Course in Applied Linear Algebra</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-crash-course-in-applied-linear-algebra.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people think of Linear Algebra as intimidating, difficult, and great for ending conversations at parties. The truth is that Linear Algebra is extraordinarily useful, often unreasonably so. By studying one equation, y = Ax, you will add an arsenal of tools and intuition to your skillset that can be applied in any technical situation (even nonlinear ones).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Landreman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-crash-course-in-applied-linear-algebra.html</guid></item><item><title>A Few Good Public Servants: How Great Analysis Inspires Action</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-few-good-public-servants-how-great-analysis-inspires-action.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is it like to work in public service? Hear stories from the halls of the Obama White House to New York City Hall of how data and analytics have transformed government in the past decade. From your hometown Mayor's Office of Data Analytics to data teams across the country, learn how a growing number of public servants are using data to ignite change in public policy and operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kelly Jin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-few-good-public-servants-how-great-analysis-inspires-action.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>A Primer on Gaussian Processes for Regression Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-primer-on-gaussian-processes-for-regression-analysis.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Fonnesbeck</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/a-primer-on-gaussian-processes-for-regression-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian Inference for Fun and Profit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/bayesian-inference-for-fun-and-profit.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mitzi Morris</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/bayesian-inference-for-fun-and-profit.html</guid></item><item><title>Bringing mental health data to doctors</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/bringing-mental-health-data-to-doctors.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an edge to gain from the vast amounts of data in Healthcare. It’s now possible to continuously monitor patients’ health, but where to begin? What data is useful to a doctor who is not trained in mental health care? How do you make findings actionable? In this session, you’ll hear about lessons learned in starting, scaling, &amp;amp; optimizing data science initiatives at a growing tech company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Lynch</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/bringing-mental-health-data-to-doctors.html</guid></item><item><title>Build an AI-powered Pet Detector in Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/build-an-ai-powered-pet-detector-in-visual-studio-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered what breed that dog or cat is? Let’s build a pet detector service to recognize them in pictures!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Kampf</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/build-an-ai-powered-pet-detector-in-visual-studio-code.html</guid></item><item><title>Cleaning, optimizing and windowing pandas with numba</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/cleaning-optimizing-and-windowing-pandas-with-numba.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has accrued a sizable debt in flexibility and maintainability to deliver excellent performance. This talk will show how Pandas maintainers and Two Sigma are using Numba to pay off some of this debt in one of the gnarliest parts of the code: window operations. If merged to mainstream Pandas, this work will deduplicate code, make it easier to debug and make window operations extensible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Diego Torres Quintanilla</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/cleaning-optimizing-and-windowing-pandas-with-numba.html</guid></item><item><title>Conda-press, or Reinventing the Wheel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/conda-press-or-reinventing-the-wheel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conda-press (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/regro/conda-press"&gt;https://github.com/regro/conda-press&lt;/a&gt;) is a new tool that lets you transform conda packages into Python wheels. This talk will: discuss why in the world you would want to do such a terrible thing, demonstrate that you can do such a terrible thing (live!), dive-in to how such as terrible thing is done, and define some safety precautions when doing such a terrible things&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anthony Scopatz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/conda-press-or-reinventing-the-wheel.html</guid></item><item><title>Effective Python and R collaboration</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/effective-python-and-r-collaboration.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and R are extremely powerful by itself, long are the days where there was a library or tool in one language that doesn't have a decent alternative in the other and new initiatives such as Apache Arrow are shaping a great future of collaboration between multiple languages. We will explore how will the future looks for multilingual data science teams in the open-source and in the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Rodriguez</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/effective-python-and-r-collaboration.html</guid></item><item><title>From Raw Recruit Scripts to Perfect Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/from-raw-recruit-scripts-to-perfect-python.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stanley van der Merwe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/from-raw-recruit-scripts-to-perfect-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Generating realistic, differentially private data sets using GANs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/generating-realistic-differentially-private-data-sets-using-gans.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The value of individual-level data for research must be balanced against the privacy concerns of individuals. I discuss an approach for generating synthetic data sets that preserve relevant statistical properties of input data while also providing privacy guarantees for individuals in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joshua Falk</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/generating-realistic-differentially-private-data-sets-using-gans.html</guid></item><item><title>Geo Experiments and Causal Impact in Incrementality Testing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/geo-experiments-and-causal-impact-in-incrementality-testing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can we find the incremental number of conversions driven by a new marketing campaign? This presentation will cover how we used geo experiments and CausalImpact to answer this question at HelloFresh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Tyler</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/geo-experiments-and-causal-impact-in-incrementality-testing.html</guid></item><item><title>Hacking the Data Science Challenge</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/hacking-the-data-science-challenge.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michoel Snow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/hacking-the-data-science-challenge.html</guid></item><item><title>Is Spark still relevant? Multi-node CPU and single-node GPU workloads with Spark, Dask and RAPIDS.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/is-spark-still-relevant-multi-node-cpu-and-single-node-gpu-workloads-with-spark-dask-and-rapids.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We compare Dask, Spark, and RAPIDS in a typical business workload: dataset exploration, model building, prediction and dashboarding / reporting. Of specific interest are infrastructure, ease of use and some general musings on the practicality of these compute frameworks. This talk will specifically address the relevance of these systems to the unique brand of problems we face in modern businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Dill</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/is-spark-still-relevant-multi-node-cpu-and-single-node-gpu-workloads-with-spark-dask-and-rapids.html</guid></item><item><title>Launching a new warehouse with SimPy at Rent the Runway</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/launching-a-new-warehouse-with-simpy-at-rent-the-runway.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opening a warehouse is a long and challenging process, not to mention costly. So if you're going to go through all that work to open and operate a warehouse, you'll want to make sure you can run it as efficiently as possible. Enter SimPy (rhymes with 'Blimpie'). SimPy is a discrete event simulator software library that allows us to asynchronously schedule and process events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meghan Heintz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/launching-a-new-warehouse-with-simpy-at-rent-the-runway.html</guid></item><item><title>Managing Stakeholders: The Key to Successful Data Science for Business</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/managing-stakeholders-the-key-to-successful-data-science-for-business.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A successful data science project is one that results in implementation, e.g., putting a model into production or using the result to support an organizational change. But implementation is only partially a technical problem. Successful implementation depends on people. This talk will cover multi-level stakeholder analysis, and techniques for engagement from project scoping to delivery of results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauren Oldja</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/managing-stakeholders-the-key-to-successful-data-science-for-business.html</guid></item><item><title>Neural Networks for Natural Language Processing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/neural-networks-for-natural-language-processing.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matti Lyra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/neural-networks-for-natural-language-processing.html</guid></item><item><title>New Trends in Estimation and Inference</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/new-trends-in-estimation-and-inference.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cameron Davidson-Pilon</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/new-trends-in-estimation-and-inference.html</guid></item><item><title>Pandas vs Koalas: The Ultimate Showdown!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/pandas-vs-koalas-the-ultimate-showdown.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, we won’t be debating which animal is more adorable but we will be discussing the difference between doing data science locally vs doing data science at scale. Most Data Scientist are aware of working with Python and Pandas but you can only work with small amounts of data. With Koalas, Data Scientist can use all the same API's they are familiar with from Panadas but at scale with PySpark.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amanda Moran</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/pandas-vs-koalas-the-ultimate-showdown.html</guid></item><item><title>Propensity Score Matching: A Non-experimental Approach to Causal Inference</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/propensity-score-matching-a-non-experimental-approach-to-causal-inference.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Propensity score matching provides an alternative framework for causal inference when random assignment is not possible. The technique draws on core data science skills of predictive model building and algorithm development. Data scientists who need alternatives to experiments will find this a useful and accessible addition to their methodological toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Johns</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/propensity-score-matching-a-non-experimental-approach-to-causal-inference.html</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying uncertainty in machine learning models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/quantifying-uncertainty-in-machine-learning-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many models give a lot more information during the inference process that we usually know. We will begin with an intrinsic estimation of all the distribution with random forest algorithm. Then we will extend those 'prediction intervals' to almost every regression models thanks to the quantile loss. Eventually we will discuss about probability calibration to measure uncertainty in classification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samuel Rochette</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/quantifying-uncertainty-in-machine-learning-models.html</guid></item><item><title>Role playing Annotation workshop</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/role-playing-annotation-workshop.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sumowska</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/role-playing-annotation-workshop.html</guid></item><item><title>Same API, Different Execution</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/same-api-different-execution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can the Python data science and scientific computing ecoystem remain in the hands of community open source projects? Or will increasingly complex performance and hardware requirements leave room only for vertically integrated corporate sponsored projects?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saul Shanabrook</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/same-api-different-execution.html</guid></item><item><title>Scalable Machine Learning with Dask</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/scalable-machine-learning-with-dask.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has a great ecosystem for machine learning, especially on relatively small datasets processed on a single machine. We'll use Dask to scale libraries like NumPy, pandas, and scikit-learn to larger datasets and larger problems. We'll see that problems can be compute- or memory-bound (or both). We'll see strategies for dealing with these, using a cluster to parallelize our computation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Augspurger</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/scalable-machine-learning-with-dask.html</guid></item><item><title>Semantic modeling of data science code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/semantic-modeling-of-data-science-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programming languages and libraries are proliferating in the data science community. In an effort to reduce communication barriers and enable automation and intelligent tooling, we are developing software to automatically construct language-agnostic semantic models of data science code written in Python or R. In this talk, we introduce our methods and illustrate them by example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Evan Patterson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/semantic-modeling-of-data-science-code.html</guid></item><item><title>Simplified Data Quality Monitoring of Dynamic Longitudinal Data: A Functional Programming Approach</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/simplified-data-quality-monitoring-of-dynamic-longitudinal-data-a-functional-programming-approach.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data scientists are often tasked with being the first to detect issues of data quality that may have serious consequences for downstream consumers of their data. We will demonstrate how to simplify data quality monitoring through a functional programming approach that empowers the 5 key pillars of a user-friendly workflow: readability, compositionality, reproducibility, efficiency, and robustness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacqueline Gutman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/simplified-data-quality-monitoring-of-dynamic-longitudinal-data-a-functional-programming-approach.html</guid></item><item><title>Small Big Data: using NumPy and Pandas when your data doesn't fit in memory</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/small-big-data-using-numpy-and-pandas-when-your-data-doesnt-fit-in-memory.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your data is too big to fit in memory—loading it crashes your program—but it's also too small for a complex Big Data cluster. How to process your data simply and quickly?  In this talk you'll learn the basic techniques for dealing with Small Big Data: money, compression, batching and parallelization, and indexing. In particular, you'll learn how to apply these techniques to NumPy and Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Itamar Turner-Trauring</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/small-big-data-using-numpy-and-pandas-when-your-data-doesnt-fit-in-memory.html</guid></item><item><title>Spark Backend for Ibis: Seamless Transition Between Pandas and Spark</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/spark-backend-for-ibis-seamless-transition-between-pandas-and-spark.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ibis a library that provides unified pandas-like API on top of both single-node local execution (e.g. pandas) and multi-node remote execution (e.g. BigQuery, Impala). In this talk, we will introduce a new backend for executing Ibis programs on Spark and show how you can write analytics that run on both Spark and pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Li Jin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/spark-backend-for-ibis-seamless-transition-between-pandas-and-spark.html</guid></item><item><title>The physics of deep learning using tensor networks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-physics-of-deep-learning-using-tensor-networks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tensor networks have been used in Physics to find efficient expressions of many-body quantum systems, describing systems from materials to holographic spacetime. As it happens, one can also use tensor networks in machine learning. Exploring the equivalence between these two affords us intuition on inductive bias, which is the set of assumptions that determine our choice of machine learning model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marianne Hoogeveen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-physics-of-deep-learning-using-tensor-networks.html</guid></item><item><title>Time series for scikit-learn people</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/time-series-for-scikit-learn-people.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will frame the topic of time series forecasting in the language of machine learning. This framing will be used to introduce the skits library which provides a scikit-learn-compatible API for fitting and forecasting time series models using supervised machine learning. Finally, a real-world deployment of skits involving thousands of forecasts per hour will be demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ethan Rosenthal</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/time-series-for-scikit-learn-people.html</guid></item><item><title>To comment or not</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/to-comment-or-not.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every programmer has asked themselves “how many comments are too many?” To the newest programmers, comments may seem magical–a way of documenting without giving instructions to the computer. But commenting engages the same vulnerability as more advanced challenges (i.e. pair programming &amp;amp; code review) and is likely to pique the insecurity of many programmers (especially the copy-and-paste or tutorial-level programmer)!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Veronica Hanus</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/to-comment-or-not.html</guid></item><item><title>Using Graph Nets (GNs) to predict molecular properties</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/using-graph-nets-gns-to-predict-molecular-properties.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will be showing how Graph Nets (GNs)—a set of statistical models that directly operate on molecular topology by updating and aggregating information between atoms and bonds—can approximate per-atom, per-bond, and per-molecule properties derived by quantum mechanics (QM), with errors within the uncertainty thereof, and an over-500-fold speed up&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chaya D Stern</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/using-graph-nets-gns-to-predict-molecular-properties.html</guid></item><item><title>What we learned by running a large custom Bayesian forecasting model in production</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/what-we-learned-by-running-a-large-custom-bayesian-forecasting-model-in-production.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Kolonial.no we built and implemented our own custom Bayesian forecasting model in PyMC3 - and learned a lot in the process. In this talk, we share our thoughts on when to do what we did, and more important, when not to do it. We also share how we stumbled into numerous pitfalls on the way but managed to climb out again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jens Fredrik Skogstrom</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/what-we-learned-by-running-a-large-custom-bayesian-forecasting-model-in-production.html</guid></item><item><title>Working with Maps: Extracting Features for Traffic Crash Insights</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/working-with-maps-extracting-features-for-traffic-crash-insights.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to work with maps, but didn't know where to start? This talk will focus on feature engineering for a real-world project: pulling maps from OpenStreetMap, creating road segments, and adding features from other data sources. The features are used by Insight Lane, building tools for traffic departments and advocacy groups to better understand traffic crash risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jenny Turner-Trauring: Working with Maps</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/working-with-maps-extracting-features-for-traffic-crash-insights.html</guid></item><item><title>Zarr vs. HDF5</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/zarr-vs-hdf5.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zarr and HDF5 are libraries and data formats for storing chunked, compressed N-dimensional data. This talk will give a brief introduction to the their shared functionality, but then focus on the their differences. This talk cover how show how each library handles compression, data storage, and extension points. This talk should help the audience choose the correct tool for their problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joe Jevnik</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/zarr-vs-hdf5.html</guid></item></channel></rss>