<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Documentation at Scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2014/documentation-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information is powerful — every day we see it transform the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation doesn't always have to be about a software workflow or open source project — it can be used to develop and convey ideas much larger than yourself. Information architecture is a powerful tool for developing ideas over time. It enables us to evolve and distill information at a much larger scale than a single person or team could ever achieve on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take these concepts, and apply open source workflow tools like GitHub's Pull Requests and Write the Docs, and the distributed evolution of ideas and information has never been more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll explore these concepts, learn how to foster a community of distributed contributors, encourage contributions early on, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python-Guide.org will be used as an example, a Python-specific knowledge base written by 168 people and accessed by over 50,000 people every month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kenneth Reitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-05:write-the-docs-2014/documentation-at-scale.html</guid><category>documentation</category></item><item><title>Documenting Domain Specific Knowledge</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2014/documenting-domain-specific-knowledge.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of my career as a software engineer, I've written documentation for very general purpose tools, where users' had an existing familiarity. For the last six months I've been working on a cryptography library, a domain most developers are ignorant of. We set out with the goal of making our documentation accessible to any developer, regardless of previous cryptographic experience, which presents unique challenges. This talk will dive into what these challenges are, and how we try to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Gaynor</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-05:write-the-docs-2014/documenting-domain-specific-knowledge.html</guid><category>documentation</category></item></channel></rss>