<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-apac-2015.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>R0 DAY03-03 Kernel-mapper (Tool to simplify the use of PyOpenCL) - Kilik Kuo (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day03-03-kernel-mapper-tool-to-simplify-the-use.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kilik Kuo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-27:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day03-03-kernel-mapper-tool-to-simplify-the-use.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Kilik Kuo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to provide a simpler way for people to utilize GPU power via PyOpenCL.
Also provide a more clearer line to separate tasks easily for people we're good at OpenCL kernel programming &amp;amp; python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABOUT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience with Python for 5+ years.
Being fascinated by the coding style and simplicity of expression, and the people who use it !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current job - Software engineer in Mozilla Taiwan, worked on FxOS.
Previous job - Associate principal engineer in CyberLink, Windows / Mac desktop application&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/kilik.kuo"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/kilik.kuo&lt;/a&gt;
組織/公司 Mozilla Taiwan
頭銜 Software Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/48"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY03-K2 Andy Terrel (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day03-k2-andy-terrel-pycon-apac-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andy Terrel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-27:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day03-k2-andy-terrel-pycon-apac-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Andy Terrel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy is a computational scientist with experience implementing distributed, large data applications. In his research, he is known for creating novel algorithms to speed implementations of mathematical models on the world's largest supercomputers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy received his Computer Science PhD at the University of Chicago in 2010. He has held research positions at Argonne National Lab, Sandia National Lab, Institute of Computational Engineering and Sciences at The University of Texas-Austin, and the Texas Advanced Computing Center. In industry, Andy served as lead developer at Kove, Inc. during its early stages, where he helped bring a record-breaking SAN disk array to market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy is a passionate advocate for open source scientific codes. To this end, he is a board member of the NumFOCUS foundation and has been involved in the wider scientific Python community since 2006. Andy has contributed to numerous projects in the scientific stack and helps push for data to become a first class object for scientists worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Marsface Project: Detecting Pseudo-artificial Structures ... - Hideki Tanaka (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/marsface-project-detecting-pseudo-artificial-pycon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hideki Tanaka</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/marsface-project-detecting-pseudo-artificial-pycon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;R2 DAY2-04 Marsface Project: Detecting Pseudo-artificial Structures on Mars
Speaker: Hideki Tanaka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery of &amp;quot;Face on Mars&amp;quot; by NASA in 1976 has attracted widespread popular and scientific interest over the past few decades. In this project, we apply various object detection techniques, such as conventional haar-like feature based methods and state-of-the-art deep learning methods, in order to detect such pseudo-artificial structures on Mars and other planets. The scientific Python ecosystem plays a crucial role in the exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hideki Tanaka is a PyData.Tokyo organizer, optical design engineer, photographer based in Tokyo. He is a machine learning and deep learning enthusiast who is addicted to data science competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/HidekiPhoto"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/HidekiPhoto&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;atelierhide
組織/公司 PyData.Tokyo
頭銜 Organizer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/71"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/71&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Orchestrating the execution of workflows for media streaming ... - Shuen-Huei Guan (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/orchestrating-the-execution-of-workflows-for-media.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shuen-Huei Guan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/orchestrating-the-execution-of-workflows-for-media.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orchestrating the execution of workflows for media streaming service and even more
Speaker: Shuen-Huei Guan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of advantages about cloud computing is potentially huge-scale resources for your task. And it's especially beneficial to data driven process with heavy computing. In this talk, the idea of job script to orchestrate the execution of workflows across multiple computing nodes is introduced. An implementation based on AWS SWF (Simple Workflow) is described with examples of processing for music streaming and video streaming in KKBOX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shuen-Huei Guan, or just Drake, started his career as a technical director and, then, R&amp;amp;D manager in animation industry for 9 years with Hollywood experts and ingenious artists. What he has been playing with are Pixar's RenderMan, stereoscopic vision, or even other computer graphics research papers. The only common thing within is Python, which he uses to build prototype or even final product. And then, he brought what cultivated from that visual industry into music industry, KKBOX. But, this time, the challenges come from video streaming service. Quite dramatic, right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://about.me/drakeguan"&gt;http://about.me/drakeguan&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;drakeguan
組織/公司 KKBOX
頭銜 Sr. Principal Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/92"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 D2-03 Easy contributable i18n process with Sphinx - Takayuki Shimizukawa (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-d2-03-easy-contributable-i18n-process-with-apac.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Takayuki Shimizukawa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-d2-03-easy-contributable-i18n-process-with-apac.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Takayuki Shimizukawa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sphinx can extract paragraphs from sphinx document and store them into gettext format translation catalog files.
Gettext format translation catalog is easy to translate from one language to other languages.
Also Sphinx support internationalization by using such catalog files.
You can use your favolite editors or services to translate your sphinx docs.
In this session, I'll explain 3 things; (1) entier process to translate sphinx docs. (2) automation mechanism for the process. (3) tips, tricks and traps for wrinting docs and translating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sphinx co-maintainer since 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Let's start Sphinx&amp;quot; Japanese ebook author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sphinx-users.jp account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon JP organizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://about.me/shimizukawa"&gt;http://about.me/shimizukawa&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;shimizukawa
組織/公司 BePROUD corp / PyCon JP / Sphinx-usres.jp
頭銜 Python developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/50"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-01 Openstack Swift Benchmark with Ansible - Charles Hsu (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-01-openstack-swift-benchmark-with-ansible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Charles Hsu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-01-openstack-swift-benchmark-with-ansible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Charles Hsu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Using Ansible for OpenStack Swift benchmark&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline is here, may be modified in a future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduct Openstack Swift&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single Node Swift (SAIO Swift) (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/swift/development_saio.html"&gt;http://docs.openstack.org/developer/swift/development_saio.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swift Cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce Ansible&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other tools (Fabric/Slatstack/Chef)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's problems and pains&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure multiple swift nodes (swift proxy/object/container servers) without extra packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy/manage multiple benchmark nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweep all data in Swift nodes (Dev Cluster)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a benchmark test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting benchmark result from benchmark nodes and errors from swift nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat it again, again and again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Ansible&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define a cluster and nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy benchmark nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting and aggregate result form benchmark node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's next?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move it to Docker?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;thecharz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;組織/公司 SwiftStack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;頭銜 Techical Support Enginner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/12"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ansible"></category><category term="openStack"></category><category term="swift"></category></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-02 Python Debugger Uncovered - Dmitry Trofimov (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-02-python-debugger-uncovered-dmitry-pycon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dmitry Trofimov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-02-python-debugger-uncovered-dmitry-pycon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dmitry Trofimov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain how to implement a debugger for Python. We'll start with simple command line debugger, then look how it is implemented in modern IDEs like PyCharm and Pydev. Then we go further in the details and uncover the tricks used to implement some interesting features like multiprocess debugging, debugging of Django and Jinja2 templates and attaching to a launched Python process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on PyCharm project I put my efforts into making development in Python even more pleasurable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;DmitryTrofimov
組織/公司 JetBrains
頭銜 PyCharm Team Lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/39"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/39&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-03 Programmatic Debugging with GDB and Python - Scott Tsai (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-03-programmatic-debugging-with-gdb-and.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Scott Tsai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-03-programmatic-debugging-with-gdb-and.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Scott Tsai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target Audience: Developers that use both C/C++ and Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is the scripting language of choice for GDB but debugger scripting and programmatic debugging is underutilized in general because not enough developers are both GDB power users and familiar with Python. This talk aims to remedy that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Device driver, firmware, system software developer. Open source contributor, Linux enthusiast. Worked in several Taiwanese consumer electronics companies, a big multinational corporation and a Silicon Valley startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scottt.tw/"&gt;http://scottt.tw/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;scottttw
組織/公司 Awit Systems
頭銜 Software Developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/104"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/104&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-04 The Future of GUI Programming with Python - Tzu-ping Chung (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-04-the-future-of-gui-programming-with-tzu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tzu-ping Chung</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-04-the-future-of-gui-programming-with-tzu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tzu-ping Chung&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a great programming language suitable for a wide variety of purposes. Among all these exciting things, however, there is one area with which Python is not great: GUI applications. In this talk, we will first take a look at existed solutions for GUI programming in Python, comparing their characteristics and features. We will then discuss how GUI programming with Python should be done in an ideal world, and what can be done (or is being done) to take us one step closer to our ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://uranusjr.com/"&gt;https://uranusjr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;uranusjr
組織/公司 BIMEtek Co. Ltd.
頭銜 Software Architect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/18"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-05 RPyScan - Melvin Foo, Hannie Ching, Tan Le Xuan (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-05-rpyscan-melvin-foo-hannie-ching-tan-le.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Melvin Foo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-05-rpyscan-melvin-foo-hannie-ching-tan-le.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Melvin Foo, Hannie Ching, Tan Le Xuan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of low cost 3D printers, there is an increasing demand for 3D technology in many diverse fields. However, 3D printing requires a 3D model as input, usually modeled in a computer. But why should we tediously create a model from scratch, when we can simply scan the objects and modify them? In this project, we present RPyScan, an effective and low cost DIY 3D scanner which makes use of photogrammetry to infer depth information from photos. With enough points, this will create a 3D model of the scanned object. This is in contrast to most 3D scanners on the market, which makes use of RGBD (Depth) and lasers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About Melvin, Le Xuan and Hannie
We are students from Dunman High School, Singapore. We have learnt Python for the past few months to one plus year since we studied Computing as an A-level subject. We learnt about the theoretical and algorithmic aspects of computer science (e.g. data structures and searching) and applied this knowledge to practical (Google App Engine) Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melvin is really enthusiastic and passionate about everything related to technology. He loves software and hardware equally. He is currently the chairperson of his school's Infocomm Club and has attained many national and international accolades such as Singapore Management University's InnovateIT and Information Technology Standards Committee's CodeXtremeApps hackathon school category, where he dabbled in home automation and created Internet-connected chairs and cookers prototypes. He also represented Singapore in the APICTA (Asia Pacific ICT Alliance) Awards and was pivotal in encouraging his school mates to contribute towards open source projects where Dunman High was recognized as the top participating school in Google Code-in 2014. He was also the youngest high school presenter at PyCon SG 2014. When he is not studying, you can find him in his home 'lab' working on his IoT projects. In his free time, he plays video games and fantasizes about owning an Occulus Rift, and also coaches badminton to young kids.  You can learn more about him on his website www.melvinfoo.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Xuan is a budding Computing student who is ever excited to learn more about technology. Though he is relatively new in this area, his huge fascination with gadgets and devices motivates him to consistently find out more about how they work. He frequently creates various kinds of programs as part of this hobby, and can sometimes be found tinkering with pieces of machinery, thinking about how they might be improved. As part of his school curriculum, he has created a web application in celebration of Singapore’s 50th birthday (SG50) using Google App Engine and Python, took part in Google Code-in 2014 and the 2015 IDA National JC Coding Championship, and attended a number of related seminars and talks. He is interested in delving deeper into the areas of virtual reality and artificial intelligence. Besides Computing, he plays the piano and the French horn, enjoys playing video games for leisure, and recently picked up sports to be more active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hannie shows a strong interest in both hardware and software. She has a strong determination to learn new things and is not afraid of hard work. In the short few months since she started learning Computing, she created a web application using Python for SG50 and has participated in events such as Google Code-in 2014 and the 2015 National JC and HS Coding Championships. She actively engages herself in infocomm programmes such as an SMU Panel Discussion on “Creating the Future through Computing” and “The Science Behind Thoughts” conducted by A Star Research Institute of High Performance Computing (IHPC). In the foreseeable future, she hopes to explore emerging technologies such as projected keyboards. Besides Computer Science, she has a passion for classical music and plays the Piano, Violin and Viola. She also enjoys sports such as Volleyball and Archery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.melvinfoo.com/"&gt;http://www.melvinfoo.com/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;MEOWEENFUU
組織/公司 Dunman High School
頭銜 Student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/56"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-06 MMO Game Server Design with Twisted Python - Dan Maas (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-06-mmo-game-server-design-with-twisted-dan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dan Maas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-06-mmo-game-server-design-with-twisted-dan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dan Maas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Python server drives top MMO strategy games like &amp;quot;Thunder Run: War of Clans&amp;quot;, with 4 million accounts and over 1,000 concurrent logins. This talk will explain the basic architecture of our server-side software, with special focus on how we use the open-source Twisted library to write high-performance, low-latency network code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我會講中文，希望可以用中文發表此演講&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan Maas leads software architecture as CTO of SpinPunch, a Y Combinator startup developing the world's most advanced HTML5 game engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, Dan created Emmy Award-winning computer animation for Disney, National Geographic, PBS, and the BBC. His novel 3D graphics pipeline was recognized by NASA/JPL and Pixar for creating spectacular space mission visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dcine.com/"&gt;http://www.dcine.com/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;mbagamer
組織/公司 Maas Digital / SpinPunch
頭銜 CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/25"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-K1 Ecosystem Threats to Python - Van Lindberg (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-k1-ecosystem-threats-to-python-van-pycon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Van Lindberg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-k1-ecosystem-threats-to-python-van-pycon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Van Lindberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Lindberg has worked professionally as an engineer, as a lawyer, and as an executive. He currently has a dual legal/technical role at Rackspace, and has worked out of both the legal department and the Office of the CTO. In April 2012, the American Bar Association Journal named Van as one of &amp;quot;America's Top 12 Techiest Attorneys.&amp;quot; He has been involved with open source since 1994, when a friend introduced him to Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the legal side, Van leads Rackspace's Intellectual Property program, directing Rackspace's strategy and policy around patent, copyright, trademark, trade secret, and open source matters. Van also heads Rackspace's lobbying efforts relative to patent reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, Van runs Rackspace's technical leadership corps, known internally as the &amp;quot;TCT.&amp;quot; Van also works in technical strategy and ecosystem engagement at Rackspace, identifying emerging technologies, separating out differentiating versus non-differentiating product elements, and using open source strategies to be more competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, Van worked at the law firm of Haynes and Boone, where he wrote &amp;quot;Intellectual Property and Open Source,&amp;quot; published by O'Reilly and Associates, and grew an open source practice helping businesses with everything from open source compliance to business strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Van's open source practice, he did IP transactional work, patent prosecution, litigation, and post-grant actions (ex parte and inter partes reexams/reviews).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van currently serves as chairman of the board of the Python Software Foundation, on the board of the OpenStack Foundation, and as the chair of the Docker Governance Advisory Board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY1-K2 Kenneth Reitz (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-k2-kenneth-reitz-pycon-apac-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kenneth Reitz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day1-k2-kenneth-reitz-pycon-apac-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Kenneth Reitz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Reitz is a versatile talent computer genius. Kenneth has a well-understood on Photography and has released many masterpieces on famous photo sharing platforms such as flickr and 500px. But most important, Kenneth is a grand Open Source software contributors who invents and leads many popular github projects. The most widely used one is Requests, a revolutionary package that allows tens of thousands Python Web Developers to develop Web services with human-friendly syntax instead of using the tedious , trivial urllib which Python standard library provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite Kenneth has a groundbreaking stride in Python Web Development, he is always a kind Python mentor for novice and expert Python developers. Under Kenneth's lead, the Github project &amp;quot;python-guide&amp;quot; has abundant resources helping many beginners to break the programming ice. On the other side, for the experts, Kenneth has established many great practices for writing good code, including project structuring, coding style, documentation and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth embraces the elegant Architectures and APIs. Hence, Kenneth founded KennethReitz.com to provide Architecture solutions for numerous enterprises. In 2011, Kenneth joined the Heroku team for developing the best Python offering and playing a Heroku's voice in Python Community. Also, Kenneth is one of the fellows in Python Software Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2-01 利用 IPython Notebook 來互動簡報與教學 - Tzer-jen Wei (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-01-li-yong-ipython-notebook-lai-hu-dong-yu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tzer-jen Wei</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-01-li-yong-ipython-notebook-lai-hu-dong-yu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tzer-jen Wei&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;介紹利用 IPython notebook 來讓簡報更加有互動性的經驗。讓 Demo 與剪報流程合而為一，利用 IPython notebook 的互動特性，即時的讓內容呈現，每一次都能呈現最新的資訊。
用 Python code 取代 Pseudo Code 將實際的執行結果視覺化逐步呈現，而不是事先弄好畫好的模擬結果。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://about.me/weijr"&gt;http://about.me/weijr&lt;/a&gt;
組織/公司 NDHU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/42"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/42&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2-02 Building a Scalable Python gRPC Service using Kubernetes - Ian Lewis (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-02-building-a-scalable-python-grpc-service.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Lewis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-02-building-a-scalable-python-grpc-service.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ian Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gRPC and Kubernetes are two new technologies that make it easy to manage robust, highly available web services that talk to each other using a fast, flexible protocol. Python is well suited to building the logic for these kind of services. Python is a flexible language that can be highly efficient when tuned properly and allows you to make use of the extensive set of Python libraries that are publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will talk about how to combine these technologies and use Python to create a scalable gRPC service and then how to actually manage and scale it using the Kubernetes cluster manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian Lewis is a Developer Advocate working at Google on the Google Cloud Platform Team in Tokyo Japan. He is an long time Python user and enthusiast. He developed the IT events service connpass.com using Python and Django, and continues to promote Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian is a founder, and Vice Chair of the Board, for the PyCon JP management team. Ian helps with managing the website, and media relations (Twitter, Facebook, online magazine articles, etc.) for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ianlewis.org/"&gt;http://www.ianlewis.org/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;IanMLewis
組織/公司 Google Inc.
頭銜 Developer Advocate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/65"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/65&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2-04 How developers are building applications on the cloud - Ben Cheng (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-04-how-developers-are-building-on-the-ben.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Cheng</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-04-how-developers-are-building-on-the-ben.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ben Cheng&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before SoftLayer was a cloud service provider, it was a group of keen developers. One day our developers set out to create the modular, scalable infrastructure services they wanted in order to develop the cloud solution of their dreams. So SoftLayer started with an API that provides precision control and now is constantly working at finding ways to put more tools at developers’ fingertips. Join us in this session as Angus Ip takes the audience though SoftLayer’s journey and its developer profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Cheng, will join the session and talk about how Oursky is building its application on the cloud.  He will also give you advice on how to build an effective cloud backend for your application development and implementations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer workshop on June 7 morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SoftLayer Experts (TBA)
組織/公司 IBM SoftLayer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/111"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/111&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2 Bingo Game (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-bingo-game-pycon-apac-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-bingo-game-pycon-apac-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python, Redis, Pubsub.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/schedule/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2-K1 Static typing in Python? - Robert Bradshaw (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-k1-static-typing-in-python-robert-bradshaw.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Bradshaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-k1-static-typing-in-python-robert-bradshaw.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Robert Bradshaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Bradshaw is a software engineer at Google, working on tools for doing petabyte-scale data processing. He is also active in the open source community, leading the Cython project since it's inception and as a long-time contributor to the open source mathematics software Sage. He received a B.S. in Mathematics and Linguistics from Brigham Young University and a Ph.D. in Mathematics from University of Washington with William Stein studying questions related to the Birch and Swinnerton-Dyer conjecture. Robert currently resides in Seattle, Washington with his wife Camille and their two sets of young twins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2-K2 Arnaud Bergeron (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-k2-arnaud-bergeron-pycon-apac-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Arnaud Bergeron</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-k2-arnaud-bergeron-pycon-apac-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Arnaud Bergeron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnaud is a long-time supporter of open-source who started with a modest patch to OpenBSD about keyboard encodings many years ago. He worked on Sage for a bit as well as submitting various small patches to a number of projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While doing some machine learning work for his masters he enjoyed working with GPUs so much that he switched his thesis to focus on using GPUs for computations. Soon after he finished his masters, he ended up working as one of the core developers on Theano dealing mostly with improving and expanding the current GPU support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2 閃電秀 Lightning Talk (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-shan-dian-xiu-lighting-talk-pycon-apac.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-shan-dian-xiu-lighting-talk-pycon-apac.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/schedule/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY3-01 Python HDF5 Use Case - Liang Bo Wang (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day3-01-python-hdf5-use-case-liang-bo-wang-apac.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liang Bo Wang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day3-01-python-hdf5-use-case-liang-bo-wang-apac.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Liang Bo Wang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDF5 是一個用來存取數據的函式庫，Matlab 的儲存格式 (.mat) 即基於該格式設計。相較於多數人熟悉的 Database，HDF5 的功能更為單純，它只負責做好讀取、 儲存資料而並不提供 Query、Join 等操作，但也因此在 I/O 表現上更為出色。常見的應用為 sensor、實驗數據記錄與傳輸、大矩陣的操作等。HDF5 在 Python 的接口實作主要有 PyTables 及 h5py，兩者針對不同的使用情境有不同的設計。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在本 talk 中，會先介紹 HDF5 格式與特色，在 Python 中如何用 PyTables、h5py 存取 與異同，以及與主流資料庫、pickle 物件串流化的比較。最後示範 HDF5 如何有效的完成 以下幾個情境中的問題：存取 pandas DataFrame 物件、在大型矩陣進行區域計算、追蹤 Deep Learning 學習記錄。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A master student active in Taipei Python and R meetups. His research topic focuses on network analysis of cancer genetics. After his intern in MSRA, he's currently working on digital histopathology analysis using convolutional neural network (CNN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://liang2.tw/"&gt;http://liang2.tw/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;ccwang002
組織/公司 Bioinfo &amp;amp; Biostat Core Lab, NTU CGM
頭銜 Student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/24"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY3-02 Play Data, Play Ball! - Summit Suen (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day3-02-play-data-play-ball-summit-suen-pycon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Summit Suen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day3-02-play-data-play-ball-summit-suen-pycon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Summit Suen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever notice that how many numbers had been collected and recorded during a sports game? Not only practice makes perfect; for modern sports players, numbers plays an even important role in improving their performance. This talk will bring a brief introduction of sports data analysis to you, and hands-on practice.
- Introduction to Sabermetrics / Mathletics / Money ball
- Play baseball data (not only R, now with python)
- A simple practice: Let's explore MLB/CPBL data!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 5 years of experience in scientific research, with well-trained mathematical modeling and statistical analysis skills. And 2+ years of comprehensive hands-on experience developing data products/applications (academic as well as industrial), including enterprise products and volunteer open data projects.
Rich practices on Parallel computing, Distributed system, Virtual container (Docker), Cloud platform, Machine learning, Data mining and Data visualization.
Also an open data and open source enthusiast, actively volunteering for related local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tw.linkedin.com/in/suensummit"&gt;http://tw.linkedin.com/in/suensummit&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;SummitSuen
組織/公司 Drawpie Design
頭銜 Data Scientist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/103"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY3-04 Sphinx autodoc: automated API documentation - Takayuki Shimizukawa (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day3-04-sphinx-autodoc-automated-api-takayuki.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Takayuki Shimizukawa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day3-04-sphinx-autodoc-automated-api-takayuki.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Takayuki Shimizukawa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the automated documentation feature of Sphinx, you can make with ease the extensive documentation of Python program.
You just write python function documents (docstrings), Sphinx organizes them into the document, can be converted to a variety of formats.
In this session, I'll explain a documentation procedure that uses with sphinx autodoc and autosummary extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sphinx co-maintainer since 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Let's start Sphinx&amp;quot; Japanese ebook author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sphinx-users.jp account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon JP organizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://about.me/shimizukawa"&gt;http://about.me/shimizukawa&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;shimizukawa
組織/公司 BePROUD corp / PyCon JP / Sphinx-usres.jp
頭銜 Python developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/69"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/69&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0D3K1 Crossing Language Barriers with julia SciPy and Ipython - Steven G. Johnson (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0d3k1-crossing-language-barriers-with-julia-scipy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steven G. Johnson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0d3k1-crossing-language-barriers-with-julia-scipy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Steven G. Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steven G. Johnson is an associate professor of applied mathematics at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), where he previously received a Ph.D. in physics and B.S. degrees in physics, mathematics, and computer science. His research interests include scientific computing and both the analytical and computational study of nanophotonic media (such as photonic crystals and metamaterials) for both classical and quantum phenomena. He is the co-author of nearly 200 papers and three books. SGJ was the co-recipient of the 1999 J. H. Wilkinson Prize for Numerical Software due to his work on the FFTW library, and has since then developed several popular free/open-source packages for technical computing, including MPB, Meep, and NLopt, as well as contributing to SciPy and other free software. He is active in the development of the new technical-computing language, Julia, and will introduce Julia at PyCon along with the ways in which Julia benefits from and interoperates with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1-D1-06 Millions way to avoid overfitting when building a portfolio - Chia-Yi Yen (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-d1-06-millions-way-to-avoid-overfitting-when-a.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chia-Yi Yen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-d1-06-millions-way-to-avoid-overfitting-when-a.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:  Chia-Yi Yen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You never know how to build a successful portfolio that always gives you significant return, but you definitely should know what would make you build a model that is doomed to be a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overfitting is the most common one. In the brief talk, I would like to share some experience how to avoid overfitting. At least in some ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples would be shown in Python toolkit like ipython, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, and seaborn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chia-Yi Yen, you can call her &amp;quot;Yen&amp;quot; just like the Japanese dollar yen, is a financial engineer in a local hedge fund. She has been responsible for multi-factor model construction, data infrastructure, data Extract-Transform-Load solution, and other numeric analysis projects. She is active in many open-source communities like Python and R, and she is also the organizer of Taiwan R-Ladies community, which is a female meetup of everything about data in the world of R language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Risksoft Technology Ltd., Quantitative Strategies Department
頭銜 Financial Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/91"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/91&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY1-01 when thinking functionally with Python - Apua Juan (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-01-when-thinking-functionally-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Apua Juan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-01-when-thinking-functionally-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Apua Juan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;參考 declarative programming, 重新審視使用 Python 語言解決問題時, 可能遭遇的問題 (例如副作用), 提出語言的特性與優勢, 與如何撰寫比較單純少出錯. 並於最後總結 Python 學習優勢與未來建議大家注意的方向.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another Python lover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 HP CSI
頭銜 Senior Software Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/27"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/27&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY1-02 快快樂樂成為 Coding Ninja (by pytest) - Chun-Yu Tseng (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-02-kuai-kuai-le-le-cheng-wei-coding-ninja.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chun-Yu Tseng</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-02-kuai-kuai-le-le-cheng-wei-coding-ninja.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Chun-Yu Tseng&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 擁有的 unittest 深受早期 JUnit 測試框架的影響，充斥著不太 Pythonic 的 API 與設計。然而，在近年 JUnit 早已大量使用 annotation/fixtures/asertThat ... 新元素時，難道我們還得繼續用舊方法寫測試嗎？本演講除了介紹測試神器 pytest 的主要功能以外，亦會展示如何善用 pytest  來撰寫各種類型的測試：unit testing, integration testing, functional testing。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;魯蛇喬 &amp;#64; 均一教育平台
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://about.me/excusemejoe"&gt;https://about.me/excusemejoe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://about.me/excusemejoe"&gt;https://about.me/excusemejoe&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;excusemejoe
組織/公司 誠致教育基金會
頭銜 軟體工程師&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/83"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/83&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY1-03 ZoneIDAProc: Instrumentation-based Dynamic Accessing - Tzung-Bi Shih (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-03-zoneidaproc-instrumentation-based-tzung.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tzung-Bi Shih</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-03-zoneidaproc-instrumentation-based-tzung.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tzung-Bi Shih&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZoneIDAProc provides an easy way to export Linux proc-like interface for python program.  It is intuitive and convenient for showing process internal data; even expose a complex computation.  The talk focuses on demonstrating the magic of ZoneIDA and how it increases your program's versatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzung-Bi Shih was born in Xi-Hu, Taiwan, in 1988.  He received Bachelor and M.S. degree in Computer Science from National Chiao Tung University in 2010 and 2011, respectively.  He was a R&amp;amp;D engineer in Trend Micro during 2011-2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has been a Python programmer for 2 years.  He is a beginning researcher and he is interested in operating system, computer architecture, especially, in parallel computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Independent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/53"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/53&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY1-05 Network Security and Analysis with Python - Lee Yang Peng (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-05-network-security-and-analysis-with-lee.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lee Yang Peng</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day1-05-network-security-and-analysis-with-lee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Lee Yang Peng&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I developed and evaluated Analytics, a tool that analyses packet data to learn information about network protocol formats. Analytics attempts to discover constants and enumeration fields among packet data, while providing visualization to aid analysts. My experiments on fixed length protocol headers show that the heuristics implemented for Analytics in detecting constants and enumeration fields are mostly accurate. It has an average accuracy in detecting constants of 76.8% and an average accuracy in detecting enumeration fields of 88.6%. As Analytics consists of heuristics to detect the targeted fields in network traces, it can also be applied onto proprietary or unknown protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my talk, audience can learn about network security and its significance. Poor network security can result in vulnerabilities in an organization, which may result in commercial espionage, the leakage of company secrets, or the control of computers connected to the network to perform illegal activities. Audience can also benefit from my talk by learning about Deep Packet Inspection, a common process used in large organizations to maintain network security and prevent the transfer or malicious data through a network. Experts in the field can appreciate the tool, 'Analytics', that demonstrates the use of Python in garnering information about unknown network protocol formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a 16 year old student from Dunman High School&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Dunman High School
頭銜 Student&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY2-01 Global Interpreter Lock: Episode I - Break the Seal - Tzung-Bi Shih (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day2-01-global-interpreter-lock-episode-i-break.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tzung-Bi Shih</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day2-01-global-interpreter-lock-episode-i-break.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tzung-Bi Shih&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to achieve high throughput, we usually execute independent tasks simultaneously in a process through leveraging multi-threaded technology.  The tasks are truly parallel because multi-processor and hyper-threading technologies are quite mature in modern x86 CPU.  While thing happens within CPython, the behavior will not be what we think.  The talk addresses on CPython limitation of parallelism and enumerates some common practices to evade the seal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzung-Bi Shih was born in Xi-Hu, Taiwan, in 1988.  He received Bachelor and M.S. degree in Computer Science from National Chiao Tung University in 2010 and 2011, respectively.  He was a R&amp;amp;D engineer in Trend Micro during 2011-2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has been a Python programmer for 2 years.  He is a beginning researcher and he is interested in operating system, computer architecture, especially, in parallel computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Independent&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY2-03 Python 讓你的眼睛聽得見 - Yuchi Lin (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day2-03-python-rang-ni-de-yan-jing-ting-de-jian.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yuchi Lin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day2-03-python-rang-ni-de-yan-jing-ting-de-jian.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yuchi Lin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我所介紹的內容將著重於唇語的影像辨識上，我們從現實生活的經驗裡能得知，在嘈雜環境下只由聲音來與他人溝通是困難且模糊的，但若你能同時看著對方的唇形，將能大幅提昇對話的品質。為了實現這個目標，我採用 Python' OpenCV 來對影像做分析處理，從影像中擷取出代表性的特徵，進一步觀察連續的字元在轉換時是否具有相似的特徵點。未來將結合語音訊號，增強語音辨識的效能。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我就讀於台大工科海洋系資訊組碩士班，現階段研究的主題為模式識別(pattern recognition)。在接觸 Python 前我常用的語言是 C 及 MatLab，在踏入 Python 領域後才發現原來程式語言能如此得平易近人，尤其在參加過 Taipei.py 後更深刻的體會到 Python 的多樣性。很高興能成為 Python 愛好者的一員!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 National Taiwan University
頭銜 Student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/76"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/76&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY2-05 ceph 介紹 - 高 國棟 (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day2-05-ceph-jie-shao-gao-guo-dong-pycon-apac.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>高 國棟</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day2-05-ceph-jie-shao-gao-guo-dong-pycon-apac.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 高 國棟&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# storage system 簡介
# 簡介 ceph
# ceph 運作方式
# rados 介紹
# rbd 介紹
# 快速佈署單機版 ceph
# 如何利用 python 連接 ceph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;喜歡研究電腦技術，專注與 linux, python, scala 相關技術。偶爾會在社群演講。演講內容多以底層技術為主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.blackwhite.tw/"&gt;http://www.blackwhite.tw/&lt;/a&gt;
組織/公司 inwinstack
頭銜 Research and development engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/37"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/37&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY3-02 工程師沒告訴設計師的事 / Happy Together: Designer and Programmer - TsungWei Hu, Andy Fang</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day3-02-gong-cheng-shi-mei-gao-su-she-ji-shi-de.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>TsungWei Hu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day3-02-gong-cheng-shi-mei-gao-su-she-ji-shi-de.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: TsungWei Hu, Andy Fang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designers are trained and think differently from programmers. In general, designers work with static HTML while programmers work on codes and frameworks. Often, they hardly collaborate without bumping into each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Django themes are flexible, but only for programmers. They are not designer friendly. Django templates hate designers who can't code. They need a better way to collaborate among projects, to maximize their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diazo is a smart approach to theming a website. It offers an interface between designers and developers, this brings separation of concerns, and helps to eliminate the gap. While Diazo is a technology developed by the Plone community, it can also work with various web frameworks and deploy with WSGI/Apache/Nginx. In this talk, we will showcase how Diazo works in real world, and the possibility to build a new ecosystem among web developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. TsungWei Hu, Project Planner, RCHSS, Academia Sinica
個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org.tw/marr"&gt;http://python.org.tw/marr&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;l34marr
2. Andy Fang, Manager, MingTak
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mingtak.com.tw/"&gt;http://www.mingtak.com.tw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/95"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/95&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R1 DAY3-03 Python與電子設計自動化：用愛與堅持實現專業 - Ko-Lung Yuan (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-day3-03-pythonyu-dian-zi-she-ji-zi-dong-hua-ai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ko-Lung Yuan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-day3-03-pythonyu-dian-zi-she-ji-zi-dong-hua-ai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ko-Lung Yuan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDA領域一直是C/C++的天下，從業界到學界，無一例外。
且看一個熱愛Python的小子如何無所不用其及地使用Python，甚至反客為主，闖出一片天下。
這場演講中，你將會看到一個對於Python痴謎的人，分享他在EDA領域中堅持地使用Python奮鬥的經驗和成果。
如果您是EDA的同行，您可以來看看他是如何用Python寫出一個簡單但是好用的電路分析工具，也可以來看看對稱性編碼如何對電路進行特性上的優化。
如果您是喜歡演算法的朋友，您可以來看看除了線性規劃之外，還有哪一種新的模型化方式可以求解K-分割問題、背包問題、裝箱問題、虛擬布林規劃等，同時還有一個現成的Python套件可以馬上使用！
如果您想要了解如何使用Python來撰寫script幫助加速您的實驗，一定要來了解一下script-king這個工具。
當然，如果您只是一個喜愛Python的朋友，也十分歡迎來交交朋友，相互交流。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an engineer of Electronics Design Automation at ATopTech[1], a book/blog author of programming techniques and of course... a Python fan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I majored in EE and CAD(EDA field, especially in logic synthesis and design verification) during graduate school[2] and university. Now I focus on the technique of clock tree synthesis. Even if Python is not related to my work but I still love Python so much that I would like to use Python on everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I've developed some Python packages or tools such as minickt[3], mc-solver[4], sym-encoder[5] and script-king[6]. Interested people can find them in Github or PyPI or you can refer to my papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also a blogger[7] mainly writing articles of programming techniques(Python, Django[8] and others) and I will publish a new book about Django learning at the end of May or in early June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followings are links related to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Personal Page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com/pages/about-me"&gt;http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com/pages/about-me&lt;/a&gt;
My Github: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dokelung"&gt;https://github.com/dokelung&lt;/a&gt;
My linkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.linkedin.com/pub/ko-lung-yuan/a3/b9a/536/zh-tw"&gt;https://tw.linkedin.com/pub/ko-lung-yuan/a3/b9a/536/zh-tw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.atoptech.com"&gt;https://www.atoptech.com&lt;/a&gt;
[2] &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://alcom.ee.ntu.edu.tw/"&gt;http://alcom.ee.ntu.edu.tw/&lt;/a&gt;
[3] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dokelung/minickt"&gt;https://github.com/dokelung/minickt&lt;/a&gt;
[4] &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://handle.ncl.edu.tw/11296/ndltd/68703891060081946284"&gt;http://handle.ncl.edu.tw/11296/ndltd/68703891060081946284&lt;/a&gt;
[5] &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://alcom.ee.ntu.edu.tw/publications/iccad13-symm.pdf"&gt;http://alcom.ee.ntu.edu.tw/publications/iccad13-symm.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
[6] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dokelung/script-king"&gt;https://github.com/dokelung/script-king&lt;/a&gt;
[7] &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com"&gt;http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com&lt;/a&gt;
[8] &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com/posts/235592-django-notes-table-of-contents"&gt;http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com/posts/235592-django-notes-table-of-contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com/pages/about-me"&gt;http://dokelung-blog.logdown.com/pages/about-me&lt;/a&gt;
組織/公司 ATopTech
頭銜 R&amp;amp;D Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY1-01 Easy Map Applications Using Python - Victor Gau (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-01-easy-map-applications-using-python-gau.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Victor Gau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-01-easy-map-applications-using-python-gau.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Victor Gau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to creating map applications, javascript is always the first choice among different languages.  Little do people know that it is actually very easy to create map applications by using Python.  In this talk, three topics will be covered: (1) static map applications, (2) interactive map applications, and (3) real time Google Earth applications.  In the first topic, I will demonstrate how to use python with Google Static Maps API to create static map images.  After that, Flask-GoogleMaps and Folium will be introduced to create interactive map applications.  Finally, I will demonstrate how to use python to create real time Google Earth applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software Engineer
Volunteer &amp;#64; Kaohsiung Python User Group, Kaohsiung UseR Meetup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;runrunvictor
組織/公司 Jetway Hi-Tech Inc.
頭銜 Manager of R&amp;amp;D Department&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/63"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/63&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY1-04 教練，我想寫 Django app 給大家用 - Tim Hsu (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-04-jiao-lian-wo-xiang-xie-django-app-gei.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Hsu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-04-jiao-lian-wo-xiang-xie-django-app-gei.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tim Hsu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有的時候，我們會把我們重複的 django 程式碼抽出來變成 django 套件。 但是要能夠讓人方便的重複使用，卻有很多技巧。這裏會分析 Django 常見第三方套件的製作方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am tim, love the simplicity of python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Dorm7
頭銜 Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/16"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY1-05 Tagtoo Task Manager - Chien Hsun Chen (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-05-tagtoo-task-manager-chien-hsun-chen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chien Hsun Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-05-tagtoo-task-manager-chien-hsun-chen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Chien Hsun Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;隨著功能增加，在資料處理時需要牽涉的服務越來越多, 相互之間的關係越來越複雜, 為了解決每天營運需要處理的資料，服務，流程問題，配合 docker 解決方案，出現能解決掉原本的限制的可能性，才會自幹這個開源的專案&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like coding, ramen. and skiing. Most of time, I involve in python coding in Google Cloud Platform for big data processing and cloud architect designing. It is my pleasure to join pycon apac with lots of passion community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://works.bepress.com/lucemia/"&gt;http://works.bepress.com/lucemia/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;lucemia
組織/公司 PyCon APAC 2015
頭銜 Chair of Sponsorship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/80"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/80&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY1-06 How to scale up your Web Apps/Sites written by Python? - Theon Lin (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-06-how-to-scale-up-your-web-apps-sites-by.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Theon Lin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day1-06-how-to-scale-up-your-web-apps-sites-by.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Theon Lin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;當我們開發好網站之後，也順利上線了之後，隨著使用者的人數不停的上升，漸漸一台主機逐漸再也負擔不起經常性的使用者流量，本議程將會介紹各種不同層面的技巧與觀念，協助網站提高服務承載量，包含了頁面Cache的機制，善用非同步訊息佇列，調整單一伺服器的系統架構，到利用最為先進的雲端服務，建置服務叢集。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theon Lin is co-organizer of Taipei.py. Major in web development technologies. He is employed by Gogolook now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=125104719"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=125104719&lt;/a&gt;
組織/公司 Gogolook co. ltd
頭銜 Web Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/89"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/89&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY2-01 OpenLCDFDM: an finite-difference LCD simulator - Zong-han Xie (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-01-openlcdfdm-an-finite-difference-lcd-han.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zong-han Xie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-01-openlcdfdm-an-finite-difference-lcd-han.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Zong-han Xie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LCD is a mature display technology and widely adopted in consumer electronics. Being able to simulate LCD device is important to understand how it works as well as improve LCD technology. OpenLCDFDM is a program which uses finite difference method to perform LCD simulations. This talk will give introductions of how an LCD display works and the methods used in OpenLCDFDM to simulate such devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduated from physics department, former engineer of  INNOLUX corporation, specializing in physics simulation. I have researched into particle-in-cell simulation for plasmas and liquid crystal optics simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://zhdiary.wordpress.com/"&gt;http://zhdiary.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;dapang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/73"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/73&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY2-02 Data Analysis in Wearable Technologies - Jennifer Ma (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-02-data-analysis-in-wearable-technologies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Ma</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-02-data-analysis-in-wearable-technologies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jennifer Ma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market of &amp;quot;Wearables&amp;quot; is growing fast. Data generated from fitness bands, mobile phones, and other wearable devices increases every day. However, can doctors really use these information to diagnose diseases, prevent injuries, or promote health?
In this talk, I will apply analytic tools in Python on blood pressure, blood sugar, heart rate, and data from actimeter (accelerometer), trying to bridge the gap between clinical practice and modern gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Taipei City Hospital RenAi Branch
頭銜 Family Medicine Resident&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/97"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/97&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY2-03 Information extraction with Python - jiawei chen (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-03-information-extraction-with-python-chen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>jiawei chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-03-information-extraction-with-python-chen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: jiawei chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present a named entity recognition (NER) system for extracting attributes and values, like person, company, place or time,  from various of text data. I will introduce how to combine several python tools to build this system. First, use a python written annotation tool BRAT to create a custom annotated corpus. Second, use python to link CRFsuite, training a Conditional Random Fields model to labeling our list of text data, the labeling result will be further analyzed by pandas and scikit-learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A search engineer,  usually like to study machine learning and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;頭銜 search engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/61"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/61&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY2-05 for physics in blender: (or, what light looks like) - David Mikolas (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-05-for-physics-in-blender-or-what-light.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Mikolas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day2-05-for-physics-in-blender-or-what-light.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: David Mikolas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first told my friends and family that I was taking some time off to learn about blender and python for scientific visualization, some of them became confused and worried, thinking I had snakes in my kitchen. In fact, I'm a scientist/engineer and I need an environment to calculate things and show the results, and these two open source packages offered everything I need!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become a popular platform in physics for both professional research and teaching settings. Scipy and numpy have most of the goodies we need, and there are plenty of other libraries out there. However, depending on one's previous experience with other tools, learning to really use python &amp;quot;pythonically&amp;quot; can sometimes be a little bumpy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll first give a quick tutorial on how to get started doing physics in python the right way - the tutorial that I &lt;em&gt;wish&lt;/em&gt; I could have read in the beginning. I'll give some examples of interactive programs using the matplotlib widgets as a user interface, for a variety of engineering and physics applications. This is the International Year of Light [1] celebrating a number of optical &amp;quot;birthdays&amp;quot;, so we'll look at some of those with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I'll show some results where I cast a complicated math/optics problem as a collection of python objects (in python, everything is an object!) to make the solution more tangible. Since blender - a rendering and animation environment with python scripting built-in - eats python objects for breakfast, one can just transfer the code into blender and make animated 3D visualization of the problem setup, calculation, and final results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]  www.nature.com/news/light2015-1.16846&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David enjoys physics, math, optics, engineering... and now, python! He's worked in the semiconductor industry, both in process development and metrology. Currently he's looking at &amp;quot;what's next&amp;quot; in optical communications.  Note: check the personal link close to PyCon for additional information about talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEW LINK (July 2015)!! Works better. I'll be adding posts regularly now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://davidmikolas.blogspot.tw/"&gt;http://davidmikolas.blogspot.tw/&lt;/a&gt;
頭銜 Engineer/Scientist&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY3-01 Sentiment Analysis by NLTK - Wei-Ting Kuo (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-01-sentiment-analysis-by-nltk-wei-ting-kuo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wei-Ting Kuo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-01-sentiment-analysis-by-nltk-wei-ting-kuo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Wei-Ting Kuo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentiment analysis is useful, especially for the social media. In this talk, I'd like to introduce some background knowledge and how to use NLTK to do the sentiment analysis. Finally, i'll give a demo for the sentiment analysis for Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll keep the theory part as easy as possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wei-Ting Kuo, Taipei, Taiwan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oranizor of Docker.Taipei &amp;amp; Meteor.Taipei&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;waitingkuo
組織/公司 Brandkoop
頭銜 CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/79"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/79&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY3-02 The Implementation of Rubik's Cube Formula in PyCuber - Adrian Liaw (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-02-the-implementation-of-rubiks-cube-in.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adrian Liaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-02-the-implementation-of-rubiks-cube-in.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Adrian Liaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCuber is a Python package for dealing with Rubik's Cubes, which also contains a built-in solver. Behind these, the implementation of Rubik's Cube's algorithms (formulae) are really important, it provides several useful functions like reverse, mirror, optimise, this talk will cover all these stuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secondary school Python coder from Taiwan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 木刻思股份有限公司
頭銜 Learning Reinforcer 拍打鞭策長&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/99"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/99&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY3-03 Gandi CLI - Thomas Kuiper (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-03-gandi-cli-thomas-kuiper-pycon-apac-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Kuiper</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-03-gandi-cli-thomas-kuiper-pycon-apac-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Thomas Kuiper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written in Python, Gandi CLI is an open source command line tool to interface with Gandi's APIs. It can be used to create and manage hosting instances (Gandi IaaS and PaaS), generate and manage SSL certificates, manage domain names and their zones, as well as all other domain name-related Gandi services (such as Gandimail, Gandisite).
Gandi's API is provided free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas, originally from Germany, has been living in Taiwan for almost ten years now. Before coming to Asia, he worked for an alternative ISP in France as software developer. In Taiwan he has been working at technology companies on software for embedded devices and content management systems. In Spring 2014 he launched Gand Asia. Co. Ltd in Taiwan; a full subsidiary of Gandi.net in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;engerim42
組織/公司 Gandi
頭銜 Chief operating officer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/108"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/108&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2 DAY3-04 Building Static Blogs using Pelican - Quazi Nafiul Islam (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-04-building-static-blogs-using-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Quazi Nafiul Islam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2-day3-04-building-static-blogs-using-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Quazi Nafiul Islam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static Site Generators are now used by many developers. If you see a .github.io domain, it means that their site is statically generated and version controlled. What I want to talk about in this lecture is why static blog generators are so popular and so powerful if you want something hackable. I'll talk about pelican, its good parts, its pitfalls as well as some custom suggestions to make your workflow faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author, Student, Speaker. Language Aficionado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently a student at university, I also work part time in web development, I speak at local conferences and workshops. I also explore other languages other than Python. Currently writing a book on PyCharm (Packt), an IDE by JetBrains. I also blog about the technologies that I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nafiulis.me/"&gt;http://nafiulis.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter &amp;#64;gamesbrainiac
組織/公司 North South University
頭銜 Student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/14"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R2D102 Happy rapid prototyping embedded assembly by Python - Albert Huang (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r2d102-happy-rapid-prototyping-embedded-assembly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Albert Huang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r2d102-happy-rapid-prototyping-embedded-assembly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Albert Huang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bit-encoded parser in communication system is not easy to program, and usually written in C. Sometimes for lack of toolchain or reduction of memory footprint, programmers might still need to write it in assembly, and it's definitely not a happy task. The author tries to share his  happy experience on rapid prototyping this kind of parser in Python, and later coded them in assembly running in an embedded processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大學念交大電信系，研究所從清華資工所畢業後在通訊 IC 上從事 DSP 韌體設計，對於即時系統與通訊系統有著莫名的熱情，自從 2000 年學了 Python 之後，就一直愛不釋手，在公司裡面嘗試在所有非組合語言與 C 語言的場合都用 Python 建立方便的工具，近年來致力於讓數位訊號處理能夠深入淺出的讓有興趣的人能夠學習，希望減緩 DSP 實作的學習曲線。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;個人網頁連結 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://alberthuang314.blogspot.com/"&gt;http://alberthuang314.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter &amp;#64;AlbertHuang314
頭銜 Principal Firmware Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/32"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>