<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Python Web Conf 2022</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_python-web-conf-2022.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>After CI/CD, there's now Continuous Configuration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/after-cicd-theres-now-continuous-configuration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gunnar Grosch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/after-cicd-theres-now-continuous-configuration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last decade, the movement towards CI/CD has been transformational for getting value out to customers quickly. But in recent years, there has been new processes and tooling towards using configuration post-deployment, in the form of feature flags, operational config, or other runtime configuration. Continually adjusting the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last decade, the movement towards CI/CD has been transformational for getting value out to customers quickly. But in recent years, there has been new processes and tooling towards using configuration post-deployment, in the form of feature flags, operational config, or other runtime configuration. Continually adjusting the configuration to update and tune your code in production is a powerful, fast, and safe way to deploy value to customers. Join us in a discussion about how Amazon uses Continuous Configuration tools at scale to move fast and ensure maximum availability of our services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Includes Python-based demo of how continuous configuration can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>All The Things You Can Do In AWS Once You Know Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/all-the-things-you-can-do-in-aws-once-you-know-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brook Jamieson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/all-the-things-you-can-do-in-aws-once-you-know-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a great first language to learn, but how do you jump from print(&amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;) to actually building things in AWS? In this session, I’ll present a winning workflow for Python Newbies (hatchlings?) who are ready to move past the basics, and want to explore everything …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a great first language to learn, but how do you jump from print(&amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;) to actually building things in AWS? In this session, I’ll present a winning workflow for Python Newbies (hatchlings?) who are ready to move past the basics, and want to explore everything they can build in AWS. We’ll cover a range of topics from serverless compute and serverless API hosting, through to AI/ML, IoT and everything in between!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audiences from different software/tech backgrounds will get value out of this session regardless of their career stage, as I'll discuss how to make the leap to AWS yourself, but also how to help guide any staff you manage towards this leap as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me for an interactive and informative session, where I’ll share lots of tips, tricks and helpful resources to make your journey to AWS with Python much easier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Behind the Scenes of Wagtail's Search</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/behind-the-scenes-of-wagtails-search.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aldan Creo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/behind-the-scenes-of-wagtails-search.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search capabilities are one of the most important parts of any website. In this talk, I’ll guide you over how to do a standard setup of a search backend in the Wagtail CMS on an example test website. We’ll start from scratch, and build from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search capabilities are one of the most important parts of any website. In this talk, I’ll guide you over how to do a standard setup of a search backend in the Wagtail CMS on an example test website. We’ll start from scratch, and build from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the talk, we’ll also explore the way search is internally implemented, to better understand its capabilities and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come jump right into the world of searches, and “find” your way to index your contents and make them available to your users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Challenges of Spark Application Coexisting with NoSQL Databases</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/challenges-of-spark-application-coexisting-with-nosql-databases.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gokul Prabagaren</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/challenges-of-spark-application-coexisting-with-nosql-databases.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CapitalOne is the first US bank to exist out of on-premises and moved completely on Cloud. Over this process of modernizing our application in CapitalOne Card Rewards, we developed ground up custom transactions processing application on open source technologies like Spark, Mongo, Cassandra etc. This application currently processes millions …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CapitalOne is the first US bank to exist out of on-premises and moved completely on Cloud. Over this process of modernizing our application in CapitalOne Card Rewards, we developed ground up custom transactions processing application on open source technologies like Spark, Mongo, Cassandra etc. This application currently processes millions of customer transactions daily providing them millions of miles, cash and points everyday. In process of building our application, we came across many challenging issues to have Spark application process data from MongoDB and Cassandra backend to serve customers. This talk is going to focus on few of those issues, what is the impact of those issue and how to mitigate them. The following are list of issues this talk will focus on:
* How Cassandra Key sequence is important and how it impacts in querying
* How Cassandra batching helps and works well with Spark partitions
* Importance of Cassandra Data Modeling and its implications after MVP/Deployment
* How to manage Mongo Connection (at JVM level)
* Implications of using MongoSpark connector on its Partitioner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the issues highlighted are faced by us in our application. This talk will focus on what are these issues in Spark/Mongo/Cassandra app environment and how to mitigate them. Anyone using Spark apps with Mongo and Cassandra databases as backend can benefits from this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Code Red - Why Developers Will Lead the Energy Revolution</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/code-red-why-developers-will-lead-the-energy-revolution.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/code-red-why-developers-will-lead-the-energy-revolution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humans are creating catastrophic levels of warming on Earth that will have detrimental effects on habitability without immediate intervention — a “code red” scenario, declared by the UN Secretary General. However, there are still actionable ways we can get ahead of the worst climate change effects. Octopus Energy US CEO …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humans are creating catastrophic levels of warming on Earth that will have detrimental effects on habitability without immediate intervention — a “code red” scenario, declared by the UN Secretary General. However, there are still actionable ways we can get ahead of the worst climate change effects. Octopus Energy US CEO, Michael Lee, will discuss how developers can use their skills to help transform our energy systems, and revolutionize every household through the use of software and proprietary technology as we transition to a renewable powered future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Communication is Just as Important as Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/communication-is-just-as-important-as-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>M. Scott Ford</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/communication-is-just-as-important-as-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of a lone developer coding in their basement without social interaction is a thing of the past. These days, technical solutions are often developed by cross-functional teams whose participants have a range of technical experience. Now, more than ever, good communication skills are an essential part of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of a lone developer coding in their basement without social interaction is a thing of the past. These days, technical solutions are often developed by cross-functional teams whose participants have a range of technical experience. Now, more than ever, good communication skills are an essential part of being a software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Scott will share immediately actionable communication principles that will help you get buy-in for your ideas, reduce conflict and tension, increase productivity, be liked and respected. If you’re looking to take your career to the next level, this is one talk you won’t want to miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Communication is just as Important as Code” is one of our core values at Corgibytes, a software dev shop exclusively focused on modernizing existing software applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Corgibytes, we eliminate the binary belief that people are “technical” or “non-technical.” Everyone is expected to be both. Folks who come from a computer science background participate in sales calls and help with blog posts, and everyone, no matter their role, is expected to learn how to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preserve a culture of autonomy, motivate our members to do their best work and to enable fluid communication, we have thought extensively about optimizing the balance between asynchronous communication, routine synchronous communication, and even developed our own framework to reduce context switching that allows people the most scheduling flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Pipeline Modernization at Scale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/data-pipeline-modernization-at-scale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Calvin Hendryx-Parker &amp; Nate Dotzlaf</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/data-pipeline-modernization-at-scale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare organizations aggregate petabytes of data which help drive life-changing health and business decisions. In this presentation, we’ll show you how Indiana’s largest healthcare institution went from using proprietary tools that were hard to maintain and nearly impossible to scale — to implementing a new world of cloud …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare organizations aggregate petabytes of data which help drive life-changing health and business decisions. In this presentation, we’ll show you how Indiana’s largest healthcare institution went from using proprietary tools that were hard to maintain and nearly impossible to scale — to implementing a new world of cloud native and open source tooling, including Airflow, Spark, Delta Lakes (delta.io) and Terraform. We’ll showcase how making a big change to a data pipeline infrastructure can:
* simplify and automate workflow processes;
* enable organizations to import existing and new data sources quickly, efficiently and at scale;
* keep costs down in relation to the number and volume of data sources;
* hire and onboard new developers — who have experience working with the open source tools — quickly, eliminating the tech learning curve that existed with the proprietary tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Scraping with AI and Microsoft RPA</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/data-scraping-with-ai-and-microsoft-rpa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Natalie Roberts</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/data-scraping-with-ai-and-microsoft-rpa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Microsoft’s Power Platform it’s possible to automate repetitive mundane tasks with the art of robotic process automation. AI models are also becoming more common, and I’d like to showcase a portion of AI and its capabilities. While this isn’t related to Python as a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Microsoft’s Power Platform it’s possible to automate repetitive mundane tasks with the art of robotic process automation. AI models are also becoming more common, and I’d like to showcase a portion of AI and its capabilities. While this isn’t related to Python as a whole, the growing technology proves to be of great use for many business problems, and closely relates to computer science. Towards the end of this demo, there will be an interactive Python hangman game for crowd fun if there is time, as well as Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Demystifying Python and Tracing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/demystifying-python-and-tracing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mayur Pipaliya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/demystifying-python-and-tracing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With so much change in applications, teams that build them, and the underpinnings of those apps and services, complexity is at its peak. Traditional tracing provides limitations when it is used to troubleshoot applications built on a distributed software architecture. With microservices scaling independently, it is often common for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With so much change in applications, teams that build them, and the underpinnings of those apps and services, complexity is at its peak. Traditional tracing provides limitations when it is used to troubleshoot applications built on a distributed software architecture. With microservices scaling independently, it is often common for there to be many versions of a single instance running across a disparate infrastructure. Oh, the complexity continues! During our time together, we will unravel and demystify this complexity together as it relates to Python and Tracing so you walk away more equipped to dominate in your role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>East Meets West When Translating Django Apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/east-meets-west-when-translating-django-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Knight</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/east-meets-west-when-translating-django-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Translating a web app can seem like a daunting challenge. Thankfully, though, Django provides a bunch of features out of the box that handle the mechanics of picking languages and substituting strings. In this talk, we’ll show how easy it is to provide translations for both new apps …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Translating a web app can seem like a daunting challenge. Thankfully, though, Django provides a bunch of features out of the box that handle the mechanics of picking languages and substituting strings. In this talk, we’ll show how easy it is to provide translations for both new apps and existing ones. For example code, I’ll show Django apps I developed for small businesses operating both in the USA and in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings and structure for languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL routing and language detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing translations in message files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Areas in the app to insert translation strings (particularly overlooked areas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a bonus, we’ll also look at translating the Django admin site!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, audience members will be able to translate their Django apps without hitting common snags, helping to bring the world together just a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting Started with Airflow for Your Data Workflows</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/getting-started-with-airflow-for-your-data-workflows.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nisarg Shah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/getting-started-with-airflow-for-your-data-workflows.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While working with data products, a developer might have encountered some data tasks which require some scripts or cron jobs. A script might include a series of tasks which needs to be performed on that data. Also, the tasks might be dependent on each other’s execution status and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While working with data products, a developer might have encountered some data tasks which require some scripts or cron jobs. A script might include a series of tasks which needs to be performed on that data. Also, the tasks might be dependent on each other’s execution status and results. In these scenarios, how do you build flows in a structured way? How do you define the dependency of a task and check errors from logs? Using Airflow, you can do everything mentioned above with more flexibility and ease. The pipelines can be triggered daily, developers can get email on failures of specific tasks in the pipeline, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, initially I will go through some main benefits of using the Airflow orchestration tool. After that, I will show the comparison of python script and DAG defined in airflow. I will start from the basic installation, understanding DAG and tasks, exploring various operators (PythonOperator and BashOperator), and defining the structure. After this talk, anyone would be able to develop the pipelines in airflow which has the python/bash implementation in every task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, I would also touch upon some issues regarding fetching logs which a developer can face while using docker-swarm in the pipelines. The workaround is to use multithreading, one thread to read and print logs and the other to check the status of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to deploy Python Lambda function using AWS stack only?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-deploy-python-lambda-function-using-aws-stack-only.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pawel Piwosz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-deploy-python-lambda-function-using-aws-stack-only.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a challenge. Is it possible to use the AWS tooling only to deploy Lambda function? During this hands-on talk we will check it! Using CloudFormation we will create CodePipeline which will deploy Lambda using… CloudFormation! Is this stack and approach reliable? Is it a good choice …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a challenge. Is it possible to use the AWS tooling only to deploy Lambda function? During this hands-on talk we will check it! Using CloudFormation we will create CodePipeline which will deploy Lambda using… CloudFormation! Is this stack and approach reliable? Is it a good choice when designing CI/CD for the project? Let’s figure it out. More than half of this talk we will spend on VSCode, AWS console and CLI. You will be able to feel the work of DevOps!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to TDD a REST API</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-tdd-a-rest-api.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Zilberfeld</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-tdd-a-rest-api.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re working with a framework for writing APIs (and who doesn’t), writing tests up front, almost guarantees the tests will be ugly. And the code might not be that great, either. TDD is great for unit tests, but if you take it up a level, for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re working with a framework for writing APIs (and who doesn’t), writing tests up front, almost guarantees the tests will be ugly. And the code might not be that great, either. TDD is great for unit tests, but if you take it up a level, for REST APIs, or an end-to-end behavior, TDD may not look like the tool as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TDD can work for building REST APIs. And I’m not talking about just writing a test before the code, but the entire TDD experience, with tests passing every few minutes. But unlike “regular” TDD, it doesn’t just work. We need to prepare and plan a bit before we can harness of the power of TDD in our real-world applications. In this session, I’m going to go step by step of building APIs from scratch, including the thinking of what to do next. I’ll be using small steps, and show you where I backtracked and made changes. At the end we’ll have working APIs, with tests that prove that they work. TDD is not just for unit tests anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How’s Your Computer-side Manner?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/hows-your-computer-side-manner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ali Atkison</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/hows-your-computer-side-manner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countless studies have found direct connections between a person’s communication skills and their professional success. In today’s world, most of your professional contacts only know you virtually. What does your computer-side manner say about you? Is it helping or hindering your professional success?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an organizational standpoint …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countless studies have found direct connections between a person’s communication skills and their professional success. In today’s world, most of your professional contacts only know you virtually. What does your computer-side manner say about you? Is it helping or hindering your professional success?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an organizational standpoint, communication barriers cost the average organization $62.4 million per year in lost productivity. Is it possible your employees’ written and verbal communication skills are holding them back from being more successful, not to mention impacting your organization’s productivity and, thus, the bottom line?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join renowned communications expert Dr. Ali Atkison as she explores the nature of EI in professional communication. But this is not your mom’s EI—EI in this case stands for empathy and inquiry, your two best friends when it comes to impactful communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session you’ll learn brain-based tactics for achieving impactful communication, which is communication that accomplishes what you want it to, and that allows you to stand out as the professional you need to be to achieve success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lint All the Things!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lint-all-the-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luke Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/lint-all-the-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many teams document the conventions for their projects. However, documentation gets out of date, forgotten, or sometimes ignored. Simple documentation requires team members to constantly remember all the ‘rules’ for your project. You can better enforce those rules and free up your team members to think about harder problems …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many teams document the conventions for their projects. However, documentation gets out of date, forgotten, or sometimes ignored. Simple documentation requires team members to constantly remember all the ‘rules’ for your project. You can better enforce those rules and free up your team members to think about harder problems using linting tools like flake8, import linter, and pre-commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools provide tons of useful stuff out of the box, but you can push them so much further with customization. This allows your project to formally document conventions, but also enforce them automatically on every commit, merge, and build. This can make code reviews faster and more focused on the problems your code is meant to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce tools like flake8, import linter, and pre-commit along with some of their built-in functionality. Then, we’ll briefly explore some ways to customize them to fit your projects’ specific needs. Some examples of custom linter rules we’ll tour are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code formatted automatically and uniformly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code doesn’t import across architecture layers violating separation of concerns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common conventions are used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common anti-patterns are avoided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific layers are fully tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proper git commit message formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge commits don’t exist in topic/feature branches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll discuss ways to use those custom linter rules on every commit, merge, and build with continuous integration or git hooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Make Your Software Architecture Sexy with Domain Driven Design</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/make-your-software-architecture-sexy-with-domain-driven-design.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anastasiia Tymoshchuk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/make-your-software-architecture-sexy-with-domain-driven-design.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain Driven Design (DDD) has a huge set of tools, which could be used to design your perfect architecture - loosely coupled and highly cohesive. Anastasiia has been using DDD for a few years and created her own way to design a new architecture for a product, a feature, redesign …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain Driven Design (DDD) has a huge set of tools, which could be used to design your perfect architecture - loosely coupled and highly cohesive. Anastasiia has been using DDD for a few years and created her own way to design a new architecture for a product, a feature, redesign, refactoring and also for exploring existing products, their ecosystem and their functionality. In this talk attendees will learn on a real-world example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to start with Eventstorming to explore the user journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to move forward and explore the ecosystem of the product/software/feature/service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to finalise a new architecture with C4 diagrams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite all the attempts to create a new perfect architecture, it could be affected by the team and organisation structure. Conway’s Law says: “Any organisation that designs a system will produce a design whose structure is a copy of the organisation’s communication structure”. Anastasiia experienced this so many times in different teams and organisations, that in the past few years she started applying Team Topologies together with DDD. This worked pretty well and as a bonus Anastasiia will go through the hidden icebergs of this approach as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Minimum Viable Migrations - A Migration Path to Serverless</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/minimum-viable-migrations-a-migration-path-to-serverless.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Ellerby</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/minimum-viable-migrations-a-migration-path-to-serverless.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modernization approaches often lack the agility needed to ensure success and maximize value to users. Thinking in terms of events enables adoption of modern technologies (like Serverless) through a Series of Minimum Viable Migrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modernization approaches often lack the agility needed to ensure success and maximize value to users. Thinking in terms of events enables adoption of modern technologies (like Serverless) through a Series of Minimum Viable Migrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>New dev, old codebase: A series of mentorship stories</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/new-dev-old-codebase-a-series-of-mentorship-stories.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ramon Huidobro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/new-dev-old-codebase-a-series-of-mentorship-stories.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My aim with this talk is to inspire folks to try a hand at mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll cover the example of peers having attended a Rails Girls workshop and then a few months later being a mentor at one. Mentorship is relative, and loads of initiatives are structured this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My aim with this talk is to inspire folks to try a hand at mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll cover the example of peers having attended a Rails Girls workshop and then a few months later being a mentor at one. Mentorship is relative, and loads of initiatives are structured this way! That being said, I believe the intended audience can be relative newcomers to programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outline is as follows:
* Clarifications: Mentorship vs training vs teaching
* Volunteering mentorship (Personal examples: Teaching children, Rails Girls Summer of Code, workshops)
* Mentorship best practices
* At the workplace (Onboarding a junior developer to a recent codebase)
* Conclusions, further reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeaways/topics covered include:
* Responsibility in leaving an impression on a newer programmer
* Encouraging good habits
* Being supportive
* Learning alongside mentees
* Admitting when you don’t know the answer or the solution to something
* Letting mentees voice their ideas
* Starting out as a mentor (finding places to mentor)
* Communities of practise
* Showing mentees your problem-solving process
* Sharing the joy of sharing knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Predict Lightning Strikes using Django and AWS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/predict-lightning-strikes-using-django-and-aws.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Calvin Hendryx-Parker &amp; Will Howard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/predict-lightning-strikes-using-django-and-aws.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you could predict the first strike of any thunderstorm with a 99.6% accuracy and a 15- to 25-minute lead time (saving time, money and lives)? With FLASH Scientific Technology, the only lightning predictive service on the market, you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case study and product demo …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you could predict the first strike of any thunderstorm with a 99.6% accuracy and a 15- to 25-minute lead time (saving time, money and lives)? With FLASH Scientific Technology, the only lightning predictive service on the market, you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case study and product demo, we’ll discuss how to take an algorithm and idea from a Jupyter Notebook to production ready and cloud native. You’ll learn best practices for:
* optimizing Python code structure;
* building APIs with Django that are fast, efficient and accurate; and
* deploying serverless and scalable applications using AWS Lambda and AWS Fargate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Django"></category></entry><entry><title>Python's Web Story: Now and Next</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/pythons-web-story-now-and-next.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Everitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/pythons-web-story-now-and-next.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2019 we lamented Python’s web story. The web hasn’t stood still and neither has Python. In this keynote we reframe the issue in updated terms. We then explain how the JavaScript world has innovated like crazy, and hear from important voices in Python about the near …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2019 we lamented Python’s web story. The web hasn’t stood still and neither has Python. In this keynote we reframe the issue in updated terms. We then explain how the JavaScript world has innovated like crazy, and hear from important voices in Python about the near future of Python and the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Quaive - How to Grow a Complex Software Suite for the Long Run</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/quaive-how-to-grow-a-complex-software-suite-for-the-long-run.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guido Stevens</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/quaive-how-to-grow-a-complex-software-suite-for-the-long-run.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central theme of this talk is: time. How do you architect a software product to get better and better in the long run?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are simple answers to that question. And then there's reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're building a complex software product, different pieces of your stack evolve at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central theme of this talk is: time. How do you architect a software product to get better and better in the long run?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are simple answers to that question. And then there's reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're building a complex software product, different pieces of your stack evolve at different speeds. Yesteryear's frontend paradigm may already be oldskool, before your backend is feature-complete enough to ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there's the market, where the rubber meets the road, which has its own rhythms and slow evolution. Your whole stack may be oldskool, before the market is ready to adopt your product at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The product that is now Quaive, started 10 years ago, building on foundations that reach much further back in time. We somehow managed to not drown in technical debt. Even better: our product development is picking up pace currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will explain success factors, and highlight risks that need to be managed. We'll spend time on product vision, technical architecture, design system, team dynamics, and market dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you strike the right balance, between new feature development and refactoring technical debt? How do you combine open source ethics and community involvement, with establishing a sustainable business model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will hopefully walk away with some new insights into wicked problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Ship More, Script Less with Paketo Buildpacks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/ship-more-script-less-with-paketo-buildpacks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ram Iyengar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/ship-more-script-less-with-paketo-buildpacks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buildpacks, which appeared on the scene circa 2011, completely transformed the developer experience across the globe! First popularized by Heroku, they made single-click (or single-command) deployment a reality and appeared like magic. Several barriers to entry to using Heroku/Buildpacks - such as pricing, hosting, etc. - were solved by the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buildpacks, which appeared on the scene circa 2011, completely transformed the developer experience across the globe! First popularized by Heroku, they made single-click (or single-command) deployment a reality and appeared like magic. Several barriers to entry to using Heroku/Buildpacks - such as pricing, hosting, etc. - were solved by the use of Cloud Foundry, which prompted users to make use of a parallel standard for Buildpacks. With the mainstream adoption of containers, the build experience has transformed entirely. Consequently, the Buildpacks’ internals have also changed to allow the export of containers. After several years, the Buildpacks communities at Heroku and Cloud Foundry have converged over an open standard termed the Cloud Native Buildpacks specification. Implementations of this specification is available from Heroku, Paketo, Google, and several others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I aim to demonstrate the lifecycle and utility of Paketo Buildpacks, especially when using Python applications. By using Paketo (Cloud Native Buildpacks), this experience is greatly simplified for developers. The build-and-deploy phase is greatly simplified for all applications and services. Developers can essentially cut out all the noise that arises in the form of “config hell” while focusing solely on solving the core business problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Standing on the shoulders of giants, securely.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/standing-on-the-shoulders-of-giants-securely.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justin Womersley</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/standing-on-the-shoulders-of-giants-securely.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the software supply chain, why is it important, and how to manage it securely? Justin Womersley, of PyUp.io, will explore the topic of the Python software supply chain, how to configure it, how to keep it secure, and what the future may look like for responsibly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the software supply chain, why is it important, and how to manage it securely? Justin Womersley, of PyUp.io, will explore the topic of the Python software supply chain, how to configure it, how to keep it secure, and what the future may look like for responsibly standing on the shoulders of the giant that is the open-source software stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Stop Burning Down Rainforests: Mint NFTs using Python and the XRP Ledger</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/stop-burning-down-rainforests-mint-nfts-using-python-and-the-xrp-ledger.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matt Hamilton &amp; Ami Zou</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/stop-burning-down-rainforests-mint-nfts-using-python-and-the-xrp-ledger.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people have heard about NFTs (Non Fungible Tokens) and their uses in art, licensing, gaming and more. But one of the big criticisms is the environmental impact of some of the original blockchains. In this talk we will be showing how to build a Python web service to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people have heard about NFTs (Non Fungible Tokens) and their uses in art, licensing, gaming and more. But one of the big criticisms is the environmental impact of some of the original blockchains. In this talk we will be showing how to build a Python web service to mint NFTs on the XRP Ledger, the first carbon neutral blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Technical Communities at an Enterprise Scale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/technical-communities-at-an-enterprise-scale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marianna Polatoglou &amp; Monica Ho</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/technical-communities-at-an-enterprise-scale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bring technical people together and technical communities will form organically. It is then a matter of sustaining and fostering this collaboration to support their being successful. This ensures strong technical alignment and empowers the communities to bring forth changes to current workflows and establish best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within Bloomberg, we …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bring technical people together and technical communities will form organically. It is then a matter of sustaining and fostering this collaboration to support their being successful. This ensures strong technical alignment and empowers the communities to bring forth changes to current workflows and establish best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within Bloomberg, we call our technical communities Guilds. Since medieval times, the term ‘Guild’ has described a collection of experts who come together to solve challenges and share tricks of their craft. In this talk, we will share how Bloomberg’s Guilds program achieves this by encouraging “communities of interest” to form around specific technologies and related technical topics, and to advance their adoption within the company – with a particular focus on the activities of the Python Guild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The Flower</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/the-flower.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Noel Musicha</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/the-flower.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whoever tells the most compelling story shapes the future. What story does your work tell? When you are gone, what will be the proof of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whoever tells the most compelling story shapes the future. What story does your work tell? When you are gone, what will be the proof of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Tutorial: Practical Intro Blockchain for Python Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-practical-intro-blockchain-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gwendolyn Faraday</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-practical-intro-blockchain-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you curious about blockchain development and interested in trying it out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline
* The first part of this talk will cover all the basic elements of the inner workings of blockchain. To demonstrate this, we will be building a blockchain from scratch in Python.
Next, we will cover how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you curious about blockchain development and interested in trying it out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline
* The first part of this talk will cover all the basic elements of the inner workings of blockchain. To demonstrate this, we will be building a blockchain from scratch in Python.
Next, we will cover how to connect with, retrieve, and store information with a test blockchain using web3.py and related libraries.
* Finally, we will talk about some of the specifics for how to build applications on the blockchain and build a few apps to demonstrate how everything fits together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk, you will leave with:
* An understanding of all the basics of how blockchains work.
* Knowing how to run a local, test Ethereum blockchain.
* A basic knowledge of web3.py and how build Python applications on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Understanding Common Causes of Cryptographic Vulnerabilities</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/understanding-common-causes-of-cryptographic-vulnerabilities.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Howard Poston</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/understanding-common-causes-of-cryptographic-vulnerabilities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cryptography is essential for cybersecurity and data protection, but it is extremely easy to get wrong. Incidents like Zerologon demonstrate how easy it is for a simple tweak to a cryptographic algorithm to break everything. It’s difficult to know what will break a cryptographic algorithm, and the modern …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cryptography is essential for cybersecurity and data protection, but it is extremely easy to get wrong. Incidents like Zerologon demonstrate how easy it is for a simple tweak to a cryptographic algorithm to break everything. It’s difficult to know what will break a cryptographic algorithm, and the modern algorithms we rely on today are considered secure because a lot of people have tried to break them and no one has succeeded yet. That said, there are some fundamental and common mistakes that undermine the security of cryptographic algorithms. This session discusses some of the main ways in which cryptography can go wrong, what happens when these errors occur, and best practices for mitigating the risks of bad cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Chaos Toolkit to Determine Resiliency for Your Web App</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/using-chaos-toolkit-to-determine-resiliency-for-your-web-app.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Karan Balkar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/using-chaos-toolkit-to-determine-resiliency-for-your-web-app.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction
Chaos engineering is the process through which one can conduct a series of experiments in order to build confidence in a system’s capability to withstand unexpected behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objective
The objective of this talk is to help developers working on Python-based web apps to learn about how they …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction
Chaos engineering is the process through which one can conduct a series of experiments in order to build confidence in a system’s capability to withstand unexpected behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objective
The objective of this talk is to help developers working on Python-based web apps to learn about how they can use a simple toolkit to carry out such chaos experiments. The Chaos toolkit (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chaostoolkit.org/"&gt;https://chaostoolkit.org/&lt;/a&gt;) would help Python developers to customize their experiments as per their project requirements. This can be further automated leveraging CI/CD and Cloud technologies to be able to maintain resiliency in production apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem statement
More often than not developers face a lot of issues when scaling their applications or when certain unpredictable situations occur. Using the Chaos toolkit developers can determine the resiliency of their application under a chaos situation. In addition, developers can create custom experiments that could be automated to identify failures before they become outages. The session will demonstrate how to achieve a better resiliency using the Chaos toolkit for existing web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeaways
Key takeaways from this sessions:
* Understanding important concepts of Chaos engineering
* Learn what is meant by steady state hypothesis and create experiments for your Python based web app
* Automating the process through CI/CD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demo solution highlights
Following are the highlights:
* Demonstrating how to setup your first experiment using Chaos toolkit
* Defining steady-state-hypothesis, probes and controls
* Running the experiment under various chaos conditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome to Plone 6</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/welcome-to-plone-6.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erico Andrei</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/welcome-to-plone-6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Plone content management system is one of the earliest and most successful open-source stories of the Python community. In this talk, we present its latest version, Plone 6, and how you can build your next solution, whether using its classic SSR front end or its now React front …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Plone content management system is one of the earliest and most successful open-source stories of the Python community. In this talk, we present its latest version, Plone 6, and how you can build your next solution, whether using its classic SSR front end or its now React front end, or using its REST API as a headless content store for your Django and Flask apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Plone"></category></entry><entry><title>What Do We Pay Our People?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/what-do-we-pay-our-people.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Agustin Lebron</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/what-do-we-pay-our-people.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges for tech leaders is the subject of compensation. What are market rates? What's the right structure? Cash, equity, options, benefits? It can be a minefield. In this talk we'll discuss some useful general principles and rules of thumb when thinking about comp, and go …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges for tech leaders is the subject of compensation. What are market rates? What's the right structure? Cash, equity, options, benefits? It can be a minefield. In this talk we'll discuss some useful general principles and rules of thumb when thinking about comp, and go through some worked examples to focus the discussion. By the end you'll have a clear picture of the comp landscape, how to think about it, and you'll have some tools to help you make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>What's Your Type? A Real World Use Case for Python Type Hints</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/whats-your-type-a-real-world-use-case-for-python-type-hints.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lee Briggs</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/whats-your-type-a-real-world-use-case-for-python-type-hints.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type hints for python have been available since Python 3.5, but it’s rare to see the Python type system used in the wild. As a dynamic language, it’s easy to gain the habit of allowing Python programs to “fail fast” and handle type and syntax errors …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type hints for python have been available since Python 3.5, but it’s rare to see the Python type system used in the wild. As a dynamic language, it’s easy to gain the habit of allowing Python programs to “fail fast” and handle type and syntax errors at runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when using Python for infrastructure as code, this can start to create a difficult and painful feedback loop for code that is heavily iterated upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll take a look at how the type system dramatically can improve an infrastructure as code programs, and see how it can improve the feedback loop. Finally, we’ll examine some of the strong and weak parts of the Python type system against other popular languages and make a case for improvements that could benefit the wider python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing Better Documentation for Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/writing-better-documentation-for-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Meredydd Luff</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/writing-better-documentation-for-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re building something for developers, you want it to get used. This means your potential users need to find your library, framework, or API. They need to work out whether it’s useful for them, learn how to use it, and solve problems they encounter along the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re building something for developers, you want it to get used. This means your potential users need to find your library, framework, or API. They need to work out whether it’s useful for them, learn how to use it, and solve problems they encounter along the way. All these things depend on your developer docs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about important functions of your developer docs that you might not think about, some particular pitfalls of documenting things for developers, and how we can make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that:
* Your docs are content marketing? Your prospective users are out there, Googling “how to [what your project does]”, and your docs are the answer.
* Your docs define your product? When a developer is evaluating your project, this is what they’re reading, not your glossy website.
* Your docs are your user interface? Developers using your API aren’t looking at your website - they’re looking at your docs, and their code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s look at some “dos and don’ts”:
* Do know what type of doc you’re writing. Tutorials are not the same thing as reference docs. I’ll walk you through a useful framework for thinking about types of documentation.
* Don’t confuse reference docs and API docs. Merely enumerating the classes, methods and functions of your API isn’t enough to describe its behaviour. I’ll explain why it’s tempting, and why it’s a bad idea!
* Do make it easy to navigate between types of documentation. Your user is on a journey, from “what should I use?” to “how do I use it?” to “what arguments does this function take?”. Make it easy for them.
* Do talk to your users. They will tell you where the weaknesses in your docs are. Even better: have a public Q&amp;amp;A forum, where deficiencies in your documentation get found and filled in, and the long tail takes care of itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to convince you that your docs are your UI, your marketing and the definition of your product - and that it’s worth acting like it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Confessions of Joe Developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/confessions-of-joe-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/confessions-of-joe-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 17 years of professional Python development at Octopus Energy, NASA, and various agencies, Daniel Roy Greenfeld has picked up a lot of easy tricks stolen from the best and brightest in the software community that make him look good in front of his peers and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 17 years of professional Python development at Octopus Energy, NASA, and various agencies, Daniel Roy Greenfeld has picked up a lot of easy tricks stolen from the best and brightest in the software community that make him look good in front of his peers and colleagues. And now, at great risk to his career and reputation, he is going to show you how he does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Get Promoted When Your Team is Remote</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-get-promoted-when-your-team-is-remote.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Debbie Madden</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-get-promoted-when-your-team-is-remote.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you get ahead when everyone is apart? In today's talk, we'll discuss how to set yourself up for success in today's remote world - whether your goal is to score a raise, get a promotion or move onto a new team. And please - bring your questions - we'll have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you get ahead when everyone is apart? In today's talk, we'll discuss how to set yourself up for success in today's remote world - whether your goal is to score a raise, get a promotion or move onto a new team. And please - bring your questions - we'll have lots of time for you to ask what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Quickly Make a Website of a Data Visualization ​​</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-quickly-make-a-website-of-a-data-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica Garson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/how-to-quickly-make-a-website-of-a-data-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you’ll learn to use the Tweets counts endpoint and Dash to create a website that automatically refreshes to show how much you are Tweeting throughout the week. Dash allows you to quickly set up a Flask app to create a web framework for data visualizations …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you’ll learn to use the Tweets counts endpoint and Dash to create a website that automatically refreshes to show how much you are Tweeting throughout the week. Dash allows you to quickly set up a Flask app to create a web framework for data visualizations using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda of the talk is as follows:
* What is Dash
* Why Dash?
* What problem was I solving for?
* Overview of the solution
* Getting started with the Twitter API
* Demo
* Deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>HTMX + Flask: Modern Python Web Apps, Hold the JavaScript</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/htmx-flask-modern-python-web-apps-hold-the-javascript.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Kennedy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/htmx-flask-modern-python-web-apps-hold-the-javascript.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been a strong drumbeat to move away from server-side programming and lean more and more heavily on JavaScript, especially for dynamic and interactive web sites. With the recent release of HTMX, there is another path Python developers can choose. Use declarative programming on the client side with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been a strong drumbeat to move away from server-side programming and lean more and more heavily on JavaScript, especially for dynamic and interactive web sites. With the recent release of HTMX, there is another path Python developers can choose. Use declarative programming on the client side with nearly pure HTML and CSS and double down on back-end Python (Flask, Django, FastAPI, and other frameworks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, Michael Kennedy will present some of the cleanest Flask code you have seen while at the same time adding rich interactivity on the front-end – all the while with no JavaScript in side. It’s a new, and likely better, way to think about building dynamic Python web apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>In-Place Migrations with Plone, Feels Like Magic</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/in-place-migrations-with-plone-feels-like-magic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Annette Lewis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/in-place-migrations-with-plone-feels-like-magic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plone migrations are challenging by nature. There's no one size meets all approach. Add-ons and custom content can make the task feel impossible at times. However, once all the details are hammered out — and when it's all send and done — the final process can feel like magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six Feet …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plone migrations are challenging by nature. There's no one size meets all approach. Add-ons and custom content can make the task feel impossible at times. However, once all the details are hammered out — and when it's all send and done — the final process can feel like magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six Feet Up was tasked with migrating a Plone site from 5.1 to 5.2 on Python 3. In this case study, we discuss:
* choosing a migration method&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;preparing the site and data, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refining the migration steps to ensure a smooth In-Place migration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/introduction-to-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kenten Danas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/introduction-to-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone with Python knowledge can deploy a workflow using Apache Airflow — a platform created by the community to programmatically author, schedule and monitor workflows. The platform does not limit the scope of your pipelines; you can use it to build ML models, transfer data, manage your infrastructure and more …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone with Python knowledge can deploy a workflow using Apache Airflow — a platform created by the community to programmatically author, schedule and monitor workflows. The platform does not limit the scope of your pipelines; you can use it to build ML models, transfer data, manage your infrastructure and more. During this presentation, Kenten will share use cases and typical integration points/workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Nuclia: AI Search as a Service with OSS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/nuclia-ai-search-as-a-service-with-oss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ramon Navarro Bosch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/nuclia-ai-search-as-a-service-with-oss.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will be separated into four parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVP: How we were able to deliver value based on Guillotina framework for a fast prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data normalization: How we normalize unstructured data, including videos and audios, and extract value from it using NLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NucliaDB: a new open-source, cloud native &amp;amp; multimodal …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will be separated into four parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVP: How we were able to deliver value based on Guillotina framework for a fast prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data normalization: How we normalize unstructured data, including videos and audios, and extract value from it using NLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NucliaDB: a new open-source, cloud native &amp;amp; multimodal indexing database with high reading performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuclia OSS: Our open source plan and how we want to help OSS projects like Fast API, Django, Guillotina, Plone, Flask, Pyramind... to deliver more value. The talk will cover how Nuclia is changing the search industry status quo: It will show how using Nuclia's end-to-end API, is able to index and process any kind of data, including audios and videos, to boost applications with an AI &amp;amp; multi-language semantic search engine. We will specially focus on NucliaDB, the NLP database designed to store non structured information to provide fine grained searchability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Production-Ready Python Serverless Web APIs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/production-ready-python-serverless-web-apis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Raphael Jambalos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/production-ready-python-serverless-web-apis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After weeks of intensive research and a dozen small projects, you have now decided to use Serverless Framework to develop a huge production Python web API and deploy it to AWS Lambda. But how exactly do you transition from the simple app structure you saw in tutorials to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After weeks of intensive research and a dozen small projects, you have now decided to use Serverless Framework to develop a huge production Python web API and deploy it to AWS Lambda. But how exactly do you transition from the simple app structure you saw in tutorials to the mature production-ready form you need? That's exactly the same problem we faced over the past 24 months. In this talk, I will share my team's experience on how we solved this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directory Structure - how to arrange your Python code
* Controllers, Handlers, Helpers, Models, Gateways: Building your app's directories for single responsibility between components
* Multi-repository vs. Single-repository approach: The pros and cons
* Lambdalith (monolith Lambda) vs. Lambda Functions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python development in the context of AWS Lambda
* Don't be afraid to use Exceptions - monitoring your app's performance with the error count in Lambda
* Use print statements deliberately - using CloudWatch to create searchable logs and metric filters to create alarms out of your logs
* Use AWS Lambda Layers to package Python packages with OS Native dependencies (i.e psycopg2, cryptography)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools of the trade: Leveraging AWS Services to reduce the development you have to do in-house and focus on the features that make your client's business stand out
* Lambda - as your compute engine.
* API Gateway - for your routes and data validation
* DynamoDB - as your NoSQL database
* SQS - for your queue service
* Parameter Store - for storing configuration
* Step Functions - orchestrating workflows in AWS
* Cognito - using AWS' ready-made authentication service
* ECS - when your workloads reach past 15mins, turn to ECS containers to finish the job&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black Belt Lambda: using Serverless Framework features to get ahead of Lambda's limitations and ensure best practices
* Using AWS Layers
* Prune your Lambda Applications regularly
* Managing environment variables
* Have a local environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Taming the Monolith and Transitioning to Service Architecture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/taming-the-monolith-and-transitioning-to-service-architecture.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nathan Van Gheem</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/taming-the-monolith-and-transitioning-to-service-architecture.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you built (or inherited) a successful monolith! Well, successful in that you have many customers; however, now problems are everywhere. How do you scale this thing? How do you build teams as your company grows? Come to this talk to learn strategies on navigating the difficulties of scaling …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you built (or inherited) a successful monolith! Well, successful in that you have many customers; however, now problems are everywhere. How do you scale this thing? How do you build teams as your company grows? Come to this talk to learn strategies on navigating the difficulties of scaling a Monolith. Learn about transition strategies and service architecture design patterns to help you scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The 10,000 Steps of Open Source Project Health</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/the-10000-steps-of-open-source-project-health.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dmitry Vinnik</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/the-10000-steps-of-open-source-project-health.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human health is complex - it’s not something we can buy; it’s something we have to earn! This exact approach goes for open source projects and their communities. A truly dedicated and loyal fanbase cannot be bought; it has to be nurtured. But what do we mean when …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human health is complex - it’s not something we can buy; it’s something we have to earn! This exact approach goes for open source projects and their communities. A truly dedicated and loyal fanbase cannot be bought; it has to be nurtured. But what do we mean when we call a community and the open source project &amp;quot;healthy&amp;quot;? This question is what we are trying to answer at Facebook!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will look at the approach that Facebook Open Source team takes to measure the current state of Facebook open source projects, and how we use these metrics to prioritize and to direct our DevRel focus. Ultimately, we aim to show how by looking at information about your open source communities, your team can concentrate on the quality of the projects instead of only the quantity of repositories that you make public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The Growth Mode Playbook for Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/the-growth-mode-playbook-for-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kathy Keating</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/the-growth-mode-playbook-for-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we want to survive and thrive in our roles as developers, there are skills beyond coding that will make us most effective in our roles. These skills are the ones that will help us get promoted, and be seen as highly valuable within our organizations. They are especially …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we want to survive and thrive in our roles as developers, there are skills beyond coding that will make us most effective in our roles. These skills are the ones that will help us get promoted, and be seen as highly valuable within our organizations. They are especially valuable to learn as the companies around use grow - really fast. In this talk, I’ll share my top 10 skills that I practice every day, and encourage my teams of developers to embrace, so that we can all thrive as we, and our companies grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Tutorial: Let's Forget About Excel: Conda + Jupyter + Pandas to leave office behind</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-lets-forget-about-excel-conda-jupyter-pandas-to-leave-office-behind.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Sol</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-lets-forget-about-excel-conda-jupyter-pandas-to-leave-office-behind.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excel? Where we’re going, we don’t need Excel. You can leave Office and the Spreadsheet behind. You can use Python, Conda, Jupiter, and Pandas to quickly load, analyze and export your data in a better way. No more memory limits, strange functions, and manual processes. Let’s …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excel? Where we’re going, we don’t need Excel. You can leave Office and the Spreadsheet behind. You can use Python, Conda, Jupiter, and Pandas to quickly load, analyze and export your data in a better way. No more memory limits, strange functions, and manual processes. Let’s go to the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a 3 hour workshop to give a Python beginner a walk into Pandas. We'll learn:
* How to install Conda for Python, Pandas, and all of its Data processing ecosystem.
* How to use Jupyter Lab and Jupiter Notebooks.
* How to use Pandas for data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About Pandas, including:
* Import and Export data.
* Analyze and clean data.
* Filtering.
* Data Processing.
* Simple plotting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About Jupyter, including:
* Simple Markdown.
* Sharing Notebooks.
* Exporting as HTML or PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Open Earth Observations for Measuring Economic Indicators</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/using-open-earth-observations-for-measuring-economic-indicators.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aakash Gupta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/using-open-earth-observations-for-measuring-economic-indicators.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The alarming speed with which the COVID19 global pandemic spread across the world and the subsequent quarantine &amp;amp; work-from-home (WFH) measures initiated by various governments has created an unprecedented situation. There has been a sharp decline in economic activity and the global GDP is projected to contract by 3% (IMF …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The alarming speed with which the COVID19 global pandemic spread across the world and the subsequent quarantine &amp;amp; work-from-home (WFH) measures initiated by various governments has created an unprecedented situation. There has been a sharp decline in economic activity and the global GDP is projected to contract by 3% (IMF projections April 2020). That is equivalent to $3tn of lost economic output &amp;amp; precious jobs. World Bank believes that the pandemic will also push the poorer section of the society into extreme poverty. However, the pandemic has also given us an opportunity to observe the impact - EO/ Satellite data is being used to quantify the impact on the global economy. We discuss the various methods with which economic activity can be measured. As an example, we will also illustrate how, NO2 data can be extracted from multi-spectral satellite imagery, and highlight changes in pollution levels across major industrial belts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Wagtail Live: Bringing a live blogging tool to the Django ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/wagtail-live-bringing-a-live-blogging-tool-to-the-django-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tidjani Dia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/wagtail-live-bringing-a-live-blogging-tool-to-the-django-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear about the Google Summer of Code 'Wagtail Live' project and experience. Wagtail Live enables reporters to instantly publish to a live blog by submitting messages via apps like Telegram and Slack. The audience can read the posts right away as the live blog page instantly updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear about the Google Summer of Code 'Wagtail Live' project and experience. Wagtail Live enables reporters to instantly publish to a live blog by submitting messages via apps like Telegram and Slack. The audience can read the posts right away as the live blog page instantly updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>We Accidentally Created a Serverless Application</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/we-accidentally-created-a-serverless-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>JJ Asghar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/we-accidentally-created-a-serverless-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will describe our situation, and how we ended up with a serverless application by accident. We talk about where we started, our use case, and how it turns out leveraging FaaS, Python and the Code-Engine Serverless platform we created a system that is surprisingly robust …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will describe our situation, and how we ended up with a serverless application by accident. We talk about where we started, our use case, and how it turns out leveraging FaaS, Python and the Code-Engine Serverless platform we created a system that is surprisingly robust and super cheap to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>You Shall Not Password: Modern Authentication for Web Apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/you-shall-not-password-modern-authentication-for-web-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/you-shall-not-password-modern-authentication-for-web-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the good old days, your users would log into a web app with a username and password. But now people expect an alphabet soup of SSO, 2FA, OAuth, OIDC, SAML, FIDO2, OTP… What do they all mean - and why do they matter? Why is central authentication useful? What …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the good old days, your users would log into a web app with a username and password. But now people expect an alphabet soup of SSO, 2FA, OAuth, OIDC, SAML, FIDO2, OTP… What do they all mean - and why do they matter? Why is central authentication useful? What does two-factor authentication really protect us from, and what’s still wide open? Learn how to keep your users safe as we discuss the good, the bad and the ugly of modern authentication mechanisms for the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll cover what authentication is, common ways of doing it, and common pitfalls. We’ll also cover what makes a web authentication system good, and whether that’s distinct from whether it’s secure (spoiler alert: it is!). Attendees will come away with a sense of what the authentication landscape looks like for modern web apps and why, and a few weird industry factoids to share at dinner parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at anyone passingly familiar with web development, with an interest in security, or who simply wants to know what’s really going on when you ‘sign in with Google.’
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>A Vulnerable Tale About Burnout</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/a-vulnerable-tale-about-burnout.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Julia Simon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/a-vulnerable-tale-about-burnout.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This vulnerable tale is a personal journey through the unpredictable world of burnout and depression. It could have been easily predicted because Julia was &amp;quot;doing it all&amp;quot;. Yet, it was totally unexpected because she assumed her mental health was strong and stable; she could handle anything. Until she couldn …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This vulnerable tale is a personal journey through the unpredictable world of burnout and depression. It could have been easily predicted because Julia was &amp;quot;doing it all&amp;quot;. Yet, it was totally unexpected because she assumed her mental health was strong and stable; she could handle anything. Until she couldn’t and everything became unbearable. She made the impossible and necessary decision to stop working in order to recover, setting out on what became four months of self-discovery. Julia will talk about what led her to this state, what it looked like, and how she was able to get the necessary help to feel strong enough to not only go back to work, but to shift career paths all together: a hopeful and positive outcome that arose out of dark times. Julia will talk about key takeaways that allow her to maintain a healthier balance at work and in life, especially in this all-remote pandemic reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Be the CEO of Your Career</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/be-the-ceo-of-your-career.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Mead</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/be-the-ceo-of-your-career.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does career success mean to you?  How will you achieve it?  In this session, whether you want to climb the corporate ladder or find greater fulfillment in your current role, you’ll learn creative methods to help you achieve your ultimate career success.  We’ll discuss these three …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does career success mean to you?  How will you achieve it?  In this session, whether you want to climb the corporate ladder or find greater fulfillment in your current role, you’ll learn creative methods to help you achieve your ultimate career success.  We’ll discuss these three questions:
* What do you want?  Defining success in your terms
* How do you win? Mastering the “career behaviors” that matter most
* Why does it matter? Creating your legacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a Sign-to-Speech prototype with TensorFlow and DeepStack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/building-a-sign-to-speech-prototype-with-tensorflow-and-deepstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steven Kolawole</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/building-a-sign-to-speech-prototype-with-tensorflow-and-deepstack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I built an end-to-end working prototype that uses Computer Vision to detect sign language meanings in images/live videos and generate equivalent, realistic voice of words communicated by the sign language, while also using Machine Translation to map the returned texts to local African languages (in progress), all in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I built an end-to-end working prototype that uses Computer Vision to detect sign language meanings in images/live videos and generate equivalent, realistic voice of words communicated by the sign language, while also using Machine Translation to map the returned texts to local African languages (in progress), all in real-time. It was fun. And it was stressful too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’d talk about the highs and lows of working on this project while also elaborating on the groundwork, the process, the results, and the future scope of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous knowledge expected Machine Learning, Deep Learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Interactive Apps in Python with Streamlit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/building-interactive-apps-in-python-with-streamlit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Banjo Obayomi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/building-interactive-apps-in-python-with-streamlit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing full stack web applications can be an exhaustive process, with having to manage both frontend and backend development. For python developers frameworks like Django take time to learn and come with many bells and whistles that may not be needed for simple applications. Streamlit is a framework that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing full stack web applications can be an exhaustive process, with having to manage both frontend and backend development. For python developers frameworks like Django take time to learn and come with many bells and whistles that may not be needed for simple applications. Streamlit is a framework that blends raw python code with a simple API that turns scripts into shareable web apps in minutes., without needed any front end experience. This talk will walk through creating a Streamlit app and showing off how flexible the framework is for building solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Stateful Workloads in Kubernetes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/building-stateful-workloads-in-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Richardson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/building-stateful-workloads-in-kubernetes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s day 2. Kubernetes is running. You have your deployments and services set. Now how do you migrate the data store? Let’s journey together on this code-focused tour through Persistent Volumes, Persistent Volume Claims, and StatefulSets. We’ll craft and launch a strategy to care for your …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s day 2. Kubernetes is running. You have your deployments and services set. Now how do you migrate the data store? Let’s journey together on this code-focused tour through Persistent Volumes, Persistent Volume Claims, and StatefulSets. We’ll craft and launch a strategy to care for your users’ data in this new container world. You can power your business on Kubernetes: stateless or stateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s (relatively) easy to build stateless web properties in containers, but it’s a much different beast to build data stores in Kubernetes. We’ll disambiguate PV, PVC, and Stateful Sets in simple ways so you can get past this next hurdle of K8s knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Choose Your Own (QA) Adventure</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/choose-your-own-qa-adventure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dana Scheider</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/choose-your-own-qa-adventure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every organisation needs quality processes in place to ensure the software it produces is maintainable and satisfies customer needs. But what to do when your organisation doesn’t have, or can’t have, a dedicated QA team? You’re in luck. This talk covers everything you’ll need to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every organisation needs quality processes in place to ensure the software it produces is maintainable and satisfies customer needs. But what to do when your organisation doesn’t have, or can’t have, a dedicated QA team? You’re in luck. This talk covers everything you’ll need to know to not only adopt quality processes within your development teams, but to create an organisational culture conducive to releasing reliable, maintainable, and consistently high quality software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a former QE now working as a developer. I’ve been responsible for making quality process recommendations that have now been adopted across my organisation. This talk covers a combination of quality engineering skills engineers may not have developed yet, as well as processes like TDD and code review that contribute to quality while also being more traditionally in the purview of developers. This talk uses Total Quality Management (TQM) as a model for software quality processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Computational Thinking for Creatives - Decoding Barriers to Entry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/computational-thinking-for-creatives-decoding-barriers-to-entry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/computational-thinking-for-creatives-decoding-barriers-to-entry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;1:00 What is computational thinking
2:00 Why understanding computational thinking can help coding problem solving
4:00 How to bridge the gap of learning to code for creatives like designers
8:00 Establishing the thought process of sequential problem solving
16:00 Prepare people to understand how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;1:00 What is computational thinking
2:00 Why understanding computational thinking can help coding problem solving
4:00 How to bridge the gap of learning to code for creatives like designers
8:00 Establishing the thought process of sequential problem solving
16:00 Prepare people to understand how to abstract problems down into steps
24:00 Use visual aides and diagrams to help visual learners understand key concepts of computational thinking
30:00 With patterns people can build the basis for creating algorithms
34:00 Goals of creating training to learn to code while being mindful of different learning styles
36:00 The results including how people were able to get a handle on coding due to computational thinking
40:00 Review Key points and lessons learned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Daily Mindfulness: How Breathing and Movement can Make a Difference</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/daily-mindfulness-how-breathing-and-movement-can-make-a-difference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>JuliaSimon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/daily-mindfulness-how-breathing-and-movement-can-make-a-difference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has taken its toll on our collective mental health, as stress and anxiety have been at a collective all-time high. Join this interactive session to learn some very simple techniques that can make all the difference in helping us feel more grounded and centered. Breathing and movement …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has taken its toll on our collective mental health, as stress and anxiety have been at a collective all-time high. Join this interactive session to learn some very simple techniques that can make all the difference in helping us feel more grounded and centered. Breathing and movement help us move energy through our bodies enabling us to calm our nervous system and approach our daily lives with a greater sense of balance and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Federated Learning in Computer Vision</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/federated-learning-in-computer-vision.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aditya Lohia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/federated-learning-in-computer-vision.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While researchers have been advancing computer vision algorithms month by month, developers face the problem of training and deploying those same algorithms in the real world. Often, the reason behind low accuracies is accounted for by the low quantity and quality of data available for the problem. Over the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While researchers have been advancing computer vision algorithms month by month, developers face the problem of training and deploying those same algorithms in the real world. Often, the reason behind low accuracies is accounted for by the low quantity and quality of data available for the problem. Over the past few months, federated learning has been the talk of the town because of its promising future in computer vision. What is federated learning? How to use it? Is it possible to deploy federated learning solutions in the real world? The main focus of this talk will be to demonstrate why, where, and how to use federated learning in computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Functional Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/functional-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Vujic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/functional-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How functional is Python? Is functional programming even applicable with the idea of writing Pythonic code, or the Zen of Python? These things have been on my mind lately, since I have switched from Clojure to writing full time Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share my thoughts and ideas on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How functional is Python? Is functional programming even applicable with the idea of writing Pythonic code, or the Zen of Python? These things have been on my mind lately, since I have switched from Clojure to writing full time Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share my thoughts and ideas on how to find a possible way to be both Pythonic, and Functional. I will demo how to get super fast feedback loops during development by using a thing called REPL Driven Development, keeping it Pythonic while adding functional patterns like Railway Oriented Programming, and demo some really cool Python specific tools such as the toolz library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Make the Most of Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/make-the-most-of-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paolo Melchiorre</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/make-the-most-of-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is one of the longest running open source web frameworks but despite this it is still one of the best around and continues to be actively developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching such software can be intimidating to a novice developer as well as an experienced one because it is the result …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is one of the longest running open source web frameworks but despite this it is still one of the best around and continues to be actively developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching such software can be intimidating to a novice developer as well as an experienced one because it is the result of over 15 years of excellent developers work and it would take a long time to get to know it thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will see together the way I found for anyone to take full advantage of Django while contributing to its success and that of its community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Stirring the Pot: How to Leverage Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/stirring-the-pot-how-to-leverage-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matt Harrison</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/stirring-the-pot-how-to-leverage-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is Machine Learning and how can I leverage it? Machine learning is taking over the world and a lot of it is done with Python. This talk will introduce the concepts behind machine learning and then show how to implement them with the scikit-learn library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is Machine Learning and how can I leverage it? Machine learning is taking over the world and a lot of it is done with Python. This talk will introduce the concepts behind machine learning and then show how to implement them with the scikit-learn library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Tutorial: End-to-End Testing with Playwright</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-end-to-end-testing-with-playwright.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Knight</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-end-to-end-testing-with-playwright.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody gets frustrated when web apps are broken, but testing them thoroughly doesn't need to be a chore. Playwright, a new open-source browser automation tool from Microsoft, makes testing web apps fun! Playwright outperforms other tools like Selenium WebDriver with a slew of nifty features like automatic waiting, mobile …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody gets frustrated when web apps are broken, but testing them thoroughly doesn't need to be a chore. Playwright, a new open-source browser automation tool from Microsoft, makes testing web apps fun! Playwright outperforms other tools like Selenium WebDriver with a slew of nifty features like automatic waiting, mobile emulation, and network interception. Plus, with isolated browser contexts, Playwright tests can set up * much* faster than traditional Web UI tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will build a Python test automation project from the ground up. We will automate web search engine tests together step-by-step using Playwright for interactions and pytest for execution. We'll also explore Playwright tricks like cross-browser testing, capturing videos, and even running tests in parallel! By the end of this tutorial, you'll be empowered to test modern web apps with modern web test tools. You'll also have an example project to be the foundation for your future tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Reproducible Experiments to Create Better Machine Learning Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/using-reproducible-experiments-to-create-better-machine-learning-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Milecia McGregor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/using-reproducible-experiments-to-create-better-machine-learning-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you start exploring multiple model architectures with different hyperparameter values, you need a way to quickly iterate. There are a lot of ways to handle this, but all of them require time and you might not be able to go back to a particular point to resume or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you start exploring multiple model architectures with different hyperparameter values, you need a way to quickly iterate. There are a lot of ways to handle this, but all of them require time and you might not be able to go back to a particular point to resume or restart training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how you can use the open-source tool, DVC, to compare training metrics using two methods for tuning hyperparameters: grid search and random search. You’ll learn how you can save and track the changes in your data, code, and metrics without adding a lot of commits to your Git history. This approach will scale with your data and projects and make sure that your team can reproduce results easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Wagtail CMS: Past, present and future</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/wagtail-cms-past-present-and-future.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phil Dexter</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/wagtail-cms-past-present-and-future.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear about Wagtail's growth, interesting use cases, clients and sponsors, what's coming up on the roadmap and ways to get involved with the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear about Wagtail's growth, interesting use cases, clients and sponsors, what's coming up on the roadmap and ways to get involved with the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Should Developers Care About Container Security?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/why-should-developers-care-about-container-security.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eric Smalling</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/why-should-developers-care-about-container-security.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Container scanning tools, industry publications, and application security experts are constantly telling us about best practices for how to build our images and run our containers. Often these non-functional requirements seem abstract and are not described well enough for those of us that don’t have an appsec background …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Container scanning tools, industry publications, and application security experts are constantly telling us about best practices for how to build our images and run our containers. Often these non-functional requirements seem abstract and are not described well enough for those of us that don’t have an appsec background to fully understand why they are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go over several of the most common practices to best containerize Python applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;show examples of how your application can be exploited in a container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and most importantly, how to easily spot issues and fix your Dockerfiles and deployment manifests before you commit your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Zero to Production-Ready: A Best-Practices Process for Docker Packaging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/zero-to-production-ready-a-best-practices-process-for-docker-packaging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Itamar Turner-Trauring</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/zero-to-production-ready-a-best-practices-process-for-docker-packaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it’s time to package your Python application for Docker, there are a whole lot of best practices to follow: my personal list has 70 best practices and it keeps growing. As a result, it can be unclear what’s important, what’s not, where to start, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it’s time to package your Python application for Docker, there are a whole lot of best practices to follow: my personal list has 70 best practices and it keeps growing. As a result, it can be unclear what’s important, what’s not, where to start, and what to put off until later. If you’re not careful, you can get distracted by optimizing your Docker image size, and neglect to make your image secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying problem is that Docker packaging is complicated: it’s at the intersection of multiple organizational processes, from development, to deployment, to debugging, to upgrades. Add on 50 years of technology development going back to early Unix design decisions, and the result is a huge number of details to get right, many of which interact with each other in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, once you understand how Docker packaging fits in with all the development and operational processes you’re already doing, those details become a lot less daunting. In particular, by following a structured iterative process for creating your Docker packaging artifacts (Dockerfile etc.), you can think through the decisions you’ll need to make, figure out which new processes you need to start implementing, and make sure you’ve implemented the important details first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help you take control of your packaging, this talk will cover an iterative six-step process for packaging an application with Docker, starting with security and ending up with optimizations like build time and image size, along with a few examples of some of the relevant best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>An Imposter is Among Us (pretty sure it’s me…): Fighting Imposter Syndrome</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/an-imposter-is-among-us-pretty-sure-its-me-fighting-imposter-syndrome.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elizabeth Gray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/an-imposter-is-among-us-pretty-sure-its-me-fighting-imposter-syndrome.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning about Imposter Syndrome for the first time was like hearing someone describe my entire life. There was a TERM for what I was feeling! A term for not feeling good enough, a definition for those times when you feel like you don’t belong where you are. What …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning about Imposter Syndrome for the first time was like hearing someone describe my entire life. There was a TERM for what I was feeling! A term for not feeling good enough, a definition for those times when you feel like you don’t belong where you are. What no one ever explained to me was how do you keep these feelings from impeding your success? Are there methods to help combat feeling like a failure? Come with me on a journey to identify the target, find tools that work for you, and then use your knowledge to help others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the Target
What is Imposter Syndrome and who does it effect? There can be many ways that Imposter Syndrome manifests. In fact, some of you may suffer from a symptom of imposter syndrome and not even realize it. These symptoms, recognized or not, can then create behaviors that demean individual talents and efforts in order to protect you. Recognizing these harmful behaviors and thought patterns can help create a better atmosphere both for the individual and for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the Tools
Now that we can identify some elements of Imposter Syndrome, we need to find tools and methods to help keep the feelings at bay. Are there methods that can help you recognize when you or someone else is experiencing these types of feelings? Ways to create a better atmosphere to help teammate who may be struggling? Find strategies and tricks to keep Imposter Syndrome from impeding success, both in your daily life and in your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using your Powers for Good (Or Evil, I don’t judge)
Now that we know what we are dealing with, how can we use this knowledge to better our personal lives and the lives of our team? Can we identify some of the behaviors we engage in that may be a trigger for others suffering with Imposter Syndrome? What does it look like, when we come together as a community to create a safe area where no one feels out of place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Apache Pulsar Development 101 with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/apache-pulsar-development-101-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Timothy Spann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/apache-pulsar-development-101-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session I will get you started with real-time cloud native streaming programming with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start off with a gentle introduction to Apache Pulsar and setting up your first easy standalone cluster. We will then l show you how to produce and consume message to Pulsar …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session I will get you started with real-time cloud native streaming programming with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start off with a gentle introduction to Apache Pulsar and setting up your first easy standalone cluster. We will then l show you how to produce and consume message to Pulsar using several different Python libraries including Python client, websockets, MQTT and even Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this session you will be building real-time streaming and messaging applications with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Applications of Natural Language Processing Across Several Industry Verticals</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/applications-of-natural-language-processing-across-several-industry-verticals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/applications-of-natural-language-processing-across-several-industry-verticals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability of a machine to understand human language. NLP is a popular field of data science and is widely used across different industry verticals to solve for various challenges. This talk will highlight NLP, what it is and will follow into how 5 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability of a machine to understand human language. NLP is a popular field of data science and is widely used across different industry verticals to solve for various challenges. This talk will highlight NLP, what it is and will follow into how 5+ industries use NLP to solve for their use cases. The industries include retail, finance, real estate, entertainment, marketing and more. This talk will then progress into some practical implementations of the common industrial solutions that are widely used across the globe today. These applications include building or chatbots, automated customer service solutions and recommendation engines. Furthermore, using open-source libraries to build these NLP utilizations will be discussed and presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Greener</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/building-greener.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Jones</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/building-greener.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a growing number of industries turn their focus on climate change, innovating in order to do their part on the journey to Net Zero - how does software engineering fit into this picture, with the industry handcuffed to its consumption of resources?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will dive into …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a growing number of industries turn their focus on climate change, innovating in order to do their part on the journey to Net Zero - how does software engineering fit into this picture, with the industry handcuffed to its consumption of resources?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will dive into the various resources required to develop and host modern software, some of the innovative ways in which large organisations like Microsoft are reducing their resource consumption, as well as the ways in which we can reduce our impact on the environment through architectural choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>CI/CD with Python: From Code to Cloud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/cicd-with-python-from-code-to-cloud.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Keler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/cicd-with-python-from-code-to-cloud.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During our session we'll be taking our Python Code to the Cloud. We'll be building a containerized Python Application, passing through security and compliance gates all the way to our Kubernetes cluster using Helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During our session we'll be taking our Python Code to the Cloud. We'll be building a containerized Python Application, passing through security and compliance gates all the way to our Kubernetes cluster using Helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Continuously Deliver Content to my Blog with Markdown, GitHub, Python, and Netlify</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/continuously-deliver-content-to-my-blog-with-markdown-github-python-and-netlify.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Waylon Walker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/continuously-deliver-content-to-my-blog-with-markdown-github-python-and-netlify.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After being sick of long and broken builds from my javascript-based static site generator I decided it was time to switch to a language I was far more comfortable in. At the time I was really interested in learning how to build my own frameworks with pluggy, so a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After being sick of long and broken builds from my javascript-based static site generator I decided it was time to switch to a language I was far more comfortable in. At the time I was really interested in learning how to build my own frameworks with pluggy, so a new static site generator was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markata was born
The idea of markata is a plugins all the way down static site generator at the intersection of markdown and data. It comes with 6 defines lifecycle methods, 21 pre-defined plugins, a cache store built on diskcahe, and a configuration system. Creating new functionality is as easy as making as decorating lifecycle functions with a markata lifecycle method and adding it to the list of active plugins in your markata.toml.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 lifecycle methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21 pre-defined plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cache store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;toml based configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown
All of the content on this site is written in markdown and always has been. Moving to the new site I chose to use pymdown-extensions so that I could potentially use some of their great existing extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluggy
Comes from pytest and allows users to easily modify the framework to their liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diskcache
Markata defines a diskcache cache for you. Markata provides a convenience function to help make your own unique cache key consistently. Plugins can access the cache, add to it, and set their own expiration interval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuration
Everything is in toml.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub Actions
Rendering the site inside of github actions with the cache is pretty straightforward with these four steps. Keying off of the configuration will bust the cache every time we change the configuration. You can hack a full rebuild by changing anything inside of the configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I deploy to netlify but any static site host would work.
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Greater Relationships Lead to Greater Results!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/greater-relationships-lead-to-greater-results.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Gingerich &amp; Tom Kaden</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/greater-relationships-lead-to-greater-results.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how listening well – by leaning in, being interested, simplifying your schedule, talking less, asking good questions, and negotiating the win/win - improves communication, creates empathy and connection, and leads to greater results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how listening well – by leaning in, being interested, simplifying your schedule, talking less, asking good questions, and negotiating the win/win - improves communication, creates empathy and connection, and leads to greater results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Implementing Strong Data Encryption in Python Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/implementing-strong-data-encryption-in-python-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sam Craig</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/implementing-strong-data-encryption-in-python-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data encryption is essential for the modern business. It’s necessary for preventing data breaches, achieving regulatory compliance, and minimizing risk to customers, shareholders, and the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that most data encryption solutions are a band-aid that doesn’t meet a business’s actual needs. Encrypting data …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data encryption is essential for the modern business. It’s necessary for preventing data breaches, achieving regulatory compliance, and minimizing risk to customers, shareholders, and the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that most data encryption solutions are a band-aid that doesn’t meet a business’s actual needs. Encrypting data at some point in its lifecycle provides no benefit if the data is unencrypted when an attacker tries to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses the limitations of common encryption schemes and the threats that they do and don’t protect against. After discussing what doesn’t work, we’ll look at how to implement encryption that actually works in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Inclusion &amp; Community in the Face of Crisis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/inclusion-community-in-the-face-of-crisis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/inclusion-community-in-the-face-of-crisis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python communities around the world are confronting uncertainty and unanswered questions as a series of crises have unfolded over the past two years. In this talk I would like to reflect on how we can preserve a sense of community in the face of crisis. As we emerge into …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python communities around the world are confronting uncertainty and unanswered questions as a series of crises have unfolded over the past two years. In this talk I would like to reflect on how we can preserve a sense of community in the face of crisis. As we emerge into a post-Covid-19 world, and as we deal with the human and economic consequences of a new war, what challenges might we all face in the future? How can we build and foster community and still keep everyone safe? What are our sources of optimism and hope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Instant Self-Contained Development Environments for Everyone</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/instant-self-contained-development-environments-for-everyone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yshay Yaacobi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/instant-self-contained-development-environments-for-everyone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has become increasingly difficult &amp;amp; time consuming to start working on a new codebase, especially in a polyglot microservice world. Using several patterns &amp;amp; developer containers we can create an amazing developer experience that will allow anyone to instantly deep-dive into coding on any machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has become increasingly difficult &amp;amp; time consuming to start working on a new codebase, especially in a polyglot microservice world. Using several patterns &amp;amp; developer containers we can create an amazing developer experience that will allow anyone to instantly deep-dive into coding on any machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the concept of a self-contained repository - a repository that contains all relevant information for workstation/dependency configuration, build, debug, CI/CD, secrets (encrypted), docs and more that reside in the repository. We’ll explore the idea of a development container and how we can use free OSS technologies (like Git Docker &amp;amp; Docker Compose, Kubernetes, GPG, VSCode, Tilt…) to create a stable development environment that works out-of-the-box and provides all the power, speed and capabilities of modern development &amp;amp; cloud native tooling. Live code examples will be showcased as part of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Adding RSS... YES!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-adding-rss-yes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mario Munoz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-adding-rss-yes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Compost Everything!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-compost-everything.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-compost-everything.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: DateTime vs datetime</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-datetime-vs-datetime.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael McFadden</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-datetime-vs-datetime.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: From Markdown to Blog with Markata</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-from-markdown-to-blog-with-markata.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Waylon Walker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-from-markdown-to-blog-with-markata.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: How I downloaded the entire Steam database through GitHub actions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-how-i-downloaded-the-entire-steam-database-through-github-actions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Falk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-how-i-downloaded-the-entire-steam-database-through-github-actions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Sciagraph: always-on profiling for production batch jobs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-sciagraph-always-on-profiling-for-production-batch-jobs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Itamar Turner-Trauring</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-sciagraph-always-on-profiling-for-production-batch-jobs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Solar Eclipse Data Collection with Raspberry Pis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-solar-eclipse-data-collection-with-raspberry-pis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Malynda Chizek Frouard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-solar-eclipse-data-collection-with-raspberry-pis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Malware Hunting-Using Python as Attack Weapon</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/malware-hunting-using-python-as-attack-weapon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Filipi Pires</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/malware-hunting-using-python-as-attack-weapon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working as Security Researcher at Saporo…I’m Hacking is NOT a crime Advocate and RedTeam Village Contributor. I’m part of the Staff team of DEFCON Group São Paulo-Brazil, International Speakers in Security and New technologies events in many countries such as US, Canada, Germany …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working as Security Researcher at Saporo…I’m Hacking is NOT a crime Advocate and RedTeam Village Contributor. I’m part of the Staff team of DEFCON Group São Paulo-Brazil, International Speakers in Security and New technologies events in many countries such as US, Canada, Germany, Poland, and others. I’ve served as University Professor in Graduation and MBA courses at Brazilian colleges. In addition, I’m Creator and Instructor of the Course Malware Attack Types with Kill Chain Methodology (PentestMagazine) and Malware Analysis - Fundamentals (HackerSec ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Modern, Fully Featured Open Source Video and Media CMS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/modern-fully-featured-open-source-video-and-media-cms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Markos Gogoulos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/modern-fully-featured-open-source-video-and-media-cms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With MediaCMS, a modern and open-source CMS built in Django/React, you can create your own YouTube style video portal in just a few minutes — and self-host your content! In this presentation and live demo, I’ll:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;showcase MediaCMS’ functionality through a demo installation,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discuss uses cases,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;share a …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With MediaCMS, a modern and open-source CMS built in Django/React, you can create your own YouTube style video portal in just a few minutes — and self-host your content! In this presentation and live demo, I’ll:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;showcase MediaCMS’ functionality through a demo installation,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discuss uses cases,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;share a road map of future development, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review the CMS’ architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will also feature best practices for organizing an open-source project to facilitate cooperation and contributions. We’ll also explore different options towards sustainability of an open-source project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Origami</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/origami.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Annette Lewis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/origami.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Playwright Comes to Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/playwright-comes-to-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrey Lushnikov &amp; Max Schmitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/playwright-comes-to-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Andrey Lushnikov. I’m a Principal Engineer at Microsoft, former Chrome DevTools engineer and Chrome Puppeteer technical lead with over 11 years of experience in software engineering. Today, I’m a member of the Playwright core team. Playwright was first released in 2020 and has …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Andrey Lushnikov. I’m a Principal Engineer at Microsoft, former Chrome DevTools engineer and Chrome Puppeteer technical lead with over 11 years of experience in software engineering. Today, I’m a member of the Playwright core team. Playwright was first released in 2020 and has been dominating JavaScript cross-browser testing ever since. Now, Playwright comes to Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome, Firefox &amp;amp; Safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows, Linux &amp;amp; MacOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unmatched functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beautiful built-in tooling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free &amp;amp; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too good? Come see yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll spend an imaginary month with Playwright for Python. On day 1, we’ll set up reliable, cross-browser, end-to-end tests using Playwright for Python in less than 60 seconds. On day 3, we’ll learn how to easily author end-to-end tests using Playwright codegen feature. On day 7, we’ll debug our first test using Playwright Inspector. On day 30, we’ll use Playwright Tracing to analyze a test that fails exclusively on CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, we’ll also learn about the framework’s unique APIs and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the journey, you’ll be comfortable to start using Playwright for Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Coding Mistakes, Causes of Vulnerabilities and How to Solve It!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/python-coding-mistakes-causes-of-vulnerabilities-and-how-to-solve-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Van Der Made</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/python-coding-mistakes-causes-of-vulnerabilities-and-how-to-solve-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will have a look at common mistakes in Python that can cause serious code vulnerabilities. We will subsequently have a look at what those vulnerabilities can cause and how you can get “hacked”. We will also discuss how developer and security teams struggle to talk …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will have a look at common mistakes in Python that can cause serious code vulnerabilities. We will subsequently have a look at what those vulnerabilities can cause and how you can get “hacked”. We will also discuss how developer and security teams struggle to talk in a common language to prevent and mitigate those vulnerabilities. Lastly, we will see how you can prevent and mitigate them in real-life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Securing Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/securing-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/securing-django-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications, b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding, and c) lack of awareness of secure first web …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications, b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding, and c) lack of awareness of secure first web applications among developers. The vulnerable web applications put the data of the customers at greater risk and the compromised code can lead to problems beyond control. It is very important to develop secure web applications to protect customer data and code to mitigate the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will focus on two aspects. First, performing penetration testing on Django web applications to identify vulnerabilities and scanning for Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) Top 10 risks. Second, strategies and configuration settings for making the source code and Django applications secure. We will also discuss the Djangohunter tool to identify incorrectly configured Django applications that are exposing sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security aspects of Django web applications (03 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Penetration testing of Django web applications (07 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of OWASP Top 10 risks (10 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Djangohunter tool demonstration (06 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategies and configuration settings to make Django Application secure (10 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion and Questions (04 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Towards Reliability</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/towards-reliability.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jayesh Ahire</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/towards-reliability.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applications are evolving continuously. In modern cloud-native microservice architecture-based applications, finding out if your application is reliable or not is hard. Being able to Observe your system doesn't really mean it's reliable. In this talk, we will learn about how to make your software more reliable, touch base on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applications are evolving continuously. In modern cloud-native microservice architecture-based applications, finding out if your application is reliable or not is hard. Being able to Observe your system doesn't really mean it's reliable. In this talk, we will learn about how to make your software more reliable, touch base on the concept of SLOs, and see a demo of how we can easily collect telemetry data and ensure the reliability of a Python-based microservice application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Tutorial: Idiomatic Pandas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-idiomatic-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matt Harrison</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/tutorial-idiomatic-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas can make it quick and easy to slice and dice your data. But what if you need to come back to your manipulations? How do you track data from end to end? How do you write code that you can share with your colleagues? How do you write …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas can make it quick and easy to slice and dice your data. But what if you need to come back to your manipulations? How do you track data from end to end? How do you write code that you can share with your colleagues? How do you write code that you will understand later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>