<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>7 Years With Django: To Core Developer and Back</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/7-years-with-django-to-core-developer-and-back.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One night, in September 2007, I read every page of Django's
documentation and the entire (then draft) Django Book. Over the next few
years I became a frequent contributor to Django, including becoming a
core developer and later a member of the DSF board. Now I'm largely
uninvolved with Django's development. This talk is the story of my time
with Django. This talk is a walk through my time with Django -- from
emailing Adrian to ask about attending a sprint that had already
happened, to contributing patches, to the multi-db GSOC, to Eric
Florenzano's keynote, becoming a core developer, joining the board, to
slowly fading away and becoming an emeritus developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Gaynor</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/7-years-with-django-to-core-developer-and-back.html</guid></item><item><title>A More Accessible Django Girls</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/a-more-accessible-django-girls.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appropriate planning and accommodations make Django Girls workshops and
other tech events more open to many groups, including people with
disabilities, Deaf attendees, attendees with mental illnesses, and more.
You'll leave this talk with some concrete things you can do to make your
next meetup, workshop, or conference more inclusive of people with
disabilities, including how to advertise your accommodations, what to
look for in a venue, and some free tools to help your website be more
accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lacey Williams Henschel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/a-more-accessible-django-girls.html</guid></item><item><title>Born in (the) #LFK</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/born-in-the-lfk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s fitting that we gather in Lawrence, Kansas, to celebrate the 10th
birthday of Django, developed and first put to use in the basement of
what was once a US Post Office in downtown Lawrence. After all, as I
hope to show, our lovely #LFK has a history of influencing the wider
world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Ryan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/born-in-the-lfk.html</guid></item><item><title>Development Milestones: 1.0 Onwards</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/development-milestones-10-onwards.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every release, Django adds some more headline features which let us get
work done. We'll take a quick look at the major releases, the headline
features they shipped, and wonder how we ever wrote a site with Django
1.0.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marc Tamlyn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/development-milestones-10-onwards.html</guid></item><item><title>Django Built a Nonprofit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/django-built-a-nonprofit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2008, the Sunlight Foundation is a nonprofit that uses the
civic tech to make government more accountable and transparent. From a
single Drupal site, to an organization powered by Django, we’ll tell the
story of how a Python web framework built a successful nonprofit. The
history of our open source Django apps tell the story of a growing
organization and an open government movement. We'll cover various Django
apps we have published and how each reflected the state of our
organization, the open government community, or Django at the time they
were created.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Turk</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/django-built-a-nonprofit.html</guid></item><item><title>Django Regrets</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/django-regrets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the benefit of hindsight, here are a bunch of things I've regretted
about doing, and not doing, in helping develop Django. Learn from my
mistakes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrian Holovaty</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/django-regrets.html</guid></item><item><title>Django: The Conspiracy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/django-the-conspiracy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ten years after the project known as &amp;quot;Django&amp;quot; was released to the
public, there are still unanswered questions. Why did one of the
original authors flee the country? What happened to all the removed
magic? And, more importantly, why are there secret messages hidden in
the template parser's regular expressions? I'll be attempting to throw
light on some of the dark secrets of Django and, perhaps, finally divine
its true purpose, after almost a decade of searching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Godwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/django-the-conspiracy.html</guid></item><item><title>Documentation as Empathy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/documentation-as-empathy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover my view of documentation within programming culture
as it has grown over the years. As a primary person involved with Read
the Docs, and Write the Docs, I have seen a lot of angles, and
appreciate documentation more every year. I believe better documentation
is a fundamental aspect of how we can improve programming culture, and
an often misunderstood part of outreach and education. Read the Docs
started in Lawrence, and has grown from there. This seems like the
perfect venue to wax poetic about why documentation matters, and tell
the story of Read the Docs along the way. The Django community is one
where documentation has always been valued, and I think that
understanding how it lead to its success and why it's an important
virtue going forward is important. This talk will make you think more
deeply about the social impact of documentation, and hopefully make you
question if it should be a higher priority in your development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Holscher</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/documentation-as-empathy.html</guid></item><item><title>Give a Python a Pony</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/give-a-python-a-pony.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was faced with one of the scariest situations
there is for a self-employed developer: I was burned out. The blinking
cursor in Vim was taunting me and no number of GitHub issues could
motivate me to churn out more than a few lines of code in a day. This
burnout, though, led me back to an early love: I started teaching full
time.This is a talk in two parts. In part one, I’ll talk about some of
the teaching triumphs I’ve had and witnessed thanks to a new career, the
Python and Django worlds, and my employer, Treehouse (and others!). In
the second part, I’ll share ways you can start teaching in your own
communities and using your own talents, so we can all make the world
better through learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kenneth Love</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/give-a-python-a-pony.html</guid></item><item><title>How Django Is Good For Your Health</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/how-django-is-good-for-your-health.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You know Django as the web framework behind sites like Instagram and
Pinterest, but Django is used in many places now. One such place is the
pharmaceutical industry, which is the definition of large corporate
enterprises. Drug discovery is an immensely hard and expensive
challenge. Believe it or not Django can play a meaningful role in that
endeavor and ultimately be good for your health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Bruce</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/how-django-is-good-for-your-health.html</guid></item><item><title>Open Source Community Organizing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/open-source-community-organizing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stories and tips from creating new communities and steering established
ones in new directions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mikeal Rogers</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/open-source-community-organizing.html</guid></item><item><title>Snakes, Ponies and Balloons: Stories of Teaching Django to Thousands of Women</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/snakes-ponies-and-balloons-stories-of-teaching.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django Girls is a workshop for total beginners into the world of web
building. Started by two Polish girls in Berlin and now organized all
over the world in 45 cities, Django Girls aim to inspire women to fell
in love with programming. Ola will share with you how she went from not
knowing anything about teaching programming or feminism, to knowing a
little bit more thanks to thousands of people who participated in the
workshop formula Django Girls created. You'll learn the secrets of
explaining the Internet, servers or Django ORM to people who never done
this before. And how to find 100+ women who want to learn to code just
about anywhere. This talk is your introduction to the world of getting
girls excited about snakes, ponies and balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ola Sitarska</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/snakes-ponies-and-balloons-stories-of-teaching.html</guid></item><item><title>Django Origins (and some things I have built with Django)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/some-things-ive-made-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How &amp;quot;The CMS&amp;quot; became Django and then what happened later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simon Willison</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/some-things-ive-made-with-django.html</guid></item><item><title>The Mysterious Django Community in Mexico</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/django-birthday/the-mysterious-django-community-in-mexico.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I set out to bring Django Girls to the city of Tijuana, I never
expected to find so many programmers. Even more unexpected was a small
group of Python/Django developers I found, passionate about kickstarting
the Python community in Baja California. As Django Girls (and later,
Django Girls Ensenada) came and went, I learned more about the Django
community in other cities of Mexico, including the reason why I never
heard of them before organizing the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrea Gonzalez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-11:django-birthday/the-mysterious-django-community-in-mexico.html</guid></item></channel></rss>