<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - PyLadiesCon 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Build Your First LLM-based Application with Haystack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/build-your-first-llm-based-application-with-haystack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is advancing at an unprecedented pace, with new large language models (LLMs) emerging almost daily. These models, coupled with innovative ideas, revolutionize how we build applications. However, for software developers, entering the field of NLP can be overwhelming because of all new NLP concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haystack is an open-source Python framework designed to empower developers in building LLM applications using the latest language models and state-of-the-art NLP approaches by providing all the tools you need. Haystack's composable pipeline system and LLM-based building components open up a world of possibilities, enabling generative question answering, document retrieval, chatbots, and much more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll begin with a high-level overview of key NLP concepts, including vector databases, document preprocessing, word embeddings, LLMs, and prompting. This will lay the groundwork for understanding the core concepts required to develop applications powered by LLMs. Once we've explored these fundamental concepts, we’ll combine them together to create a generative question-answering application tailored for custom documents using Haystack. By end of this talk, you'll have a solid grasp of NLP basics and learn how to use it for your needs in your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bilge Yücel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/build-your-first-llm-based-application-with-haystack.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Cache me if you can: Boosting performance with Data Caching in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/cache-me-if-you-can-boosting-performance-with-data-caching-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the joys of data caching in Python and how it can turbocharge your code's performance. We'll dive deep into caching, explaining what it is and why it's crucial for optimizing code performance. We'll discuss various caching techniques and approaches, so you can take away practical knowledge on how to implement caching in Python.
And wait, there's more! We'll also cover bottlenecks and things to consider when implementing caching to ensure optimal performance.
By the end of this talk, you'll have a newfound appreciation for the power of caching and will be amazed at how easy it is to get started with caching. If you want to say &amp;quot;goodbye&amp;quot; to long load times and &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; to efficient programming- this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Bhatia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/cache-me-if-you-can-boosting-performance-with-data-caching-in-python.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Collaboration Infrastructure in Data Science: Tools, Challenges, and Best Practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/collaboration-infrastructure-in-data-science-tools-challenges-and-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have mature collaboration tools in the PyData ecosystem like JupyterHub for shared infrastructure, conda for package &amp;amp; environment management, and Dask for distributed computing. However, the process for setting-up and using a platform with all these tools requires in-depth knowledge of these tools. This talk hopes to discuss some friendly solutions for collaborative practices like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing ongoing work, visualizations, and dashboards with reproducible environments
Designing for scalability (distributed compute) and productionization
Monitoring and managing team resources to minimize cloud costs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-requisites: A basic understanding of Python-based data science tools (NumPy, pandas, matplotlib, etc.) and workflows (exploratory analysis, visualization, etc.) is required – if you have used Jupyter Notebooks, created environments using the conda package manager, and performed a &lt;cite&gt;groupby&lt;/cite&gt; operation in pandas, you should be able to follow along with the talk comfortably. While not necessary, experiential knowledge of data workflows, previous experience working in a team, and familiarity with distributed computing principles will help you get the most value out of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pavithra Eswaramoorthy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/collaboration-infrastructure-in-data-science-tools-challenges-and-best-practices.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Créer une communauté de 5000 expertes en apprentissage automatique</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/creer-une-communaute-de-5000-expertes-en-apprentissage-automatique.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote talk in French&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Caroline Therwath-Chavier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/creer-une-communaute-de-5000-expertes-en-apprentissage-automatique.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Django Ninja - uma excelente opção para o desenvolvimento web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/django-ninja-uma-excelente-opcao-para-o-desenvolvimento-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django-ninja é um framework não muito popular nessa terra onde reina FastAPI, porém bastante útil ao se tratar de desenvolvimento web.
Assim como o Django Rest Framework (DRF), ele opera sobre o consolidado framework web Django, provendo maneiras bastante simples de construir APIs REST, e sua grande vantagem é utilizar Schemas baseados em Pydantic, o que o torna infinitamente mais rápido que os Serializers do DRF, além também possuir suporte a async.
Por operar sobre o Django, traz a grande vantagem de utilizar sua arquitetura bem organizada e intuitiva, todas as vantagens de já possuir um ORM simples e conhecido, e a interface do admin para lidar com o banco de dados.
Suas views são function baseds, extremamente simples e intuitivas, e ele já gera automaticamente uma documentação de cada endpoint exposto no formato openapi, por isso a produtividade é muito boa!
Nessa palestra, vou mostrar um resumo de suas funcionalidades para que mais pessoas considerem utilizar Django-ninja em suas aplicações!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ana Dulce Padovan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/django-ninja-uma-excelente-opcao-para-o-desenvolvimento-web.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Djangonaut Space, how we organized a mentorship program</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/djangonaut-space-how-we-organized-a-mentorship-program.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting to contribute to a big project might be scary or you just don’t know how to start. So it is not surprising that it is difficult to find new dedicated contributors to a project. This is something that Djangonaut Space organizers want to help with and make people feel that they are part of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that goal in mind, Djangonaut Space launched its first 3-month mentorship program in the Summer of 2023 mentoring 6 members of the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on Djangonaut Space here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://djangonaut.space/"&gt;https://djangonaut.space/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start with why the Django community felt there was a need for a mentorship program. This will include where this idea came from and how other communities might identify a similar need. Then we will go over how Djangonaut Space began. This will include the power of a pilot and what you will need to consider when organizing your own mentorship program.Finally we will see the outcomes of the Djangonaut Space program. This will cover our successes and what didn’t work as we expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can attendees learn:
- How to organize a mentorship program for your own project community
- Things to think about before you start one
- All about Djangonaut Space&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sarah Abderemane</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/djangonaut-space-how-we-organized-a-mentorship-program.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Drones : Do Software ao Hardware!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/drones-do-software-ao-hardware.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nesta palestra será abordado como foi utilizado código em Python para programar a Raspberry Pi 4+ no objetivo de desenvolver um Drone de busca que tivesse sua trajetória determinada e seguida de forma automática sem a necessidade do rádio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariana Oliveira</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/drones-do-software-ao-hardware.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Exploring Generative AI through the lens of Open source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/exploring-generative-ai-through-the-lens-of-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Generative AI (the technology behind AI tools like ChatGPT) &amp;amp; its applications.
- Brief overview of Open source &amp;amp; its importance in software development, collaboration, knowledge sharing etc.
- How collaboration through open source will benefit Generative AI.
- Showcasing popular Open source frameworks for Generative AI such as TensorFlow, PyTorch etc. &amp;amp; exploring some successful open source generative AI projects.
- How to contribute to AI open source projects with some resources to learn &amp;amp; collaborate&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aparna Soneja</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/exploring-generative-ai-through-the-lens-of-open-source.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>How and why I built a PyLadies avatar generator in 2 days</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/how-and-why-i-built-a-pyladies-avatar-generator-in-2-days.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mariana Bocoi, a DevOps infrastructure engineer and part of the PyLadies Stockholm community, shared her experience of creating a PyLadies avatar generator in just two intense days. She discussed the frustrations and ideas that led to this project, emphasizing the importance of inclusivity and diversity in tech representations. Mariana was inspired to create more representative avatars after realizing the limitations of existing logos in reflecting diverse identities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariana Bocoi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/how-and-why-i-built-a-pyladies-avatar-generator-in-2-days.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>How to Make a Docs Site: Shortcuts for Busy Devs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/how-to-make-a-docs-site-shortcuts-for-busy-devs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joanna Jablonski's talk, &amp;quot;How to Make a Doc Site,&amp;quot; offers practical advice on creating documentation sites that are easy to set up, maintain, and use. Joanna, an experienced educator in the Python community, emphasizes treating documentation like code—using tools such as issue trackers, version control, and static site generators like Docusaurus or MKDocs. She highlights the importance of structuring docs by user tasks and employing user-friendly language and SEO practices. Joanna also stresses writing clarity, focusing on reader needs, and using skimmable formats like vertical lists. The talk provides essential tips on tools, information architecture, and writing techniques to help developers create effective documentation sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joanna Jablonski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/how-to-make-a-docs-site-shortcuts-for-busy-devs.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>IAcelearando despliegues poderosos</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/iacelearando-despliegues-poderosos.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;¿La IA puede simplificar el flujo de trabajo de un DevOps? En esta apasionante charla, descubriremos cómo la IA puede acelerar las tareas de despliegue, que originalmente se basaron en scripts manuales, a través de una automatización rápida y segura. ¡Tan pronto como se haga una nueva release, es momento de desplegarla!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rossana Suarez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/iacelearando-despliegues-poderosos.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Como podemos saber se os resultados da pesquisa são bons? Keynote: How can we tell if the search results are good?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-como-podemos-saber-se-os-resultados-da-pesquisa-sao-bons-keynote-how-can-we-tell-if-the-search-results-are-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following subjects will be addressed in this talk:
* Implicit and explicit feedback
* Online and offline evaluation metrics
* Domain expert evaluation methodology
* Creating an evaluation dataset
* Continuous experimentation framework
* Open-source tools&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thais Viana</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-como-podemos-saber-se-os-resultados-da-pesquisa-sao-bons-keynote-how-can-we-tell-if-the-search-results-are-good.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: PyScript: Empowering Rich Python Applications in the Browser 在浏览器中运行Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-pyscript-empowering-rich-python-applications-in-the-browser-zai-liu-lan-qi-zhong-yun-xing-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyLadiesCon 2023 keynote talk in Chinese&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sophia Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-pyscript-empowering-rich-python-applications-in-the-browser-zai-liu-lan-qi-zhong-yun-xing-python.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Starting my career, the Open Source way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-starting-my-career-the-open-source-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote in English&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-starting-my-career-the-open-source-way.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Transcendence: The Power of Representation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-transcendence-the-power-of-representation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover representation in tech. It will have some code examples in it that show diversity statistics at some big tech companies and look at how these can affect women currently in the industry and women looking to join. I will share my own experiences being a woman in the Python community and how representation has helped and hurt in my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-transcendence-the-power-of-representation.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Tu voz en Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-tu-voz-en-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nuestras voces importan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hablar en público y dar charlas técnicas es una forma de empoderarnos y hacernos presentes, por eso te quiero compartir mi experiencia exponiendiome y gestionando esas situaciones que nos pueden dar miedo o echar para atrás.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pero entiendo que lo de hablar en público no está hecho para todo el mundo, por eso te quiero contar que alternativas existen para poder alzar tu voz y hacer que te escuchen en el mundo Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sé que no es fácil elevar la voz en ningún medio, sea escrito o hablado, y menos en un entorno que nos empuja a sufrir el Síndrome de la impostora. Pero te voy a compartir los ases que guardo bajo la manga amiga&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jimena Bermúdez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-tu-voz-en-python.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Mujeres en tecnología: experiencias de una Principal Data Scientist</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/mujeres-en-tecnologia-experiencias-de-una-principal-data-scientist.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk in Spanish&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Judit Guimera Busquets</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/mujeres-en-tecnologia-experiencias-de-una-principal-data-scientist.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion: Challenges for Women Working in Technology</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-challenges-for-women-working-in-technology.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;APAC Panel Discussion in English&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joeun Park</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-challenges-for-women-working-in-technology.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion - Unity in Diversity: The Voices of PyLadies Global Council</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-unity-in-diversity-the-voices-of-pyladies-global-council.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panel Discussion in English&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-unity-in-diversity-the-voices-of-pyladies-global-council.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion: Vozes na Tecnologia: Contando Experiências na Indústria de Tecnologia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-vozes-na-tecnologia-contando-experiencias-na-industria-de-tecnologia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panel Discussion in Portuguese&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Débora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-vozes-na-tecnologia-contando-experiencias-na-industria-de-tecnologia.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Panel: Empoderando a las Mujeres en la Industria Tecnológica: Experiencias y Perspectivas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/panel-empoderando-a-las-mujeres-en-la-industria-tecnologica-experiencias-y-perspectivas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panel Discussion in Spanish&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yodra López</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/panel-empoderando-a-las-mujeres-en-la-industria-tecnologica-experiencias-y-perspectivas.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Project TEDDY (Text-based Early Distress Detector for Youth)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/project-teddy-text-based-early-distress-detector-for-youth.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mona Obedoza, a high schooler, tech enthusiast, and aspiring AI engineer, presented &amp;quot;Project Teddy,&amp;quot; a text-based early distress detector for youth. As a passionate coder and AI advocate, she developed Teddy using Python and tools like Google Colab and Streamlit. The project aims to help teachers identify mental health concerns in student essays, flagging potential issues for guidance counselors. Mona detailed her process of data gathering, AI model training, and web deployment, emphasizing the importance of AI in early intervention. She encouraged schools to implement Teddy and expressed her ongoing commitment to using technology for positive change, while also promoting coding education for girls through hackathons and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mona Obedoza</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/project-teddy-text-based-early-distress-detector-for-youth.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>PyLadies 2023 Introduction</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/pyladies-2023-introduction.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PyLadiesCon 2023 introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lynn Root</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/pyladies-2023-introduction.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Pyladies Bioinfo Brasil</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/pyladies-bioinfo-brasil.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Em meados do ano 2020, com o crescimento das PyLadies Brasil no Slack, algumas PyLadies se organizaram e criaram um canal com intuito de unir mais meninas e mulheres para estudar Bioinformática, a qual é a área em que utiliza os métodos computacionais para analisar e compreender os fenômenos biológicos, em especial, os moleculares.
Assim como todas as áreas da computação, a Bioinformática ainda é predominantemente masculina. Logo, reunir as meninas para se apoiarem, estudarem e discutirem sobre Bioinformática, nos faz ver o quanto podemos juntas ser e fazer melhor. E, sabe-se que a diversidade promove mais inovação tecnológica e o céu é o limite para nossos sonhos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pri Boyano</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/pyladies-bioinfo-brasil.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>PyLadies Maputo - Construir uma comunidade que promove a diversidade, conecta, encoraja e desenvolve competências profissionais e humanas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/pyladies-maputo-construir-uma-comunidade-que-promove-a-diversidade-conecta-encoraja-e-desenvolve-competencias-profissionais-e-humanas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Construir uma comunidade que promove a diversidade, conecta, encoraja e desenvolve competências profissionais e humanas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cecilia Tivir</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/pyladies-maputo-construir-uma-comunidade-que-promove-a-diversidade-conecta-encoraja-e-desenvolve-competencias-profissionais-e-humanas.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>PyLadiesCon 2023 Closing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/pyladiescon-2023-closing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyLadiesCon 2023 Closing&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/pyladiescon-2023-closing.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>PyLadiesCon 2023 Opening</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/pyladiescon-2023-opening.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The opening talk for PyLadiesCon 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/pyladiescon-2023-opening.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Pythonic Principles: Best Practices for Clean Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/pythonic-principles-best-practices-for-clean-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's simplicity and readability make it a popular choice for developers. However, being Pythonic goes beyond writing functional code; it's about crafting elegant, maintainable, and collaborative code. This talk is designed for Python enthusiasts of all levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll explore the significance of Pythonic programming and its impact on code readability.
Outcomes: By the end of this talk, participants will:
1. Understand the significance of Pythonic programming and its benefits.
2. Become familiar with style guidelines and best practices.
3. Learn techniques to write clean, readable, and Pythonic code.
4. Cultivate a Pythonic mindset for code development and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Swarooprani Manoor</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/pythonic-principles-best-practices-for-clean-code.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>时间序列特征一键式提取神器-tsfresh</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/shi-jian-xu-lie-te-zheng-yi-jian-shi-ti-qu-shen-qi-tsfresh.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;时间序列特征一键式提取神器&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">April</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/shi-jian-xu-lie-te-zheng-yi-jian-shi-ti-qu-shen-qi-tsfresh.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Sparkling Connections: Making PyLadies' Contributions Visible Thru Mastodon Bots</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/sparkling-connections-making-pyladies-contributions-visible-thru-mastodon-bots.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outline for the talk is as follows:
- Introduction
- Explaining the background of the project and why visibility is important
- Showcasing of both the repository and the bot
- Explanaining of the bot’s architecture and set-up
- Providing a forward-looking perspective (upcoming features and future developments)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that the talk will inspire more PyLadies’ to share material publicly and to make the public perception of experts in the field more diverse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cosima Meyer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/sparkling-connections-making-pyladies-contributions-visible-thru-mastodon-bots.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Survival Guide to typing in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/survival-guide-to-typing-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk is split in 3 parts:
1. Quick presentation of type annotation, typing module, collections, Protocols
2. What is static typing, how to setup MyPy using pyproject.toml, quick tips on how to annotate functions to avoid anti-patterns
3. When static typing isn't enough, good use of TypeGuards&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hana Poulpe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/survival-guide-to-typing-in-python.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Testing in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/testing-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You'll leave this talk able to do the following:
- use Pytest to run your tests
- use unittest.mock to create mocks of objects and functions
- use unittest.patch to replace functions outside of the scope of your test
- inspect the arguments your mocked functions are called with and assert against them
- write asynchronous mocks
- use the parametrize library to run your tests on a variety of different inputs&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessie Newman</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/testing-in-python.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Usando Python para curar enfermedades genéticas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/usando-python-para-curar-enfermedades-geneticas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La charla abrirá con una breve introducción a la enfermedad de Huntington y lo suficiente de genética para entender el caso práctico. Éste es el verdadero centro de la charla y consistirá en editar el ADN de unx paciente con CRISPR (una herramienta de corte y empalme biológico) y un script de Python (que diseñará las secuencias genéticas necesarias para el experimento) para tratarlo. Todo esto nos servirá para ver el tremendo potencial de la sinergia entre la ingeniería genética y Python en el ámbito sanitario.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marina Moro López</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/usando-python-para-curar-enfermedades-geneticas.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item></channel></rss>