<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning talks 2018-05-02 and 2018-05-03</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/lightning-talks-2018-05-02-and-2018-05-03.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-02:pyastro-2018/lightning-talks-2018-05-02-and-2018-05-03.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Lightning talks 2018-05-01</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/lightning-talks-2018-05-01.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-01:pyastro-2018/lightning-talks-2018-05-01.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>A Complete fiasco - Dealing with Atomic Data and a Pythonic Solution</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/a-complete-fiasco-dealing-with-atomic-data-and-a-pythonic-solution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atomic data is used ubiquitously throughout the astrophysics and
astronomy community. Whether it is performing radiative transfer
calculations in a protoplanetary disk or interpreting observed spectra
in the solar corona, observers and modelers alike rely heavily on vast
amounts of detailed atomic data. These databases, which contain data
from both laboratory experiments and large simulation codes, are often
difficult to access, have no common format, and require a great deal of
effort (and funding) to assemble. One such example is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chiantidatabase.org/"&gt;CHIANTI
atomic database&lt;/a&gt; which has been maintained continuously since 1995 and
is heavily used by solar physicists. Recently I’ve begun work on a
package called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/wtbarnes/fiasco"&gt;fiasco&lt;/a&gt; (the Italian name for the style of bottle used
to store a Chianti wine) which provides a high-level interface to the
CHIANTI database. In this talk, I’ll discuss the difficulties of working
with this data, the software and techniques used to parse the data, and
the high-level interface. Additionally, and most importantly, I will
discuss the possible use of fiasco as a general interface to any atomic
database and how this might extend the usefulness of the package into
the general astronomy community. My hope is that this last point in
particular will generate much discussion and interest in how to improve
programmatic interfaces to this type of data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will Barnes</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/a-complete-fiasco-dealing-with-atomic-data-and-a-pythonic-solution.html</guid><category>fiasco</category></item><item><title>Astropy Overview</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/astropy-overview.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrian Price-Whelan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/astropy-overview.html</guid></item><item><title>Catch that asteroid with poliastro</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/catch-that-asteroid-with-poliastro.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.poliastro.space/"&gt;poliastro&lt;/a&gt; is a Python library for Astrodynamics focused on interplanetary trajectories, interactive visualization and user friendliness. It features core algorithms like propagation (Kepler problem), orbit determination (Lambert problem), orbital maneuvers computation (Hohmann, bielliptic) and conversion between classical, equinoctial and cartesian orbital elements. It also ships simple methods for orbit plotting and makes heavy use of astropy.units, astropy.time and astropy.coordinates for correctness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will present benchmarks of some poliastro algorithms accelerated with numba against its FORTRAN counterparts, review its interactive plotting capabilities and comment about the validation strategies used for the algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juan Luis Cano</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/catch-that-asteroid-with-poliastro.html</guid><category>poliastro</category></item><item><title>Data Analysis tools for JWST</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/data-analysis-tools-for-jwst.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of the tools being developed for JWST users. This includes interactive tools for data visualization as well as tools to facilitate scripted workflows for photometric and spectroscopic data analysis. The talk will also outline our open-source development model and highlight areas where community contributions will be most effective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pey Lian Lim</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/data-analysis-tools-for-jwst.html</guid></item><item><title>Developing End User Tools for DKIST Data Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/developing-end-user-tools-for-dkist-data-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Daniel K. Inouye Solar Telescope (DKIST) is a 4m solar telescope currently under construction on Haleakalā in Hawaii. In this talk I will give an overview of the software under development to enable users to perform scientific analysis on the data collected by the DKIST. This software is being developed in Python using SunPy and Astropy to provide the core tools. The DKIST data centre is expected to generate approximately 3 Pb of calibrated science quality data a year once telescope operations are at full capacity. The data centre will provide no pre-processing of the data before download, which is an extra challenge to the user software. The tools that will be written for these data will include, search and retrieval from the data centre, cataloguing and searching data local to the user and then reading of this data and metadata in a way which is compatible with existing tooling. This talk will describe these stages and the new and existing tools used in implementing them, as well as the challenges faced while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stuart Mumford</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/developing-end-user-tools-for-dkist-data-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>How Python in Astronomy has Impacted My Professional Life</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/how-python-in-astronomy-has-impacted-my-professional-life.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, my participation in the Python in Astronomy in 2016 taught me what it takes to make software that is actual useful for others and revealed the incredible encouraging and supportive community of astronomy python coders. Just releasing software is not enough - it needs good documentation, automated testing, and encourage contributions from others. Interacting with the astronomy python community has shown me that it is now better for my career to make all my code public. As one illustration, I will use the dust_extinction package that I started after the 2016 meeting. This package provides dust extinction curves using the astropy affiliated template package and is based on the astropy modeling and units packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Karl Gordon</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/how-python-in-astronomy-has-impacted-my-professional-life.html</guid></item><item><title>How to get career credit for writing software</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/how-to-get-career-credit-for-writing-software.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern scientific research depends on software and yet the activities of a research software engineer aren't generally recognized by the academy. In this talk I'll discuss why our inability to recognize the importance of research software is a serious threat to our long-term success and offer some potential tactics for elevating the role of software in academia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Arfon Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/how-to-get-career-credit-for-writing-software.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks 2018-04-30</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/lightning-talks-2018-04-30.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/lightning-talks-2018-04-30.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>More Usable Flops per Watt - A Highly-optimized Correlation Function</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/more-usable-flops-per-watt-a-highly-optimized-correlation-function.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Galaxy clustering is determined by a combination of cosmological parameters, non-linear gravitational collapse, and the physics of galaxy formation. Consequently, comparing the observed and predicted correlation functions provides a stringent test for galaxy formation theories as well as precise values of cosmological parameters. However, quantifying the clustering strength requires computing pair-wise separations -- an inherently quadratic process. Since large galaxy surveys, and consequently the theoretical models, contain millions of galaxies, computing the correlation function becomes a bottleneck in the analysis pipeline. With upcoming surveys like Large Synoptic Survey Telescope and the Square Kilometre Array (SKA), the number of detected sources will increase many-folds, and will exacerbate the bottleneck. I will show that software tuned to the underlying CPU hardware can speed up the calculation by almost two orders of magnitude. For modern CPUs, such a tuning involves proper utilization of the cache hierarchy, vectorized code targeting the Single Instruction Multiple Data (SIMD) capable wide vector registers as well as many-core parallelization. Here I present Corrfunc -- a suite of OpenMP-parallelized clustering codes that exploit current CPU micro-architecture with custom Advanced Vector Extensions (AVX) and Streaming SIMD Extensions (SSE) intrinsics. Corrfunc can compute a variety of correlation functions for source positions in either a Cartesian geometry (i.e., generated from cosmological simulations) or for positions on the sky. The algorithm within Corrfunc can be easily adapted to a variety of different measurements and has already been implemented for nearest neighbour searches, group finding in galaxy surveys, weak lensing measurements etc. By design, Corrfunc is highly optimized and can compute wprp for mathcal{O}(1 million) galaxies in ~ 6 seconds on a post-2011 CPU, which is at least a factor of few faster than existing public correlation function routines. Corrfunc is covered by a suite of tests, extensive documentation and is publicly available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/manodeep/Corrfunc"&gt;https://github.com/manodeep/Corrfunc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Manodeep Sinha</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/more-usable-flops-per-watt-a-highly-optimized-correlation-function.html</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Solar Flares Using Machine - Learning Methods</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/predicting-solar-flares-using-machine-learning-methods.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we discuss the application of various machine learning algorithms -- such as Support Vector Machine, a sparse linear regression (Lasso), and Convolutional Neural Network, which are all available in the open source python libraries called scikit-learn and caffe -- to image data from the photosphere, chromosphere, transition region, and corona taken by instruments aboard the Solar Dynamics Observatory in order to predict solar activity on a variety of time scales. Such an approach may be useful since, at the present time, there are no physical models of flares available for real-time prediction. We discuss our results (Bobra and Couvidat, 2015; Bobra and Ilonidis, 2016; Jonas et al., 2017) as well as other attempts to predict flares using machine-learning (e.g. Ahmed et al., 2013; Nishizuka et al. 2017) and compare these results with the more traditional techniques used by the NOAA Space Weather Prediction Center (Crown, 2012). We also discuss some of the challenges in using machine-learning algorithms for space science applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Monica Bobra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/predicting-solar-flares-using-machine-learning-methods.html</guid></item><item><title>SunPy Overview</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/sunpy-overview.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Danny Ryan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/sunpy-overview.html</guid></item><item><title>The role of Python in the first detection of Gravitational Waves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/the-role-of-python-in-the-first-detection-of-gravitational-waves.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last 2 years saw the spectacular birth of Gravitational Wave astronomy, which featured the first ever detection of signals generated by colliding black holes, and a neutron star merger of which the afterglow has been observed across the EM spectrum. I will give a quick overview of the recent discoveries, and then explain how Python plays a key role in this field. I will focus on the automation of the Virgo interferometer and on analysis tools used for understanding the disturbances that are limiting the sensitivity of these complex instruments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bas Swinkels</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/the-role-of-python-in-the-first-detection-of-gravitational-waves.html</guid></item><item><title>[The Struggles of] Developing Python Packages for Spectroscopy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/the-struggles-of-developing-python-packages-for-spectroscopy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An overview of some of the challenges faced in developing spectroscopic open-source packages for the astronomy community, and what we've done to try and overcome them. The talk discusses three spectroscopy-focused packages at different stages of development and how we plan to ensure community traction while working under bureaucratic constraints, building in inter-operatibility with other python packages, and providing accessibility for contributors of a wide range of programming backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nick Earl</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:pyastro-2018/the-struggles-of-developing-python-packages-for-spectroscopy.html</guid></item></channel></rss>