<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-thailand-2018.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>A JS developer tries python, escapes from Jupyter to build a product</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/a-js-developer-tries-python-escapes-from-jupyter-to-build-a-product.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Washer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/a-js-developer-tries-python-escapes-from-jupyter-to-build-a-product.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks are great to prototype ideas, but aren’t shippable product (to real users). To bridge the gap between this (a notebook) and a successful product, you must own the user experience and work with product design and feature planning.
Sometimes you must go on an adventure back to being a junior, get some new tech off the shelf and work your way back to familiar territory. Learn how a JS developer with limited python experience worked through tooling and workflow planning choices to iterate to victory.
See how you can use python to work closely with product/UI designers to shape a reproducible product workflow and solve a user problem.
Ideal audience: People with any level of python experience who want to see how it can fit into the wider picture of product development in the trenches of a startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm the Chief Javascript Cowboy (aka Engineering Lead for Frontend) at Stitched, a startup combining graph theory, natural language processing and machine learning to improve understanding and allocation of people and projects in large companies. We're based in London, UK, but I'm from New Zealand!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Aaaarrgghh, Spider! Web scraping with Scrapy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/aaaarrgghh-spider-web-scraping-with-scrapy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Kohl</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/aaaarrgghh-spider-web-scraping-with-scrapy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A quick yet reasonably thorough introduction to Scrapy, the high-level web crawling &amp;amp; scraping framework for Python. Includes a demo, cause I like living on the edge.
The &amp;quot;core concepts demo&amp;quot; is a hands-on introduction, starting from a simple example and progressively adding more features. It covers the following topics:
* Spiders (Spider, CrawlSpider, etc)
* Selectors (XPath, CSS, Regex, etc)
* Items &amp;amp; item loaders
* Input &amp;amp; output processors
* Pipelines
Slides from the previous version of this talk: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/citizen428/aaaarrgghh-spider-web-scraping-with-scrapy"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/citizen428/aaaarrgghh-spider-web-scraping-with-scrapy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby developer since ~2003. Py-curious, Love FP. I talk a lot about programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Alternative way for build async server</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/alternative-way-for-build-async-server.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phatthana Batt Tongon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/alternative-way-for-build-async-server.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ถ้าคุณอยากสร้าง api server โดยใช้ async แต่ยังไม่รู้ว่าจะเลือก async framework ตัวไหน ผมมี framework ตัวใหม่ชื่อ Sanic มานำเสนอ Sanic สร้างโดยพยายามให้เหมือน Flask ซึ่งเป็น framework ที่ใช้ง่าย แต่ Sanic จะเน้นความเร็วที่สุด
This session is about Sanic framework. Sanic is async io framework design like Flask. Why Sanic is fast? We will look inside Sanic how they design it and why. How Kaidee use Sanic.
ถ้าคุณกำลัง หรืออยากสร้าง high load api server สักตัวหนึ่ง นี่เป็น session ที่คุณควรเข้ามาฟัง&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical lead &amp;#64;Kaidee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;former startup founder, personal acquire by Kaidee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start working since 2nd years in university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full stack developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Craft beer explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monster hunter :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building a sustainable codebases with Type Annotations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/building-a-sustainable-codebases-with-type-annotations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yothin Muangsommuk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/building-a-sustainable-codebases-with-type-annotations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maintaining large and fast-growing codebase is always hard. Especially on dynamic type language like Python. The good news is Python is now offering type annotations and it will help you understand your code more easily.
In this talk, We'll introduce you to the new syntax of type annotations and the tooling around type annotations ecosystem which will make your development workflow more productive. We'll share our experience on how we embrace type annotation to our development team and also some common pitfalls you might want to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yothin is a Pythonista at Pronto Tools. He has been writing Python since 2010 with love on Pythonic way and the zen of Python. While he's not doing Python stuff, he's a Trekkie.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>DIY: Python with partially charged batteries</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/diy-python-with-partially-charged-batteries.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Watcharapol Watcharawisetkul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/diy-python-with-partially-charged-batteries.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we discuss how some features in standard Python library can be manually re-implemented using a subset of Python itself. Examples include:
- built-in &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;range&lt;/tt&gt; function
- &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;namedtuple&lt;/tt&gt; class constructor
- &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;property&lt;/tt&gt; decorator
- &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;Enum&lt;/tt&gt; class (since Python 3.4)
- &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;dataclass&lt;/tt&gt; (since Python 3.7)
- etc.
Throughout the process of re-implementing these features, we should gain more in-depth understanding the mechanisms inside Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmer: Specialized in problem solving, algorithm and data structure. Interested in robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Django Backend from zero to deployment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/django-backend-from-zero-to-deployment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarit Ritwirune</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/django-backend-from-zero-to-deployment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the topics
1. &lt;cite&gt;CRUD&lt;/cite&gt; for frontend guy (DjangoREST)
2. Report Query for management level(Djang-ORM)
3. Send the Push Notification for customers(FCM)
4. Test With Runner (pytest)
5. Deploy (Docker)
This talk will not cover &lt;cite&gt;Gitlab-runner&lt;/cite&gt;, AWS EC2, S3/CloudFront, route53&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django REST lover and ReactJS beginner. Implement &amp;amp; code ~10 projects from last year. Struggling to get all 3 skills. They are DevOps, Backend, and Frontend in order to lead multiple teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Enabling Blockchain Energy Trading among Smart Buildings through the Use of Multi-Agent Systems and Internet of Things Devices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/enabling-blockchain-energy-trading-among-smart-buildings-through-the-use-of-multi-agent-systems-and-internet-of-things-devices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Warodom Khamphanchai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/enabling-blockchain-energy-trading-among-smart-buildings-through-the-use-of-multi-agent-systems-and-internet-of-things-devices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enabling Blockchain Energy Trading among Smart Buildings through the Use of Multi-Agent Systems and Internet of Things Devices
Due to the proliferation and continuously improvement of solar PV, energy storage, electric vehicles, Internet of things (IoT) devices, these open up new opportunities and change the ways how end-use customers (smart homes and smart buildings) engage in the electricity market. Rather than passively consume energy by purchasing electricity with a fixed tariff from an electric utility, in the near future they can become prosumers who are able to generate revenue on their excess energy and able to obtain transparently-source, reliable energy. This talk discusses the development of a Multi-Agent System Platform, so called PEA HiVE, with Blockchain Energy Trading application.  Python is selected to be the development language for the IoT integration and backend, whereas Hyperledger and React Native are chosen to be the Blockchain development platform and our mobile frontend respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Khamphanchai received his PhD from the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, USA. His research interests are home/building energy management systems, Internet of things, multi-agent systems, machine learning, data analytics, demand response, cyber-physical systems, and power system operation and control. His research focus is to develop building energy management open source software (BEMOSS) for energy savings and peak demand reduction in small- and medium-sized commercial buildings. The current released version of BEMOSS is made available on the Github repository (URL: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bemoss/bemoss_os"&gt;https://github.com/bemoss/bemoss_os&lt;/a&gt;) and on the United States Department of Energy (DOE) website (URL: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://energy.gov/eere/buildings/downloads/building-energy-management-open-source-software-development-bemoss"&gt;http://energy.gov/eere/buildings/downloads/building-energy-management-open-source-software-development-bemoss&lt;/a&gt;)
Dr. Khamphanchai was a full stack Python developer focusing on developing applications for building energy management and multi-agent systems development, which is the foundation of the BEMOSS platform. He is also the active member of the IEEE Power and Energy Society, the IEEE Internet of Things Society, the IEEE Computer Society, TechShop DC/Arlington, Google Developer Group (GDG) Washington D.C., Modev Washington D.C., as well as DC robotics group. He received his Masters degrees in Electric Power System Management Field of Study from the School of Environment, Resources and Development (SERD), Asian Institute of Technology (AIT), Thailand in 2011 and the B.Eng. degree in Electrical Engineering from Chulalongkorn University, Thailand in 2009.
His dissertation topic is: &amp;quot;An Agent-based Platform for Demand Response Implementation in Smart Buildings&amp;quot;
For more info, please visit : kwarodom.wordpress.com or contact: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:kwarodom&amp;#64;vt.edu"&gt;kwarodom&amp;#64;vt.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to serverless Python with AWS Lambda</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/introduction-to-serverless-python-with-aws-lambda.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Murat Knecht</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/introduction-to-serverless-python-with-aws-lambda.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just a Python function. That's all we usually need to answer web requests, to process uploaded images or to have our chatbot reply to chat messages. To run a Python function, you don't want to create and maintain a server. Instead, you want FaaS: Functions-as-a-Service!
In my talk, I'll explain the idea and power of FaaS. We'll also consider potential challenges and limitations to be aware of. Persisting data and pricing are obvious ones, but you likely might want to organize your code differently, too, if you want to build an entire app on FaaS and think about versioning, too. Finally, I'll demo how to answer an HTTP request with a AWS Lambda function, for example to build a chatbot or answer a SMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You are smart, motivated and have a unique perspective&lt;/em&gt; -- that's my premise as CTO of engageSPARK &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://engagespark.com"&gt;http://engagespark.com&lt;/a&gt;. Originally I'm from Berlin, and have worked there for a couple of years, but for the past three years I've served at engageSPARK in Cebu, Philippines, and enjoy almost every minute of it. CTO means being team lead, architect, coder and coach. I find challenge and joy in all these roles.
On the tech-side, I work mostly with Python and Golang, but secretly enjoy languages with the odd super power like LISP. I use Emacs, and highly respect Vim power-users, because they're so incredibly fast.
I try to live purposefully and deliberately. That's why I joined engageSPARK as the first opportunity Labs &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opplabs.org"&gt;http://opplabs.org&lt;/a&gt; company. Let me know how I can help you live your life well.
Oh, and if ever &lt;strong&gt;you find yourself in Cebu, do say Hi!&lt;/strong&gt; (For example on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/murat-knecht/"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/murat-knecht/&lt;/a&gt; or at muratk[&amp;#64;my company's name.com] . We have a desk and Internet for you, if you're willing to share some of your knowledge and uniqueness. :) In any case, always glad to help out with sightseeing tips and a cold beverage.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Logo Detection Using PyTorch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/logo-detection-using-pytorch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nithiroj Tripatarasit</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/logo-detection-using-pytorch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk. We will walk through the one significant use of deep learning for digital marketing and ad tech, the image recognition, which brands use to identify their potential clients, deliver personalized offerings and analyze the spending in the world of social media. The easiest way to identify the brand is by its logo.
The logo detection can be done by object detection models.  We will use PyTorch, a popular deep learning framework in Python, to build the model to identify a brand by its logo in an image.  Along the talk, we'll see the relative value of deep learning architectures-Deep Neural Network (DNN) and Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) , learn the effect of data size, augment the data when we don't have much, and use the transfer learning technique to improve the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lifelong learner, tech lover, and deep learning enthusiast.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;My work&lt;/strong&gt;
- iOS apps &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://itunes.apple.com/th/developer/nithiroj-tripatarasit/id704045425"&gt;https://itunes.apple.com/th/developer/nithiroj-tripatarasit/id704045425&lt;/a&gt;
- Android apps &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Neo+Edutainment"&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Neo+Edutainment&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Experiences:&lt;/strong&gt;
- fast.ai International Fellowship Program (Mar 19 - Apr 30, 2018) &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.fast.ai/2018/01/17/international-spring-2018/"&gt;http://www.fast.ai/2018/01/17/international-spring-2018/&lt;/a&gt;
- Deep Learning, a 5-course specialization by deeplearning.ai on Coursera. Specialization Certificate earned on March 9, 2018 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/X7TVC4FK8J82"&gt;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/X7TVC4FK8J82&lt;/a&gt;
- Machine Learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/3DJQGJEUN2ZH"&gt;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/3DJQGJEUN2ZH&lt;/a&gt;
- Deep Learning Workshops by Google Developer Experts &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/197ONJWkT6qgf5CzEL1UJlxr9P9gW5Rbz/view?usp=sharing"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/197ONJWkT6qgf5CzEL1UJlxr9P9gW5Rbz/view?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Playing with Social Network, Geo-Spatial, Financial Flow, and Banking System Data: Graph-Theoretic Computation in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/playing-with-social-network-geo-spatial-financial-flow-and-banking-system-data-graph-theoretic-computation-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Poomjai Nacaskul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/playing-with-social-network-geo-spatial-financial-flow-and-banking-system-data-graph-theoretic-computation-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Playing with Social Network, Geo-Spatial, Financial Flow, and Banking System Data: Graph-Theoretic Computation in Python
Much of 'Big Data' revolution has to do with dealing with non-traditional datatypes and feeding machine learning engines with non-numerical variables. Just as Convolutional Neural Networks excel at object recognition task precisely because the convolution layers expressly capture grid-array information embedded in the 2-dimensional visual field, analysis involving network-patterned objects (individuals in an online social network, transportation nodes, banking accounts with payment network, etc.) stands to benefit from the ability to extract graph-theoretic properties from the network connectivity patterns, either to provide insights in and of themselves, or as pre-processing to further machine learning task down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bachelor's) Physics &amp;amp; Economics (double major), Case Western Reserve University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Master's) Operations Research (minor in Finance), Weatherhead School of Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Doctorate's) Computational Intelligence &amp;amp; Operational Research, Imperial College, London&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bank of Thailand) Head of Quantitative Models &amp;amp; Financial Engineering, Financial Supervision Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(SCB - current) FSVP, Quantitative Models &amp;amp; Enterprise Analytics, Business Intelligence, Transformation Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Powerful geographic web framework GeoDjango</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/powerful-geographic-web-framework-geodjango.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mitsuki Sugiya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/powerful-geographic-web-framework-geodjango.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Services dealing with location information in recent years are rapidly increasing.
However, a perspective of building development environment that handles geometric information from scratch is very hard work.
As one of the solutions, I would like to introduce a module of Django and GeoDjango for easy developing of location information.
A speaker talks about the following topics:
- Overview GeoDjango
- Way to start the project and how to use features (Demo)
- What a Can (and Cannot) Do with GeoDjango
The talk gives you my knowledge to develop applications using location information more easily with GeoDjango.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working in Japan as a web applications engineer, Pythonista, a motorcycle rider (SWM GRAN MILANO 400), hobbyist drawing illustrations. At University, I was studying to analyze non-language information using motion capture system. I love IT, my all friends, my country and Japanese animation culture.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python + XPath = Extra Parsing Power</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/python-xpath-extra-parsing-power.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Reiter</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/python-xpath-extra-parsing-power.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's power in manipulating strings and handling nested data structures is well known. So much so that for many mild XML and HTML processing use cases one can get the job done using only built-ins and common parts of the standard library.  But the markup language world offers many powerful tools which do not map so directly onto python's data model.  And there are large gains to be had if we use native XML tools alongside python and give each component the chance to shine when it can.  At the same time learning new tools takes time and adding new parsing and query engines to a project consumes resources.  The aim of this talk is to highlight those situations where the benefits of calling in heavy machinery from the XML world outweigh the costs.
We begin with an overview of the XPath query language and use example queries to highlight differences between python's nested data model and that of common markup languages.  For example HTML distinguishes between attributes and content while a nested collection of python dicts, list and tuples only has content.  To be sure we can express the same information in both models.  But we can write shorter, clearer and more-efficient-to-process queries when we retain the distinction. Similarly we can traverse python's built-in data structures with combinations of various braces and parentheses but it is not so simple to pass references into such nested structures and then navigate around.  With an XPath processor and common document object model such actions are straightforward – and arguably more pythonic than a solution built entirely on native language features.
Finally we connect things back together with some simple web-scraping examples.  Here we use XPath queries to quickly extract elements of interest and then leverage python's string handling capabilities to swiftly convert that content into native data types.
Examples will employ both the lxml parsing library and the selenium web scraping framework.  The goal is to focus on use cases where the XML machinery is worth employing.  All the wrappers are similar and we wish to highlight that it does not particularly matter which package you learn – it matters that you learn when to employ XPath and a proper DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon is Managing Director of Data Finnovation, a Singapore-based startup that is changing the way the financial services industry handles data. Before joining the Fintech movement he spent 15 years modelling and trading fixed income and currency derivatives for banks in New York, Tokyo, London and Singapore.  During this time Jon worked as a quant and trader, and managed both market-making and electronic trading teams.  Prior to working in the capital markets Jon studied Computer Science at Brown University where he earned an ScM in Computer Science and an A.B. in both Mathematical Economics and Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Talk to your Python app - using LINE!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/talk-to-your-python-app-using-line.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Uli Hitzel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-17:pycon-thailand-2018/talk-to-your-python-app-using-line.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning &amp;amp; Artifical Intelligence are intriguing topics - however, the complexity of these concepts makes it impossible to just quickly use those to build an app. The good news is: you do not have to be a data scientist to build intriguing apps that are able to listen, speak and see.
What we will cover:
* Open APIs and Cognitive Services
* Visualizing Data
* Building an application to use with LINE messenger
* Python Requests Library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data &amp;amp; Automation Geek, based in Singapore. Python, Git, Redis, HTTP. Worked for companies including Red Hat, Microsoft, IBM, Playboy and Yahoo!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Beginner's Guide to Deep Natural Language Processing with PyTorch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/a-beginners-guide-to-deep-natural-language-processing-with-pytorch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Prachya Boonkwan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/a-beginners-guide-to-deep-natural-language-processing-with-pytorch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is a challenging subfield of Artificial Intelligence, in which human's ability to understand and produce language is imitated. With the advent of deep learning in mid-2000s, many NLP tasks previously done in traditional statistical methods have gained significant accuracy improvement, thanks to its powerful feature extraction.
This talk will go into the basic ideas of natural language processing, some building blocks of neural networks for deep learning, and how to assemble them into a piece of runnable code for various NLP tasks. PyTorch will be used as the main gear, because we can easily cope with both static and dynamic network architectures while maintaining the code readability. The speaker kindly assumes the audience to have some knowledge in Python (intermediate: especially classes and objects), university calculus (basic), and linguistics (very basic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prachya Boonkwan is a computational linguist and a computer scientist with 16-years experience in natural language processing using Python. He received B.Eng. (honors) and M.Eng. degrees in Computer Engineering from Kasetsart University in 2002 and 2005, respectively. He received a Ph.D. degree in Informatics (specializing in natural language processing) from the University of Edinburgh, UK, in 2014. Since 2005, he has been working as a researcher for Language and Semantic Technology Lab at NECTEC, Thailand. His topics of interest include: grammar induction, statistical parsing, statistical machine translation, natural language processing, machine learning, and formal syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A journey from Monolith into Microservices architecture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/a-journey-from-monolith-into-microservices-architecture.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pinnapong Silpsakulsuk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/a-journey-from-monolith-into-microservices-architecture.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my personal experience with one of my previous employer. I joined them at the time that their entire company backend was run on a huge PHP based Monolith application which cannot scale out and required the largest Amazon EC2 instance at that time in order to handle all the workloads. By the time I left them, we have successfully migrated the system into Microservices architecture. This talk will walk you through multiple points of time during that period. Explaining how we gradually pull functionalities out of the legacy system. What kind of challenges have we faced along the way. What have we learned so far.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/groupw66/talks-pycon-th-2018"&gt;https://github.com/groupw66/talks-pycon-th-2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A software developer who has been working on broad range of technologies from a small embedded system board to a large complex system in the cloud. Interested in software development practices and software architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>AI in Security, Finance, and eCommerce</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/ai-in-security-finance-and-ecommerce.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>TaeWoo Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/ai-in-security-finance-and-ecommerce.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hollywood vs. Reality in facial recognition
* high traffic areas like the AOT / Suvarnabhumi airport / anywhere where scanning for person of interest might be crucial for security personnel
* why AI fails in traditional sense of security, particularly ID verification, and video surveillance
* democratization of AI , and crazy / weird / non-traditional uses of machine learning, particularly in areas of payment transfers, ecommerce transactions ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 Years in Engineering &amp;amp; Data in NYC / Silicon Valley
Solar One Media: Ad tech big data (RTB) processing 2 TB data/mo and $15m/year in ad spend
One Smart Lab: AI in video surveillance &amp;amp; biometrics for finance, ecommerce, and security
Media: - One Smart Lab on Wall Street Journal &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/OneSmartLab/photos/a.1927919570760201.1073741828.1927901097428715/2080374985514658/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/OneSmartLab/photos/a.1927919570760201.1073741828.1927901097428715/2080374985514658/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&lt;/a&gt;
- AT&amp;amp;T NYC hackathon winner &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.onesmartlab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/att-hackagthon-nblurred.jpg"&gt;https://www.onesmartlab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/att-hackagthon-nblurred.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
- Contributor to Yahoo SMB Advisors &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://smallbusiness.yahoo.com/advisor/confessions-reformed-black-hat-ppc-marketer-cpc-arbitrage-190531966.html"&gt;https://smallbusiness.yahoo.com/advisor/confessions-reformed-black-hat-ppc-marketer-cpc-arbitrage-190531966.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Artisanal Async Adventures</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/artisanal-async-adventures.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonas Obrist</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/artisanal-async-adventures.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to write an efficient server, asynchronous networking is an excellent strategy to do so. To build a production ready system, you would use asyncio, tornado, twisted, trio or another popular implementation. However, to fully understand how and why it works, I will ignore these solutions and instead craft an artisanal asynchronous implementation in front of your very eyes. Step by step we will turn a blocking socket server, only capable of handling a single connection at a time, into a beautiful non blocking server that has no trouble dealing with many connections at once. By the end, you should see that asynchronous code is not magical at all, but nevertheless incredibly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a Python developer from Switzerland, living in Japan. I got started with Python developing modifications for the video game Counter-Strike before getting my first job building websites using Django. There I got involved with the popular open source Content Management System django CMS. Nowadays I work primarily with the Tornado framework and various asyncio libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Attack of Pythons: Gotchas and Landmines in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/attack-of-pythons-gotchas-and-landmines-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manoj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/attack-of-pythons-gotchas-and-landmines-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python may be one of the simplest and most flexible programming languages out there, but it is still a programming language. It still has syntax, datatypes, and some occasional dark corners. Python &amp;quot;warts&amp;quot; are things for which people have criticized Python, typically aspects of the language or mechanisms of its implementation, because such aspects either expose certain surprising inconsistencies, are regarded as omissions, or cause irritation for parts of the community in some sense.
This talk will be about common pitfalls (termed warts/landmines) that people face using Python programming language.
Prerequisites: The only prerequisite is that you must have some basic familiarity with Python programming language. Although it'll be good that you have laptops with Python already setup, it's not required as such!
If you are really curious how this talk will go, you can watch a similar talk for Ruby and Javascript at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/talks/wat"&gt;https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/talks/wat&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founder and Organizer for PyData Delhi. Keynote and international speaker at many Python conferences around the world. To-be Software Engineer at Yelp!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>AutoBuddy: A Home Automation System</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/autobuddy-a-home-automation-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>François Wautier</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/autobuddy-a-home-automation-system.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AutoBuddy is a home automation system build almost entirely with Python. It uses asyncio and thus required that I created/adapted a number of libraries to use asyncio throughout. AutoBuddy grew organically through hit and misses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a software engineer for over 30 years. I used the Internet before the World Wide Web existed. I still love the stuff. Now, Home Automation is my hobby even though my wife and kids keeps complaining about it. I wrote AutoBuddy, so I think I am the best person to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Build dynamically scaled highly available python application with MySQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/build-dynamically-scaled-highly-available-python-application-with-mysql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ronen Baram</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/build-dynamically-scaled-highly-available-python-application-with-mysql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MySQL High Availability clusters allow you to develop any application that can scale to accommodate for any load your application need to serve. We will explore the new InnoDB Cluster, understand how it works and how to build it. Next we will talk about MySQL NDB Cluster and how it's different to InnoDB Cluster.
Finally, we will do a live demo of both to show in real life how you can use them both with your Python application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more then 25 years in the IT industry, with strong focus on open source solutions, for the last 9 years acting as a MySQL technical consultant for many APAC companies and organisations. Based in Melbourne and serves ANZ as a core territory.
Have a great passion to talk, learn and share knowledge. Overall nice person, given the morning coffee was reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>CoderDojo - a free programming club for kids</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/coderdojo-a-free-programming-club-for-kids.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mishari Muqbil</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/coderdojo-a-free-programming-club-for-kids.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many of us, programming wasn't something we studied in the classroom but a passion driven by curiosity, a love for technology and the urge to share. CoderDojo takes these principles and combines them into a self-directed learning environment. This talk covers the overall structure and concepts of CoderDojo, why you should set one up, lessons learned after operating CoderDojo for a year and why community-driven education is the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mishari has been using Linux since 1994, coordinator with the distributed computing effort to break RC5-56 in 1997, built Thailand's largest Renderfarm for the animation Khan Kluay where he also started using Python.
Currently his obsessions are:
* Delivering Systems as a Service at Proteus Ops
* Homeschooling his kids (and fixing education)
* Organizing Bangkok Scientifique, a monthly meetup for people interested in science and technology
* Co-Founder of CoderDojo Thailand
* Co-Founder of SciDojo Thailand, a support network for parents who want to build a science culture in their household
* OpenstreetMap contributor
* Cycling&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Concurrent Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/concurrent-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ukrid Kuldiloke</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/concurrent-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ทอร์คนี้จะพูดถึงหัวข้อต่อไปนี้
- Concurrency หลายๆ แบบใน python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thread&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Characteristic ของ concurrency แต่ละแบบ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ข้อดี/ข้อเสีย ของ concurrency ในแต่ละแบบ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;สถานการณ์แบบไหน ควรใช้ concurrency แบบไหน&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ตัวอย่างการใช้งาน code example, library example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/ukrid.kuldiloke/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/ukrid.kuldiloke/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Continuous code quality with sonarqube</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/continuous-code-quality-with-sonarqube.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adisak Srisuriyasavad</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/continuous-code-quality-with-sonarqube.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SonarQube: เป็นโปรแกรมที่ใช้ในการพัฒนาคุณภาพโปรแกรมได้โดยมีความสามารถดังนี้
- ใช้ในการวัดคุณภาพ source code โดยสามารถตรวจสอบได้ทั้ง Bug, Vulnerability, Code Smell, Duplications, coverage
- วิเคราะห์กราฟความสัมพันธ์ของคุณภาพจาก issue ที่ตรวจสอบพบ
- วิเคราะห์ issues ที่ตรวจพบ และสามารถกำหนดงานให้กับคนในทีมได้อีกด้วย&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ผมเคยทำงานในสาย programmer มาเป็นเวลา 10 ปีเพิ่งเริ่มทำงานในบทบาทของ Quality Assurance ผมยังไม่ค่อยมีประสบการณ์เกี่ยวกับการวัดคุณภาพมากนัก แต่ผมก็สามารถทำงานนี้ได้เป็นอย่างดีเพราะเครื่องมือตัวนี้ ผมทำได้ ผมก็เชื่อว่าทุกคนที่ได้ลองใช้ก็จะทำได้เช่นกันครับ&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Creating a Startup</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/creating-a-startup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tiwa York</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/creating-a-startup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tiwa talks about what it takes to create a startup, what distinguishes SMEs and Startups.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaidee.com"&gt;https://www.kaidee.com&lt;/a&gt;
--------&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiwa York is the Head Coach of Kaidee (a.k.a CEO). He is passionate about changing lives through trading second hand goods, startups, and building great teams.
Along with a team of 5 awesome people, Tiwa founded an online marketplace which is now known as Kaidee in 2011. Today, Kaidee is a C2C online marketplace with 200 thousand monthly sellers, listing 1.8 million items for sale and reaching 7 million people per month. In 2016, 2 million items were sold via Kaidee valued at over 2.4 billion USD.
Tiwa has been recognized for his passion, his leadership, and his efforts to build the team and culture at Kaidee. Prior to his current role, he worked in digital advertising with leadership roles in Admax Network and Omnicom Media Group.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Creating amazing APIs in Flask with Flask RESTplus</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/creating-amazing-apis-in-flask-with-flask-restplus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Avi Aryan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/creating-amazing-apis-in-flask-with-flask-restplus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been using Flask with Flask RESTplus to create REST API based backend projects for around 3 years now. For those who don't know, Flask RESTplus is an amazing library for REST API development with features like automatic live documentation, input payload validation, neat code organization, automatic response marshaling and a lot of extensibility. You can easily extend it to include other features like response pagination, ETag caching, rate limiting, custom authentication and authorization system and basically anything else you can imagine. In this talk, I will share my hard gained knowledge with code snippets on how to quickly get started and do all these amazing things in Flask RESTplus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avi is a full-stack web engineer at Toptal with four years of professional experience. He has worked with most of the popular stack used on the web today including Python, JavaScript, and Go. He is also a multiple-time Google Summer of Code participant, where he mentors budding developers to contribute to open-source projects. These days he is working on his Blockchain based social media startup called HapRamp which aims to revolutionalize the social media ecosystem in India.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Deep learning in the household</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/deep-learning-in-the-household.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Surasak Watthanayontkit</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/deep-learning-in-the-household.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, Machine Learning was thought of as the subject requiring intensive computing power and comprehensive understanding of mathematics. Thus, public assumed that it was the job exclusively for giant tech companies with super-genius researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the community has achieved substantial advancements and they are open enough to share their achievements and computing resources to the public at no expenses. Frameworks like TenserFlow, Keras make building a Deep Learning model require only a Python code snippet. Furthermore, Transfer Learning helps developing models even easier by taking portions of pre-trained more generic models, many of which are open-sourced. This has potentials to accelerate the machine learning apps on mobile devices, one of the emerging trend in the field, where compactness and performance are preferred over accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With rich on-line resources around, including online courses (many of which are free), blog posts, and computing resources available at no expenses, the talk covers the steps to apply those knowledge to build a small, yet useful app based on Deep Learning model - without Deep Pockets, a Ph.D., and mega infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is intended for beginners with background in traditional software developments. Mathematical knowledge in differential calculus (derivatives - not in the context of Stock Futures) is useful but not required as it may be touched briefly. Audiences are not expected to walk away as subject matter experts after finishing the talk but the speaker hope to spark inspiration to learn more on the subject and eventually end up developing something for their own use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earned a B.Eng. nearly 20 years ago, when the vocabularies like &amp;quot;Deep Learning&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Data Science&amp;quot; had not even been materialized. His full time job is traditional software development (Python is not used) and it has no direct relevance to Machine Learning.
He discovered MOOCs in late 2013 and completed his first MOOC on Coursera in 2014. Since then, he has completed over 60 courses (he tries to increase the number even though has already lost the exact count) including a number of Python programming and Machine Learning courses.
In his spare time, apart from doing MOOCs/writing Python programs and practicing Keras/TensorFlow framework, he also writes Swfit programs (and published one on iOS AppStore, although, again, Swift is not used in his full time job) He also does endurance sports like long distance running (a.k.a. marathons), triathlons, and high-altitude trekking&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Flask ณ Kaidee</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/flask-n-kaidee.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Poohdish Rattanavijai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/flask-n-kaidee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ในทอล์คนี้จะเล่าถึงประสบการ์ณของทีมงาน Kaidee ในการใช้ Flask microframework ในหัวข้อต่างๆ เช่น
- ทำไมเราถึงเลือกใช้ Flask
- มี framework อื่นที่เราใช้มั้ย
- ประสบการ์ณที่เจอจากการใช้งาน
หมายเหตุ: ทอล์คนี้จะไม่ได้ลงลึกทางเทคนิคมากนัก ภาษา: ไทย เหมาะสำหรับ: บุคคลทั่วไป, ผู้ที่ยังไม่เคยใช้งาน Flask ในทราฟฟิคสูงๆ, หรืออยากฟังประสบการ์ณการใช้งานจากทีมอื่น&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am:
- Thai, atheist.
- Coder, software enthusiast, teacher wannabe.
- Read more than 7 lines per day.
- Use spaces, not tabs.
- Like to laugh and making people laugh.
- Gamers and #NUFC
- Enjoy reading between the lines.
- happen to be Software Architect at Kaidee.com&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>FOSSASIA introduction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/fossasia-introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Noah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/fossasia-introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the FOSSASIA organisation, an organisation developing software applications for social change, using a wide range of technologies.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fossasia.org/"&gt;https://fossasia.org/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.fossasia.tw/"&gt;https://www.fossasia.tw/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://join.fossasia.tw/"&gt;https://join.fossasia.tw/&lt;/a&gt; --------&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;volunteer of FOSSASIA,
volunteer of many PyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How many coin in your piggy bank with micro-python &amp; 3D-Printer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/how-many-coin-in-your-piggy-bank-with-micro-python-3d-printer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Montri Sroymukda</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/how-many-coin-in-your-piggy-bank-with-micro-python-3d-printer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need share my experience esp82266 with micro-python and 3D-Printer. Start with small problem.  &amp;quot;How many coin in your piggy bank&amp;quot;
I resolve problem and make a new question: &amp;quot;how to real time update how many coin in your piggy bank&amp;quot;. This project can apply to many project.
So I am share code in github &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-micropython-beginner"&gt;https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-micropython-beginner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-relay-wemos"&gt;https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-relay-wemos&lt;/a&gt; and I fixed small bug I found on Marlin 3D-Printer firmware and make video help every-one under stand 3D-Printer Technology.
And I have youtube channel for share how to, review, teach 3D-Printer, drone, micro controller, Etc &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/deenajacom"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/deenajacom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a maker. I love IOT, 3D-Printer and Micro-python technology make my life happy. I need share my experience esp82266 with micro-python it easy. Every one can do by self. So I am share code in github &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-micropython-beginner"&gt;https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-micropython-beginner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-relay-wemos"&gt;https://github.com/montri2025/esp8266-relay-wemos&lt;/a&gt; and I help fixed small bug on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/MarlinFirmware/Marlin"&gt;https://github.com/MarlinFirmware/Marlin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/montri2025/marlin1.6-micromake-C1"&gt;https://github.com/montri2025/marlin1.6-micromake-C1&lt;/a&gt; just have one fork and make video help every-one understand 3D-Printer Technology. And I have youtube channel for share how to, review, teach 3D-Printer, drone, micro controller, Etc: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/deenajacom"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/deenajacom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hy: Running a webapp with LISP on Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/hy-running-a-webapp-with-lisp-on-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Murat Knecht</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/hy-running-a-webapp-with-lisp-on-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is so much more than just a readable language: It's also a &lt;em&gt;powerful platform&lt;/em&gt; with an amazing standard library and tons of libraries! Let's use that platform to run another language, &lt;em&gt;a LISP&lt;/em&gt;.
Hy &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hylang.org"&gt;http://hylang.org&lt;/a&gt; is a LISP running on the Python platform. In this Lightning Talk I'll demo a small Flask webapp written in Hy, and show how Hy macros allow us to express our intention clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You are smart, motivated and have a unique perspective&lt;/em&gt; -- that's my premise as CTO of engageSPARK &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://engagespark.com"&gt;http://engagespark.com&lt;/a&gt;. Originally I'm from Berlin, and have worked there for a couple of years, but for the past three years I've served at engageSPARK in Cebu, Philippines, and enjoy almost every minute of it. CTO means being team lead, architect, coder and coach. I find challenge and joy in all these roles.
On the tech-side, I work mostly with Python and Golang, but secretly enjoy languages with the odd super power like LISP. I use Emacs, and highly respect Vim power-users, because they're so incredibly fast.
I try to live purposefully and deliberately. That's why I joined engageSPARK as the first opportunity Labs &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opplabs.org"&gt;http://opplabs.org&lt;/a&gt; company. Let me know how I can help you live your life well.
Oh, and if ever &lt;strong&gt;you find yourself in Cebu, do say Hi!&lt;/strong&gt; (For example on LinkedIn &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/murat-knecht/"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/murat-knecht/&lt;/a&gt; or at muratk[&amp;#64;my company's name.com] . We have a desk and Internet for you, if you're willing to share some of your knowledge and uniqueness. :) In any case, always glad to help out with sightseeing tips and a cold beverage.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Image Classification using Deep Learning in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/image-classification-using-deep-learning-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sandeep Saurabh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/image-classification-using-deep-learning-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be talking about the Capsule Networks which is the latest buzz word in whole deep learning community. The talk will connect the dots from the past methods till Capsule networks and show how to make them work in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have done my Bachelors and Masters of Technology from prestigious Indian Institute of Technology -Delhi, in Mathematics and Computing. Since college days, I have been working in neural network projects using all kinds of languages like MATLAB, Java and python. I did internship in distributed computing at Chinese Academy of Science in 2011 and the experience which I had there was incredible. It taught me the importance and pleasure of interacting and sharing knowledge with people around the world. Currently I am working as a Senior Data Scientist in an analytics firm BRIDGEi2i Analytics Solutions in Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduce syntax and history of Python from 2.4 to 3.6</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/introduce-syntax-and-history-of-python-from-24-to-36.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manabu Terada</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/introduce-syntax-and-history-of-python-from-24-to-36.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we began to use Python in some production systems at 2.3 or 2.4. I think Python 2.4 had enough functionality to build any system. Many tools ware created and used.
Python 2.4 was released nearly 15 years ago. Since then Python has been steadily evolving. Although it is possible to create a system with only Python 2.4, it is necessary to know the latest Python trends in order to write code that is better, more maintainable, and more performance-oriented.
There are also features and grammar in the web knockout that are often overlooked, not only by new python users, but also by seasoned Python veterans. I will introduce those features and grammar that I think are important while comparing the grammar and functions incorporated in Python 2.4 and now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manabu is the founder and CEO of CMS Communications Inc., a Tokyo-based professional Plone and Python development company.
Manabu has contributed east Asian language functions to Plone. He has been Board chair of PyCon Japan and is a core member of the Japan Plone Users Group. He was Guest Associate Professor of Hitotsubashi University in 2011, and he became a PSF Contributing member in September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introducing TOKYO, Japan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/introducing-tokyo-japan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manabu Terada</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/introducing-tokyo-japan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talk
Announcing PyCon JP, 15-18 September, 2018 and PloneConf, 5-11 November, 2018 both in Ota City Industrial Plaza (PiO), Tokyo!
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pycon.jp/"&gt;https://www.pycon.jp/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2018.ploneconf.org/"&gt;https://2018.ploneconf.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manabu is the founder and CEO of CMS Communications Inc., a Tokyo-based professional Plone and Python development company.
Manabu has contributed east Asian language functions to Plone. He has been Board chair of PyCon Japan and is a core member of the Japan Plone Users Group. He was Guest Associate Professor of Hitotsubashi University in 2011, and he became a PSF Contributing member in September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Modern Open Source: Challenges and Opportunities</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/modern-open-source-challenges-and-opportunities.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wes McKinney</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/modern-open-source-challenges-and-opportunities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern Open Source: Challenges and Opportunities
Community-led Open Source and You
This keynote gives a broad overview of the social, commercial and technological context of the open source software development.
In closing, Wes introduces URSA LABS, an innovation lab to support the creation of data science tools. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ursalabs.org"&gt;https://ursalabs.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wes McKinney has been creating fast, easy-to-use data wrangling and statistical computing tools, mostly in the Python programming language, since 2007. He is best known for creating the pandas project and writing the book Python for Data Analysis.
He is a PMC member of the Apache Arrow and Parquet projects in The Apache Software Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Monitoring your Python Application</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/monitoring-your-python-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aravind Putrevu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/monitoring-your-python-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Application Performance Monitoring (APM) is a solution built on Elastic Stack. APM helps you to build/store data points in Elasticsearch and visualize. It automatically collects information from your python application/service.
This talk mainly targets at introducing the solution, why it is needed and what you can do with data. It ends with once data is stored within Elasticsearch, what else you can use (ex. Infrastructure Monitoring, Machine Learning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aravind is a loquacious person, who has something to talk about everything. He is passionate about evangelising technology, meeting developers and helping in solving their problems. He is a backend developer and has six years of development experience. Currently, he works as a Developer Advocate At Elastic and interact with developer community in South East Asia and India.
He has deep interest in Machine Learning, Security Incident Analysis and IoT tech. In his free time, he plays around Raspi or a Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCons in APAC</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/pycons-in-apac.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Iqbal Abdullah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/pycons-in-apac.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk gives an overview of PyCons in the Asia-Pacific region, since 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day job is running Xoxzo Inc, a cloud telephony platform based in Tokyo.
Helped found PyCon JP and PyCon MY.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>PyThaiNLP : Thai natural language processing in Python.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/pythainlp-thai-natural-language-processing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wannaphong Phatthiyaphaibun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/pythainlp-thai-natural-language-processing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am a PyThaiNLP founder. PyThaiNLP is a python module similar to nltk , but it's working primarily on Thai language instead of English. It supports both Python 2.7 and Python 3.
GitHub : &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyThaiNLP/pythainlp"&gt;https://github.com/PyThaiNLP/pythainlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a PyThaiNLP founder.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Events in Asia</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/python-events-in-asia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Noah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/python-events-in-asia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talk
Introducing regional PyCons and other Python-related events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSSASIA volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python for Life Sciences</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/python-for-life-sciences.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kulwadee Somboonviwat</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/python-for-life-sciences.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has gained increasing popularity among bioinformatics researchers and practitioners. In this talk, I will explain how Python is being used to decipher the language of Life.
The talk is divided into three parts. In the first part, I will briefly describe how biological molecules (e.g. DNA, Protein) are represented in computer programs. In the second part, I will present key Pythonic software tools in bioinformatics. Finally, in the third part, I will talk about two Biological data analysis tasks solved with Python, namely molecular sequence analysis and molecular structure analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a researcher who loves using Python. My current interests include bioinformatics, question answering systems, chatbots, and deep learning. I have been using Python since 2008. My first Python project is the development of multi-threaded Pythonic web crawler using Stackless Python and PostgreSQL. In 2013, I have started collaborating with biochemists and helped them analyzing biological data by using Python as the main language. I speak Thai, English, and also some Japanese. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python for Self-Trackers: How to Visualize and Better Understand Your Life in Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/python-for-self-trackers-how-to-visualize-and-better-understand-your-life-in-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Koester</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/python-for-self-trackers-how-to-visualize-and-better-understand-your-life-in-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s easier than ever to track our lives, work and bodies with a smartphone, wearable, home sensor or computer. But what can we do with all this data? Can it help you become a better version of yourself?
While we often hear about data in terms of data leaks and surveillance, personal data and self-tracking can be empowering too.  With smartphones, wearables, tracking apps, home sensors, and many other methods, it’s easier than ever to collect a lot of data on our lives. But we are still struggling to engage and find meaning in all of the data we collect.
Python and its data science toolset can help transform personal data into a personal dashboard of data visualizations and predictive models. How can python help us better collect, visualize, understand and find patterns in our personal data and self-tracking?
In this talk, I’ll show you how to track your life in different ways, and, with python’s data science toolkit, how to engage and understand that data. The stated goal of the quantified self and self-tracking is to “measure or document something about your self such that it gains meaning.” I think we can go one step further and use data to become better; use data to become data-driven!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Koester (&amp;#64;markwkoester) is a self-tracker, writer, and web and mobile app developer.
Creator: - PhotoStatsApp www.photostats.io, a photo tracking app without the cloud,
- PodcastTracker www.podcasttracker.com, a web app to log your podcast listening, and
- Biomarker Tracker www.biomarkertracker.com, a health analytics service to better understand your blood test results.
He currently runs a boutique dev shop (Int3c.com) and is an active open source contributor.  Former Regional Lead in Greater China at Techstars, a seed-stage accelerator. He regularly writes about self-tracking, quantified self and data-driven life at www.markwk.com.
Social Media:
* &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/markwkoester"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/markwkoester&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/markwkoester"&gt;https://twitter.com/markwkoester&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/markwkoester"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/markwkoester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Software Foundation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/python-software-foundation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Younggun Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/python-software-foundation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Younggun introduces what the Python Software Foundation does, how to join it, and what membership entails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon Korea Organizer (former) PSF Board Director a mediocre software engineer a frequent PyCon traveler&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Pythonic Functional Programming with Coconut</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/pythonic-functional-programming-with-coconut.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anthony Khong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/pythonic-functional-programming-with-coconut.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With functions being first-class citizens, Python allows us to build programmes with higher-order functions. However, it is often cumbersome to do something that would be bread-and-butter in a typical functional language. The lack of concise syntax for lambdas, currying and function compositions is a nuisance. The lack of boilerplate-less pattern matching and pattern matching could be a deal breaker. This talk presents Coconut, a functional superset of Python, which aims to enable writing elegant functional code, whilst staying with the familiar Python environment and libraries. We will identify various pain points of writing functional code in Python, and demonstrates how Coconut addresses the problems. In particular, we will start with a basic coding problem, and move on to designing a machine-learning pipeline with a functional approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a data scientist in Agoda, an innovative accommodation website that places a huge emphasis in machine learning algorithms. I have been using Python on a daily basis since 2013 as a freelance data scientist and algorithmic trader. I am also a functional programming enthusiast, and my experience mainly comes from writing Scala code in Agoda and using Haskell for scripting. I enjoy writing functional-style code in Python, and have been actively trying to marry the two for years. My other passion include high-performance computing, Bayesian statistics and Vim.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python's Scientific Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/pythons-scientific-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manoj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/pythons-scientific-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talk
Introducing NumFocus, an organisation to support Python's scientific ecosystem, and the associated PyData network of meetups.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://numfocus.org/"&gt;https://numfocus.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydata.org/delhi2017/"&gt;https://pydata.org/delhi2017/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founder and Organizer for PyData Delhi. Keynote and international speaker at many Python conferences around the world. To-be Software Engineer at Yelp!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Rage Against The Learning Machine (A New Hope)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/rage-against-the-learning-machine-a-new-hope.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>errazudin ishak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/rage-against-the-learning-machine-a-new-hope.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is ranked numero uno in Gartner’s Top 10 Strategic Technology Trends for 2017. In recent years, it has received a lot of attention and already revolutionized many areas from finance to image recognition to transportation. This talk, aims to make machine learning simple, fun and accessible to anyone with working examples covering couple of tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Errazudin works as Data Masseuse at Jauhar Science Research, Malaysia. His job focuses on making sense out of massive data. He has previously spoken at several meetups and conferences and has worked with various technologies. In his free time, he loves to compose Ahmad-Jais-like tunes in his dream or try to help his little daughter with her super tough kindergarten homework.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sequence Labeling with python-crfsuite</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/sequence-labeling-with-python-crfsuite.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Arthit Suriywongkul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/sequence-labeling-with-python-crfsuite.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labeling sequences (any kind of sequences), using Python. E.g. using python-crfsuite, sklearn-crfsuite, PyStruct, pytorch-crf, and others. Not as trendy as &amp;quot;deep learning&amp;quot;, but:
- quite reliable, used in leading linguistic packages,
- can give good results on limited training data (provided you can specify features, which requires domain knowledge),
- but computationally intensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colab Notebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bit.ly/crf-wordseg"&gt;https://bit.ly/crf-wordseg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bit.ly/crf-wordseg-slides"&gt;https://bit.ly/crf-wordseg-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Studying Thai with programming</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/studying-thai-with-programming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Delfino</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/studying-thai-with-programming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm an educator with a background in computer science. I've worked as a firmware engineer at a large corporation and as a software developer at a small firm and taught at innovative high schools teaching mathematics and CS. I'm currently teaching at an international school in Bangkok. I am part Thai but born and raised in America in the state of Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Teaching and Learning with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/teaching-and-learning-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Delfino</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/teaching-and-learning-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will feature discussions of how Python can be used to teach principles of computer science but it isn't limited to educators. Learning about learning is an increasingly important skill in today's world of rapidly evolving technology. I will share my experience teaching computer science and computer programming starting with being a part of the team that changed my university's Intro to Programming course from using C++ to Python. Then, I'll share tools I've used to engage students in Python programming including repl.it and Raspberry Pi and run through some of the lessons I've taught with them. I'll also discuss education best practices and how learners can apply them to their own self-education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm an educator with a background in computer science. I've worked as a firmware engineer at a large corporation and as a software developer at a small firm and taught at innovative high schools teaching mathematics and CS. I'm currently teaching at an international school in Bangkok. I am part Thai but born and raised in America in the state of Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Hungry Bot</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/the-hungry-bot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Uli Hitzel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/the-hungry-bot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Showing the result of running image recognition algorithms (in this case, the Computer Vision API on Azure) against his own Instagram feed and getting back a word cloud.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hacks.sotong.io"&gt;http://hacks.sotong.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data &amp;amp; Automation Geek, based in Singapore. Python, Git, Redis, HTTP. Worked for companies including Red Hat, Microsoft, IBM, Playboy and Yahoo!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>The near awesomeness of NumPy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/the-near-awesomeness-of-numpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/the-near-awesomeness-of-numpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The near awesomeness of NumPy: why NumPy is useful for scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>The power of Jupyter notebooks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/the-power-of-jupyter-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Amy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/the-power-of-jupyter-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By Jupyter! I'm gonna show you the power of Jupyter!
By that I mean I'm going to do a live demo of Jupyter notebooks.
When I was a kid I grew up with the BBC Model B. When you switched this thing on, you got a prompt. You could launch into BASIC and write programs. Suddenly you felt powerful. The possibilities were endless. 30 years later, Jupyter again gives me that same feeling of being able to explore, solve problems, and that awesome power was right there at your fingertips.
The exciting thing about this talk is that people will be able to interact with it as I go, and even write some code.
I'll explain what Jupyter is, what it's used for, and then I'll do a demo using Jupyter to mess around with some data and make some plots. Then wow the crowd with an animation.
I'll set up a sandboxed notebook that the audience can access, such that they can follow along and try out the code on their mobile phones or laptops. For Android users, I'll then show them what they need to do to install jupyter running under termux, a debian-like environment for Android (no rooting required). Then I'll show them the awesome power of being able to write Python on a mobile device, by writing a script to log my phone's location and take photos, and show them by SSHing into a jupyter session on my phone and walking around with it.
Live demos galore!! What can possibly go wrong?? But the nice thing is, because the jupyter notebooks will be running locally, I don't have to depend on the internet.
My hope is that this talk will inspire people that programming is fun and exciting, and to remove the barrier to entry of it being hard to set up an environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days I pretend I'm a lazy layabout but actually I am always working on some kind of weird software projects. In a previous life I helped save the world at the UN. I'm also helping to (dis)organise this event.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Unimaginable Things in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/unimaginable-things-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Watcharapol Watcharawisetkul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/unimaginable-things-in-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Writing a good frontend test cases using RobotFramework</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/writing-a-good-frontend-test-cases-using-robotframework.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Min Khant Zaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/writing-a-good-frontend-test-cases-using-robotframework.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is a short talk about how a simple Gherkin-styled Python based Robotframework could be used to write test cases. It covers the brief installation using python envwrapper - an environment isolation package and simply showing 2 python scripts which is usable with Robotframework and 1~2 Robotframework's keyword-based testing. It will also cover some important inbuilt functions in Robotframeworks such as sending out keystrokes to the System and using some other libraries to help and make front-end testing a much more awesome experience. Another part of the talk would be describing a single keyword base and some yaml scripts to make the test-cases more reusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name's Min Khant Zaw. I am Computer Science student who is enthusiastic about mostly near-to-the-metal stuff. I mostly code in C++, Java and Python but I use C++ the most because I like playing around with Algorithms.  I am also the President of the IT Society in my campus and had organized over 10 events for the Computer Science students. I mostly spent my time listening to British Synth Pop and spitting out all the crappy codes I can come up with in Sublime Text.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>