<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - PyData Berlin 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A concrete guide to time-series databases with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/a-concrete-guide-to-time-series-databases-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We evaluated time-series databases and complementary services to stream-process sensor data. In this talk, our evaluation will be presented. The final implementation will be shown, alongside python-tools we've built and lessons learned during the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding time-series data is essential to handle automatically generated data, be it from server logs, IoT devices or any other continuous measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to handle the large amounts of incoming data from concrete mixing trucks, we evaluated a number of time-series databases as well as services to stream-process the data. For all of those decisions a key question was, of course, how well any of these tools integrate with our existing, all-Python backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right angle on time-series data will help you move tons of data with little engineering effort. In this talk, you'll learn from our practical experiences of choosing and implementing a time-series database in a Python context. You'll go away with a better understanding of how you can efficiently store, analyse and exploit streaming data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Heiner Tholen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/a-concrete-guide-to-time-series-databases-with-python.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Time Series</category></item><item><title>A journey through 4 industries with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/a-journey-through-4-industries-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this keynote, I will share the lessons learned from using Python in 4 industries. Apart from machine learning applications that I build in my day to day as a data scientist and machine learning engineer, I also use Python to develop games for my own gaming company, Quill Game Studios. There is a lot of versatility in Python, and it's been my pleasure to use it to solve many interesting problems. I hope that this talk can give inspiration to various types of applications in your own industry as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Shu Chang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/a-journey-through-4-industries-with-python.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Accelerating Public Consultations with Large Language Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/accelerating-public-consultations-with-large-language-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Local Planning Authorities (LPAs) in the UK rely on written representations from the community to inform their Local Plans which outline development needs for their area. With an average of 2000 representations per consultation and 4 rounds of consultation per Local Plan, the volume of information can be overwhelming for both LPAs and the Planning Inspectorate tasked with examining the legality and soundness of plans. In this study, we investigate the potential for Large Language Models (LLMs) to streamline representation analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that LLMs have the potential to significantly reduce the time and effort required to analyse representations, with simulations on historical Local Plans projecting a reduction in processing time by over 30%, and experiments showing classification accuracy of up to 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we discuss our experimental process which used a distributed experimentation environment with Jupyter Lab and cloud resources to evaluate the performance of the BERT, RoBERTa, DistilBERT, and XLNet models. We also discuss the design and prototyping of web applications to support the aided processing of representations using Voilà, FastAPI, and React. Finally, we highlight successes and challenges encountered and suggest areas for future improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michele Dallachiesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/accelerating-public-consultations-with-large-language-models.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Actionable Machine Learning in the Browser with PyScript</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/actionable-machine-learning-in-the-browser-with-pyscript.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyScript brings the full PyData stack in the browser, opening up to unprecedented use cases for interactive data-intensive applications. In this scenario, the web browser becomes a ubiquitous computing platform, operating within a (nearly) zero-installation &amp;amp; server-less environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to create full-fledged interactive front-end machine learning applications using PyScript. We will dive into the the main features of the PyScript platform (e.g. built-in Javascript integration and local modules ), discussing new data &amp;amp; design patterns (e.g. loading heterogeneous data in the browser), required to adapt and to overcome the limitations imposed by the new operating environment (i.e. the browser).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valerio Maggio</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/actionable-machine-learning-in-the-browser-with-pyscript.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>PyScript</category></item><item><title>Advanced Visual Search Engine with Self-Supervised Learning (SSL)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/advanced-visual-search-engine-with-self-supervised-learning-ssl.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image retrieval is the process of searching for images in a large database that are similar to one or more query images. A classical approach is to transform the database images and the query images into embeddings via a feature extractor (e.g., a CNN or a ViT), so that they can be compared via a distance metric. Self-supervised learning (SSL) can be used to train a feature extractor without the need for expensive and time-consuming labeled training data. We will use DINO's SSL method to build a feature extractor and Milvus, an open-source vector database built for evolutionary similarity search, to index image representation vectors for efficient retrieval. We will compare the SSL approach with supervised and pre-trained feature extractors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antoine Toubhans</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/advanced-visual-search-engine-with-self-supervised-learning-ssl.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Self-Supervised Learning</category></item><item><title>Apache Arrow - Connecting and accelerating dataframe libraries across the PyData</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/apache-arrow-connecting-and-accelerating-dataframe-libraries-across-the-pydata.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apache Arrow is a multi-language toolbox for accelerated data interchange and in-memory processing, and is becoming the de facto standard for tabular data. This talk will give an overview of the recent developments both in Apache Arrow itself as how it is being adopted in the PyData ecosystem (and beyond) and can improve your day-to-day data analytics workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joris Van den Bossche</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/apache-arrow-connecting-and-accelerating-dataframe-libraries-across-the-pydata.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Apache Arrow</category></item><item><title>Apache StreamPipes for Pythonistas: IIoT data handling made easy!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/apache-streampipes-for-pythonistas-iiot-data-handling-made-easy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The industrial environment offers a lot of interesting use cases for data enthusiasts. There are myriads of interesting challenges that can be solved by data scientists.
However, collecting industrial data in general and industrial IoT (IIoT) data in particular, is cumbersome and not really appealing for anyone who just wants to work with data.
Apache StreamPipes addresses this pitfall and allows anyone to extract data from IIoT data sources without messing around with (old-fashioned) protocols. In addition, StreamPipes newly developed Python client now gives Pythonistas the ability to programmatically access and work with them in a Pythonic way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a basic introduction into the functionality of Apache StreamPipes itself, followed by a deeper discussion of the Python client. Finally, a live demo will show how IIoT data can be easily derived in Python and used directly for visualization and ML model training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra material:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bossenti/pycon-23-streampipes-pythonistas"&gt;https://github.com/bossenti/pycon-23-streampipes-pythonistas&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.com/pyconde-pydata-berlin-2023/talk/LXBGZS/#:~:text=See%20also%3A-,slide%20deck%20(3.7%C2%A0MB),-Tim%20Bossenmaier"&gt;https://pretalx.com/pyconde-pydata-berlin-2023/talk/LXBGZS/#:~:text=See%20also%3A-,slide%20deck%20(3.7%C2%A0MB),-Tim%20Bossenmaier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Bossenmaier</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/apache-streampipes-for-pythonistas-iiot-data-handling-made-easy.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Apache StreamPipes</category></item><item><title>Ask-A-Question - an FAQ-answering service for when there's little to no data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/ask-a-question-an-faq-answering-service-for-when-theres-little-to-no-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing data science in international development often means finding the right-sized solution in resource-constrained settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk walks you through how my team helped answer thousands of questions from pregnant folks and new parents on a South African maternal and child health helpline, which model we ended up choosing and why (hint: resource-constraints!), and how we've packaged everything into a service that anyone can start for themselves,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the talk, I hope you'll know how to start your own FAQ-answering service and learn about one example of doing data science in international development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Suzin You</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/ask-a-question-an-faq-answering-service-for-when-theres-little-to-no-data.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>AutoGluon - AutoML for Tabular, Multimodal and Time Series Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/autogluon-automl-for-tabular-multimodal-and-time-series-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AutoML, or automated machine learning, offers the promise of transforming raw data into accurate predictions with minimal human intervention, expertise, and manual experimentation. In this talk, we will introduce AutoGluon, a cutting-edge toolkit that enables AutoML for tabular, multimodal and time series data. AutoGluon emphasizes usability, enabling a wide variety of tasks from regression to time series forecasting and image classification through a unified and intuitive API. We will specifically focus on tasks on tabular and time series tasks where AutoGluon is the current state-of-the-art, and demonstrate how AutoGluon can be used to achieve competitive performance on tabular and time series competition data sets. We will also discuss the techniques used to automatically build and train these models, peeking under the hood of AutoGluon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Caner Turkmen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/autogluon-automl-for-tabular-multimodal-and-time-series-data.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>AutoGluon</category><category>AutoML</category></item><item><title>Bayesian Marketing Science - Solving Marketing's 3 Biggest Problems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/bayesian-marketing-science-solving-marketings-3-biggest-problems.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will present two new open-source packages that make up a powerful and state-of-the-art marketing analytics toolbox. Specifically, PyMC-Marketing is a new library built on top of the popular Bayesian modeling library PyMC. PyMC-Marketing allows robust estimation of customer acquisition costs (via media mix modeling) as well as customer lifetime value.
In addition, I will show how we can estimate the effectiveness of marketing campaigns using a new Bayesian causal inference package called CausalPy. The talk will be applied with a real-world case-study and many code examples. Special emphasis will be placed on the interplay between these tools and how they can be combined together to make optimal marketing budget decisions in complex scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Wiecki</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/bayesian-marketing-science-solving-marketings-3-biggest-problems.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Bayesian</category></item><item><title>BHAD - Explainable unsupervised anomaly detection using Bayesian histograms</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/bhad-explainable-unsupervised-anomaly-detection-using-bayesian-histograms.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The detection of outliers or anomalous data patterns is one of the most prominent machine learning use cases in industrial applications. I present a Bayesian histogram anomaly detector (BHAD), where the number of bins is treated as an additional unknown model parameter with an assigned prior distribution. BHAD scales linearly with the sample size and enables a straightforward explanation of individual scores, which makes it very suitable for industrial applications when model interpretability is crucial. I study the predictive performance of the proposed BHAD algorithm with various SoA anomaly detection approaches using simulated data and also using popular benchmark datasets for outlier detection. The reported results indicate that BHAD has very competitive predictive accuracy
compared to other more complex and computationally more expensive algorithms, while being explainable and fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.org/project/bhad/"&gt;https://pypi.org/project/bhad/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Vosseler</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/bhad-explainable-unsupervised-anomaly-detection-using-bayesian-histograms.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Bayesian</category></item><item><title>Building a personal internet front-page with spaCy and Prodigy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/building-a-personal-internet-front-page-with-spacy-and-prodigy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the internet can be a bit overwhelming, so I thought I would make a tool to create a personalized summary of it! In this talk, I'll demonstrate a personal front-page project that allows me to filter info on the internet on a certain topic, built using spaCy, an open-source library for NLP, and Prodigy, a scriptable annotation tool. With this project, I learned about the power of working with tools that provide extensive customizability without sacrificing ease of use. Throughout the talk, I'll also discuss how design concepts of developer tools can improve the development experience when building complex and adaptable software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Victoria Slocum</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/building-a-personal-internet-front-page-with-spacy-and-prodigy.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>spaCy</category><category>Prodigy</category><category>NLP</category></item><item><title>Common issues with Time Series data and how to solve them</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/common-issues-with-time-series-data-and-how-to-solve-them.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time-series data is all around us: from logistics to digital marketing, from pricing to stock markets. It's hard to imagine a modern business that has no time series data to forecast. However, mastering such forecasting is not an easy task. For this talk, together with other domain experts, I have collected a list of common time series issues that data professionals commonly run into. After this talk, you will learn to identify, understand, and resolve such issues. This will include stabilising divergent time series, organising delayed / irregular data, handling missing values without anomaly propagation,
and reducing the impact of noise and outliers on your forecasting models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vadim Nelidov</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/common-issues-with-time-series-data-and-how-to-solve-them.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Time Series</category></item><item><title>Contributing to an open-source content library for NLP</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/contributing-to-an-open-source-content-library-for-nlp.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bricks is an open-source content library for natural language processing, which provides the building blocks to quickly and easily enrich, transform or analyze text data for machine learning projects. For many Pythonistas, contributing to an open-source project seems scary and intimidating. In this tutorial, we offer a hands-on experience in which programmers and data scientists learn how to code their own building blocks and share their creations with the community with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leonard Püttmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/contributing-to-an-open-source-content-library-for-nlp.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Cooking up a ML Platform - Growing pains and lessons learned</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/cooking-up-a-ml-platform-growing-pains-and-lessons-learned.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is a ML platform and do you even need one? When should you consider investing in your own ML platform? What challenges can you expect building and maintaining one? Tune in and discover (some) answers to these questions and more! I will share a first-hand account of our ongoing journey towards becoming a ML platform team within Delivery Hero's Logistics department, including how we got here, how we structure our work, and what challenges and tools we are focussing on next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cole Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/cooking-up-a-ml-platform-growing-pains-and-lessons-learned.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Create interactive Jupyter websites with JupyterLite</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/create-interactive-jupyter-websites-with-jupyterlite.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks are a popular tool for data science and scientific computing, allowing users to mix code, text, and multimedia in a single document. However, sharing Jupyter notebooks can be challenging, as they require installing a specific software environment to be viewed and executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JupyterLite is a Jupyter distribution that runs entirely in the web browser without any server components. A significant benefit of this approach is the ease of deployment. With JupyterLite, the only requirement to provide a live computing environment is a collection of static assets. In this talk, we will show how you can create such static website and deploy it to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeremy Tuloup</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/create-interactive-jupyter-websites-with-jupyterlite.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Delivering AI at Scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/delivering-ai-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows our yellow vans, trucks and planes around the world. But do you know how data drives our business and how we leverage algorithms and technology in our core operations? We will share some “behind the scenes” insights on Deutsche Post DHL Group’s journey towards a Data-Driven Company.
• Large-Scale Use Cases: Challenging and high impact Use Cases in all major areas of logistics,
including Computer Vision and NLP
• Fancy Algorithms: Deep-Neural Networks, TSP Solvers and the standard toolkit of a Data
Scientist
• Modern Tooling: Cloud Platforms, Kubernetes , Kubeflow, Auto ML
• No rusty working mode: small, self-organized, agile project teams, combining state of the art
Machine Learning with MLOps best practices
• A young, motivated and international team – German skills are only “nice to have”
But we have more to offer than slides filled with buzzwords. We will demonstrate our passion for our work, deep dive into our largest use cases that impact your everyday life and share our approach for a timeseries forecasting library - combining data science, software engineering and technology for efficient and easy to maintain machine learning projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Severin Schmitt</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/delivering-ai-at-scale.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Driving down the Memray lane - Profiling your data science work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When handling a large amount of data, memory profiling the data science workflow becomes more important. It gives you insight into which process consumes lots of memory. In this talk, we will introduce Mamray, a Python memory profiling tool and its new Jupyter plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Dynamic pricing at Flix</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/dynamic-pricing-at-flix.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the talk we give a brief overview of how we use Dynamic Pricing to tune the prices for rides based on demand, time of purchase, unexpected events strike etc., and other criteria to fulfil our business requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amit Verma</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/dynamic-pricing-at-flix.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>evosax - JAX-Based Evolution Strategies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/evosax-jax-based-evolution-strategies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tired of having to handle asynchronous processes for neuroevolution? Do you want to leverage massive vectorization and high-throughput accelerators for evolution strategies (ES)? evosax allows you to leverage JAX, XLA compilation and auto-vectorization/parallelization to scale ES to your favorite accelerators. In this talk we will get to know the core API and how to solve distributed black-box optimization problems with evolution strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Robert Lange</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/evosax-jax-based-evolution-strategies.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>JAX</category></item><item><title>Exploring the Power of Cyclic Boosting</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/exploring-the-power-of-cyclic-boosting.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have recently open-sourced a pure-Python implementation of Cyclic Boosting, a family of general-purpose, supervised machine learning algorithms. Its predictions are fully explainable on individual sample level, and yet Cyclic Boosting can deliver highly accurate and robust models. For this, it requires little hyperparameter tuning and minimal data pre-processing (including support for missing information and categorical variables of high cardinality), making it an ideal off-the-shelf method for structured, heterogeneous data sets. Furthermore, it is computationally inexpensive and fast, allowing for rapid improvement iterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modeling process, especially the infamous but unavoidable feature engineering, is facilitated by automatic creation of an extensive set of visualizations for data dependencies and training results. In this presentation, we will provide an overview of the inner workings of Cyclic Boosting, along with a few sample use cases, and demonstrate the usage of the new Python library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felix Wick</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/exploring-the-power-of-cyclic-boosting.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Geospatial Data Processing with Python - A Comprehensive Tutorial</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/geospatial-data-processing-with-python-a-comprehensive-tutorial.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will learn about the various Python modules for processing geospatial data, including GDAL, Rasterio, Pyproj, Shapely, Folium, Fiona, OSMnx, Libpysal, Geopandas, Pydeck, Whitebox, ESDA, and Leaflet. You will gain hands-on experience working with real-world geospatial data and learn how to perform tasks such as reading and writing spatial data, reprojecting data, performing spatial analyses, and creating interactive maps. This tutorial is suitable for beginners as well as intermediate Python users who want to expand their knowledge in the field of geospatial data processing&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martin Christen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/geospatial-data-processing-with-python-a-comprehensive-tutorial.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Getting started with JAX</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/getting-started-with-jax.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deepminds JAX ecosystem provides deep learning practitioners with an appealing alternative to TensorFlow and PyTorch. Among its strengths are great functionalities such as native TPU support, as well as easy vectorization and parallelization. Nevertheless, making your first steps in JAX can feel complicated given some of its idiosyncrasies. This talk helps new users getting started in this promising ecosystem by sharing practical tips and best practises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simon Pressler</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/getting-started-with-jax.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>JAX</category></item><item><title>Haystack for climate Q/A</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/haystack-for-climate-qa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can NLP and Haystack help answer sustainability questions and fight climate change? In this talk we walkthrough our experience using Haystack to build Question Answering Models for the climate change and sustainability domain. We discuss how we did it, some of the challenges we faced, and what we learnt along the way!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vibha Vikram Rao</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/haystack-for-climate-qa.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How Are We Managing? Data Teams Management IRL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-are-we-managing-data-teams-management-irl.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The title 'Data Scientist' has been in use for 15 years now. We have been attending PyData conferences for over 10 years as well. The hype around data science and AI seems higher than ever before. But How are we managing?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noa Tamir</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-are-we-managing-data-teams-management-irl.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>How Chatbots work – We need to talk!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-chatbots-work-we-need-to-talk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatbots are fun to use, ranging from simple chit-chat ('How are you today?') to more sophisticated use cases like shopping assistants, or the diagnosis of technical or medical problems. Despite their mostly simple user interaction, chatbots must combine various complex NLP concepts to deliver convincing, intelligent, or even witty results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yuqiong Weng</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-chatbots-work-we-need-to-talk.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How Python enables future computer chips</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-python-enables-future-computer-chips.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the semiconductor division of Carl Zeiss it's our mission to continuously make computer chips faster and more energy efficient. To do so, we go to the very limits of what is possible, both physically and technologically. This is only possible through massive research and development efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we tell the story how Python became a central tool for our R&amp;amp;D activities. This includes technical aspects as well as organization and culture. How do you make sure that hundreds of people work in consistent environments? – How do you get all people on board to work together with Python? – You have lots of domain experts without much software background. How do you prevent them from creating a mess when projects get larger?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-python-enables-future-computer-chips.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How to baseline in NLP and where to go from there</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-baseline-in-nlp-and-where-to-go-from-there.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the build-measure-learn paradigm and the role of baselines in natural language processing (NLP). We will cover the common NLP tasks of classification, clustering, search, and named entity recognition, and describe the baseline approaches that can be used for each task. We will also discuss how to move beyond these baselines through weak learning and transfer learning. By the end of this talk, attendees will have a better understanding of how to establish and improve upon baselines in NLP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tobias Sterbak</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-baseline-in-nlp-and-where-to-go-from-there.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How to build observability into a ML Platform</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-build-observability-into-a-ml-platform.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As machine learning becomes more prevalent across nearly every business and industry, making sure that these technologies are working and delivering quality is critical. In her talk, Alicia will discuss the importance of machine learning observability and why it should be a fundamental tool of modern machine learning architectures. Not only does it ensure models are accurate, but it helps teams iterate and improve models quicker. Alicia will dive into how Shopify has been prototyping building observability into different parts of its machine learning platform. This talk will provide insights on how to track model performance, how to catch any unexpected or erroneous behaviour, what types of behavior to look for in your data (e.g. drift, quality metrics) and in your model/predictions, and how observability could work with large language models and Chat AIs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Bargar</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-build-observability-into-a-ml-platform.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How to Feed Facts to Large Language Models and Reduce Hallucination</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-feed-facts-to-large-language-models-and-reduce-hallucination.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLM), like ChatGPT, have shown miraculous performances on various tasks. But there are still unsolved issues with these models: they can be confidently wrong and their knowledge becomes outdated. GPT also does not have any of the information that you have stored in your own data. In this talk, you'll learn how to use Haystack, an open source framework, to chain LLMs with other models and components to overcome these issues. We will build a practical application using these techniques. And you will walk away with a deeper understanding of how to use LLMs to build NLP products that work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mathis Lucka</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-feed-facts-to-large-language-models-and-reduce-hallucination.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How to Optimize Infrastructure, Tools and Teams for ML Workflows</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-optimize-infrastructure-tools-and-teams-for-ml-workflows.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the role of a machine learning enabler engineer in facilitating the development and deployment of machine learning models. We will discuss best practices for optimizing infrastructure and tools to streamline the machine learning workflow, reduce time to deployment, and enable data scientists to extract insights and value from data more efficiently. We will also examine case studies and examples of successful machine learning enabler engineering projects and share practical tips and insights for anyone interested in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yann Lemonnier</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-optimize-infrastructure-tools-and-teams-for-ml-workflows.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>How to teach NLP to a newbie &amp; get them started on their first project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-teach-nlp-to-a-newbie-get-them-started-on-their-first-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The materials presented during this tutorial are open source and can be used by coaches and tutors who want to teach their students how to use Python for text processing and text classification. (A minimal understanding of programming (in any language) is required by the students)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lisa Andreevna Chalaguine</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-to-teach-nlp-to-a-newbie-get-them-started-on-their-first-project.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Hyperparameter optimization for the impatient</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/hyperparameter-optimization-for-the-impatient.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last years, Hyperparameter Optimization (HPO) became a fundamental step in the training of Machine Learning (ML) models and in the creation of automatic ML pipelines.
Unfortunately, while HPO improves the predictive performance of the final model, it comes with a significant cost both in terms of computational resources and waiting time.
This leads many practitioners to try to lower the cost of HPO by employing unreliable heuristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will provide simple and practical algorithms for users that want to train models
with almost-optimal predictive performance, while incurring in a significantly lower cost and waiting time. The presented algorithms are agnostic to the application and the model being trained so they can be useful in a wide range of scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide results from an extensive experimental activity on public benchmarks, including comparisons with well-known techniques like Bayesian Optimization (BO), ASHA, Successive Halving. We will describe in which scenarios the biggest gains are observed (up to 30x) and provide examples for how to use these algorithms in a real-world environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the code used for this talk is available on [GitHub](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/awslabs/syne-tune"&gt;https://github.com/awslabs/syne-tune&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martin Wistuba</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/hyperparameter-optimization-for-the-impatient.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>I broke the PyTorch model - Debugging custom PyTorch models in a structured manner</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/i-broke-the-pytorch-model-debugging-custom-pytorch-models-in-a-structured-manner.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When building PyTorch models for custom applications from scratch there's usually one problem: The model does not learn anything. In a complex project, it can be tricky to identify the cause: Is it the data? A bug in the model? Choosing the wrong loss function at 3 am after an 8-hour coding session?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will build a toolbox to find the culprits in a structured manner. We will focus on simple ways to ensure a training loop is correct, generate synthetic training data to determine whether we have a model bug or problematic real-world data, and leverage pytest to safely refactor PyTorch models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, visitors will be well equipped to take the right steps when a model is not learning, quickly identify the underlying reasons, and prevent bugs in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Clara Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/i-broke-the-pytorch-model-debugging-custom-pytorch-models-in-a-structured-manner.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Improving Machine Learning from Human Feedback</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/improving-machine-learning-from-human-feedback.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large generative models rely upon massive data sets that are collected automatically. For example, GPT-3 was trained with data from &amp;quot;Common Crawl&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Web Text&amp;quot;, among other sources. As the saying goes — bigger isn't always better. While powerful, these data sets (and the models that they create) often come at a cost, bringing their &amp;quot;internet-scale biases&amp;quot; along with their &amp;quot;internet-trained models.&amp;quot; While powerful, these models beg the question — is unsupervised learning the best future for machine learning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ML researchers have developed new model-tuning techniques to address the known biases within existing models and improve their performance (as measured by response preference, truthfulness, toxicity, and result generalization). All of this at a fraction of the initial training cost. In this talk, we will explore these techniques, known as Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF), and how open-source machine learning tools like PyTorch and Label Studio can be used to tune off-the-shelf models using direct human feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erin Mikail Staples</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/improving-machine-learning-from-human-feedback.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>reinforcement learning</category><category>human feedback</category><category>pytorch</category><category>label studio</category></item><item><title>Incorporating GPT-3 into practical NLP workflows</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/incorporating-gpt-3-into-practical-nlp-workflows.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show how large language models such as GPT-3 complement rather than replace existing machine learning workflows. Initial annotations are gathered from the OpenAI API via zero- or few-shot learning, and then corrected by a human decision maker using an annotation tool. The resulting annotations can then be used to train and evaluate models as normal. This process results in higher accuracy than can be achieved from the OpenAI API alone, with the added benefit that you'll own and control the model for runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ines Montani</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/incorporating-gpt-3-into-practical-nlp-workflows.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Large Scale Feature Engineering and Datascience with Python &amp; Snowflake</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/large-scale-feature-engineering-and-datascience-with-python-snowflake.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Snowflake as a data platform is the core data repository of many large organizations. With the introduction of Snowflake's Snowpark for Python, Python developers can now collaborate and build on one platform with a secure Python sandbox, providing developers with dynamic scalability &amp;amp; elasticity as well as security and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll explain the core concepts of Snowpark for Python and how they can be used for large scale feature engineering and data science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Gorkow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/large-scale-feature-engineering-and-datascience-with-python-snowflake.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Snowflake</category></item><item><title>Let's contribute to pandas (3 hours) PART.1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin are excited to bring you this open source workshop dedicated to contributing to pandas. This tutorial is 3 hours. We will have a break and continue with the same group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noa Tamir</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part1.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Let's contribute to pandas (3 hours) PART.2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin are excited to bring you this open source workshop dedicated to contributing to pandas. This tutorial is 3 hours. We will have a break and continue with the same group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noa Tamir</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part2.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/lorem-ipsum-dolor-sit-amet.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A life without joy is like software without meaningful test data - it's uncertain and unreliable. The search for the perfect test data is a challenge. Real data should not be too real. Random data should not be too random. This is a randomly real and a really random journey to discover the balance between these two, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miroslav Šedivý</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/lorem-ipsum-dolor-sit-amet.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>Methods for Text Style Transfer - Text Detoxification Case</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/methods-for-text-style-transfer-text-detoxification-case.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global access to the Internet has enabled the spread of information throughout the world and has offered many new possibilities. On the other hand, alongside the advantages, the exponential and uncontrolled growth of user-generated content on the Internet has also facilitated the spread of toxicity and hate speech. Much work has been done in the direction of offensive speech detection. However, there is another more proactive way to fight toxic speech -- how a suggestion for a user as a detoxified version of the message. In this presentation, we will provide an overview how texts detoxification task can be solved. The proposed approaches can be reused for any text style transfer task for both monolingual and multilingual use-cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daryna Dementieva</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/methods-for-text-style-transfer-text-detoxification-case.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>NLP</category></item><item><title>Most of you don't need Spark. Large-scale data management on a budget with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/most-of-you-dont-need-spark-large-scale-data-management-on-a-budget-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python data ecosystem has matured during the last decade and there are less and less reasons to rely only large batch process executed in a Spark cluster, but with every large ecosystem, putting together the key pieces of technology takes some effort. There are now better storage technologies, streaming execution engines, query planners, and low level compute libraries. And modern hardware is way more powerful than what you'd probably expect. In this workshop we will explore some global-warming-reducing techniques to build more efficient data transformation pipelines in Python, and a little bit of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guillem Borrell</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/most-of-you-dont-need-spark-large-scale-data-management-on-a-budget-with-python.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Neo4j graph databases for climate policy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/neo4j-graph-databases-for-climate-policy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we walkthrough our experience using Neo4j and Python to model climate policy as a graph database. We discuss how we did it, some of the challenges we faced, and what we learnt along the way!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marcus Tedesco</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/neo4j-graph-databases-for-climate-policy.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Graph Databases</category><category>Neo4j</category></item><item><title>Observability for Distributed Computing with Dask</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/observability-for-distributed-computing-with-dask.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debugging is hard. Distributed debugging is hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dask is a popular library for parallel and distributed computing in Python. Dask is commonly used in data science, actual science, data engineering, and machine learning to distribute workloads onto clusters of many hundreds of workers with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when things go wrong life can become difficult due to all of the moving parts. These parts include your code, other PyData libraries like NumPy/pandas, the machines you're running on, the network between them, storage, the cloud, and of course issues with Dask itself. It can be difficult to understand what is going on, especially when things seem slower than they should be or fail unexpectedly. Observability is the key to sanity and success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we describe the tools Dask offers to help you observe your distributed cluster, analyze performance, and monitor your cluster to react to unexpected changes quickly. We will dive into distributed logging, automated metrics, event-based monitoring, and root-causing problems with diagnostic tooling. Throughout the talk, we will leverage real-world use cases to show how these tools help to identify and solve problems for large-scale users in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk should be particularly insightful for Dask users, but the approaches to observing distributed systems should be relevant to anyone operating at scale in production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hendrik Makait</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/observability-for-distributed-computing-with-dask.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Pandas 2.0 and beyond</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/pandas-20-and-beyond.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has reached a 2.0 milestone in 2023. But what does that mean? And what is coming after 2.0? This talk will give an overview of what happened in the latest releases of pandas and highlight some topics and major new features the pandas project is working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joris Van den Bossche</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/pandas-20-and-beyond.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Performing Root Cause Analysis with DoWhy, a Causal Machine-Learning Library</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/performing-root-cause-analysis-with-dowhy-a-causal-machine-learning-library.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will introduce the audience to DoWhy, a library for causal machine-learning (ML). We will introduce typical problems where causal ML can be applied and will specifically do a deep dive on root cause analysis using DoWhy. To do this, we will lay out what typical problem spaces for causal ML look like, what kind of problems we're trying to solve, and then show how to use DoWhy's API to solve these problems. Expect to see a lot of code with a hands-on example. We will close this session by zooming out a bit and also talk about the PyWhy organization governing DoWhy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Blöbaum</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/performing-root-cause-analysis-with-dowhy-a-causal-machine-learning-library.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Causal Inference</category><category>DoWhy</category></item><item><title>Polars - make the switch to lightning-fast dataframes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/polars-make-the-switch-to-lightning-fast-dataframes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will report on our experiences switching from Pandas to Polars in a real-world ML project. Polars is a new high-performance dataframe library for Python based on Apache Arrow and written in Rust. We will compare the performance of polars with the popular pandas library, and show how polars can provide significant speed improvements for data manipulation and analysis tasks. We will also discuss the unique features of polars, such as its ability to handle large datasets that do not fit into memory, and how it feels in practice to make the switch from Pandas. This talk is aimed at data scientists, analysts, and anyone interested in fast and efficient data processing in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Bierhance</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/polars-make-the-switch-to-lightning-fast-dataframes.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>polars</category></item><item><title>Postmodern Architecture - The Python Powered Modern Data Stack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/postmodern-architecture-the-python-powered-modern-data-stack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Modern Data Stack has brought a lot of new buzzwords into the data engineering lexicon: &amp;quot;data mesh&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;data observability&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;reverse ETL&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;data lineage&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;analytics engineering&amp;quot;. In this light-hearted talk we will demystify the evolving revolution that will define the future of data analytics &amp;amp; engineering teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our journey begins with the PyData Stack: pandas pipelines powering ETL workflows...clean code, tested code, data validation, perfect for in-memory workflows. As demand for self-serve analytics grows, new data sources bring more APIs to model, more code to maintain, DAG workflow orchestration tools, new nuances to capture (&amp;quot;the tax team defines revenue differently&amp;quot;), more dashboards, more not-quite-bugs (&amp;quot;but my number says this...&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data maturity journey is a well-trodden path with common pitfalls &amp;amp; opportunities. After dashboards comes predictive modelling (&amp;quot;what will happen&amp;quot;), prescriptive modelling (&amp;quot;what should we do?&amp;quot;), perhaps eventually automated decision making. Getting there is much easier with the advent of the Python Powered Modern Data Stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will cover the shift from ETL to ELT, the open-source Modern Data Stack tools you should know, with a focus on how dbt's new Python integration is changing how data pipelines are built, run, tested &amp;amp; maintained. By understanding the latest trends &amp;amp; buzzwords, attendees will gain a deeper insight into Python's role at the core of the future of data engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">John Sandall</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/postmodern-architecture-the-python-powered-modern-data-stack.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Architecture</category></item><item><title>Pragmatic ways of using Rust in your data project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/pragmatic-ways-of-using-rust-in-your-data-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing efficient data pipelines in Python can be tricky. The standard recommendation is to use vectorized functions implemented in Numpy, Pandas, or the like. However, what to do, when the processing task does not fit these libraries? Using plain Python for processing can result in lacking performance, in particular when handling large data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a modern, performance-oriented programming language that is already widely used by the Python community. Augmenting data processing steps with Rust can result in substantial speed ups. In this talk will present strategies of using Rust in a larger Python data processing pipeline with a particular focus on pragmatism and minimizing integration efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Prohm</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/pragmatic-ways-of-using-rust-in-your-data-project.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Rust</category></item><item><title>Prompt Engineering 101</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/prompt-engineering-101.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A modern AI start-up is a front-end developer plus a prompt engineer&amp;quot; is a popular joke on Twitter.
This talk is about LangChain, a Python open-source tool for prompt engineering. You can use it with completely open-source language models or ChatGPT. I will show you how to create a prompt and get an answer from LLM. As an example application, I will show a demo of an intelligent agent using web search and generating Python code to answer questions about this conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lev Konstantinovskiy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/prompt-engineering-101.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Prompt Engineering</category></item><item><title>PyCon &amp; PyData Berlin 2023: Lightning talks from day 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/pycon-pydata-berlin-2023-lightning-talks-from-day-1.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Multiple Speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/pycon-pydata-berlin-2023-lightning-talks-from-day-1.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>lightning</category></item><item><title>PyCon &amp; PyData Berlin 2023: Lightning talks from day 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/pycon-pydata-berlin-2023-lightning-talks-from-day-2.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Multiple Speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/pycon-pydata-berlin-2023-lightning-talks-from-day-2.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>lightning</category></item><item><title>Raised by Pandas, striving for more: An opinionated introduction to Polars</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/raised-by-pandas-striving-for-more-an-opinionated-introduction-to-polars.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is the de-facto standard for data manipulation in python, which I personally love for its flexible syntax and interoperability. But Pandas has well-known drawbacks such as memory in-efficiency, inconsistent missing data handling and lacking multicore-support. Multiple open-source projects aim to solve those issues, the most interesting is Polars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polars uses Rust and Apache Arrow to win in all kinds of performance-benchmarks and evolves fast. But is it already stable enough to migrate an existing Pandas' codebase? And does it meet the high-expectations on query language flexibility of long-time Pandas-lovers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will explain, how Polars can be that fast, and present my insights on where Polars shines and in which scenarios I stay with pandas (at least for now!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nico Kreiling</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/raised-by-pandas-striving-for-more-an-opinionated-introduction-to-polars.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>polars</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Rapid model development and stable, high-performance deployments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/rapid-model-development-and-stable-high-performance-deployments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the boundary of model development and MLOps lies the balance between the speed of deploying new models and ensuring operational constraints. These include factors like low latency prediction, the absence of vulnerabilities in dependencies and the need for the model behavior to stay reproducible for years. The longer the list of constraints, the longer it usually takes to take a model from its development environment into production. In this talk, we present how we seemingly managed to square the circle and have both a rapid, highly dynamic model development and yet also a stable and high-performance deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Bourjau</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/rapid-model-development-and-stable-high-performance-deployments.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Shrinking gigabyte sized scikit-learn models for deployment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/shrinking-gigabyte-sized-scikit-learn-models-for-deployment.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present an open source library to shrink pickled scikit-learn and lightgbm models. We will provide insights of how pickling ML models work and how to improve the disk representation. With this approach, we can reduce the deployment size of machine learning applications up to 6x.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pavel Zwerschke</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/shrinking-gigabyte-sized-scikit-learn-models-for-deployment.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>scikit-learn</category></item><item><title>Teaching Neural Networks a Sense of Geometry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/teaching-neural-networks-a-sense-of-geometry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By taking neural networks back to the school bench and teaching them some elements of geometry and topology we can build algorithms that can reason about the shape of data. Surprisingly these methods can be useful not only for computer vision – to model input data such as images or point clouds through global, robust properties – but in a wide range of applications, such as evaluating and improving the learning of embeddings, or the distribution of samples originating from generative models. This is the promise of the emerging field of Topological Data Analysis (TDA) which we will introduce and review recent works at its intersection with machine learning. TDA can be seen as being part of the increasingly popular movement of Geometric Deep Learning which encourages us to go beyond seeing data only as vectors in Euclidean spaces and instead consider machine learning algorithms that encode other geometric priors. In the past couple of years TDA has started to take a step out of the academic bubble, to a large extent thanks to powerful Python libraries written as extensions to scikit-learn or PyTorch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jens Agerberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/teaching-neural-networks-a-sense-of-geometry.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>The Battle of Giants - Causality vs NLP - From Theory to Practice</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/the-battle-of-giants-causality-vs-nlp-from-theory-to-practice.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 3.2 new papers published on Arxiv every day in 2022, causal inference has exploded in popularity, attracting large amount of talent and interest from top researchers and institutions including industry giants like Amazon or Microsoft. Text data, with its high complexity, posits an exciting challenge for causal inference community. In the workshop, we'll review the latest advances in the field of Causal NLP and implement a causal Transformer model to demonstrate how to translate these developments into a practical solution that can bring real business value. All in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aleksander Molak</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/the-battle-of-giants-causality-vs-nlp-from-theory-to-practice.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>The Beauty of Zarr</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/the-beauty-of-zarr.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'd be talking about Zarr, an open-source data format for storing chunked, compressed N-dimensional arrays. This talk presents a systematic approach to understanding and implementing Zarr by showing how it works, the need for using it, and a hands-on session at the end. Zarr is based on an open technical specification, making implementations across several languages possible. I'd mainly talk about Zarr's Python implementation and show how it beautifully interoperates with the existing libraries in the PyData stack.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sanket Verma</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/the-beauty-of-zarr.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Zarr</category></item><item><title>The bumps in the road - A retrospective on my data visualisation mistakes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/the-bumps-in-the-road-a-retrospective-on-my-data-visualisation-mistakes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will delve into the importance of effective data visualisation in today's world. We will explore how it can help convey insights from data using Matplotlib and best practices for creating informative visualisations. We will also discuss the limitations of static visualisations and examine the role of continuous integration in streamlining the process and avoiding common pitfalls. By the end of this talk, you will have gained valuable insights and techniques for creating informative and accurate data visualisations, no matter what tools you're using.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Artem Kislovskiy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/the-bumps-in-the-road-a-retrospective-on-my-data-visualisation-mistakes.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Data Visualisation</category></item><item><title>The future of the Jupyter Notebook interface</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/the-future-of-the-jupyter-notebook-interface.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks have been a widely popular tool for data science in recent years due to their ability to combine code, text, and visualizations in a single document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its popularity, the core functionality and user experience of the Classic Jupyter Notebook interface has remained largely unchanged over the past years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately the Jupyter Notebook project decided to base its next major version 7 on JupyterLab components and extensions, which means many JupyterLab features are also available to Jupyter Notebook users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we will demo the new features coming in Jupyter Notebook version 7 and how they are relevant to existing users of the Classic Notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeremy Tuloup</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/the-future-of-the-jupyter-notebook-interface.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Jupyter</category></item><item><title>The Spark of Big Data - An Introduction to Apache Spark</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/the-spark-of-big-data-an-introduction-to-apache-spark.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get ready to level up your big data processing skills! Join us for an introductory talk on Apache
Spark, the distributed computing system used by tech giants like Netflix and Amazon. We'll
cover PySpark DataFrames and how to use them. Whether you're a Python developer new to
big data or looking to explore new technologies, this talk is for you. You'll gain foundational
knowledge about Apache Spark and its capabilities, and learn how to leverage DataFrames and
SQL APIs to efficiently process large amounts of data. Don't miss out on this opportunity to up
your big data game!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pasha Finkelshteyn</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/the-spark-of-big-data-an-introduction-to-apache-spark.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Spark</category></item><item><title>Towards Learned Database Systems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/towards-learned-database-systems.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Database Management Systems (DBMSs) are the backbone for managing large volumes of data efficiently and thus play a central role in business and science today. For providing high performance, many of the most complex DBMS components such as query optimizers or schedulers involve solving non-trivial problems. To tackle such problems, very recent work has outlined a new direction of so-called learned DBMSs where core parts of DBMSs are being replaced by machine learning (ML) models which has shown to provide significant performance benefits. However, a major drawback of the current approaches to enabling learned DBMS components is that they not only cause very high overhead for training an ML model to replace a DBMS component but that the overhead occurs repeatedly which renders these approaches far from practical. Hence, in this talk, I present my vision of Learned DBMS Components 2.0 to tackle these issues. First, I will introduce data-driven learning where the idea is to learn the data distribution over a complex relational schema. In contrast to workload-driven learning, no large workload has to be executed on the database to gather training data. While data-driven learning has many applications such as cardinality estimation or approximate query processing, many DBMS tasks such as physical cost estimation cannot be supported. I thus propose a second technique called zero-shot learning which is a general paradigm for learned DBMS components. Here, the idea is to train model&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carsten Binnig</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/towards-learned-database-systems.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>Unlocking Information - Creating Synthetic Data for Open Access</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/unlocking-information-creating-synthetic-data-for-open-access.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many good project ideas fail before they even start due to the sensitive personal data required. The good news: a synthetic version of this data does not need protection. Synthetic data copies the actual data's structure and statistical properties without recreating personally identifiable information. The bad news: It is difficult to create synthetic data for open-access use, without recreating the exact copy of actual data.
This talk will give hands-on insights into synthetic data creation and challenges along its lifecycle. We will learn how to create and evaluate synthetic data for any use case using the open-source package Synthetic Data Vault. We will find answers to why it takes so long to synthesize the huge amount of data dormant in public administration. The talk addresses owners who want to create access to their private data as well as analysts looking to use synthetic data. After this session, listeners will know which steps to take to generate synthetic data for multi-purpose use and its limitations for real-world analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonia Scherz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/unlocking-information-creating-synthetic-data-for-open-access.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Use Spark from anywhere - A Spark client in Python powered by Spark Connect</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/use-spark-from-anywhere-a-spark-client-in-python-powered-by-spark-connect.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, developers, researchers, and the community have successfully built tens of thousands of data applications using Spark. Since then, use cases and requirements of data applications have evolved: Today, every application, from web services that run in application servers, interactive environments such as notebooks and IDEs, to phones and edge devices such as smart home devices, want to leverage the power of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Spark's driver architecture is monolithic, running client applications on top of a scheduler, optimizer and analyzer. This architecture makes it hard to address these new requirements: there is no built-in capability to remotely connect to a Spark cluster from languages other than SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spark Connect introduces a decoupled client-server architecture for Apache Spark that allows remote connectivity to Spark clusters using the DataFrame API and unresolved logical plans as the protocol. The separation between client and server allows Spark and its open ecosystem to be leveraged from everywhere. It can be embedded in modern data applications, in IDEs, Notebooks and programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk highlights how simple it is to connect to Spark using Spark Connect from any data applications or IDEs. We will do a deep dive into the architecture of Spark Connect and give an outlook of how the community can participate in the extension of Spark Connect for new programming languages and frameworks - to bring the power of Spark everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martin Grund</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/use-spark-from-anywhere-a-spark-client-in-python-powered-by-spark-connect.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Spark</category></item><item><title>Using transformers – a drama in 512 tokens</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/using-transformers-a-drama-in-512-tokens.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;'Got an NLP problem nowadays? Use transformers! Just download a pretrained model from the hub!' - every blog article ever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if it's that easy, because nearly all pretrained models have a very annoying limitation: they can only process short input sequences. Not every NLP practitioner happens to work on tweets, but instead many of us have to deal with longer input sequences. What started as a minor design choice for BERT, got cemented by the research community over the years and now turns out to be my biggest headache: the 512 tokens limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll ask a lot of dumb questions and get an equal number of unsatisfying answers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much text actually fits into 512 tokens? Spoiler: not enough to solve my use case, and I bet a lot of your use cases, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can feed a sequence of any length into an RNN, why do transformers even have a limit? We'll look into the architecture in more detail to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somebody smart must have thought about this sequence length issue before, or not? Prepare yourself for a rant about benchmarks in NLP research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can we do to handle longer input sequences? Enjoy my collection of mediocre workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marianne Stecklina</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/using-transformers-a-drama-in-512-tokens.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>NLP</category><category>Transformers</category></item><item><title>Visualizing your computer vision data is not a luxury, it's a necessity</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/visualizing-your-computer-vision-data-is-not-a-luxury-its-a-necessity.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to take your Computer Vision projects to the next level? Then don't miss this talk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization is a crucial ingredient for the success of any computer vision project.
It allows you to assess the quality of your data, grasp the intricacies of your project, and communicate effectively with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll showcase the power of data visualization with compelling examples. You'll learn about the benefits of data visualization and discover practical methods and tools to elevate your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't let this opportunity pass you by: join us and learn how to make data visualization a core feature of your Computer Vision projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chazareix Arnault</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/visualizing-your-computer-vision-data-is-not-a-luxury-its-a-necessity.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Computer Vision</category></item><item><title>WALD - A Modern &amp; Sustainable Analytics Stack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/wald-a-modern-sustainable-analytics-stack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The name WALD-stack stems from the four technologies it is composed of, i.e. a cloud-computing Warehouse like Snowflake or Google BigQuery, the open-source data integration engine Airbyte, the open-source full-stack
BI platform Lightdash, and the open-source data transformation tool DBT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a Formula 1 Grand Prix dataset, I will give an overview of how these four tools complement each other perfectly for analytics tasks in an ELT approach. You will learn the specific uses of each tool as well as their particular features. My talk is based on a full tutorial, which you can find under waldstack.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Florian Wilhelm</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/wald-a-modern-sustainable-analytics-stack.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>When A/B testing isn't an option - an introduction to quasi-experimental methods</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/when-ab-testing-isnt-an-option-an-introduction-to-quasi-experimental-methods.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identification of causal relationships through running experiments is not always possible. In this talk, an alternative approach towards it, quasi-experimental frameworks, is discussed. Additionally, I will present how to adjust well-known machine-learning algorithms so they can be used to quantify causal relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Inga Janczuk</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/when-ab-testing-isnt-an-option-an-introduction-to-quasi-experimental-methods.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Causal Inference</category></item><item><title>'Who is an NLP expert?' - Lessons from building an in-house QA-system</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/who-is-an-nlp-expert-lessons-from-building-an-in-house-qa-system.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Innovations such as sentence-transformers, neural search and vector databases fueled a very fast development of question-answering systems recently. At scieneers, we wanted to test those components to satisfy our own information needs using a slack-bot that will answer our questions by reading through our internal documents and slack-conversations. We therefore leveraged the HayStack QA-Framework in combination with a Weaviate vector database and many fine-tuned NLP-models.
This talk will give you insights in both, the technical challenges we faced and the organizational learnings we took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/dt2nx7246jl753p/2023_who%20is%20an%20NLP%20Expert.pdf?dl=0"&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dt2nx7246jl753p/2023_who%20is%20an%20NLP%20Expert.pdf?dl=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alina Bickel</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/who-is-an-nlp-expert-lessons-from-building-an-in-house-qa-system.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>NLP</category></item><item><title>Why GPU Clusters Don't Need to Go Brrr?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/why-gpu-clusters-dont-need-to-go-brrr.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forget specialized hardware. Get GPU-class performance on your commodity CPUs with compound sparsity and sparsity-aware inference execution.
This talk will demonstrate the power of compound sparsity for model compression and inference speedup for NLP and CV domains, with a special focus on the recently popular Large Language Models. The combination of structured + unstructured pruning (to 90%+ sparsity), quantization, and knowledge distillation can be used to create models that run an order of magnitude faster than their dense counterparts, without a noticeable drop in accuracy. The session participants will learn the theory behind compound sparsity, state-of-the-art techniques, and how to apply it in practice using the Neural Magic platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Damian Bogunowicz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/why-gpu-clusters-dont-need-to-go-brrr.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>Writing Plugin Friendly Python Applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/writing-plugin-friendly-python-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, plugin systems are a ubiquitous way to extend and modify the behavior of applications and libraries. When software is written in a way that is plugin friendly, it encourages the use of modular organization where the contracts between the core software and the plugin have been well thought out. In this talk, we cover exactly how to define this contract and how you can start designing your software to be more plugin friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the talk we will be creating our own plugin friendly application using the pluggy library to show these design principles in action. At the end of the talk, I also cover a real-life case study of how the package manager conda is currently making its 10 year old code more plugin friendly to illustrate how to retrofit an existing project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Travis Hathaway</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/writing-plugin-friendly-python-applications.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item></channel></rss>