<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - PyCon DE 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>5 Things about fastAPI I wish we had known beforehand</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/5-things-about-fastapi-i-wish-we-had-known-beforehand.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An exchange of views on fastAPI in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FastAPI is great, it helps many developers create REST APIs based on the OpenAPI standard and run them asynchronously. It has a thriving community and educational documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FastAPI does a great job of getting people started with APIs quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will point out some obstacles and dark spots that I wish we had known about before. In this talk we want to highlight solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FastAPI's extensive use of pydantic for data parsing, validation, transformation, and OpenAPI definition export.
* The role of starlette in managing routes and middleware, including insights into creating custom middleware.
A discussion on FastAPI's documentation and the importance of DocStrings for accurate documentation.
The application of the &amp;quot;Don't Repeat Yourself&amp;quot; (DRY) principle with Pydantic to create highly reusable model pools with inheritance for use in FastAPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander Hendorf is responsible for data and artificial intelligence at the boutique consultancy KÖNIGSWEG GmbH. Through his commitment as a speaker and chair of various international conferences as PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin, he is a proven expert in the field of data intelligence. He's been appointed Python Software Foundation and EuroPython fellow for this various contributions. He has many years of experience in the practical application, introduction and communication of data and AI-driven strategies and decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/hendorf"&gt;https://twitter.com/hendorf&lt;/a&gt;
LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hendorf/"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/hendorf/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander CS Hendorf</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/5-things-about-fastapi-i-wish-we-had-known-beforehand.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>fastapi</category><category>pydantic</category><category>rest-API</category><category>starlette</category></item><item><title>Accelerate Python with Julia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/accelerate-python-with-julia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speeding up Python code has traditionally been achieved by writing C/C++ — an alien world for most Python users. Today, you can write high performance code in Julia instead, which is much much easier for Python users. This tutorial will give you hands-on experience writing a Python library that incorporates Julia for performance optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julia is a modern data science language which solves the two-language problem by being both easy to use and high performant. Although different from Python, the language can be quickly learned by Python users, making it a good choice for speeding up pieces of code. Julia, in addition to being a similar language, is designed for high-performance applied mathematics and has high-quality libraries for multi-dimensional arrays, dataframes, distributed computing and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The older alternative of writing pieces of code in C, C++, Cython or Rust is much more cumbersome: Here, programmers have to cope with a low-level language, static types, pointers, no garbage collector, lack of scientific libraries and other difficulties not normally faced by Python users. There was simply no better alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will be fully hands-on, using Jupyter Notebook and Binder to provide a smooth and easy-to-use environment for each participant. Both Julia and Python work seamlessly within Jupyter. We start with an introduction to the basics of Julia, focusing on the core differences with Python and how to work around common translation difficulties. Then we'll take a look at the interfaces between Julia and Python and build a Python sample project that runs Julia code. Finally, we will benchmark our solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tutorial you will be able to use Julia to speed up your Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephan Sahm</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/accelerate-python-with-julia.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Julia</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Accelerating Python Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/accelerating-python-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a beautiful language for fast prototyping and and sketching ideas quickly. People often struggle to get their code into production though for various reasons. Besides of all security and safety concerns that usually are not addressed from the very beginning when playing around with an algorithmic idea, performance concerns are quite frequently a reason for not taking the Python code to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will look at the &amp;quot;missing performance&amp;quot; worries using a simple numerical problem and how to speed the corresponding Python code up to top notch performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jens Nie</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/accelerating-python-code.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>An unbiased evaluation of environment management and packaging tools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/an-unbiased-evaluation-of-environment-management-and-packaging-tools.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python packaging is quickly evolving and new tools pop up on a regular basis. Lots of talks and posts on packaging exist but none of them give a structured, unbiased overview of the available tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will shed light on the jungle of packaging and environment management tools, comparing them on a basis of predefined features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna-Lena Popkes</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/an-unbiased-evaluation-of-environment-management-and-packaging-tools.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Aspect-oriented Programming - Diving deep into Decorators</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/aspect-oriented-programming-diving-deep-into-decorators.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The aspect-oriented programming paradigm can support the separation of
cross-cutting concerns such as logging, caching, or checking of permissions. This can improve code modularity and maintainability.
Python offers decorator to implement re-usable code for cross-cutting task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is an in-depth introduction to decorators.
It covers the usage of decorators and how to implement simple and more advanced decorators. Use cases demonstrate how to work with decorators.
In addition to showing how functions can use closures to create decorators,
the tutorial introduces callable class instance as alternative.
Class decorators can solve problems that use be to be tasks for metaclasses. The tutorial provides uses cases for class decorators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the focus is on best practices and practical applications, the tutorial
also provides deeper insight into how Python works behind the scene.
After the tutorial participants will feel comfortable with functions that take
functions and return new functions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mike Müller</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/aspect-oriented-programming-diving-deep-into-decorators.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Behind the Scenes of tox - The Journey of Rewriting a Python Tool</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/behind-the-scenes-of-tox-the-journey-of-rewriting-a-python-tool.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;tox is a widely-used tool for automating testing in Python. In this talk, we will go behind the scenes of the creation of tox 4, the latest version of the tool. We will discuss the motivations for the rewrite, the challenges and lessons learned during the development process. We will have a look at the new features and improvements introduced in tox 4. But most importantly, you will get to know the maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jürgen Gmach</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/behind-the-scenes-of-tox-the-journey-of-rewriting-a-python-tool.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>BLE and Python - How to build a simple BLE project on Linux with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/ble-and-python-how-to-build-a-simple-ble-project-on-linux-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) is a part of the Bluetooth standard aimed at bringing wireless technology to low-power devices, and it's getting into everything - lightbulbs, robots, personal health and fitness devices, and plenty more. One of the main advantages of BLE is that everybody can integrate those devices into their tools or projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, BLE is not the most developer-friendly protocol and these devices most of the time don't come with good documentation. In addition, there are not a lot of good open-source tools, examples, and tutorials on how to use Python with BLE. Especially if one wants to build both sides of the communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce the concepts and properties used in BLE interactions and look at how we can use the Linux Bluetooth Stack (Bluez) to communicate with other devices. We will look at a simple example and learn along the way about common pitfalls and debugging options while working with BLE and Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for everybody that has a basic understanding of Python and wants to have a deeper understanding of how BLE works and how one could use it in a private project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bruno Vollmer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/ble-and-python-how-to-build-a-simple-ble-project-on-linux-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Bringing NLP to Production (an end to end story about some multi-language NLP services)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/bringing-nlp-to-production-an-end-to-end-story-about-some-multi-language-nlp-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Models in Natural Language Processing are fun to train but can be difficult to deploy. The size of their models, libraries and necessary files can be challenging, especially in a microservice environment. When services should be built as lightweight and slim as possible, large (language) models can lead to a lot of problems. With a recent real-world use case as an example, which runs productively for over a year and in 10 different languages, I will walk you through my experiences with deploying NLP models. What kind of pitfalls, shortcuts, and tricks are possible while bringing an NLP model to production?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn about different ways and possibilities to deploy NLP services. I will speak briefly about the way leading from data to model and a running service (without going into much detail) before I will focus on the MLOps part in the end. I will take you with me on my past journey of struggles and successes so that you don't need to take these detours by yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Larissa Haas</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/bringing-nlp-to-production-an-end-to-end-story-about-some-multi-language-nlp-services.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Building Hexagonal Python Services</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/building-hexagonal-python-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The importance of enterprise architecture patterns is all well-known and applicable to varied types of tasks. Thinking about the architecture from the beginning of the journey is crucial to have a maintainable, therefore testable, and flexible code base. In We are going to explore the Ports and Adapters(Hexagonal) pattern by showing a simple web app using Repository, Unit of Work, and Services(Use Cases) patterns tied together with Dependency Injection. All those patterns are quite famous in other languages but they are relatively new for the Python ecosystem, which is a crucial missing part.
As a web framework, we are going to use FastAPI which can be replaced with any framework in a matter of time because of the abstractions we have added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shahriyar Rzayev</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/building-hexagonal-python-services.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure From Python Code: How Far Could We Go?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/cloud-infrastructure-from-python-code-how-far-could-we-go.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover how Infrastructure From Code (IfC) can revolutionize Cloud DevOps automation by generating cloud deployment templates directly from Python code. Learn how this technology empowers Python developers to easily deploy and operate cost-effective, secure, reliable, and sustainable cloud software. Join us to explore the strategic potential of IfC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Asher Sterkin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/cloud-infrastructure-from-python-code-how-far-could-we-go.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Code Cleanup - A Data Scientist's Guide to Sparkling Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/code-cleanup-a-data-scientists-guide-to-sparkling-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does your production code look like it's been copied from Untitled12.ipynb? Are your engineers complaining about the code but you can't find the time to work on improving the code base? This talk will go through some of the basics of clean coding and how to best implement them in a data science team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Corrie Bartelheimer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/code-cleanup-a-data-scientists-guide-to-sparkling-code.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Data-driven design for the Dask scheduler</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/data-driven-design-for-the-dask-scheduler.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically, changes in the scheduling algorithm of Dask have often been based on theory, single use cases, or even gut feeling. Coiled has now moved to using hard, comprehensive performance metrics for all changes - and it's been a turning point!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guido Imperiale</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/data-driven-design-for-the-dask-scheduler.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Dask</category></item><item><title>Data Kata: Ensemble programming with Pydantic PT 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/data-kata-ensemble-programming-with-pydantic-pt-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write code as an ensemble to solve a data validation problem using Pydantic. Working together is not just about code - learn how to listen to colleagues, make typos in front of everyone, become a supportive team member, defend your ideas and maybe even accept criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lev Konstantinovskiy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/data-kata-ensemble-programming-with-pydantic-pt-1.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Data Kata: Ensemble programming with Pydantic PT 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/data-kata-ensemble-programming-with-pydantic-pt-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write code as an ensemble to solve a data validation problem using Pydantic. Working together is not just about code - learn how to listen to colleagues, make typos in front of everyone, become a supportive team member, defend your ideas and maybe even accept criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lev Konstantinovskiy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/data-kata-ensemble-programming-with-pydantic-pt-2.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>FastAPI and Celery - Building Reliable Web Applications with TDD</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/fastapi-and-celery-building-reliable-web-applications-with-tdd.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to use the FastAPI web framework and Celery task queue to build reliable and scalable web applications in a test-driven manner. We will start by setting up a testing environment and writing unit tests for the core functionality of our application. Next, we will use FastAPI to create an api to perform some long-running task. Finally, we will then see how Celery can help us offload long-running tasks and improve the performance of our application.
By the end of this talk, attendees will have a strong understanding of TDD and how to apply it to your FastAPI and Celery projects, and you will be able to write tests that ensure the reliability and maintainability of your code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Avanindra Kumar Pandeya</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/fastapi-and-celery-building-reliable-web-applications-with-tdd.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Fear the mutants. Love the mutants.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/fear-the-mutants-love-the-mutants.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers often use code coverage as a target, which makes it a bad measure of test quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutation testing changes the game: create mutant versions of your code that break your tests, and you'll quickly start to write better tests!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and learn to use it as part of your CI/CD process. I promise, you'll never look at penguins the same way again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Max Kahan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/fear-the-mutants-love-the-mutants.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>From notebook to pipeline in no time with LineaPy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/from-notebook-to-pipeline-in-no-time-with-lineapy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nightmare before data science production: You found a working prototype for your problem using a Jupyter notebook and now it's time to build a production grade solution from that notebook. Unfortunately, your notebook looks anything but production grade. The good news is, there's finally a cure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open-source python package LineaPy aims to automate data science workflow generation and expediting the process of going from data science development to production. And truly, it transforms messy notebooks into data pipelines like Apache Airflow, DVC, Argo, Kubeflow, and many more. And if you can't find your favorite orchestration framework, you are welcome to work with the creators of LineaPy to contribute a plugin for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn the basic concepts of LineaPy and how it supports your everyday tasks as a data practitioner. For this purpose, we will transform a notebook step by step together to create a DVC pipeline. Finally, we will discuss what place LineaPy will take in the MLOps universe. Will you only have to check in your notebook in the future?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Frauholz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/from-notebook-to-pipeline-in-no-time-with-lineapy.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Giving and Receiving Great Feedback through PRs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/giving-and-receiving-great-feedback-through-prs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you struggle with PRs? Have you ever had to change code even though you disagreed with the change just to land the PR? Have you ever given feedback that would have improved the code only to get into a comment war? We'll discuss how to give and receive feedback to extract maximum value from it and avoid all the communication problems that come with PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Andersson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/giving-and-receiving-great-feedback-through-prs.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Great Security Is One Question Away</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/great-security-is-one-question-away.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a decade of writing code, I joined the application security team. During the transition process, I discovered that there are many myths about security, and how difficult it is. Often devs choose to ignore it because they think that writing more secure code would take them ages. It is not true. Security doesn't have to be scary. From my talk, you will learn the most useful piece from the Application Security theory. It will be practical and not boring at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wiktoria Dalach</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/great-security-is-one-question-away.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>How to connect your application to the world (and avoid sleepless nights)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/how-to-connect-your-application-to-the-world-and-avoid-sleepless-nights.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's say you are the ruler of a remote island. For it to succeed and thrive you can't expect it to be isolated from the world. You need to establish trade routes, offer your products to other islands, and import items from them. Doing this will certainly make your economy grow! We're not going to talk about land masses or commerce, however, you should think of your application as an island that needs to connect to other applications to succeed. Unfortunately, the sea is treacherous and is not always very consistent, similar to the networks you use to connect your application to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will explore some techniques and libraries in the Python ecosystem used to make your life easier while dealing with external services. From asynchronicity, caching, testing, and building abstractions on top of the APIs you consume, you will definitely learn some strategies to build your connected application gracefully, and avoid those pesky 2 AM errors that keep you awake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luis Fernando Alvarez</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/how-to-connect-your-application-to-the-world-and-avoid-sleepless-nights.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>How to increase diversity in open source communities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/how-to-increase-diversity-in-open-source-communities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today state of the art technology and scientific research strongly depend on open source libraries. The demographic of the contributors to these libraries is predominantly white and male. This situation creates problems not only for individual contributors outside of this demographic but also for open source projects such as loss of career opportunities and less robust technologies. In recent years there have been a number of various recommendations and initiatives to increase the participation in open source projects of groups who are underrepresented in this domain. While these efforts are valuable and much needed, contributor diversity remains a challenge in open source communities. This talk highlights the underlying problems and explores how we can overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maren Westermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/how-to-increase-diversity-in-open-source-communities.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Introducing FastKafka</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/introducing-fastkafka.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;FastKafka is a Python library that makes it easy to connect to Apache Kafka queues and send and receive messages. In this talk, we will introduce the library and its features for working with Kafka queues in Python. We will discuss the motivations for creating the library, how it compares to other Kafka client libraries, and how to use its decorators to define functions for consuming and producing messages. We will also demonstrate how to use these functions to build a simple application that sends and receives messages from the queue. This talk will be of interest to Python developers looking for an easy-to-use solution for working with Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tvrtko Sternak</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/introducing-fastkafka.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Kafka</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Async programming</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/introduction-to-async-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous programming is a type of parallel programming in which a unit of work is allowed to run separately from the primary application thread. Post execution, it notifies the main thread about the completion or failure of the worker thread. There are numerous benefits to using it, such as improved application performance, enhanced responsiveness, and effective usage of CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronicity seems to be a big reason why Node.js is so popular for server-side programming. Most of the code we write, especially in heavy IO applications like websites, depends on external resources. This could be anything from a remote database POST API call. As soon as you ask for any of these resources, your code is waiting around for process completion with nothing to do. With asynchronous programming, you allow your code to handle other tasks while waiting for these other resources to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we are going to talk about asynchronous programming in Python. Its benefits and multiple ways to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dishant Sethi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/introduction-to-async-programming.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Machine Learning Lifecycle for NLP Classification in E-Commerce</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/machine-learning-lifecycle-for-nlp-classification-in-e-commerce.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running machine learning models in a production environment brings its own challenges. In this talk we would like to present our solution of a machine learning lifecycle for the text-based cataloging classification system from idealo.de. We will share lessons learned and talk about our experiences during the lifecycle migration from a hosted cluster to a cloud solution within the last 3 years. In addition, we will outline how we embedded our ML components as part of the overall idealo.de processing architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gunar Maiwald</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/machine-learning-lifecycle-for-nlp-classification-in-e-commerce.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Maps with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/maps-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind the Pythonic principle that &amp;quot;simple is better than complex&amp;quot; we'll see how to create a web map with the Python based web framework Django using its GeoDjango module, storing geographic data in your local database on which to run geospatial queries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paolo Melchiorre</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/maps-with-django.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Django</category></item><item><title>Maximizing Efficiency and Scalability in Open-Source MLOps - A Step-by-Step Approach</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/maximizing-efficiency-and-scalability-in-open-source-mlops-a-step-by-step-approach.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents a novel approach to MLOps that combines the benefits of open-source technologies with the power and cost-effectiveness of cloud computing platforms. By using tools such as Terraform, MLflow, and Feast, we demonstrate how to build a scalable and maintainable ML system on the cloud that is accessible to ML Engineers and Data Scientists. Our approach leverages cloud managed services for the entire ML lifecycle, reducing the complexity and overhead of maintenance and eliminating the vendor lock-in and additional costs associated with managed MLOps SaaS services. This innovative approach to MLOps allows organizations to take full advantage of the potential of machine learning while minimizing cost and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Elvers</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/maximizing-efficiency-and-scalability-in-open-source-mlops-a-step-by-step-approach.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>MLOps</category></item><item><title>MLOps in practice - our journey from batch to real-time inference</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/mlops-in-practice-our-journey-from-batch-to-real-time-inference.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will present the challenges we encountered while migrating an ML model from batch to real-time predictions and how we handled them. In particular, I will focus on the design decisions and open-source tools we built to test the code, data and models as part of the CI/CD pipeline and enable us to ship fast with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Theodore Meynard</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/mlops-in-practice-our-journey-from-batch-to-real-time-inference.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Modern typed python - dive into a mature ecosystem from web dev to machine learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/modern-typed-python-dive-into-a-mature-ecosystem-from-web-dev-to-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typing is at the center of &amp;quot;modern Python&amp;quot;, and tools (mypy, beartype) and libraries (FastAPI, SQLModel, Pydantic, DocArray) based on it are slowly eating the Python world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks explores the benefits of Python type hints, and shows how they are infiltrating the next big domain: Machine Learning&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sami Jaghouar</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/modern-typed-python-dive-into-a-mature-ecosystem-from-web-dev-to-machine-learning.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Monorepos with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/monorepos-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working with python is fun.
Managing python packaging, linters, tests, CI, etc. is not as fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every maintainer needs to worry about consistent styling, quality, speed of tests, etc as the project grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monorepos have been successful in other communities - how does it work in Python?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slide: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HwjFcndvIJycyGqX4F2c6w0IidNPz4rbBtv7WxfvoVk"&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HwjFcndvIJycyGqX4F2c6w0IidNPz4rbBtv7WxfvoVk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abdeali Kothari</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/monorepos-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Monorepos</category></item><item><title>Practical Session - Learning on Heterogeneous Graphs with PyG</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/practical-session-learning-on-heterogeneous-graphs-with-pyg.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build and analyze heterogeneous graphs using PyG, a machine graph learning library in Python. This workshop will provide a practical introduction to the concept of heterogeneous graphs and their applications, including their ability to capture the complexity and diversity of real-world systems. Participants will gain experience in creating a heterogeneous graph from multiple data tables, preparing a dataset, and implementing and training a model using PyG.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ramona Bendias</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/practical-session-learning-on-heterogeneous-graphs-with-pyg.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Rethinking codes of conduct</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/rethinking-codes-of-conduct.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Python Software Foundation Code of Conduct is turning 10 years old in 2023? It was voted in as they felt they were &amp;quot;unbalanced and not seeing the true spectrum of the greater community&amp;quot;. And thought that with time they could &amp;quot;advance towards a more diverse representation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that a big thing? Codes of conduct are an important part of any community, outlining the values of the community. They establish clear guidelines for acceptable behavior and help to create a safe and inclusive environment in the community. This can prevent discrimination and promote equal opportunities for all members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the role of code of conduct in communities, it's history in the PSF, and discuss strategies for rethinking what it means to have and enforce a Code of Conduct. We will look at the existing challenges that the Python communities face when implementing codes of conduct and talk about possible solutions. How does it look like when it works well and when it doesn't?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an essential part of any open source project, reflecting on these guidelines can help to ensure that the projects are successful and sustainable in the long term. Thinking back to Python, which also turns 20 in 2023: &amp;quot;Python got to where it is by being open, and it'll continue to prosper by remaining open&amp;quot;. It's important we continue this mission, after all, one of the things many people love about Python is the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tereza Iofciu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/rethinking-codes-of-conduct.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Rusty Python - A Case Study</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/rusty-python-a-case-study.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a very expressive and powerful language, but it is not always the fastest option for performance-critical parts of an application. Rust, on the other hand, is known for its lightning-fast runtime and low-level control, making it an attractive option for speeding up performance-sensitive portions of Python programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will present a case study of using Rust to speed up a critical component of a Python application. We will cover the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of Rust and its benefits for Python developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profiling and identifying performance bottlenecks in Python application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing a solution in Rust and integrating it with the Python application using PyO3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measuring the performance improvements and comparing them to other optimization techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will learn about the potential for using Rust to boost the performance of their Python programs and how to go about doing so in their own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Robin Raymond</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/rusty-python-a-case-study.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Rust</category></item><item><title>Software Design Pattern for Data Science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/software-design-pattern-for-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if every data science work is special, a lot can be learned from similar problems solved in the past. In this talk, I will share some specific software design concepts that data scientists can use to build better data products.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Theodore Meynard</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/software-design-pattern-for-data-science.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Design Patterns</category><category>Data Science</category></item><item><title>Specifying behavior with Protocols, Typeclasses or Traits. Who wears it better?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/specifying-behavior-with-protocols-typeclasses-or-traits-who-wears-it-better.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the use of Python's typing.Protocol, Scala's Typeclasses, and Rust's Traits.
They all offer a very powerful &amp;amp; elegant mechanism for abstracting over various concepts (such as Serialization) in a modular manner.
We will compare and contrast the syntax and implementation of these constructs in each language and discuss their strengths and weaknesses. We will also look at real-world examples of how these features are used in each language to specify behavior, and consider differences in terms of type system expressiveness and effectiveness. By the end of the talk, attendees will have a better understanding of the differences and similarities between these three language features, and will be able to make informed decisions about which one is best suited for their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kolja Maier</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/specifying-behavior-with-protocols-typeclasses-or-traits-who-wears-it-better.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Rust</category><category>Scala</category></item><item><title>Staying Alert - How to Implement Continuous Testing for Machine Learning Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/staying-alert-how-to-implement-continuous-testing-for-machine-learning-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proper monitoring of machine learning models in production is essential to avoid performance issues. Setting up monitoring can be easy for a single model, but it often becomes challenging at scale or when you face alert fatigue based on many metrics and dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Emeli Dral</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/staying-alert-how-to-implement-continuous-testing-for-machine-learning-models.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Streamlit meets WebAssembly - stlite</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/streamlit-meets-webassembly-stlite.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Streamlit, a pure-Python data app framework, has been ported to Wasm as &amp;quot;stlite&amp;quot;.
See its power and convenience with many live examples and explore its internals from a technical perspective.
You will learn to quickly create interactive in-browser apps using only Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yuichiro Tachibana</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/streamlit-meets-webassembly-stlite.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>streamlit</category><category>webassembly</category></item><item><title>The CPU in your browser - WebAssembly demystified</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/the-cpu-in-your-browser-webassembly-demystified.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the recent years we saw an explosion of usage of Python in the browser:
Pyodide, CPython on WASM, PyScript, etc. All of this is possible thanks to the
powerful functionalities of the underlying platform, WebAssembly, which is essentially a virtual CPU inside the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonio Cuni</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/the-cpu-in-your-browser-webassembly-demystified.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>WebAssembly</category></item><item><title>The State of Production Machine Learning in 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the number of production machine learning use-cases increase, we find ourselves facing new and bigger challenges where more is at stake. Because of this, it's critical to identify the key areas to focus our efforts, so we can ensure our machine learning pipelines are reliable and scalable. In this talk we dive into the state of production machine learning in the Python Ecosystem, and we will cover the concepts that make production machine learning so challenging, as well as some of the recommended tools available to tackle these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover key principles, patterns and frameworks around the open source frameworks powering single or multiple phases of the end-to-end ML lifecycle, incluing model training, deploying, monitoring, etc. We will be covering a high level overview of the production ML ecosystem and dive into best practices that have been abstracted from production use-cases of machine learning operations at scale, as well as how to leverage tools to that will allow us to deploy, explain, secure, monitor and scale production machine learning systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alejandro Saucedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Thou Shall Judge But With Fairness: Methods to Ensure an Unbiased Model</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/thou-shall-judge-but-with-fairness-methods-to-ensure-an-unbiased-model.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is your model prejudicial? Is your model deviating from the predictions it ought to have made? Has your model misunderstood the concept? In the world of artificial intelligence and machine learning, the word &amp;quot;fairness&amp;quot; is particularly common. It is described as having the quality of being impartial or fair. Fairness in ML is essential for contemporary businesses. It helps build consumer confidence and demonstrates to customers that their issues are important. Additionally, it aids in ensuring adherence to guidelines established by authorities. So guaranteeing that the idea of responsible AI is upheld. In this talk, let's explore how certain sensitive features are influencing the model and introducing bias into it. We'll also look at how we can make it better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nandana Sreeraj</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/thou-shall-judge-but-with-fairness-methods-to-ensure-an-unbiased-model.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>What are you yield from?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/what-are-you-yield-from.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many developers avoid using generators. For example, many well-known python libraries use lists instead of generators. The generators themselves are slower than normal list loops, but their use in code greatly increases the speed of the application. Let's discover why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxim Danilov</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/what-are-you-yield-from.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>What could possibly go wrong? - An incomplete guide on how to prevent, detect &amp; mitigate biases in data products</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/what-could-possibly-go-wrong-an-incomplete-guide-on-how-to-prevent-detect-mitigate-biases-in-data-products.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within this talk, I want to look at the topic of data ethics with a practical lens and facilitate the discussion about how we can establish ethical data practices into our day to day work. I will shed some light on the multiple sources of biases in data applications: Where are potential pitfalls and how can we prevent, detect and mitigate them early so they never become a risk for our data product. I will walk you through the different stages of a data product lifecycle and dive deeper into the questions we as data professionals have to ask ourselves throughout the process. Furthermore, I will present methods, tools and libraries that can support our work. Being well aware that there is no universal solution as tools and strategies need to be chosen to specifically address requirements of the use-case and models at hand, my talk will provide a good starting point for your own data ethics journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lea Petters</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/what-could-possibly-go-wrong-an-incomplete-guide-on-how-to-prevent-detect-mitigate-biases-in-data-products.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item></channel></rss>