<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - PyTexas 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DAY 2 Keynote - "Full-Stack Python"</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/day-2-keynote-full-stack-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Full-Stack Python&amp;quot;
Andrew Knight, also known as “Pandy,” is the Automation Panda. He’s a software quality champion who loves to help people build better-quality software. In the past, he’s built large-scale test automation projects that run continuously and reliably. Currently, as a Developer Advocate at Applitools, Pandy helps folks make their apps visually perfect. He serves as Director of Test Automation University, which offers a multitude of free courses on software testing from the world’s leading instructors. An avid supporter of open source software, Pandy is a Playwright Ambassador as well as the lead developer for Boa Constrictor, the .NET Screenplay Pattern. On the side, he is writing a book on software testing with Manning Publications. Check out his tech blog at AutomationPanda.com, and follow him on Twitter at &amp;#64;AutomationPanda.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andy "Pandy" Knight</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/day-2-keynote-full-stack-python.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>DuckTyping, Metaclasses &amp; Recursion: Bldg Generalized Deep Collection Type</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/ducktyping-metaclasses-recursion-bldg-generalized-deep-collection-type.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Duck Typing, Metaclasses, &amp;amp; Recursion: Building a Generalized Deep Collection Type&amp;quot;
Quickly groking and working with deeply nested collections like combinations of dicts and lists (and sometimes other types too) is a common problem, whether it's trying to understand a data set, an API response, or detailed instructions or results from infrastructure as code. Let's talk about current solutions to the problem, their limitations, and how to make that all even easier. Let's talk about making a DeepCollection that can handle anything.
Speaker: Joseph Nix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Nix is the CEO and a founder of Terminal Labs, a seasoned Python developer, and a scientist at heart with a background in astrophysics. He has created and maintained several open source projects. He has consulted on many DevOps, Data Science, and Python WebDev projects, and enjoys training other consultants and engineers. He is eager to make an impact in every project he’s involved in and in his community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joseph Nix</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/ducktyping-metaclasses-recursion-bldg-generalized-deep-collection-type.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Having fun with application design</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/having-fun-with-application-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Having fun with application design&amp;quot;
Do you ever look at your software systems and workflows holistically? Do you ever wonder what could be achieved through smarter designs and dedicated effort? When you design your applications, do you consider developer efficiency and satisfaction as much as end-user experience? Python offers the simplicity and flexibility to achieve both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will explore a journey from supporting disjointed components and addressing ad hoc business requests to developing a technical vision and creating an elegant solution that both serves business needs and offers developers a pleasant support experience. I will also highlight the design thinking approach, software architecture “-ilities” concepts, and the decision process that took place during this project.
Speaker: Natalya Buga&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natalya is a senior software developer at Bloomberg. She is passionate about designing elegant and intuitive applications that solve her users’ needs, while offering developers a pleasant support experience. During her career, Natalya has supported various business areas, while using different languages and technologies. Natalya is new to Python but has enjoyed using it from the outset. Currently, Natalya works in the field of RegTech, supporting Bloomberg's Compliance teams in their goal of adhering to regulatory requirements and best compliance practices to protect the reputation and privacy of clients' firms and their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalya Buga</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/having-fun-with-application-design.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>HoloViz: Visualization and Interactive Dashboards in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/holoviz-visualization-and-interactive-dashboards-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;HoloViz: Visualization and Interactive Dashboards in Python&amp;quot;
Do you use data visualization to understand data and tell stories? Do you need to visualize big data? Are you interested in leveling up your visualization skills and creating dashboards with HoloViz? This talk is for you!
Speaker: Sophia Yang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophia Yang is a Senior Data Scientist and a Developer Advocate at Anaconda. She is passionate about the data science community and the Python open-source community. She is the author of multiple Python open-source libraries such as condastats, cranlogs, PyPowerUp, intake-stripe, and intake-salesforce. She serves on the Steering Committee and the Code of Conduct Committee of the Python open-source visualization system HoloViz. She also volunteers at NumFOCUS, PyData, and SciPy conferences. She holds an M.S. in Computer Science, an M.S. in Statistics, and a Ph.D. in Educational Psychology from The University of Texas at Austin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sophia Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/holoviz-visualization-and-interactive-dashboards-in-python.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>How to Build and Ship More Secure Python Apps with Sigstore</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/how-to-build-and-ship-more-secure-python-apps-with-sigstore.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;How to Build and Ship More Secure Python Apps with Sigstore&amp;quot;
Software supply chain security is increasingly important to the open-source ecosystem, but the learning curve can be steep. Certificate authorities, transparency logs, keys, signing… and even keyless signing! What do these terms all mean and how can a Python developer incorporate tools that make their projects more secure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a high-level overview of the developer-first open-source project, Sigstore, within the Python context. We’ll go through each component of Sigstore, including how to sign a software artifact with Cosign, how Fulcio issues certificates, and finally how developers and end users alike can verify claims made on the Rekor public ledger. We’ll discuss how PyPI is leveraging Sigstore to help with verifying and trusting dependencies we all rely on. Finally, we’ll go through a demonstration of creating, publishing and signing a containerized Python app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will walk away with an understanding of how they can navigate software security more effectively and be better citizens of open source by implementing recommended security practices.
Speaker: Lisa Tagliaferri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa Tagliaferri builds teams, technical resources, and open-source software in the tech startup space. Lisa is currently Head of Developer Education at Chainguard and an adjunct professor at Rutgers University. Lisa previously led the Developer Education teams at Sourcegraph and at DigitalOcean. Lisa has written popular open-access books and tutorials on Python, machine learning, Linux, and cloud infrastructure, drawing over 45 million global readers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lisa Tagliafierri</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/how-to-build-and-ship-more-secure-python-apps-with-sigstore.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks, DAY 2 - PyTexas 202</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-pytexas-202.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks, DAY 2 - PyTexas 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;00:00 - Andrew &amp;quot;Pandy&amp;quot; Knight
05:42 - Ilan Schnell
13:20 - Mara Manskie
16:20 - Josh Schneider
20:10 - Adam Allevato
25:55 - Brandon Rhodes&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lightning Talks, DAY 2 - PyTexas 202</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-pytexas-202.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Practical Decorators</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/practical-decorators.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Practical Decorators&amp;quot;
Show some examples of useful decorators and talk about the pros and cons of the decorator protocol.
Speaker: Josh Schneider&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Automation architect at Dell Technologies. Geeky dad with 1+ years in Improv comedy training and performing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josh Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/practical-decorators.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Put your Pants on and lint all your Python code!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/put-your-pants-on-and-lint-all-your-python-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Put your Pants on and lint all your Python code!&amp;quot;
Are you struggling to enforce custom code conventions in large codebases? Learn how to automate this process while maintaining a consistent CI time using Pylint and Pants Build. Attendees will be able to apply the stack in their own codebases right away.
Speaker: Aurelien Didier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Engineer who loves to experiment with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aurelian Didier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/put-your-pants-on-and-lint-all-your-python-code.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Unlocking the Power of Health Data: An Introduction to FHIR and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/unlocking-the-power-of-health-data-an-introduction-to-fhir-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Unlocking the Power of Health Data: An Introduction to FHIR and Python&amp;quot;
Healthcare organizations generate and store vast amounts of data, but accessing and utilizing this data can be a challenge. One solution to this problem is FHIR (Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources), a standard for exchanging electronic health information. In this talk, we will explore the basics of FHIR and its data model, as well as how to use Python to interact with FHIR servers and manipulate FHIR data. We will also discuss real-world examples of how FHIR and Python are being used in the healthcare industry to improve patient care and drive innovation. Attendees will come away with a solid understanding of FHIR and Python, and be equipped to start using these technologies to unlock the power of their own health data.
Speaker: Aly Sivji&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aly Sivji is a Canadian ex-pat living in Chicago. By day, he works as a Team Lead at Jasper Health building a digital health platform to improve the management and delivery of cancer care. By night, he co-organizes the Chicago Python Users Group (ChiPy). Aly is an active participant in the ChiPy Mentorship Program and he loves helping intermediate developers become experts. Outside of Python, Aly enjoys cycling, reading, and rewatching old TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aly Sivji</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/unlocking-the-power-of-health-data-an-introduction-to-fhir-and-python.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Using Python for Digital Investigations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/using-python-for-digital-investigations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Using Python for Digital Investigations&amp;quot;
With the vast amount of publicly available data unleashed by the internet's rise, anyone can now document war crimes, track extremist movements, and investigate environmental abuses. This talk will cover how Python tools and developers can accelerate and improve the accessibility of such digital investigations, and hold power to account.
Speaker: Tristan Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tristan Lee is a Data Scientist &amp;amp; Developer at Bellingcat, a non-profit independent research collective that uses open-source data to investigate human rights abuses, environmental issues, wrongdoings by the powerful, the radical fringes of society, and everything in between. His work focuses on far-right and conspiracy theory networks online, as well as tool development and open-source software community outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristan Lee</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-02:/pytexas-2023/using-python-for-digital-investigations.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>A Build Engineer in a buildless lang</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/a-build-engineer-in-a-buildless-lang.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;A Build Engineer in a buildless lang&amp;quot;
There’s more to Python than the language. And there’s more to Build Engineering than building code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An entire ecosystem of amazing tools sit just beyond the atmosphere of Python’s interpreter. It’s a Build Engineer’s job to ensure you’re using the right ones, configured the right way, and that they run cohesively. As IBM Watson Orders' Build Engineer I am the guardian of the developer experience of almost 100 engineers and data scientists in a Python monorepo. In the past year pre-submit time plummeted, the ease-of-use of local development tools skyrocketed, and I became a maintainer of an Open Source Build System. I am restlessly passionate about their developer experience as well as yours. You should be too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come find out why Build Engineering is important to you and your org, through one person’s constant struggle to expect better, how to find and foster Build Engineering, and how you can build better Python for yourself and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Joshua Cannon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/thejcannon/PyTexas2023"&gt;https://github.com/thejcannon/PyTexas2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joshua Cannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/a-build-engineer-in-a-buildless-lang.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>A Tale of Two Typings</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/a-tale-of-two-typings.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;A Tale of Two Typings&amp;quot;
We discuss two different methodologies we have used to add type annotations to our Python services: gradually adding type annotations, or incrementally re-writing the code with type annotations. We'll discuss the benefits and challenges of each, when either may be appropriate, and our real-world experiences doing both.
Speaker: Thomas Stephens&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Stephens</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/a-tale-of-two-typings.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Automating your Cloud Cost Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/automating-your-cloud-cost-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Automating your Cloud Cost Analysis&amp;quot;
Public Cloud is often touted as a cheaper option, but the bills we get in the mail can be long and convoluted. For better or worse, any dollar spent in the cloud is a result of an architecture decision. This talk will give attendees a firm understanding of the relationship between the architecture and the invoice and the key metrics to keep an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover:
What is FinOps and why is it important
Key metrics for measuring Cloud spend
Automating Cloud Invoices
Using Python, a SQL database, and FaaS, we can build a pipeline that automatically retrieves our invoice, and populates a searchable table to derive insights such as our top 5 most used services and biggest growing services. Attendees with small developers account to large multi-account deployments will better understand the impact of their architecture on their wallet.
Speaker: Amy Arambulo Negrette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With fifteen years of industry experience, Amy Arambulo Negrette has built web applications for a variety of industries including Yahoo! Fantasy Sports and NASA Ames Research Center. One of her projects modernized two legacy systems impacting the entire research center and won her a Certificate of Excellence from the Ames Contractor Council. More recently, she built APIs for enterprise clients for a cloud consulting firms and led a team of Cloud Software Engineers. Amy has survived acquisitions, layoffs, and balancing life with two children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amy Arambulo Negrette</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/automating-your-cloud-cost-analysis.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Build your own Chat-GPT</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/build-your-own-chat-gpt.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Build your own Chat-GPT&amp;quot;
Interested in machine learning and chatbots? This talk is for you! We'll go over the OpenAI API and use cases, particularly how you can build your own ChatGPT over text message using Python.
Speaker: Lizzie Siegle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lizzie is an international speaker, engineer, and Twilio developer evangelist known for rickrolling developers with code, Python sea shanty Tiktoks, and developing trending apps like Wordle via SMS or blog posts relating code to Taylor Swift.
She previously studied Computer Science at Bryn Mawr College.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lizzie Siegle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/build-your-own-chat-gpt.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>DAY 1 Keynote - "Walking The Line"</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/day-1-keynote-walking-the-line.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Walking The Line&amp;quot;
Brandon draws on more than 20 years of experience with Python and 30 years with Unix to offer effective patterns and practices to the audiences of his talks, writing, and training. His Python Patterns website offers Pythonic alternatives to the design patterns that are necessary in less flexible languages. He’s the author of both the old PyEphem astronomy library as well its modern alternative Skyfield, along with smaller projects like the elegant little logging_tree module that’s compatible with every Python back to Python 2.3. He is a Fellow of the Python Software Foundation, on whose behalf he served as the volunteer chair of PyCon 2016–2017 in Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brandon Rhodes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/day-1-keynote-walking-the-line.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Exploring Socio-technical Security Concerns in Critical Opensource Python Repositories</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/exploring-socio-technical-security-concerns-in-critical-opensource-python-repositories.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Exploring Socio-technical Security Concerns in Critical Open-source Python Repositories&amp;quot; Speaker: Jessy Ayala.
Looking at open-source security concerns from a socio-technical perspective is currently underexplored. In this talk, we will learn about analyzing such risks by looking at governance structures, pull requests, and GitHub configurations in open-source 3D printer projects and the overall top Python repositories.
PyTexas 2023&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessy Ayala</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/exploring-socio-technical-security-concerns-in-critical-opensource-python-repositories.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Improving code without losing your mind</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/improving-code-without-losing-your-mind.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Improving code without losing your mind&amp;quot;
Do you find it harder to work with parts of your project? Do you shy away from working with aspects of your code? When showing people what you're working on, do you feel the need to explain why it got that way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our projects grow, they usually become harder to maintain. This happens when we focus too much on adding new features. As a result, our code becomes hard to change or understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give you a tool you can use to unwind that code, making it easier to change and understand, not to mention giving you more satisfaction.
Speaker: Chris May&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris May is a co-founder of the Python user group in Richmond, Virginia, PyRVA, and had a great career in web and python development, most recently as a Senior Full-Stack Engineer at Markel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing his impact on his coworkers and PyRVA members, Chris decided to step away from his full-time job to teach python to others through group training, coaching, and authoring resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With his infectious zest for life and Python, Chris is excited to help you become a better Python developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris May</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/improving-code-without-losing-your-mind.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks, DAY 1 - PyTexas 202</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/lightning-talks-day-1-pytexas-202.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks, DAY 1 - PyTexas 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;00:00 - Paul McGuire
05:42 - Josh Schneider
08:30 - Al Sweigart
11:15 - Shreya Batra
15:48 - Joshua Cannon
20:27 - Leon Vanstone
25:18 - Eric Adams&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lightning Talks, DAY 1 - PyTexas 202</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/lightning-talks-day-1-pytexas-202.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Real-time Event Streaming with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/real-time-event-streaming-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Real-time Event Streaming with Python&amp;quot;
As real-time event streaming has become a necessity in many organizations, a plethora of libraries, frameworks, and applications have arisen to help meet that need. These different tools each have their own strengths and weaknesses, and you may end up deciding to use one or more of them, but many problems can be solved with a simpler approach.
Speaker: Dave Klein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 29 years as a developer, architect, project manager (recovered), author, trainer, conference organizer, and homeschooling dad, Dave Klein landed his dream job as a developer advocate at Confluent. Dave is marveling in and eager to help others explore the amazing world of event streaming with Apache Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Klein</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/real-time-event-streaming-with-python.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Recursion for Beginners: A Beginner's Guide to Recursion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/recursion-for-beginners-a-beginners-guide-to-recursion.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Recursion for Beginners: A Beginner's Guide to Recursion&amp;quot;
An introduction to recursion and the Python-specific functionality for recursion. Recursion is not just for computer science wizards, and this talk breaks it down into smaller (and smaller!) concepts.
Speaker: Al Sweigart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al Sweigart is a software developer, fellow of the Python Software Foundation, and author of several programming books with No Starch Press, including the worldwide bestseller Automate the Boring Stuff with Python. His Creative Commons licensed works are available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://inventwithpython.com"&gt;https://inventwithpython.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/recursion-for-beginners-a-beginners-guide-to-recursion.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item><item><title>Trust Fall: Hidden Gems in MLFlow that Improve Model Credibility</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/trust-fall-hidden-gems-in-mlflow-that-improve-model-credibility.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Trust Fall: Hidden Gems in MLFlow that Improve Model Credibility&amp;quot;
When it comes to machine learning projects, verifying and trusting model performance results is a particularly grueling challenge. This talk will explore both how we can use Python to instill confidence in model metrics and the best way to keep models versioned to increase transparency and accessibility across the team. The tactics demonstrated will help developers save precious development time and increase transparency by incorporating metric tracking early on.
Speaker: Krishi Sharmai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krishi is a software developer at KUNGFU.AI and has been developing with Python for 5 years. She has leveraged Python for machine learning and data science, and hopes to help other developers using the knowledge she has gained by trial and error while working on consulting projects for clients across several different industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Krishi Sharmai</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/trust-fall-hidden-gems-in-mlflow-that-improve-model-credibility.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2023</category></item></channel></rss>