<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Closing ceremony</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/closing-ceremony.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Closing remarks thanks to everyone&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/closing-ceremony.html</guid></item><item><title>Defining a customizable boilerplate using Django, React and Bootstrap</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/defining-a-customizable-boilerplate-using-django-react-and-bootstrap.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you are a beginner or experienced developer, setting up the initial environment of a project can be a time-consuming task. A common solution for this problem is the use of boilerplates. Not only they reduce the setup time, but also assure strict guidelines are followed. However, most of the available boilerplates cover only one part of the problem - front or back end - and integrations are required to suit your specific needs. So, why not define your own full stack boilerplate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll share my experience and present the development process of a customizable Django, React, Bootstrap 4 with Python 3 and webpack project boilerplate. The design decisions, possible configurations and positive impacts of it's application in a production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lais Varejao</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/defining-a-customizable-boilerplate-using-django-react-and-bootstrap.html</guid></item><item><title>Dial M For Mentor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about Python community, is the availability of mentors willing to help you. Various mentors have helped me navigate the open source community and help advanced my skills. I realized finding a mentor is not as easy as it seems, and it takes a lot of courage to reach out in the first place. And then, there is impostor syndrome, where one may feel like they don't deserve the help.
In this talk, I will provide advice about working with mentor.
Asking for help is not a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</guid></item><item><title>Docker Lessons from Real-World Projects</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/docker-lessons-from-real-world-projects.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker has received a lot of hype since it became available a few years ago. While lots of developers have played around with it, going through tutorials and small demo projects, we often lack practical experience of bigger, real-world projects. Docker can be quite useful in these contexts due to provided service isolation and build reproducability, among other benefits.
This talk begins by exploring reasons for using Docker in the first place. I will then demonstrate how to convert projects with multiple dependent services and build steps to use Docker and how it changes the usual Django development workflow. Next I will go through some of the subtleties and pain points we've encountered when doing so. Some general advice for moving towards production will be offered as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rivo Laks</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/docker-lessons-from-real-world-projects.html</guid></item><item><title>Fighting the controls - madness for programmers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/fighting-the-controls-madness-for-programmers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damn it, this can't be happening! Our program crashes, and we run it again - and it crashes again. It's a madness that afflicts programmers. In fact, the activity of debugging has an inherent tendency to cognitive breakdown. How can we resist its merciless pull, and turn debugging into a methodical, safe, successful discipline?
The good news for programmers is that another discipline, aviation, has found some solutions to this problem - and we can learn from its lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniele Procida</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/fighting-the-controls-madness-for-programmers.html</guid></item><item><title>Including women in technology, fostering diversity</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/including-women-in-technology-fostering-diversity.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stories of many women organizing and working in tech communities, and their expectations and suggestions to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/including-women-in-technology-fostering-diversity.html</guid></item><item><title>Last Mile Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/last-mile-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As internet access reaches more and more people at what used to be the fringes of the technological world, we need to be sure that the web applications we build are also ready to reach users in these new environments. Assumptions that hold true in urban areas of developed countries often don't in rural or less developed areas, or those affected by conflict. In this talk, I'll be discussing some common issues and pitfalls that developers who usually work in established markets like Europe and North America encounter when writing applications for newer markets in Africa, Asia, and elsewhere. And, more importantly, what we as Django developers can do to overcome these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Wier</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/last-mile-django.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks - Wednesday - part 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-1.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Quinn</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-1.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Lightning talks - Wednesday - part 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-2.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sara Peeters</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-2.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Rants and Ruminations From A Job Applicant After One Hundred! CS Job Interviews in Silicon Valley</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/rants-and-ruminations-from-a-job-applicant-after-one-hundred-cs-job-interviews-in-silicon-valley.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is it like to interview at 1 technology company? Stressful and tiring. What is it like to interview at 100 technology companies total in 4 months? I have done that. In August 2016, I quit a full-time software job to do job searching full-time. I did a job search where I talked to ~100 technology companies in the Bay Area to find the best fit. The hiring process reflects the company culture and its values. Listen to my rants and ruminations from going through various interviewing processes from tiny seed-stage startups to large technology companies in Silicon Valley. Hiring is still broken. Only a few companies do this well. Learn how to reform your own hiring process to be more considerate and thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/rants-and-ruminations-from-a-job-applicant-after-one-hundred-cs-job-interviews-in-silicon-valley.html</guid></item><item><title>Solidarity of Systers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/solidarity-of-systers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have created a web application that provides a stand to women's to share their story. So that government organization helps them to file cases. They will also be provided legal help through SMS or E-mail portal after sign- up. It's a Normal Django App. Codechef and AAP uses an open source forum to discuss things, So I am using that in this app. Use of PostgreSQL 9.6.1 for the database. Federated knOwledge eXtraction Framework for RDF extraction from text based on Ensemble Learning.
So this application help's us highlighting how one can learn about the different ways to use the power of Django to impact billions of people in the world. What happens here is the victim has to report the same thing to many people. When she goes to Police station, to the doctor, to her lawyer, she was being told to narrate the same story to everyone in the court and many other places like lawyers, doctors... This is the most quintessential problems women faces. In police station also she needs to report it to many people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many women who have been stigmatized feel as though they are transforming from a whole person to a tainted one. They feel different and devalued by others. We can have a common place where we can ask a set of questions to her, once she will answer that we can send the set to all the concerned people. She will just ask their numbers or Mail ID's and click on a button in our web app and write the mail id or number and our web app will send the information to all intended person. A common platform, where women being anonymous will be able to share about experiences that they had. Inside some company, about some person. They will enter the story, location, gender, and some more specific things while writing their story. Based on that we will generate a map, as many plots as possible. Another woman can simply search for that location or company and can find what all bad things happen there. She can request the writer contact or mail, we will then send a mail asking the writer if we can leak and try to setup a connection between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Khushbu Parakh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/solidarity-of-systers.html</guid></item><item><title>The ghost in the algorithm: how to define and to apply digital ethics for the common good</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/the-ghost-in-the-algorithm-how-to-define-and-to-apply-digital-ethics-for-the-common-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As every epistemologist knows, even the most unbiased scientist brings their own metaphysics. Values, prejudices, ideologies: everything the neutrality of science desperately tries to remove by pushing it through the door, it comes back through the window. The same applies to developers and data scientists, in the computer science applied to decision making and to catching human attention. For this reason no algorithm -be it inside an self-driving car, an intelligent chatbot, a smart device or Facebook news feed- is perfectly neutral. It reveals the beliefs of the author. I'll try to describe the ways and real cases happening in every day life, influencing the shopping behaviors, the opinions and the political discourse, and the personal relationships of the billions connected across the globe. A digital and connected world haunted by a ghost: the ghost of an ethics we can't identify, recognise and direct toward a common good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fabio Chiusi</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/the-ghost-in-the-algorithm-how-to-define-and-to-apply-digital-ethics-for-the-common-good.html</guid></item><item><title>Weird and Wonderful things to do with the ORM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/weird-and-wonderful-things-to-do-with-the-orm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Django ORM is great! It makes it very easy to use most simple operations. But what happens when your data just doesn't quite fit a pretty relational model? With a bit of digging and a small amount of fairy dust and sticky tape, you can create some quite elegant Django-ish APIs to your weird data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marc Tamlyn</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/weird-and-wonderful-things-to-do-with-the-orm.html</guid></item><item><title>All about community panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion about the efforts to have open, and sustainable communities (in economic, physical and emotional sense) and how this reflects on individuals&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Russell Keith-Magee</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</guid></item><item><title>Autopsy of a slow train wreck: The life and death of a Django startup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/autopsy-of-a-slow-train-wreck-the-life-and-death-of-a-django-startup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows the story: armed with nothing more than a laptop and a dream, a couple of plucky geeks decide to take on the world: disrupting, innovating, and subverting their way to success. In just a few short months, they take a ramshackle collection of software and turn it into a money-printing factory that enables them to drive off into the sunset in gold-plated Lamborghinis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it isn't always like that. In fact, it &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; isn't. Venture Capitalists (VC's) make their investments betting that 15 out of 20 businesses they invest in will outright fail, 4 will maybe get a payoff, and 1 will be a massive success. We always hear about the 1 - the Facebooks, the Instagrams, the WhatsApps. But we very rarely hear about the 15 that don't succeed. And that's only counting the VC-funded companies - there are many other companies that never make it past hobby stage, or live a short, privately funded life on the back of consulting income before being quietly shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a case study of one such a failure - TradesCloud. What went right? What went wrong? And what you can learn from TradesCloud's mistakes if you're contemplating starting a business of your own?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Russell Keith-Magee</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/autopsy-of-a-slow-train-wreck-the-life-and-death-of-a-django-startup.html</guid></item><item><title>Data internationalization in Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/data-internationalization-in-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django comes with well-established batteries included for translating an application into multiple languages. However, once you try to give your users the possibility to generate multi-lingual site contents Django is no longer able to help you. In this talk I will give an overview of the multiple methods and libraries that allow you to add translatable model fields and discuss pros and cons of the specific solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raphael Michel</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/data-internationalization-in-django.html</guid></item><item><title>Django and the testing pyramid</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/django-and-the-testing-pyramid.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Model mommy lettuce factory boy expects gherkin behave. Travis mock splinter nose phantom hypothesis!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most developers recognise the importance of testing in building maintainable software, but the sheer volume of tools and approaches can be bewildering and sometimes make it sound like you're talking a different language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll look at the testing pyramid. We'll discuss how approaching our testing in layers can increase developer productivity by reducing the time taken to run our test suites. We'll look at the importance of different testing types including integration and acceptance testing. Finally we'll introduce some tools and packages you can use to make writing good tests easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end you'll be able to talk TDD and BDD like a native!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/django-and-the-testing-pyramid.html</guid></item><item><title>Floods List database</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/floods-list-database.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a first step we worked with FloodList.com to integrate their observations collated from media reports into a database hosted at the European Centre for Medium Range Weather Forecasts (ECMWF).
FloodList.com provide the data in json format via an API which is then queried on a daily basis to update the ECMWF hosted database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web interface is being developed to allow users to visualise and query the database, examples queries include the time period, season, location and flood type.
All the results of the queries are displayed on a WebMap so is it possible to locate the point on a geographical context.
The architecture of the system is based on a Django 'light' layer that runs on top of the ECMWF web infrastructure. Through an orchestrator all the requests are dispatched to some python based services that performs the computations and return the results to the Django layer that uses some templates to visualise the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These resources could be useful for contextualisation studies of the risk posed to exposed populations who inhabit flood prone areas. They will also be useful for the verification of the growing number of global and continental flood forecasting systems. Future developments include the addition of different data sources to the database as well as the integration of the web interface into the Global Flood Awareness System [GloFAS] website. With this integration we aim to encourage directly report flood events through an online form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maurizio Latini</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/floods-list-database.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks - Tuesday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-tuesday.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Gaevsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-tuesday.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Marketing for Developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/marketing-for-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If you build it, they will come,&amp;quot; they say. Not so! Marketing is crucial for anything you build that you want people to find and use. How should you market your app, or your open-source project, or your mobile app, or anything else you build -- especially as a time-strapped developer? This proposal will go over marketing tips and recommendations to make sure what you build is seen and used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tracy Osborn</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/marketing-for-developers.html</guid></item><item><title>Navigating unconscious bias</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/navigating-unconscious-bias.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people do not want to be racist, sexist, or prejudiced in general. Yet simply living in the world exposes everyone to negative stereotypes about various groups of people, which can lead anyone to internalize harmful &amp;quot;unconscious bias&amp;quot; and accidentally discriminate against people they consciously respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am endlessly impressed by Django's dedication to improving our community. Every day I hear individual Djangonauts becoming aware of the dialog around unconscious bias, and searching for tools to be better to all the people in their lives. In addition, many of the tech companies, academic institutions, and open source communities where we work have pledged to tackle diversity, equity, and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a board member of the Unconscious Bias Project, a group of tech folks, scientists, and artists who translate the social science literature into evidence-based, empowering, and empathetic resources for our peers. In this talk, I’ll give folks from all backgrounds a toolkit to identify and counteract the effects of biased comments in our tech communities, whether you're the target, the speaker, or a bystander.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/navigating-unconscious-bias.html</guid></item><item><title>Planet friendly web development with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the quote &amp;quot;Software is eating the world&amp;quot; to describe how services like Airbnb, Uber, Slack and Skype are replacing the likes of hotels, taxis and the office commute. As software engineers, part of our job is accelerating this shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's easy to think that a shift from moving atoms, to moving bits, is a net win for the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, moving all those bits for our sites around takes servers. And these servers run on electricity. And most of this electricity powering our servers comes from burning fossil fuels. And burning these is a key driver of climate change - the kind of disruption we don't want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what can we do? We're not going to stop sharing cat pics anytime soon, but we can change how we build online services to make them greener, load faster, and convert better, by borrowing techniques from web performance optimisation and containerisation, as well as good old common sense. This talk will show how we can start on the journey to more planet-friendly, sustainable django web development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Adams</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</guid></item><item><title>The OpenHolter project: DIY Cardiometry with Arduino and Django.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/the-openholter-project-diy-cardiometry-with-arduino-and-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my personal story as a heart patient seeking solutions to the high cost of cardiac measurement equipment or the lack of features I was interested in. From this desire the OpenHolter project was born: a Do-It-Yourself electro cardiogram and cardiac recorder that can be built with off the shelf parts and uses Django for heart sinus waveform analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto Rosario</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/the-openholter-project-diy-cardiometry-with-arduino-and-django.html</guid></item><item><title>To Index or Not, That's Not The Question</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/to-index-or-not-thats-not-the-question.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Database indexes play a key role in every database query. Hence, it’s not a question that you should be able to define them through Django. While you’re already kind of able to do that with &lt;cite&gt;dbindex=true&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;index_together&lt;/cite&gt;, these options are rather limiting. Django 1.11 comes with a new feature to allow you to express your index requirements much more granular.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Holtermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/to-index-or-not-thats-not-the-question.html</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the amazing world behind your ORM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/understanding-the-amazing-world-behind-your-orm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every django developer has used the ORM. It's terribly useful. Suddenly creating, retrieving, updating objects becomes easy without having to use the barbaric language that SQL can be.
But sometimes, out of nowhere, your API or view becomes really slow because of some magical thing happening behind your ORM.
The idea of this talk is to make a journey from the ORM to the database. I will hand out different tools to debug, understand what queries are executed and when. And once you have the queries, how to optimize it? How does the database execute the queries? How to optimize your number of queries, and the execution of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be explained with a same example developed along the theory to understand the application better. I will give a few examples of the problems that any developer will encounter. Then explain how to identify the problem : is it possible to lower the number of queries? If not, how can I know why a specific query is slow ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that at the end of the conference, the developer can easily access the database log, identify the view queries and understand the big lines of an EXPLAIN in the database. Not necessarily in detail, but to be able to answer: is my query making a lot of loops through many tables? Is it using an index? Am I missing an index? And what is an index by the way?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Louise Grandjonc</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/understanding-the-amazing-world-behind-your-orm.html</guid></item><item><title>Using type checking in Django projects with mypy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/using-type-checking-in-django-projects-with-mypy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has always been one of the most dynamic languages, and that's the most important factor in making it as flexible and expressive as it is. However, some recent efforts being done to also bring the world of static typing into Python, initially as a 3rd party project called mypy, and currently with some support in the core language in the form of PEP-484 + PEP-526.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From some experiences with it, mypy improved the code I write in Python, but it's main blocker now is supporting the libraries and frameworks we all use. I'm currently working on bringing support for Django to be able to have type annotations in web development projects. This talk will describe the why using this tool helps you write code and can already make your web projects better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Moisset</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/using-type-checking-in-django-projects-with-mypy.html</guid></item><item><title>Django is watching my back(end)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/django-is-watching-my-backend.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the advent of new amazing front-end frameworks and the ever-increasing power of browsers and mobile processors, webapp users expect a dynamic, seamless user experience where page refresh is out of the question. We all love Django, but server template rendering is not cool anymore. What do? Use Django as a pure back-end. In this talk, technologies, strategies and third-party packages will be discussed, which will enable you to hit the ground running when tackling your first decoupled project. Also the (somewhat) dodgy question, ‘why Django?’ will be addressed and morphed into the less drastic question ‘where Django?’ by analyzing the advantages and disadvantages of Django opposed to other technologies, while seeking out to find the mindset that will keep Django relevant in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlos de las Heras</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/django-is-watching-my-backend.html</guid></item><item><title>Level up! Rethinking the Web API framework</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/level-up-rethinking-the-web-api-framework.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think there's nothing left to explore in how we design Web API frameworks? Think again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author of Django REST framework walks through how we might approach designing a new Python-based API framework from scratch, and looks at how we can start building smarter, more productive API tooling as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should come away from this talk with a better appreciation of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How best to provide API client libraries and API documentation to your users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build APIs that support both realtime and request/response interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build APIs that are web-browsable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why you might want to consider taking a schema-first approach to your API design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Christie</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/level-up-rethinking-the-web-api-framework.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks - Monday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-monday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks covering painless.cloud &amp;amp; SCSS&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Bittner</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-monday.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Qualities of great reusable Django apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/qualities-of-great-reusable-django-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's not easy to write great Django reusable apps. In fact, it's difficult to write any reusable piece of code. The fact is, as any library, Django apps are judged by abstract ideals like elegance, simplicity, and extensibility, but it's not always clear how we can follow those qualities. That's why in this talk we'll discuss good and bad Django apps with real-world examples. For each thing learned, we'll come up with a checklist to help us with practical advice for writing nice Django apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Juvenal da Silva Junior</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/qualities-of-great-reusable-django-apps.html</guid></item><item><title>Radio Free Django - Building a radio station on Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/radio-free-django-building-a-radio-station-on-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brum Radio is an independent Internet radio station based in the UK's second city, Birmingham. When I started at the station we had a WordPress website where the schedule had to be manually updated every week from memory, you had to leave the site to listen to shows on-demand and there was no indication of what show you were listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk describes building not only a website for a radio station, but scripting a system to record each show and upload it for on-demand listening, without any manual intervention. I discuss how I built a scheduling system to deal with monthly and fortnightly shows (which is harder than it sounds), and dealing with fragile egos, while also presenting my own weekly show on the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a light talk presented by a very nervous but competent and energetic speaker, which aims to demonstrate how much you can achieve without being the most gifted programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Steadman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/radio-free-django-building-a-radio-station-on-django.html</guid></item><item><title>Serverlessness - augmenting your Django apps with Functions-as-a-Service</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/serverlessness-augmenting-your-django-apps-with-functions-as-a-service.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So-called 'serverless' platforms promise to free developers from having to worry about operating systems, hard disks, backups and scaling. Amazon, Google and Microsoft each have their own take on the serverless model, and recent third party abstractions make it much simpler to get started with Functions-as-a-Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom will take you through the pros and cons of the serverless model, and use a set of practical case studies to demonstrate ways that Django developers can take advantage of this emerging shift in the way that we host our applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Dyson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/serverlessness-augmenting-your-django-apps-with-functions-as-a-service.html</guid></item><item><title>Services, Architecture &amp; Channels</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/services-architecture-channels.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powering a website with services and microservices has both benefits and challenges; learn about both as we look at the challenges of porting code from a monolith to run as individual services, and the variety of ways you can structure services and communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll also take a detailed look at using the underlying components of Channels (ASGI) for service transport, and how the tradeoffs it's built upon affect service architecture and deployment, including real world examples and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Godwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/services-architecture-channels.html</guid></item><item><title>Setting up a Python Community in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/setting-up-a-python-community-in-zimbabwe.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organizing Python events with the aim of setting up a Python community in a collapsed economy, without an open source software development house is not an easy task. In this talk, we share the journey we have traveled trying to set up a community that defies the existing norms/culture in the IT sector in Zimbabwe. We share the experiences and the challenges we faced in setting up a Python community in Zimbabwe as well as the sacrifices we have had to make to ensure PyCon Zimbabwe would take place. In our talk, we also elaborate why the lack of know-how and information can hinder the growth of a community. We also share our successes and the milestones we have managed to reach in establishing our community. We also share on the importance of support from established communities and the impact it has on an emerging community. The aim of our talk is to share the challenges faced by developers in developing countries and convince participants on how they can contribute to OSS communities in developing countries and why they should. By the end of this talk, participants should understand why understanding the context is so important in promoting the growth of communities outside their own region. In the end, we hope to convince the audience why we felt travelling a road trip of more than 33hrs was worth the while. We will conclude by sharing with the audience what we feel should be the future of open source in Zimbabwe and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/setting-up-a-python-community-in-zimbabwe.html</guid></item><item><title>Staying DRY(er) when working with Django and frontend frameworks/libraries</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/staying-dryer-when-working-with-django-and-frontend-frameworkslibraries.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever written an API and wished you could magically export it to the frontend framework or library of your choice without having to redefine every model or every form?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, today it is possible! Come to this talk and learn how.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Emma Delescolle</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/staying-dryer-when-working-with-django-and-frontend-frameworkslibraries.html</guid></item><item><title>The art of interacting with an autistic software developer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/the-art-of-interacting-with-an-autistic-software-developer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I tell people I have autism there are roughly two common reactions. Either the mental picture of Rainman gets triggered and they don't believe me at all, or they just shrug and mumble something in the lines of &amp;quot;We all have a bit of that, don't we?&amp;quot; While I don't want to judge anyone based on those reactions, I think both perceptions are wrong or at least incomplete, and indeed symptomatic for the lack of deeper understanding of autism in the broader society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless the employment situation of normally gifted people on the autism spectrum has noticeably improved over the last couple of years. Especially in IT related professions, where autistics have even become a specific target group for recruitment. Thanks to those inclusion strategies, as well as improved diagnosis, chances are higher than ever for every one of us to end up working together with someone with a diagnosed autism spectrum disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will have a look behind the scenes of the autism spectrum. We will find out more about the strengths, weaknesses and invisible struggles of those affected. Then we will focus on the working environment of a software developer and propose tips and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sara Peeters</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/the-art-of-interacting-with-an-autistic-software-developer.html</guid></item><item><title>The Struggle of Tech: Feeling Better as a Learner</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/the-struggle-of-tech-feeling-better-as-a-learner.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coding or learning other technical skills for some is a breeze but to others it can be a challenge. In this talk we will explore of few ways that could help us find joy in learning hard things. Starting from re-framing our way of thinking about the challenge, to overcoming the struggle, finding joy in the act of learning and getting out of this process as a better person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gloria Dwomoh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/the-struggle-of-tech-feeling-better-as-a-learner.html</guid></item></channel></rss>