<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-ireland-2018.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Adding the three pillars of Observibility to your Python app</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/adding-the-three-pillars-of-observibility-to-your-python-app.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eoin Brazil</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/adding-the-three-pillars-of-observibility-to-your-python-app.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This intermediate level talk will focus on introducing the three pillars of Observibility (1: structured logging 2: metrics 3: tracing) to your Python application. The learning objective is to introduce existing Python developers to each area as well as best practices (RED/four golden signals) and the specific Python libraries they can use in their applications. It aim is that by the end people will know how to add specific tools plus related best practices to their existing applications to provide greater insight into their systems. The closest example is that this talk will pragmatically present the content of &amp;quot;Distributed Systems Observibility&amp;quot; O'Reilly into concrete actions and libraries to use. Some anecdotes and examples of how these have gone for the speaker in his production systems will also be noted.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="best-practices"></category></entry><entry><title>An Idiots Guide to (Open) Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/an-idiots-guide-to-open-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Bolster</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/an-idiots-guide-to-open-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setup, configuration, and use of Python Data Science tools, highlighting some of the technical pitfalls / statistical failings people often come across in the cleaning and analysis of data. Focus on using multiple datasets from OpenDataNI to generate insights into economic policy and educational attainment in Northern Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="data-science"></category><category term="opendata"></category></entry><entry><title>Asynchronous programming in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/asynchronous-programming-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mikhail Medvedev</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/asynchronous-programming-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous programming can have many advantages, but may be awfully complicated. It also requires a developer to think differently. In this talk I will go through what async programming is, when you should or should not use it, and what we can do to avoid getting lost. I will also explore various approaches and tools available in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="async"></category><category term="asynchronous"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a Fine Grained Image Classification System</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/building-a-fine-grained-image-classification-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Fergal Walsh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/building-a-fine-grained-image-classification-system.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Fieldguide we are developing a digital field guide for all species of flora and fauna across the planet. We are using image recognition technology to enable species identification and to help with the curation of this massive catalogue. In this talk I will describe how we are building an image recognition system with the aim of identifying all known species in the natural world. The system has gone through a number of iterations at this point using a variety of computer vision and machine learning techniques, from nearest neighbour search to classification with fine tuned deep convolutional networks. All of this has been implemented in Python using scikit-learn, Numpy, Caffe and Tensorflow. Aside from the obvious machine learning challenges in designing and training such a system we faced numerous technical challenges while implementing and scaling this system in a cost effective manner. I will discuss these challenges, our solutions and the remaining open problems. While this talk will be relatively high level with few code examples and no math (but lots moths), it will be of most interest to those who have some knowledge of machine learning concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="image-recognition"></category><category term="Computer Vision"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Django APIs, Versioning and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/django-apis-versioning-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rebecca Martin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/django-apis-versioning-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will attempt to explain how to version an API within the Django framework. Say you need to change the data that your API returns to your users, but any major changes would result in breaking the API for users of any previous versions. This talk will explain how to avoid this problem, which as a developer who works on APIs with the Django framework every day is a constant problem that I would have to face. This talk will cover: 1.) Why do I even have to version my API in the first place? Surely I can just make changes? 2.) Okay, now I understand why to version my API in Django. What about the how? (this will mainly focus on the Django REST framework's library of versioning, but other methods will be considered) 3.) Live Demo of breaking changes (oh no!) and how we can apply our knowledge from the second part of the talk and avoid these.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="APIs"></category></entry><entry><title>Functional Programming for Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/functional-programming-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neal Ó Riain</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/functional-programming-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a versatile language and it supports a wide variety of programming paradigms. At its heart it's object-oriented, but in this talk I want to discuss how you can use Python to write clean, efficient, and modular functional code. I'll begin by giving a little background on what functional programming is and why you might use it. I'll talk through some of the simple primitives of functional programming, and I'll give some useful examples of functional code for data analysis. The aim is to give a practical and pragmatic introduction to these ideas, covering some of the strengths and weaknesses of Python as a functional language.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="functional programming"></category><category term="data science"></category></entry><entry><title>High Performance Data Processing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/high-performance-data-processing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Donald Whyte</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/high-performance-data-processing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;numpy and numba are popular Python libraries for processing large quantities of data. When running complex transformations on large datasets, many developers fall into common pitfalls that kill the performance of these libraries. This talk explains how numpy/numba work under the hood and how they use vectorisation to process large amounts of data extremely quickly. We use these tools to reduce the processing time of a dataset from 3 years to 12 hours, even when the code is run on a single Macbook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="numpy"></category><category term="numba"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Coding for Pleasure</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/keynote-coding-for-pleasure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Grinberg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/keynote-coding-for-pleasure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software engineers are usually advised to invest some of their free time on side projects, as a way to hone their skills and build a portfolio to show off while job hunting. While Miguel Grinberg is a big fan of personal projects, his reasons are completely different. He hopes to convince you to start a personal project of your own after giving you a fresh perspective on this practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Python in Education</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/keynote-python-in-education.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Brett Becker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/keynote-python-in-education.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brett Becker (UCD) and Keith Quille (IT Tallaght) will jointly discuss the current state of Python in education, internationally and nationally. Brett will focus on Python education on an international level, with a focus on introductory programming courses (CS1), for both uptake trends and research findings. This then sets the scene for Keith to discuss the current state of Python in Irish education, with a specific focus on the new Leaving Certificate Computer Science Subject, which has just started its phase one. Details of the subject and its content, in particular Python will be presented. Finally an overview of a large scale initiative is described, where in the 2017-2018 academic year, the team traveled to 95 schools and delivered computing camps to just under 3000 students. This was run in parallel to teacher continuous professional development (delivered to 500 teachers), where the Python played a significant role. Interesting anecdotal findings are presented, and the plan for the initiative for the 2018-2019 academic year is described, where the team hopes to reach almost 6000 students.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Leaving Certificate Computer Science &amp; Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/leaving-certificate-computer-science-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephen Murphy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/leaving-certificate-computer-science-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is broken into 4 sections: Section 1: The structure of the Leaving Certificate Computer Science pilot scheme Section 2: The structure of the Leaving Certificate CS Specification Section 3: How Python can be applied to the Leaving Certificate CS specification Section 4 : The Computer Science Teachers' Association of Ireland and Python Ireland I am the founder of the Computer Science Teachers' Association of Ireland and have been in contact with Nicolas Laurence about links between the CSTAI and Python Ireland. Nicolas suggested that I should come to the conference and submit a talk about this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Education"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Translation with Keras</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/machine-translation-with-keras.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bojan Bozic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/machine-translation-with-keras.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will describe and present ideas for a machine translation prototype implemented in Keras. I will cover Neural Machine Translation, which is an approach to machine translation that uses a large neural network. It departs from phrase-based statistical approaches that use separately engineered subcomponents. E.g. Google uses Google Neural Machine Translation (GNMT) in preference to its previous statistical methods. NMT has highly promising performance for large training data. The common principle is encoding the meaning of input into concept space and performing translation based on encoding which leads to deeper understanding and learning of translation rules, for better translation than SMT. The problem is the tendency towards overfitting to frequent observations and overlooking special cases. With the cause that the translational function is shared, so high- and low-frequency pairs impact each other by adapting shared parameters. Smoothness of translation function makes infrequent pairs seem like noise.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keras"></category><category term="machine translation"></category></entry><entry><title>More Than You Ever Wanted To Know About Python Functions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/more-than-you-ever-wanted-to-know-about-python-functions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Smith</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/more-than-you-ever-wanted-to-know-about-python-functions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What exactly are functions? Let's talk about functions, methods, callables and closures - what they are, what you can give them, what they can give you, what you can do with them ... and what's inside. You probably think you already know everything about functions, but you probably don't! By the end of this talk, I guarantee you'll know more about callables than when you walked in, along with techniques both practical and so extreme your colleagues will never let you merge them to master. (This guarantee is legally non-binding and cannot be redeemed in any way.)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="functions"></category></entry><entry><title>Patient Data Made Real</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/patient-data-made-real.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorenzo Trojan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/patient-data-made-real.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will present how python is used to develop a machine learning based 3D medical imaging processing pipeline in axial3D. We will provide a demo taking relevant scientific packages and develop a simple algorithm to detect bony anatomy. A 3D printable model will be produced at the end of the demo. We will also show how we use existing 3D mesh python packages to adjust properties of the object for visualisation in screen and mixed reality platforms. The healthcare sector produces vast quantities of three dimensional images for the diagnosis and treatment of a large variety of medical conditions. Traditionally, the 3D images are reviewed by a highly qualified healthcare professional such as a radiologist or surgeon. As a result, the diagnosis and treatment of patient is time consuming, expensive and not scalable; moreover, this approach has limited efficacy as the medical doctor may not be able to obtain a general understanding of the anatomic three dimensional structure (e.g the shape and size of a tumor, the position of each bony fragment in a complex fracture, the location of an aneurysm together with surrounding vasculature, etc). The talk will focus on the advanced image processing techniques and Deep Learning approaches that are in active development developed both within academia and the private sector. These approaches aim to achieve a faster and better understanding of medical scans. They allow healthcare systems to provide a cheaper, faster and more effective medical service to patients. The results of the image analysis can then be rendered to the medical staff using a Virtual Reality, or an Augmented Reality system. 3D prints can also be employed to convey a very tangible experience as well as allow the medical staff to prepare for the operation by setting up a mock procedure on the 3D prints.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Powering up your Python web applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/powering-up-your-python-web-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allyn Hunt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/powering-up-your-python-web-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;App structure best practices: Benefits of using the Flask application factory. Creating a (Flask-Script) migrate.py to handle database connections. Easily move between production and development environments and database connections. Separating your app into Blueprints, to create webpage, API and logged in routes. Adding asynchronous tasks: Focusing on a real world application use case, using Redis as a message broker and Celery as an asynchronous task queue. Setting up your server connection and creating asynchronous and scheduled tasks. Adding in a JavaScript frontend: Adding a React JavaScript front end. Creating API endpoints that return JSON data. How to anchor our server rendered content to our React components and fetching data from out API. Pro's and cons of using react. Using jQuery as an alternative to React.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="flask"></category><category term="jquery"></category></entry><entry><title>Prediction of risk factors for stroke</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/prediction-of-risk-factors-for-stroke.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olga Lyashevska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/prediction-of-risk-factors-for-stroke.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common irregular heartbeat among the world’s population and is a major contributing factor to clot formation within the heart. When such a blood clot enters the cardiovascular system, it first must travel along the ascending aorta. The clot may travel along the aortic arch and travel towards the brain through the left and right common carotid arteries. If clot enters these vessels, it can become lodged within the smaller vessels of the brain and cause a stroke. We apply supervised machine learning classifiers (logit, SVM) for detecting stroke probability using simulation data. Various scenarios are implemented to examine the impact of variables such as shape of the aortic arch, varying clot dimensions and the entry point. Model selection tools (grid search, cross-validation) and classification probability are calculated for each classifier. Application will be shown using Jupyter notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Profiling: Find the Squeaky Wheel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/profiling-find-the-squeaky-wheel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nick Timkovich</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/profiling-find-the-squeaky-wheel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python sometimes gets a bad rap for being a slow language, but slow code can be written in any language. The first step towards accelerating code is identifying where it’s slow: a 100x speed up to something that takes 1% of the time pales in comparison to a 1.1x speed up of something that takes 50% of the time. The Python Standard Library provides a collection of packages to get started--profile, cProfile, and pstats--and the community well goes deeper with interactive visualizations, deterministic vs. statistical, line vs. call stack profilers. In this talk, we will demo how to instrument sample slow code using cProfile, then find the source of the problem using the interactive tool SnakeViz. Another demo will be shown using py-spy, a statistical profiler which can be attached to running processes, requiring no modification to existing code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="profiling"></category><category term="py-spy"></category></entry><entry><title>Programming by poking: some experiences in teaching with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/programming-by-poking-some-experiences-in-teaching-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Fagan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/programming-by-poking-some-experiences-in-teaching-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of the title originates from a quote by computer scientist Gerry Sussman on the new MIT introduction to programming course, which (in Sussman's view) focused more on building practical applications at the expense of many computer science fundamentals. The talk will look at some of the advantages and pitfalls of the increasing trend of using Python as an introductory programming language: partially through some personal anecdotes and partially through friends and colleagues' experiences. It will also look at the increasing divergence between those involved in software development and those who, educated through Python, are based in other domains as their primary job but are using their new Python-based knowledge to assist their daily work (in finance, insurance etc). I have rated this as Intermediate as some knowledge of Python will be needed as well as understanding some Computer Science basics (i.e arrays vs lists). Some side by side comparisons will take place using Python against Scheme (aspects of fundamental programming and comparing a 'traditional' computer science course re-written in Python), Lua (another contender for when I taught some basic programming) and C (comparison to another popular introductory language and low level details).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="programming-languages"></category></entry><entry><title>Publish a (Perfect) Python Package on PyPI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/publish-a-perfect-python-package-on-pypi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Smith</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/publish-a-perfect-python-package-on-pypi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always wanted to publish a package on PyPI, but didn't know where to start? This talk is for you! Starting with nothing, we'll build a package and publish it on PyPI using current best practices. By the end of this talk, you'll be so comfortable packaging projects you won't avoid writing &lt;cite&gt;setup.py&lt;/cite&gt; files any more! Maybe you'll even start writing new code just so you can publish it on PyPI!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyPi"></category></entry><entry><title>Python as a tool for research</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/python-as-a-tool-for-research.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Suzanne Little</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/python-as-a-tool-for-research.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Suzanne Little is a funded investigator with the Insight Centre for Data Analytics and assistant professor in the school of computing at Dublin City University. She's been using python for various research projects in her area of multimedia content analysis for almost 20 years and somewhat accidentally arrived at the point of teaching python and, in particular, Jupyter Notebooks for data analytics and visualisation. This talk will describe how python is used in the background of EU projects for driver assistance systems, the Smart Stadium for Smarter Living initiative with Croke Park and for the latest deep learning for computer vision research. Suzanne will also discuss some experiences in using python for public tech courses, undergraduate programmes and data analytics specialisations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python on Windows is Okay, Actually</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/python-on-windows-is-okay-actually.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steve Dower</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/python-on-windows-is-okay-actually.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packages that won't install, encodings that don't work, installers that ask too many questions, and having to own a PC are all great reasons to just ignore Windows. Or they would be, if they were true. Despite community perception, more than half of Python usage still happens on Windows, including web development, system administration, and data science, just like on Linux and Mac. And for the most part, Python works the same regardless of what operating system you happen to be using. Still, many library developers will unnecessarily exclude half of their potential audience by not even attempting to be compatible. This session will walk through the things to be aware of when creating cross-platform libraries. From simple things like using pathlib rather than bytestrings, through to all the ways you can get builds and tests running on Windows for free, by the end of this session you will have a checklist of easy tasks for your project that will really enable the whole Python world to benefit from your work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Recruitment Session</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/recruitment-session.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/recruitment-session.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recruiting session&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Testing python security</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/testing-python-security.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jose Manuel Ortega</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/testing-python-security.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a language that in a easy way allows to scale up from starter projects to complex applications for data processing and serving dynamic web pages. But as you increase complexity in your applications, it can be easy to introduce potential problems and vulnerabilities. In this talk, I will highlight the biggest problems we can find in python functions, how to use then in a secure way and tools and services that help you identify vulnerabilities in the python source code. These could be the main talking points: -Introduction to secure programming in python. -Introduce dangerous functions for code inyection and how we can solve this issues from a security point of view. -Common attack vectors on Python applications like Remote Command Execution and SQL injection -Best practices for avoid execution of malicious commands -Tools that help us to protect and obfuscate our source code&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Visualisation in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/visualisation-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shane Lynn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/visualisation-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to explore and grasp data structures through quick and intuitive visualisation is a key skill of any data scientist. Different tools in the Python ecosystem required varying levels of mental-gymnastics to manipulate and visualise information during a data exploration session. The array of Python libraries, each with their own idiosyncrasies, available can be daunting for newcomers and data scientists-in-training. In this talk, we will examine the core data visualisation libraries compatible with the popular Pandas data wrangling library. We'll look at the base-level Matplotlib library first, and then show the benefits of the higher-level Pandas visualisation toolkit and the popular Seaborne library. By the end of the talk, you'll be bar plotting, scatter plotting, and line plotting (never pie charting) your way to data visualisation bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="data visualization"></category><category term="seaborn"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="pandas"></category></entry><entry><title>What is new in Python 3.7?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/what-is-new-in-python-37.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephane Wirtel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/what-is-new-in-python-37.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Released in June before the conference, Python 3.7 is a feature-packed release! This talk will cover all the new features of Python 3.7, including the Data Classes and the Context Variables for the asynchronous programming with asyncio.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python 3.7"></category></entry></feed>