<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-sk-2018.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>APIs: Gateway to world's data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/apis-gateway-to-worlds-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Martin Strapko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-11:pycon-sk-2018/apis-gateway-to-worlds-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, APIs all around the web provide access to big volumes of valuable
information. Combining multiple 3rd party sources with your own
company's data can often help paint a bigger picture. Come and find out
how we used Python to integrate various APIs such as Steam, Facebook and
Appsflyer, and learn the tricks we used to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="API"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Charon and the way out from a pickle hell</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/charon-and-the-way-out-from-a-pickle-hell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Bábics</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-11:pycon-sk-2018/charon-and-the-way-out-from-a-pickle-hell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pickle ako formát pre serializáciu je tu s nami už dlhú dobu, jeho
prednosti sú jasné, rýchla serializácia a implementácia v štandardnej
knižnici.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taktiež má aj určité nevýhody, ktoré často dokážu prevýšiť, medzi nimi
sú napríklad bezpečnostné hrozby a minimálna podpora migrácií. U nás v
Quantlane bola hlavným problémom chýbajúca podpora migrácii, nakoľko
aktívny vývoj aplikácie vždy vedie k zmenám v dátových štruktúrach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Z tohto dôvodu sme vytvorili &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;charon&lt;/tt&gt;, jednoduchý serializačný
nástroj, ktorý si kladie za cieľ previesť komplexné dátové štruktúry do
jednoduchých základných typov (dict, list, skalárne hodnoty), ktoré sa
následne dajú jednoducho serializovať pomocou ďaľších knižníc ako
napriklád json, yaml a iné. Knižnica ponúka rôzne metatesty ako
napríklad kontrolovanie verzie serializačných funkcií voči dátovým typom
pomocou hashov AST, kontrolu serializačnej pipeline alebo aj kontrola či
majú všetky serializačné funkcie test.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Charon"></category><category term="Pickle"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting started with HDF5 and PyTables</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/getting-started-with-hdf5-and-pytables.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giacomo Debidda</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-11:pycon-sk-2018/getting-started-with-hdf5-and-pytables.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HDF5 is a data model, a library, a file format for storing and managing
big and complex data. PyTables is a Python package built on top of the
HDF5 library and NumPy. It provides a high-level interface with advanced
indexing and database-like query capabilities. PyTables is both easy to
use and extremely fast, so it might be an invaluable tool if you need to
work with large, hierarchical datasets. At the end of this talk you will
learn what HDF5 is, why it might be the right file format for you, and
where PyTables fits in the Python data ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Outline:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- What is HDF5 and who uses it?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Brief overview of the HDF5 data model&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- First steps with PyTables&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- PyTables tools&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Search big data with PyTables and NumExpr&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Additional resources to learn more&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="HDF5"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="PyTables"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Making Python Behave</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/making-python-behave.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vladimir Kopso</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-11:pycon-sk-2018/making-python-behave.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We at SolarWinds Pingdom believe we have made some nice tricks while
writing our end-to-end automation Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, the Python language and its ecosystem was what enabled
this magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we want to share some tips for making your code cleaner and life
easier, not only when you are trying to implement BDD at your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General tips and lessons learned from writing good behavior-driven
automation are also included.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>“Secret” information about the code we write</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/secret-information-about-the-code-we-write.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tibor Arpáš</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-11:pycon-sk-2018/secret-information-about-the-code-we-write.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Podľa môjho názoru vývojové prostredia (IDE) zanedbávaju runtime aspekt
programov, ktoré v nich píšeme. Historicky sa tieto prostredia asi
vyvinuli z textových editorov a postupne dostávaju viac a viac funkcií a
umožňujú viacero pohľadov na zdrojový kód a jeho všakovaké aspekty.
Vývojové prostredia dokážu zázraky so zdrojovými súbormi, ktoré nám
ležia na disku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avšak zdrojáky nepíšeme aby ležali na disku ale kvôli tomu aby nám
bežali ako programy. Pri behu môže vznikať kopec zaujímavých informácií
spätne využiteľných pri programovaní. Dôraz vývojových prostredí na
statické zdrojové kódy škodí najmä dynamickým programovacím jazykom ako
je Python. Chcel by som odprezentovať a získať spätnú väzbu na 3-5
nápadov ktoré majú za cieľ práve preniesť rôzne informácie z behu Python
programu naspäť do prostredia v ktorom sa píše zdrojový kód. V ideálnom
prípade presne na riadok alebo dokonca na výraz, ktorý programátor práve
píše alebo sa s ním dokonca trápi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Príklady týchto nápadov:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prezentácia stack trace informácie v IDE, na konkrétnych riadkoch kde
tento stack trace vznikol, intuitívna navigácia po framoch stacktrace,
hint na hodnoty lokálnych premenných jednotlivých framov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prenos a výpis log hlášok v IDE na konkrétmych riadkoch, ktoré tento
výpis vygenerovali&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coverage informácia na riadku, ale vrátane informácie Who Tests What
(ktorý, test vykonal tento riadok, pozri napr.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.org/ned/coveragepy/issues/170/show-who-tests-what"&gt;https://bitbucket.org/ned/coveragepy/issues/170/show-who-tests-what&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;použiteľnejšia reprezentácia spustených/úspešných/zlyhaných testov ako
momentálne používaný rozbaľovací strom. Doklikať sa ku konkrétnemu
výsledku testu v Pycharm test runneri často trvá minútu a po každom
spustení testov sa táto manuálna práca zahodí a treba začať klikať
odznova. Navrhnem intuitívnejší spôsob prezentácie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meta nápad: implementovať prezentované nápady bude stáť nezanedbateľné
úsilie. Kedže vývojových prostredí je veľké množstvo, a každé ma
rozdielne API ideálne je navrhnúť všeobecný protokol, ktorý by oddeľoval
IDE a zdroje runtime informácií podobne ako to robí Language Server
Protocol (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/"&gt;https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>7 Steps to a Clean Issue Tracker</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/7-steps-to-a-clean-issue-tracker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lasse Schuirmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/7-steps-to-a-clean-issue-tracker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of open source maintainers suffer from having to maintain the
flood of incoming issues/tikets on their project. We've scraped more
than 10000 GitHub projects and interviewed more than 100 software
developers and project managers of companies like GitLab. As a result,
we have identified a few simple steps that can help managing the load of
issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk sums up the steps and approaches needed to deal with this as
well as automate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full summary, check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://about.gitlab.com/2017/10/26/triage-issues-gitmate/"&gt;our blog post with
GitLab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="who-and-why"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Who and Why&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The talk is for project managers and open source maintainers or
software developers that deal with issues every day. This includes
specifically people working in teams with more than 30 issues a
month opened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's no background knowledge needed. The talk will be best for
people who have triaged issues before at least in a small scale and
recognize the problem, they will be able to pick up the approaches
better and faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On an emotional level, I expect the audience to get to know the
&amp;quot;attitude&amp;quot; needed to get rid of noise when triaging issues. After
the talk, they should have a few concrete steps in mind that they
can try using in the first days and eventually deduct their own
process from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="GitHub"></category><category term="GitLab"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Around the World in 30 minutes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/around-the-world-in-30-minutes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Štěpán Tomsa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/around-the-world-in-30-minutes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lidé mluví různými jazyky. Ba co hůř, oni jimi i píší a to i na
počítači. Tyto jazyky se nepíší vždy latinkou. A i když ano, není ani ta
vždy stejná. Tito lidé mají navíc v těchto jazycích a znakových sadách
dokonce i jména, poštovní adresy atd. a vyplňují je třeba do webových
formulářů. A to vše je jen začátek boje s řetězci…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To, že v řetězcích se většinou ukrývá text v nějakém lidském jazyce, asi
všichni tušíme. Snad jsme se každý i pokusili někdy nějaký takový
zpracovat, porovnávat, řadit, ti odvážnější třeba i skloňovat. Odhrňme
závěs a posviťme si na některé z těch unicodových nestvůr. Nakonec
budeme rádi, že se nám takový text aspoň zobrazí na obrazovce; a někdy
dokonce i správně. Alespoň dokud se nám na webu nezaregistruje někdo z
Klingonské říše…&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Automated network OS testing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/automated-network-os-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tomáš Kubina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/automated-network-os-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Our target was to automate recurring testing done to secure stability
of software deployed for Orange BS international networks (JunOS,
CISCO IOS).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Target is to make this automation as reliable as manual tests,
user-friendly, faster, so people can focus on more complex test and
simple and mid-simple test to be executed during nights/weekends and
be able to run them more frequently.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an lab network and decided to use NAPALM framework (library that
implements a set of functions to interact with different router vendor
devices using a unified API) as it supports all types of devices that we
need to test. There is support for configuring devices, but mainly for
retrieving operational state of devices, that is key for our testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of several months work we have now basic environment for
testing thanks to NAPALM, but for our need we had to extend it with
several functions for parsing operational data. These functions are
covering different areas as IS-IS, LDP, BFD, BGP, PIM, MPLS TE and help
us to properly check overall status of the box. As I work for OBS these
functions are Service Provider oriented. Our goal is to publish them
either as part of NAPALM official package or external extension. So also
others can benefit from the work that was done as part our project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="NAPALM"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Campaign Automation &amp; Abusing Celery Properly</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/campaign-automation-abusing-celery-properly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Dolák</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/campaign-automation-abusing-celery-properly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celery is an asynchronous task queue allowing easy distributed job
execution in Python. This talk will, after a short introduction to
Celery, share what we learned when we used it as the backbone for the
campaign automation module of Exponea experience cloud. Serving over a
hundred millions of our client's customers across the world with
incredibly diverse use cases, we have heavily used some of Celery's most
obscure functionality in often unintended ways. Join us for a bumpy ride
towards a stability and scalability and learn many insights useful if
you ever need to run some serious asynchronous jobs yourself. Barf bags
not included.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Celery"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Designing fast and scalable Python MicroServices with django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/designing-fast-and-scalable-python-microservices-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dinesh Joshi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/designing-fast-and-scalable-python-microservices-with-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;django, combined with the django REST framework, makes it very easy to
build RESTful MicroServices. However, django is perceived to have some
overhead making it hard to build fast and scalable MicroServices. This
talk shows you how to squeeze the last bit of performance from django.
We will focus on django’s key architectural components and the right way
to use them. Using profiling, we will identify bottlenecks and fix them
enabling you to build scalable RESTful services that play to django’s
strengths. At the end of the talk you will have a good handle on
building scalable MicroServices with django.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Django"></category><category term="Django REST framework"></category><category term="MicroServices"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="RESTful services"></category></entry><entry><title>Implementing distributed systems with Consul</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/implementing-distributed-systems-with-consul.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matúš Valo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/implementing-distributed-systems-with-consul.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing distributed systems is hard. Implementing distributed system
from scratch requires knowledge of specialized algorithms and
programming techniques. Consul is distributed system which enables us to
build distributed system only by using Consul HTTP API. In our
presentation, we are going to show basic concepts of consul, building
our own consul cluster and showing how consul can be used for
implementing distributed system. Our discussion will include also
showing how we can benefit from consul even when using already existing
python distributed components.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Consul"></category><category term="Distributed systems"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning: Building scalable distributed machine learning pipelines with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-building-scalable-distributed-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-building-scalable-distributed-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk would provide useful and practical understanding on how to
build industry-ready machine learning models in python through
distributed, horizontally-scalable architectures. I will include why and
when these architectures are required, best practices, caveats,
technologies to use them, and a practical implementation using celery +
rabbitmq.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="celery"></category><category term="rabbitmq"></category></entry><entry><title>Kiwi.com in ZOO</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/kiwicom-in-zoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stanislav Komanec</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/kiwicom-in-zoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Počas posledných mesiacov, kedy naša firma rástla neuveriteľným tempom,
sa začal objavovať probém zdieľania best-practice naprieč Kiwi.com. V
micro- service orientovanej architektúre bolo nemožné, aby jeden človek
mal prehľad nad technologickým stackom všetkých služieb. S týmto
problémom sme sa rozhodli bojovať a vytvoriť službu, ktorá si bude držať
nad všetkými repozitármi prehľad a bude automaticky auditovať jednolivé
projekty. Poukážem na nevyhnutnosť používania systémov, ktoré uľahčujú
prácu a súčastne sa poutžívajú na zvyšovanie kvality servicov.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="kiwi.com"></category></entry><entry><title>LOCKED SHIELDS: What a good cyber testing looks like</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/locked-shields-what-a-good-cyber-testing-looks-like.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Garaj</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/locked-shields-what-a-good-cyber-testing-looks-like.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cvičenie Locked Shields je organizované Centrom výnimočnosti pre oblasť
kybernetickej obrany (CCD CoE). Svojou veľkosťou, rozsiahlosťou a
zameraním je Lockes Shields jedným s najunikátnejších kybercvičení na
svete. Ako človek, ktorý sa tohto každoročného cvičenia sporadicky
zúčastňuje by som rád povedal niečo o tom, ako to vypadá zvnútra a ako
sa slovenská vojenská kybernetická elita cvičí na zásah proti
kybernarušiteľom.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="LOCKED SHIELDS"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Our DevOps journey, is SRE the next stop?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/our-devops-journey-is-sre-the-next-stop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Martin Strycek</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/our-devops-journey-is-sre-the-next-stop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over past few years we see significant raise in technology requirements,
complexity of managing and delivering high reliability systems. Based on
our first-hand experience we see that there does not exist one silver
bullet way of doing DevOps and way how you manage Continuous Delivery
features. At Kiwi.com the transformation went from small applications to
complex micro services architectures. This change did also impact the
infrastructure not only by numbers of servers, also on complexity of the
system and ended with hybrid model of cloud and bare metal solution. In
this talk I will cover how our team of DevOps and Engineers battles with
tasks such as deployment to many enviroments, infrastructure changes,
monitoring and also creation of processes and runbooks. We believe that
this talk can inspire you to adapt changes within your teams and never
stop improving how you manage your infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DevOps"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="SRE"></category></entry><entry><title>Programming Python as performance: live coding with FoxDot</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/programming-python-as-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Kirkbride</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/programming-python-as-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce the topic of live coding; the interactive
programming experience for generating audio and visuals but this talk
will mainly focus on audio. Live coders use programming languages to
describe rules for generating music but then re-write these rules while
the program is running. By continually writing and re-writing these
rules live coders creating a shifting musical experience that is always
in flux. All of this happens live in front of audience with the code
projected for all to see. I will go on to discuss the multiple tools
that are available for live coding and showcase the FoxDot environment,
which allows you to live code music using Python. I will talk about the
motivation for developing FoxDot and describe some of its key features
as well as how you can set it up yourself at home. The talk will be
concluded with a short demonstration that will be part explanation and
part performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="FoxDot"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Pythonic code, by example</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/pythonic-code-by-example.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Kennedy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/pythonic-code-by-example.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often hear the term Pythonic thrown around, but what exactly does it
mean? This talk will take you on a tour of some of the more important
pythonic concepts. You will see many examples of perfectly functional
Python code that is quite non-pythonic. We will evolve that code into
more an idiomatic form that fits better with the Python language and its
users.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Skynet your Infrastructure with QUADS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/skynet-your-infrastructure-with-quads.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Will Foster</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/skynet-your-infrastructure-with-quads.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The very small 2-person DevOps team within Red Hat Performance/Scale
Engineering has developed a set of Open Source Python-based systems and
network automation provisioning tools designed to end-to-end automate
the provisioning of large-scale systems and network switches using tools
like Foreman, Ansible, and other Open Source bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QUADS – or “quick and dirty scheduler” allows a normally overburdened
DevOps warrior to fully automate large swaths of systems and network
devices based on a schedule, even set systems provisioning to fire off
in the future so they can focus on important things like Netflix and
popcorn or not reading your emails while your datacenter burns in an
inferno of rapid, automated skynet provisioning. QUADS will also
auto-generate up-to-date infrastructure documentation, track scheduling,
systems assignments and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll show you how we’re using QUADS (backed by Foreman) to
empower rapid, meaningful performance and scale testing of Red Hat
products and technologies. While QUADS is a new project and under
constant development, the design approach to handling large-scale
systems provisioning as well as the current codebase is consumable for
others interested in improving the efficiency and level of automation
within their infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll also dive into purposeful development design choices, how some of
these choices might not scale for the future (but work well at present)
and provide a future roadmap of a new redesign based on Flask, Celery,
Sqlite and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DevOps"></category><category term="PyConSK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Quads"></category></entry><entry><title>The Truth about Mastering Big Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/the-truth-about-mastering-big-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/the-truth-about-mastering-big-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you think is the most essential skill a data scientist should
master? Knowledge of deep learning tools? Hadoop? SciPy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk reveals the cornerstone of data science: nothing is as
important as asking data the right questions. To make it work, we need
some tools and curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While focusing on tools, we will first go over the data science subject
as a whole, define our goals, continue with an overview of the essential
Python packages like Pandas and Jupyter Notebook, and conclude with a
live demo. The purpose of this talk is to understand our data: read it,
visualize, and formulate right questions, as well as to endorse your
imagination as a data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Tools to interact with Bitcoin and Ethereum</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/tools-to-interact-with-bitcoin-and-ethereum.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ondrej Sika</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/tools-to-interact-with-bitcoin-and-ethereum.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You probably know Bitcoin. Nowadays, Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies
ecosystem is one of fastest growing industries. Many people build
software on the top of those distributed networks. I'll show you tools
you can use to interact with Bitcoin and Ethereum. From simple stuff
like wallets and transaction to playing with smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Bitcoin"></category><category term="Ethereum"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>When your wetware has too many threads - Tips from an ADHDer on how to improve your focus</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Bassett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My brain is different. The regions involved in concentration, impulse
control, and inhibition are smaller than usual; Like somewhere between
5% and 12% of adults I have ADHD. Even if you do not have the disorder
yourself you probably work, live or know someone who does. But the world
is not designed for people with ADHD, so to be successful I’ve had to
develop techniques to keep my concentration and procrastination in
check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll briefly look at what ADHD is and how it impairs not
only concentration but also executive function. Then we’ll explore how
changes in the workplace can benefit not just those with ADHD, but
anyone whose work requires creativity or extended periods of focus.
Next, we’ll look at some persistent myths about productivity, and what
you can do personally to increase your concentration and output without
burning out. Then I’ll present some techniques you can rollout within
your team to remove distractions while improving the quality of
communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ADHD"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Conference opening (Friday) - Pycon SK 2018</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/conference-opening-friday-pycon-sk-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Kellner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/conference-opening-friday-pycon-sk-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pycon SK 2018 conference opening on Friday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;00:00 - Opening words, Richard Kellner
03:12 - Programming contest, Daniel Kontšek
05:16 - Opening words (cont'd), Richard Kellner
09:26 - Kistler
11:24 - Red Hat
12:02 - Eset
12:34 - Solargis
13:47 - Closing words, Richard Kellner&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Conference opening"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Docs or it didn't happen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/docs-or-it-didnt-happen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mikey Ariel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/docs-or-it-didnt-happen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ever skimmed through a README, tried to follow a quickstart
tutorial, attempted to decipher an error message, or typed '--help' in
your terminal, congratulations -- you have encountered documentation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long gone are the days of massive books with never-ending stories about
your software. Today's users are smarter and less patient, which means
that we no longer need to document &lt;em&gt;all the things&lt;/em&gt;, as long as what we
do document is clear, concise, helpful, and accessible. And that's where
the real work starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation requires some attitude adjustment, since prose doesn't
neatly compile into binaries as code does. But Don't Panic(tm)! No
matter what your role is in the community, you can apply a few key
principles from the technical writing world to make your project more
docs-friendly, and therefore more user- and contributor-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This high-level (and all-level) talk aims to introduce or re-acquaint
you with topics such as content strategy, docs-as-code, optimized DevOps
for docs, and contribution workflows. Open-source projects of all
shapes, ages, sizes are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Documentation"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>How do we struggle with Python in Martin?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/how-do-we-struggle-with-python-in-martin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tomáš Dudík</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/how-do-we-struggle-with-python-in-martin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Od roku 2014 sa programovacím jazykom na gymnáziu Viliama Pauliny Tótha
stal Python. O tom akým spôsobom prebieha výučba, ako sme sa k jazyku
Python dostali a aké problémy sme museli riešiť, by som sa chcel s vami
podeliť. Nedajú sa ani opomenúť herné prostredia, ktoré pri vyučovaní
využívame. Takisto v poslednom roku sme začali využívať Jupyter
Notebooky s rozšírením Nbgrader, čo výučbu opäť posunulo dopredu. Ako
inšpiráciu pre ostatných by som rád ukázal aj niektoré príklady, s
ktorými trápime našich študentov.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Education"></category><category term="JupiterNotebook"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Interviews (CC) - Pycon SK 2018</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/interviews-cc-pycon-sk-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Kellner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/interviews-cc-pycon-sk-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interviews with PyCon SK 2018 conference participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Kellner - Conference Chair:
00:00 - What was the biggest challenge you had to face, while preparing the PyCon conference?
00:22 - Do you remember your first rendezvous with Python?
00:40 - What do you like the most about working with Python?
01:00 - Will you find motivation also to prepare the next year?
01:05 - What's your favourite programming language?
01:40 - What's your favourite animal?
02:04 - Would you like to say something to the organizers?
02:54 - Is this your first time on PyCon Slovakia?
03:11 - Can you see the improvement in comparison to previous years?
03:42 - Would you like to come also next year?
03:58 - Which presentation did you like the most?
04:35 - How did you like this conference?
EXTRA
04:52 - Which library do you use the most?
05:18 - How was the party yesterday?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Conference"></category><category term="PyConSK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Open educational resources for learning Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/open-educational-resources-for-learning-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ján Gondoľ</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/open-educational-resources-for-learning-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otvorené vzdelávacie zdroje sú otvorene licencované materiály, ktoré je
možné bezplatne získavať, používať, upravovať, kombinovať s inými
zdrojmi a šíriť ďalej. Patria medzi ne výukové materiály ako napr.
články na webe, videá z konferencií a ďalších zdrojov, učebnice a
podobne. Príspevok poskytne prehľad dostupných otvorene licencovaných
vzdelávacích materiálov (predovšetkým v slovenčine, češtine a
angličtine), ako aj možností, ktorými môžu učitelia sami prispieť k
lepšej dostupnosti vzdelávacích materiálov (napr. zdieľaním odkazov s
kolegami prostredníctvom repozitára, ktorý sa momentálne pripravuje a
bude na PyConSK dostupný, či prekladom anglických materiálov do
slovenského jazyka).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EduTack"></category><category term="Otvorené vzdelávacie zdroje"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Protecting Privacy and Security — For Yourself and Your Community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/protecting-privacy-and-security-for-yourself-and-your-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justin Mayer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/protecting-privacy-and-security-for-yourself-and-your-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet service providers, ad networks, governments… Many organizations
have increasing access to our personal information. Protecting privacy
in this environment is a non-trivial effort, and the threats posed by
malicious attackers further exacerbates this problem. We, as developers,
owe it to ourselves and to our communities to do the best we can to
improve our collective security and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees of this talk will walk away with a thorough understanding of
the following topics and the problems they solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multi-factor authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encrypted DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH/VPN tunnels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full disk encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compartment isolation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“onion-skin” routing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, digital interactions with other people increasingly occur
via hosted services, which while convenient can compromise the privacy,
integrity, and control of our data. With some open-source software and
inexpensive virtual servers, we can take back control and empower us all
to securely share our lives with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Privacy"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Security"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Days in Martin and follow-up activities</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/python-days-in-martin-and-follow-up-activities.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lenka Huňorová</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/python-days-in-martin-and-follow-up-activities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;V júni 2017 sa na SPŠ Martin a na Gymnáziu V.P.T. Martin uskutočnila
dvojdňová konferencia o jazyku Python, na ktorej sa zúčastnilo cca 80
žiakov z 8 stredných škôl okresu Martin i Dolného Kubína. Prednášajúcimi
a vedúcimi workshopov boli odborníci z praxe a učitelia z vysokých škôl.
Odzneli zaujímavé prednášky, robilo sa veľa workshopov. Na konferencii
sme nadviazali spoluprácu s prednášajúcimi i lepšiu spoluprácu medzi
školami. Taktiež sa nám podarilo konferenciu a programovací jazyk Python
spopularizovať v regionálnych médiách.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Následne sme na SPŠ Martin i na Gymnáziu V.P.T. v Martine začali v šk.
roku 2017/2018 učiť programovanie v jazyku Python, robiť v tomto
jazyku ročníkové projekty, súťažiť v Zenite a celkovo tento jazyk
podporovať. Sami žiaci prinášajú nové nápady a zlepšenia, napríklad
pripraviť mini Python Day pre žiakov základných škôl, ktorí by sa
chceli venovať štúdiu programovania na SŠ a pod.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Taktiež by sme chceli na PyCone SK 2018 so žiakmi našej školy
predstaviť práce - maturitné zadania, ktoré robia v jazyku Python
alebo iné programy, ktoré robia na hodinách, prípadne vo voľnom čase.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Python Days"></category></entry><entry><title>Python programming till graduation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/python-programming-till-graduation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Kučera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/python-programming-till-graduation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Rozmýšľate, ako vyučovať programovanie v Pythone na strednej škole od
základov až k maturite?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Základnú úroveň programovania, ktorú sme predstavili minulý rok, sme
rozšírili o maturitnú úroveň. V príspevku vám predstavíme našu
metodiku Programujeme v Pythone až k maturitnej úrovni. Ukážeme vám,
ktorým témam sa venujeme, ako sme ich spracovali, a ktorý kontext úloh
sa nám osvedčil v praxi.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Tiež vám predstavíme kompletné materiály k maturitnej úrovni
(elektronické učebnice, príručky pre učiteľa, ako aj maturitnú zbierku
úloh). Pre učiteľov, ktorí majú záujem vyučovať Python, sme pripravili
školenia aj pre základnú, aj maturitnú úroveň.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;A ako vytvoriť maturitné zadanie v Pythone? V čom je to iné na rozdiel
od Pascalu? Aké úskalia nás čakajú pri tvorbe maturitných zadaní a na
čo je potrebné sa sústrediť? Aj týmto otázkam sa budeme venovať v
našom príspevku a podrobnejšie ich rozvinieme na našom workshope.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="EduTrack"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="maturita"></category></entry><entry><title>Real-time personalized recommendations using embeddings</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/real-time-personalized-recommendations-using-embeddings.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Mačina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/real-time-personalized-recommendations-using-embeddings.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recommender systems are successfully used in several domains, e.g.
product or movie recommendation. In e-commerce, the aim is to provide
personalized suggestions to users for relevant items out of all products
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will focus on item recommendation for anonymous users
when no historical data about user is available (also referred as a
cold-start problem) and challenges we have encountered. Firstly, I will
dig deeper into similar item recommendation by NLP model comparing
textual descriptions of items. This approach is based on word embeddings
extracted from neural network models, such as word2vec or fasttext.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will talk about how to apply the same idea of word embeddings
to learn a representation of each product. With the product embedding
representation, it is easy to calculate similarities between products in
real- time. Moreover, we found out that product embeddings are able to
capture style of a product, color, category or a price level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the examples will be practical using data about restaurants
reviews and fashion products. Open-source NLP library Gensim is used in
code samples. Presentation will be supported by visualization of
embeddings to get the idea behind. Everybody with any interest in
machine learning is welcome. After the presentation, you will know how
to compute relationship between pizza and pasta or how to capture a
fashion style of a user.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="NLP"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Solutions Reviews</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/solutions-reviews.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Krzysztof Żuraw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/solutions-reviews.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you ever found out a bug in production that was caused by not
understanding what are requirements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you implement your code only to see that your solutions are not
optimal for the code review? This and other similar problems can be
avoided by using solution reviews. In my talk, I want to talk about what
exactly is solutions reviews, what benefits it gives you and your team,
what are drawbacks of such methods. I will guide you through my
experiment with using different methods for solution reviews and which
were good and which weren't.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>To the Google in 80 Days</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/to-the-google-in-80-days.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>František Benko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/to-the-google-in-80-days.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We invite You on the journey of making Exponea and it's multi-terabyte
in- memory databases possible in the containerized environment of the
Google Cloud.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Join us as we grasp the wheel of our multi-server hardware-based
spaceship, navigate through the dangerous oceans of no-downtime live
migrations to safely dock in the calm waters of Google bay or did we?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Google Cloud"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Unsafe at Any Speed</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/unsafe-at-any-speed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rae Knowler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/unsafe-at-any-speed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The default settings of some libraries and tools are so useless, or even
dangerous, that they should never be used. While they give the
impression of being easy to use or performant, they actually represent
traps for the unwary user. I will show the concrete problems caused by
such defaults, and explore how to create tools with &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Žiacke projekty na PyCon SK 2018</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/ziacke-projekty-na-pycon-sk-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marek Mansell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/ziacke-projekty-na-pycon-sk-2018.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>ZODB: The Graph database for Python Developers.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ZODB is a mature graph database written in Python and optimized in
C. Just subclass off of class Persistent Object, and Persistent
Container, and your objects, graphs and applications become persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market for Graph Databases has recently exploded, as evidenced by
over $200Million invested in graph database companies. Most of the graph
databases are written in Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Python developer, you will find much greater productivity
using a graph database written in Python, than one written in statically
bound Java. The major Java databases constrain you to one of several
persistent data types. Persistent Python, supported by the ZODB allows
you to make any Python data structure persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new ZODB Demo makes it very easy to start building your own
applications on top of the ZODB. You can start by customizing the
TreeLeaf, TreeBranch and TreeRoot classes and their templates. You get
CRUD for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo includes traditional relational CRUD, Create, Read, Update, and
Delete. But it also includes the extended graph CRUD. Rename a Leaf or
Branch. Cut and paste leaves or branches, copy and paste leaves or
branches. The talk also demonstrates the soon-to-be released view
historic versions and restore a previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;You can watch the talk video here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;PythonLinks.info/zodb&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And see the slides here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf"&gt;https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="ZODB: The Graph database"></category></entry></feed>