<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pygotham-2015.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>One, two, buckle your shoe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/12-buckle-your-shoe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kat Chuang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/12-buckle-your-shoe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programming is more than just typing, and takes more than talent.
Producing software takes time, dedication, and teamwork. This talk gives
guiding points for those learning to program and a demonstration of
setting up a Flask web app.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Acceptance Test Driven Development</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/acceptance-test-driven-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica Ingrassellino</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/acceptance-test-driven-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python offers excellent frameworks for unit and integration testing.
However, many people don't realize that Python also has tools that have
been built for Acceptance Test Driven Development. This talk will focus
on Behave, an acceptance test development tool similar to Cucumber.
Behave uses Python and Selenium, making available the libraries of both
to create robust testing for front end applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>An Iterative Approach to Inverse Problems using Python's Numpy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/an-iterative-approach-to-inverse-problems-using-p.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katya Vasilaky</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/an-iterative-approach-to-inverse-problems-using-p.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a talk about inverse problems and improving on past algorithms
that have focused on inverse problems in math, data science, tomography,
and image processing. We use a new iterative method coded in Python's
Numpy and show it's ability to recover images compared to previous
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Collecting and Organizing Boiler Data From Various Online Databases</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/collecting-and-organizing-boiler-data-from-variou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steve Slotterback</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/collecting-and-organizing-boiler-data-from-variou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In New York City, building management agents and steam heating
contractors alike typically work with hundreds of buildings and at least
as many boilers. When there is an issue with the boiler, they need to be
able to get as much data about that specific boiler as quickly as
possible. Thankfully, the New York City Department of Buildings (DOB)
and the Department of Environmental Protection (DEP) have published
databases online with various data on publicly registered boilers and
burners. In this talk, I will discuss the methods I have used to scrape
these boiler and burner data from the web using python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dev Environments: The Next Generation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/dev-environments-the-next-generation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Travis Thieman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/dev-environments-the-next-generation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Development environments are a necessary part of every developer's
workflow. They can also be a great source of friction. What may begin as
simply running &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;python my_app.py&lt;/tt&gt; eventually bloats as you add more
apps, more databases, more testing frameworks, and more developers.
We'll talk about the evolution of a typical development environment, how
it lets us down, and how we try to make it better. We'll end with an
introduction to Dusty, a new tool which uses Docker containers to take
our development environments to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Foreign Function Interfaces for Web Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/foreign-function-interfaces-for-web-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tristan Fisher</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/foreign-function-interfaces-for-web-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a general-purpose programming language that is well-suited for
a web application stack. However, components of your Python application
could benefit from &amp;quot;mixing-in&amp;quot; the features of other languages. This
talk will cover strategies for integrating Python and other languages,
including Foreign Function Interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Going parallel and larger-than-memory with graphs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/going-parallel-and-out-of-core-with-task-scheduli.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Blake Griffith</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/going-parallel-and-out-of-core-with-task-scheduli.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dask is an open source, pure python library that enables parallel
larger-than-memory computation in a novel way. We represent programs as
Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAG) of function calls. These graphs are
executed by dask's schedulers with different optimizations (synchronous,
threaded, parallel, distributed-memory). Dask has modules geared towards
data analysis, which provide a friendly interface to building graps. One
module, dask.array, mimics a subset of NumPy operations. With dask.array
we can work with NumPy like arrays that are larger than RAM and
parallelization comes for free by leveraging the underlying DAG.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How Do Python Coroutines Work?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/how-do-python-coroutines-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>A. Jesse Jiryu Davis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/how-do-python-coroutines-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3's new “asyncio” module is an efficient async framework similar
to Node. But unlike Node, it emphasizes a modern idiom called
&amp;quot;coroutines&amp;quot;, rather than callbacks. Coroutines promise the best of two
worlds: the efficiency of callbacks, but with a natural and robust
coding style similar to synchronous programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In barely 30 minutes I live-code a Python 3 async framework. First, I
show how an async framework uses non-blocking sockets, callbacks, and an
event loop. This version of the framework is very efficient, but
callbacks make a mess of the code. Therefore, I implement coroutines
using Python generators and two classes called Future and Task, and
update my little framework to use coroutines instead of callbacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The live-coding demo isn't just a magic trick: watch to see how simply a
coroutine-based async framework can be implemented, and gain a deep
understanding of this miraculous new programming idiom in the Python 3
standard library.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How reviewing code makes me a better programmer!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/how-reviewing-code-makes-me-a-better-programmer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Amy Hanlon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/how-reviewing-code-makes-me-a-better-programmer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many developers see code review as a way to keep code compliant and to
reduce bugs, but code review can be so much more than that! In this
talk, I’ll share how reviewing code became one of the most valuable ways
for me to become a better programmer. I’ll cover how you can learn more
from code review, how you can improve your skills as a reviewer, and how
to influence your colleagues to give you better code review.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Improving Your Flask APIs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/improving-your-flask-apis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Peterson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/improving-your-flask-apis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll take a look at the flask-restful and flask-restful-swagger
packages and how they can be used to make your APIs simpler, cleaner,
well-documented, and easier to extend.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Intro to Building Data Pipelines in Python with Luigi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/intro-to-building-data-pipelines-in-python-with-l.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adrian Cruz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/intro-to-building-data-pipelines-in-python-with-l.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luigi is a Python package open sourced by the folks at Spotify. It
facilitates building out the workflows of working with data. You will
learn about data pipelines and why Luigi helps out dramatically. This
will be an introductory level talk, but all experience levels are
welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to HTTPS: A Comedy of Errors</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/introduction-to-https-a-comedy-of-errors-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ashwini Oruganti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/introduction-to-https-a-comedy-of-errors-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given recent increases in hostile attacks on internet services and large
scale surveillance operations by certain unnamed government
organizations, security in our software is becoming ever more important.
Through this talk, I'll give you an idea of how modern crypto works in
web services and clients, look at some of the common flaws in these
crypto implementations, and discuss recent developments in TLS.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>introduction to open and collaborative data analysis with pandas and IPython/Jupyter Notebook</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/introduction-to-open-and-collaborative-data-analy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Lewis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/introduction-to-open-and-collaborative-data-analy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data munging is typically an involved and noisy process, but pandas --
especially using the notebook format -- make it easy to share and
reproduce the process of analyzing data, from munging to analysis and
even exploratory visualization! In this talk you'll get a glimpse of the
pandas workflow and some tips for getting the most out of its use in the
IPython/Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to pysparkling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/introduction-to-pysparkling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sven Kreiss</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/introduction-to-pysparkling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A native Python implementation of Spark's RDD interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Topic Modeling in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/introduction-to-topic-modeling-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christine Doig</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/introduction-to-topic-modeling-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Topic models are a suite of algorithms that uncover the hidden thematic
structure in document collections. These algorithms help us develop new
ways to search, browse and summarize large archives of texts. This talk
will introduce topic modeling and one of it's most widely used
algorithms called LDA (Latent Dirichlet Allocation). Attendees will
learn how to use Python to analyze the content of their text documents.
The talk will go through the full topic modeling pipeline: from
different ways of tokenizing your document, to using the Python library
gensim, to visualizing your results and understanding how to evaluate
them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Large scale non-linear learning on a single CPU</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/large-scale-non-linear-learning-on-a-single-cpu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/large-scale-non-linear-learning-on-a-single-cpu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents several methods for learning non-linear models on a
single machine, where the dataset does not fit into ram. It will cover
the hashing trick, kernel approximations, neural networks, and extreme
learning machines (random neural networks). This will be a fairly
technical talk, showing off some of the lesser known out-of-core
capabilities of scikit-learn.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Metaclasses and Decorators in the Wild: Ingesting Data With FeedEater</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/metaclasses-and-decorators-in-the-wild-ingesting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Silas Ray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/metaclasses-and-decorators-in-the-wild-ingesting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;FeedEater is a small library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Suitey/FeedEater"&gt;https://github.com/Suitey/FeedEater&lt;/a&gt;) I
wrote at TripleMint that we use to manage the interface between data
sources with disparate formats and our DB. This talk runs through the
basic principles involved and shows how the pieces fit together. If you
are interested in Python metaprogramming but have never been able to see
how to use it practically, this is a good example of using it in the
real world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Mr. CKAN Goes to Washington</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/mr-ckan-goes-to-washington.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marianne Bellotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/mr-ckan-goes-to-washington.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source projects face different problems at every level of their
growth. For projects like CKAN success can be almost as frustrating as
obscurity. A python backed open data platform, CKAN is used all over the
world to catalogue and distribute public data. The United Nations uses
it, the Whitehouse uses it, governments large and small hire developers
to customize and fine tune their installations. Why then does so little
of that work make it back into CKAN core? This talk explores the
problems that mid-size open source projects face getting in-house
professional developers to contribute back, and what project maintainers
can do to encourage those using their code to share their improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python, Inc.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/python-inc.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica McKellar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/python-inc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source communities and startups have some important properties in
common. They are highly resource-constrained and must work to engage and
retain users in a competitive and ever-changing market. How can open
source communities apply startup best practices? In this talk, we take
on the role of CEO of Python, Inc. and ask ourselves what actually
matters for growing and sustaining an open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Not Recommended</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/python-not-recommended.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/python-not-recommended.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Braintree, we've moved away from using Python. We've always used Ruby
as our primary language, but Python used to be the go-to choice for
things where Ruby wasn't a good fit. I will discuss the problems we've
had with Python, why we decided to move to other solutions, and what
we've chosen instead. Finally, I'll talk about where we're continuing to
use Python and what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Pyxley: Easy Web Applications with Flask and React.js</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/pyxley-easy-web-applications-with-flask-and-reac.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nick Kridler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/pyxley-easy-web-applications-with-flask-and-reac.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flask and React.js are a great combination for building light-weight web
applications. We've developed Pyxley to provide a simple framework for
building web apps and reduce the need for writing custom Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Scraping (some of) the NYPL Catalog: a story of Requests and BeautifulSoup</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/scraping-some-of-the-nypl-catalog-a-story-of-r.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Susan Steinman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/scraping-some-of-the-nypl-catalog-a-story-of-r.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A foray into web scraping in Python&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>SQLAlchemy ORM for Beginners</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/sqlalchemy-orm-for-beginners.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jason Myers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/sqlalchemy-orm-for-beginners.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll explore how to get started with SQLAlchemy ORM. We'll learn how to
build data models, connect to databases, how the session works, and
perform CRUD operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>State of the library: matplotlib</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/state-of-the-library-matplotlib.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas A Caswell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/state-of-the-library-matplotlib.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A short summary of recent developments of matplotlib and how to write
re-usable plotting code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Python Datamodel: When and how to write objects</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/the-python-datamodel-when-and-how-to-write-objec.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Hall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/the-python-datamodel-when-and-how-to-write-objec.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've been told to stop writing objects. We've been told to write more
objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we cover the Python datamodel, when to begin writing
objects, what methods to start with that leverage the Python data model,
and how to use the &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; methods of Python. This talk assumes you know
a few of the basic builtin data structures of Python (dicts) and have at
least passing familiarity with operators (+, -, * , /, in, etc...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which should we be doing? When? How?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Science of Doubt: Creating Good Controls for Data Science Experiments.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/think-of-the-children-a-methodology-for-measurin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hillary Green-Lerman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/think-of-the-children-a-methodology-for-measurin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adaptive learning technology is used to provide personalized learning
experiences for students. A common implementation provides
individualized follow-up assignments for struggling students. Using
observed data, we show how to use bootstrapping and rejection sampling
to create a valid comparative study of groups of students who do and
don’t use adaptive technology, even when the samples are not
uncorrelated.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Untangling Twisted: How We Scaled a Python Service for Online Publishers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/untangling-twisted-how-we-scaled-a-python-servic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Muller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/untangling-twisted-how-we-scaled-a-python-servic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At OpBandit, we built a Python Twisted service that renders different
versions of news content for rendering on top publishers across six
countries. At a high level, whenever a reader requests a page on a
publisher's website, our service selects from various versions of
headlines and photos to deliver the collection of versions that we think
a user is most likely to click. This requires decision making on the fly
for each request with hard requirements for speed and reliability. This
talk will cover how we used Twisted to scale our service to provide
hundreds of millions of optimized pages / month for readers, as well as
what it's like to attempt to scale real-time data science recommendation
algorithms within Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Networkx to Explore Pathfinding</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/using-networkx-to-explore-pathfinding.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Max Bezahler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/using-networkx-to-explore-pathfinding.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we're going to cover using networkx to build a graph and
then use various networkx algorithms to find characteristics about that
path. We will cover: - Introduction to Graphing and Pathfinding - Where
to find other materials including Pycon 2015 conference materials and
websites with simulations - Creating a graph, creating static layout,
displaying nodes and edge value - Using networkx for pathfinding
specifically: dijkstra_path and astar_path - We'll go thru the
algorithm used for dijkstra and astar (A*) - Quick discussion of new
trends in path Finding: IDA*, theta* and phi* and Ant Colony
Optimization algorithm Slides and code &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be available on Github&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Python for Sarcasm Detection in Speech</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/using-python-for-sarcasm-detection-in-speech.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rachel Rakov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/using-python-for-sarcasm-detection-in-speech.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I discuss my work using Python to create a system for
sarcasm detection in speech. My goal in this task is to determine
whether human intonation alone can be modeled to predict sarcastic
speech. I first extracted speech samples from the titular character of
MTV’s late ‘90s hit TV show “Daria”. Using crowdsourcing techniques to
get the speech labeled for sarcasm, I created a corpus of speech that is
annotated for sarcasm and sincerity. I used several Python toolkits to
extract a number of acoustic features from this speech that are
indicative of sarcasm. The first tool I used was Snack Sound Toolkit, a
library for Python that does basic sound handling and analysis. I used
tools in Snack to extract a baseline of basic acoustic features that
have been found to be helpful in human sarcasm identification. I then
used NumPy, SciPy, and NLTK to model prosodic contours, and applied
these contours to the task of automatic sarcasm detection. This approach
applies sequential modeling to representations of pitch and intensity
curves obtained via k-means clustering. Using machine learning
(specifically Weka’s SimpleLogistic (LogitBoost) classifier), this
system is able to predict sarcasm with 81.57% accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Voice programming: a how-to</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/voice-programming-a-how-to.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Evan Fredericksen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/voice-programming-a-how-to.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the many people who suffer from RSI, the subject of programming
by voice is still a relatively unexplored one. Although there are
numerous proof-of-concept demonstrations available online and many
brilliant pieces of software that make voice programming possible, much
of the configuration and learning of best practices are left to the
user. This talk will cover what exactly goes into creating and using a
voice programming environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What the FORTRAN is ** Doing in Python ?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/what-the-fortran-is-doing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>en zyme</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/what-the-fortran-is-doing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exponentiation is just extended multiplication, or is it? Only up to a
point. In reality, Real numbers don't really exist, there are only a
finite number of Integers, negative zero is not always the same as
positive zero, and Complex numbers really are. All of which make
exponentiation both subtle and computationally expensive. A
retrospective and prospective of the intricacies of reification of
'number' and the occasional futility of mathematical operations in
particular, **.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What's up with th@? Adding an Operator to CPython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/whats-up-with-th-adding-an-operator-to-cpython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>John Hergenroeder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/whats-up-with-th-adding-an-operator-to-cpython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you add an operator to CPython? We'll use the recent addition of
the '&amp;#64;' operator in 3.5a1 to answer that question and dig into the
CPython internals in the process, touching on how the interpreter goes
from source to execution.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Tour of the Asynchronous Web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/a-tour-of-the-asynchronous-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Herndon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/a-tour-of-the-asynchronous-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn the difference between synchronous and asynchronous web
frameworks, why you would want asynchronicity, and some of the ways to
achieve it. We will also explore some of the currently available
asynchronous web frameworks, compare simple example applications written
in each, and take a quick look at how they perform under different
flavors of Python - 2.7, 3, and PyPy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building a data processing pipeline in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/building-a-data-processing-pipeline-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joe Cabrera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/building-a-data-processing-pipeline-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the growth of publicly available data has been enormous.
Python has a number of libraries and tool to aid you in building your
data processing pipeline. These tools include Celery, Requests,
BeautifulSoup and SQL-Alchemy. When combined together you can build an
efficient and scalable data processing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building a Real-Time Analytics Service with InfluxDB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/building-a-real-time-analytics-service-with-influ.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeremiah Malina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/building-a-real-time-analytics-service-with-influ.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Real-time Analytics&amp;quot; is a near ubiquitous term in the tech industry
today and users expect dashboards to update in real-time, but providing
real-time analytics can be hard and usually involves many moving parts.
In this talk we'll explore how InfluxDB can simplify the real-time
component of an analytics stack.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building Cross-Platform Native Desktop Applications with PyQt</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/building-cross-platform-native-desktop-applicatio.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adrian Heilbut</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/building-cross-platform-native-desktop-applicatio.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qt is a mature C++ framework for building cross-platform, native GUI
applications that target Windows, Mac, Linux, mobile, and embedded
platforms. PyQt (and PySide) provides python bindings for the Qt
library, and allows one to quickly and easily build GUI applications in
pure Python. While web-based and mobile development gets all the
attention these days, there are still many use-cases for which native
apps are much more suitable. Qt provides an extremely rich and
well-designed set of classes to build complex user interfaces both
visually (with Qt Designer) and programmatically, and PyQt makes
building native apps incredibly fast and easy. This tutorial will
introduce the main ideas and modules in Qt and how the bindings work,
and demonstrate building an application from scratch with PyQt.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building tools for Social good</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/building-tools-for-social-good.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eric Schles</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/building-tools-for-social-good.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computational tools are becoming increasingly necessary in the world of
social good. There is an increasing need for data science, automation,
search and distributed computation. In this talk I will take listeners
through a number of general purpose tools including, building a image
search database with python and a few libraries, how to build geographic
information systems with geodjango, and how to process and extract
information from pdfs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Connecting color and language</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/connecting-color-and-language.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dean Hillan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/connecting-color-and-language.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A project that maps descriptive, human-generated language for many
different colors to a collection of images. This allows specific
searches to be carried out on the color content of the images. The
technique is applied to the image collection of Paperless Post cards to
help improve user search.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Contributors, Colleagues, Clients &amp; Customers: Sustaining Open Source Communities (Keynote)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/contributors-colleagues-clients-customers-su.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nick Coghlan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/contributors-colleagues-clients-customers-su.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to open source software, what do you want to be doing? Do
you want an occasional hobby where you can have fun contributing back to
the community? Have a significant impact on the world by being able to
commit full time to growing the available pool of free &amp;amp; open source
software? Spend time getting to know the needs of a particular
organisation, and applying open source tools to solve their problems? Or
perhaps you'd prefer to understand the general needs of a broad category
of potential users, and design open source tools that will solve their
problems without customisation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting involved in open source development communities can offer all
these opportunities and more, but it also makes it incredibly easy for
us to overcommit and burn ourselves out. If we're not careful, our
unrealistic expectations can also contribute to the burnout of our
peers. To ensure sustainability, we need to come to a shared
understanding of some of the different ways we can engage with open
source communities, what we can reasonably offer for free, and what we
should expect to be paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Development with Vim and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/development-with-vim-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jerry Meeker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/development-with-vim-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using VimL and Python to write scripts for the Vim text editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Docker containers in the cloud: Provider Deathmatch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/docker-containers-in-the-cloud-provider-deathmat.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Uthaichai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/docker-containers-in-the-cloud-provider-deathmat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will be co-presented with Chris Becker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running Python applications in containers has been a paradigm shift that
has enabled developers to spend less time worrying about infrastructure
across multiple environments. Cloud providers are catching up with this
shift and have started to provide services to host containers with ease.
We'll pit the big providers against each other and declare the victor.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Garbage Collection in CPython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/garbage-collection-in-cpython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrée Monette</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/garbage-collection-in-cpython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is an overview of CPython's approach to memory management -
how the life cycle of an object progresses, how objects are flagged for
collection, and the tools that Python provides for manipulating the
garbage collector's behavior. Along the way, we'll explore how to learn
about Python language features through experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Generic Programming for Agent-Based Modeling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/generic-programming-for-agent-based-modeling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gene Callahan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/generic-programming-for-agent-based-modeling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to use the techniques of generic programming in the context of
agent-based modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hack the Derivative</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/hack-the-derivative.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Taubeneck</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/hack-the-derivative.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numerical estimates of the derivative of a function are typically done
using an approximation called &amp;quot;Finite Difference.&amp;quot; However, the accuracy
of this method is computationally bounded. Using Complex Analysis, we're
able to take the step in the imaginary direction on the complex plane
and achieve near perfect estimation of the derivative in only three
lines of code!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to the Pygame Library</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/introduction-to-the-pygame-library.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Piper Thunstrom</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/introduction-to-the-pygame-library.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn the critical building blocks of the Pygame Library, see how they
fit together, then talk about some Python specific design patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Modeling an Arithmetic Logic Unit in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/modeling-an-arithmetic-logic-unit-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joseph Mosby</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/modeling-an-arithmetic-logic-unit-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Arithmetic Logic Unit is a fundamental component of any computer.
Though its operations are commonly treated as a black box by most
software engineers, in this talk we will peer under the hood of what's
really going on inside a sample ALU.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Name Things Once</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/name-things-once-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jack Diederich</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/name-things-once-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naming things is hard so you should do as little of it as possible. Your
coworkers will thank you for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyLLVM: A compiler from Python to LLVM-IR</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/pyllvm-a-compiler-from-python-to-llvm-ir.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Herlihy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/pyllvm-a-compiler-from-python-to-llvm-ir.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LLVM Compiler Infrastructure Project provides a convenient,
transportable intermediate representation (LLVM-IR) which can be
compiled and linked into multiple types of machine-dependent assembly
code. TupleWare is a new analytical framework built at Brown University
that allows users to compile functions into distributed programs that
are automatically deployed. TupleWare compiles user functions to
LLVM-IR, and C++ code is generated and applied to the data through the
distributed framework. This talk will go through the steps of writing a
comprehensive Python front-end for TupleWare with a focus on the
construction of a compiler from a limited subset of Python to LLVM-IR.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Scaling Graph Computations with Online Algorithms</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/scaling-graph-computations-with-online-algorithms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Kelleher</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/scaling-graph-computations-with-online-algorithms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of ways to represent graphs, and a lot of interfaces and
techniques for scaling them. We'll address how you might scale arbitrary
operations on graphs by implementing a data stream that allows you to do
your computations online.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sharding Data for Fun &amp; Profit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/sharding-data-for-fun-profit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wes Chow</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/sharding-data-for-fun-profit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hash function is the veritable hammer for pounding a large array of
engineering problems into submission. Want to shard your database? Draw
a key from your data, hash it, and voila, instant deterministic load
balancing! That’s simple enough, until you look more carefully at
distributional effects, failure, and redundancy management. We’ll review
well known (consistent hashing), not so well known (rendezvous hashing),
and recent (shuffle sharding, copysets) work that goes a long way
towards engineering more favorable failure scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Teaching Python in Middle School</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/teaching-python-in-middle-school.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Meg Winston Ray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/teaching-python-in-middle-school.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of interest in bringing coding to the classroom.
Schools have a wealth of ed tech products to choose from, and many
organizations are willing to fund classrooms in this endeavour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why aren’t more students learning programming? How are the gender and
racial diversity gaps in tech industry being perpetuated in the
classroom and what can do about it? Are block-based educational
languages drawing students into computer science?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A programming curriculum writer and teacher discusses the realities of
bringing Python into the secondary classroom. We’ll explore the common
pitfalls and obstacles that teachers and students must overcome, examine
some effective approaches for classrooms with diverse learners, and
discuss why Python is a great fit for the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring a device to to collaborate and join the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Terminal Whispering</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/terminal-whispering-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Ballinger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/terminal-whispering-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The terminal emulators we run so many of our programming tools in are
more powerful than we remember to give them credit for, and the key to
that power is understanding the interface. This talk will cover terminal
colors and styles, writing to arbitrary portions of the screen, handling
signals from the terminal, determining the terminal's dimensions and
scrollback buffer behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The New Basic App: Complex Data Aggregation in Flask</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/the-new-basic-app-complex-data-aggregation-in-fl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jarret Petrillo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/the-new-basic-app-complex-data-aggregation-in-fl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flask, Twitter Bootstrap, and Python all working together make complex
data curation projects feasible. Beginning with the basics we build a a
lightweight application that does quite a bit. And build to a curious
corollary of the information age: with so much out there aggregating and
processing information could be the sole basis of a new enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Yosai Project: Security Management for Any Application</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/the-yosai-project-security-management-for-any-ap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Darin Gordon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/the-yosai-project-security-management-for-any-ap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yosai is a security management framework. It is a port of Apache Shiro,
written in Java and widely used today. Yosai encompasses Authentication,
Authorization, and Session Management using a highly modular
architecture. It features a simple, intuitive API that will help
developers adopt robust security management for their applications in
little time.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Time to Rhyme: The CMU Pronouncing Dictionary and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/time-to-rhyme-the-cmu-pronouncing-dictionary-and.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allison Parrish</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/time-to-rhyme-the-cmu-pronouncing-dictionary-and.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently made a Python module called Pronouncing, which is an easy and
fun interface for the CMU Pronouncing Dictionary. In this talk, I'll
show you how to use the library for creative English text generation
tasks: counting syllables, finding rhymes, and matching meter.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Graphs for High Quality Recommendations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/using-graphs-for-high-quality-recommendations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>amit bhattacharyya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/using-graphs-for-high-quality-recommendations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using a graph data structure and community detection algorithms to
provide recommendations to a cluster of similar buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What Can I Do With "Deep Learning"?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/what-can-i-do-with-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Kastner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/what-can-i-do-with-deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Deep learning&amp;quot; is a recent rebranding and mixing of old and new methods
in neural networks, graphical modeling, and optimization. We will
discuss the applications of these approaches, how these methods are
different than others for machine learning, and what recent advances in
the field mean for people trying to solve problems in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why doesn’t anyone use my library?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/why-doesnt-anyone-use-my-library.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Robert</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/why-doesnt-anyone-use-my-library.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When, why, and how to open source code, and how to get it into
real-world use. Lessons learned working on Pydub (audio for humans, a la
requests). It's grown to incorporate contributions from around the
world, over 1000 stars on GitHub and the nicest API you'll find this
side of the DAC.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Writing Winforms and WPF applications in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/writing-winforms-and-wpf-applications-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maksim Kozyarchuk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/writing-winforms-and-wpf-applications-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to techniques for building Winforms and WPF applications
with CPython&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>