<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Conclusion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/conclusion.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan Ogasawara</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:scipyla-2016/conclusion.html</guid></item><item><title>From SCADA to IoT with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/from-scada-to-iot-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Nahuel Defossé&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe a SCADA system build with Python with an home brew protocol called Mara for a power substation as part of a research and development project in UNPJSB of Trelew city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will describe some of the challenges faced during its development and how they were overcome. Specially non functional requirements such as reliability and low latency (MQTT, AMQP and STOMP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we will cover how we're iterating over its architecture to provide a more suitable solution for IoT field and how we're using Python at lower levels PlatformIO and how we plan to integrate CIAA (Argentine Open Industrial Computer).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nahuel Defossé</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:scipyla-2016/from-scada-to-iot-with-python.html</guid><category>SCADA</category><category>IoT</category><category>CIIA</category></item><item><title>Learning Analytics: utilizando Data Science para melhorar a educação</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/learning-analytics-utilizando-data-science-para-melhorar-a-educacao.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Matheus Braun Magrin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Na palestra é abordado o que é Learning Analytics (LA), mostrando alguns exemplos que existem no mundo e também o Prisma, da empresa Bravi. O principal foco do LA é auxiliar os alunos a atingirem sucesso acadêmico. O Prisma também ataca essa questão focando na retenção dos alunos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Além desse foco nos projetos e nos seus resultados, é abordado também as ferramentas do ecossistema Python para análise de dados. É demonstrado como elas são utilizadas no processo de análise e criação de modelos preditivos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tópicos da apresentação:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Learning Analytics&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O que é?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O que se propõe a resolver?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Que desafios já foram abordados&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Projetos que utilizam Learning Analytics:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Learning Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PAR Framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prisma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Ferramentas que utilizamos no Prisma&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jupyter notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matplotlib, seaborn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matheus Braun Magrin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:scipyla-2016/learning-analytics-utilizando-data-science-para-melhorar-a-educacao.html</guid></item><item><title>3DBMO</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/3dbmo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Paulo Giovani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:
The study of plasma oscillations in 3D real systems are usually analyzed from one-dimensional data in the form of time series. In this work we propose a Python tool which will be used to verify the dependencies between canonical time series. The spectral analysis is used to determine the hypothesis of dependence variation of the power spectrum according to the structure of system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paulo Giovani</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/3dbmo.html</guid></item><item><title>Ecuaciones diferenciales con Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/ecuaciones-diferenciales-con-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Raul Lopez Briega&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducción.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Que es una ecuación diferencial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ecuaciones diferencias ordinarias y en derivadas parciales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clasificación.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Condiciones iniciales y de frontera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Series de potencia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Series de Taylor y Fourier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpretación geométrica.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Campo de direcciones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soluciones analíticas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizando SymPy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soluciones numéricas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizando SciPy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ecuaciones en derivadas parciales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tipos de EDP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solución analítica de EDP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solución numérica utilizando método de Elementos finitos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizando FEniCS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raul Lopez Briega</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/ecuaciones-diferenciales-con-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Interactive Data Visualization in the Browser with Bokeh</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/interactive-data-visualization-in-the-browser-with-bokeh.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Bryan Van de Ven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With support from the DARPA XDATA Initiative, commercial engagements, and contributions from over 150 community members, the Bokeh visualization library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source project with heavy interest and following on GitHub (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bokeh/bokeh"&gt;https://github.com/bokeh/bokeh&lt;/a&gt;). The principal goals of Bokeh are to provide capability to developers and domain experts: easily create and share interactive, versatile, and powerful visualizations that extract insight from data sets that may be remote, large, or streaming. Bokeh provides a compelling open-source visualization platform for scientists who want to create interactive data applications in the browser for themselves, their colleagues, or for a wider audience, recently evidenced by the first instances of interactive Bokeh visualizations appearing in published journal articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give a quick overview of recent developments, and demonstrate some of the newest capabilities of Bokeh including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bokeh applications and the second generation Bokeh server (that is more performant, better documented, and much simpler to use and deploy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APIs for streaming data (both in the notebook and Bokeh applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to extend Bokeh with your own custom functionality (for example to create 3D plots or network graphs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent GIS features such as support for GeoJSON and tiled map data sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the session will conclude with a brief demonstration using the new Datashader library can be used together with Bokeh to visualize billions of data points.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bryan Van de Ven</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/interactive-data-visualization-in-the-browser-with-bokeh.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks 20/05/2016</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-20052016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular Dynamics in Ecotoxicology - Nestor Cubas Wendt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⁠⁠⁠Bioinformatics applied to RNA sequencing - Daniella Helena Hock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyLadies São Paulo - Tania Patricia Simões Yamaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to High Performance Scientific Computing with PyOpenCL - Celia Cintas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPython-Unittest - João Felipe Pimentel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Literate Programming, Pweave - Melissa Mendonça&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comunidade SciPy América Latina - Ivan Ogasawara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 Coisas para ler 1 para fazer - Raniere Silva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nestor Cubas Wendt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-20052016.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Localiza, una biblioteca para la localización óptima de equipamientos sociales</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/localiza-una-biblioteca-para-la-localizacion-optima-de-equipamientos-sociales.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Francisco Palm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El autor desarrolló entre los años 2000 y 2003 una extensión para Idrisi32 que permitía resolver problemas de localización óptima de instalaciones. Esta extensión, Localiza, fue utilizada en investigaciones en España y diversos países de América Latina, lo que sirvió de base para la publicación del libro &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ra-ma.es/libros/SISTEMAS-DE-INFORMACION-GEOGRAFICA-Y-LOCALIZACION-OPTIMA-DE-INSTALACIONES-Y-EQUIPAMIENTOSINCLUYE-CD/127/978-84-7897-611-9"&gt;Sistemas de Información Geográfica y Localización Óptima de Instalaciones y Equipamientos&lt;/a&gt;. Con las nuevas versiones de Idrisi, Localiza quedó obsoleta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idrisi (ahora llamado TerrSet) era un Sistema de Información Geográfica con importantes capacidades para el análisis ráster, lo que permitió la incorporación del cálculo de matrices de distancia basados en algoritmos de rutas de menor costo que permiten un análisis mucho mas flexible y rico que el análisis de distancias exclusivamente vectorial. Por otra parte, la ubicación de la oferta y la demanda se representa de una forma mucho mas conveniente mediante imágenes vectoriales. Por esta razón, en la implantación de la nueva versión de Localiza es fundamental contar con herramientas que permitan aplicar según sea necesario, capacidades de manipulación tanto ráster como vectorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la actualidad, las capacidades para la resolución de problemas de localización-asignación siguen siendo muy limitadas para los software SIG (libres y no libres) mas difundidos, por lo cual resulta necesario contar con una herramienta que atienda estos requerimientos. Afortunadamente, se dispone para Python bibliotecas como &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mapbox/rasterio"&gt;rasterio&lt;/a&gt; para el análisis datos ráster y &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://toblerity.github.com/fiona/"&gt;fiona&lt;/a&gt; para el análisis vectorial, los cuáles son a su vez envoltorios &lt;em&gt;pitónicos&lt;/em&gt; de la biblioteca universal para manejo de información geográfica GDAL/OGR que permiten la manipulación de varias decenas de distintos formatos de datos geográficos. Localiza intenta seguir los estándares de diseño, organización y codificación de otras bibliotecas de Python para el análisis de datos tales como &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pysal.org/"&gt;PySAL&lt;/a&gt; y &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://quant-econ.net/py/"&gt;QuantEcon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las principales ventajas de Localiza son fundamentalmente dos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Es un conjunto de utilidades que carecen por completo de dependencias de software privativo, y&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Su desarrollo como biblioteca permite el uso de las capacidades desde la línea de comandos, y para el desarrollo de aplicaciones web o de escritorio, o incluso en forma de un complemento de QGIS o similar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Localiza se encuentra en sus primeras etapas de desarrollo por lo que se espera presentar algunos resultados preliminares.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francisco Palm</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/localiza-una-biblioteca-para-la-localizacion-optima-de-equipamientos-sociales.html</guid><category>gis</category><category>rasterio</category><category>fiona</category><category>pysal</category><category>quantecon</category></item><item><title>Solving Math Programming Problems w/ Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/solving-math-programming-problems-w-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Eduardo Silva&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea in this talk is show how python can be used to solve Linear/Integer Programming Problems.  The main tool presented will be PuLP (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pythonhosted.org/PuLP/"&gt;https://pythonhosted.org/PuLP/&lt;/a&gt;), an open-source Python-based COIN-OR modelling language developed by Stu Mitchell, and the basic steps to build and solve those models with python will be addressed.
In addition, another interesting tool will be presented, SolverStudio (SolverStudio.org), developed by Andrew Mason from University of Auckland, New Zealand, which is an add-in for Excel 2007 and later on Windows that allows you to build and solve optimization models in Excel using any other Python software that runs under either IronPython or standard Python (i.e ‘CPython‘).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eduardo Silva</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/solving-math-programming-problems-w-python.html</guid></item><item><title>CondaForge and the Future of Scientific Python packaging</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/condaforge-and-the-future-of-scientific-python-packaging.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Filipe Fernandes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conda is an open-source packaging system developed for, and used by, the scientific software community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conda-forge project aims to bring a community supported collection of packages to end users using conda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While developed to meet the unique needs of scientific software developers, it is a system that brings features and utilities for the broader developer community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Filipe Fernandes</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-23:scipyla-2016/condaforge-and-the-future-of-scientific-python-packaging.html</guid><category>conda</category></item><item><title>Fighting techniques in Kaggle war</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/fighting-techniques-in-kaggle-war.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Emilio Simoni&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaggle is a startup focused in Machine learning challenges, where companies can send them problems to people solve with their machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this war scenario the best data scientists in the world are competing in all kind if challenges, as search relevance, product recommendation, user satisfaction, and even heart diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Emilio Simoni</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-23:scipyla-2016/fighting-techniques-in-kaggle-war.html</guid></item><item><title>Geração de Fármacos com Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/geracao-de-farmacos-com-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Mário Sérgio de Queiroz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existe uma área de pesquisa da Química Orgânica de grande interesse atualmente, a obtenção de fármacos com o auxílio da computação científica. A possibilidade de projetar novos compostos com propriedades bem definidas evita os altos custos da síntese experimental exploratória em alta escala. Dessa forma, foi desenvolvido pela Unicamp uma nova fórmula de modelagem molecular, baseada na metodologia QSAR-4D, chamada de LQTAGrid, que ajuda na criação de novos remédios, desenvolvido em Java Um dos problemas do LQTAGrid é a grande dificuldade que os profissionais e cientistas químicos e farmacêuticos encontram em configurar e usar o projeto. Com isso, o pesquisador responsável pelo software, professor no Centro Universitário IESB, fez uma proposta de desenvolvimento de uma plataforma Web, tornando-o mais acessível.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dessa forma, migramos o núcleo de processamento matemático do sistema para Python e criamos uma interface Web em Django que abstrai os diversos processos necessários para modelagem e análise molecular, onde parte dessas tarefas são executadas pelo Celery. Um dos pontos mais positivos desse projeto foi ver o quanto poder o Python oferece no campo científico.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mário Sérgio de Queiroz</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-23:scipyla-2016/geracao-de-farmacos-com-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks 19/05/2016</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-19052016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryan Van de Ven - OSS &amp;#64; Continuum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wesley Ramos - Teoria de Resposta ao Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raul Lopez Briega - Github Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nahuel Defossé - Pilas Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Ochoa - VisPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filpe Fernandes - Catalog Driven Workflow: SECOORA Model Skill Assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nahuel Defossé: Divy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bryan Van de Ven</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-23:scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-19052016.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>External Commands</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/external-commands.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Juan Cabral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:
Probably as a scientist you need to develop your fancy new experiment code around some obscure inherited piece of legacy software in some obscure language. In the worst scenario you can't access the original source code. The only alternative is (sadly) run the command and capture their output. This dissertation try to review all the available alternatives to interact with external commands in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juan Cabral</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:scipyla-2016/external-commands.html</guid><category>command line</category></item><item><title>import community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/scipyla2016-import-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Fernando Masanori&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:
One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, in relation to other communities, is its effort to improve diversity. There is even a Diversity Statement at PSF: &amp;quot;We have created this diversity statement because we believe that a diverse Python community is stronger and more vibrant. A diverse community where people treat each other with respect has more potential contributors and more sources for ideas.&amp;quot; I was fortunate enough to take part in nine PyCon's in ten different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil, Italy, Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada and Spain. Some were not national conferences, but were EuroPython or PyConUS. I always took note of experiences on how to improve diversity, that could be useful and replicable in my local community and would like to share at SciPyLA. There are other reports that I also would like to share, which are only beautiful stories of how Python reaches the most distant people and places you may never have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materiais:
* &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pt.slideshare.net/fmasanori/import-community-62142823"&gt;http://pt.slideshare.net/fmasanori/import-community-62142823&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:scipyla-2016/scipyla2016-import-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Software Carpentry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/software-carpentry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Raniere Silva&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raniere Silva</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:scipyla-2016/software-carpentry.html</guid></item><item><title>The Numba Library</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/the-numba-library.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The basics of the Numba library and why it can help when numpy is not enough. How it can be an easier alternative than cython or plain c++.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Edison Gustavo Muenz</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-17:scipyla-2016/the-numba-library.html</guid></item><item><title>Lighning Talks - 18/05/2016</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/lighning-talks-18052016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Lightning Talk: Slippy maps with folium+leaflet (Filipe Pires Alvarenga Fernandes)
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ocefpaf/talk_folium"&gt;https://github.com/ocefpaf/talk_folium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Filipe Pires</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-16:scipyla-2016/lighning-talks-18052016.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>SciPyLA 2016 - Abertura</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/scipyla-2016-abertura.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Materiais das apresentações dos Tutoriais&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As apresentações e/ou materiais utilizados nos tutoriais podem ser acessados pelos links abaixo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Utilización de Vispy para visualización rápida en 3D - David Ochoa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ochoadavid/SciPyLA2016-VisPy"&gt;https://github.com/ochoadavid/SciPyLA2016-VisPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Automatizando a criação de PDF's com LaTeX + Python - Melissa Mendonça&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/melissawm/tutorialscipyla2016"&gt;https://github.com/melissawm/tutorialscipyla2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Introduction to High-Performance Scientific Computing with PyOpenCL - Celia Cintas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/celiacintas/scipyla2016_tutorials/blob/master/pyopencl_intro/GPGPU%20con%20PyOpenCL.ipynb"&gt;https://github.com/celiacintas/scipyla2016_tutorials/blob/master/pyopencl_intro/GPGPU%20con%20PyOpenCL.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Fit and predict your data: Introduction to Scikit-learn - Celia Cintas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/celiacintas/scipyla2016_tutorials/blob/master/sklearnintro/fit%20%26%20predict.ipynb"&gt;https://github.com/celiacintas/scipyla2016_tutorials/blob/master/sklearnintro/fit%20%26%20predict.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Python for geoscientist - Filipe Pires Alvarenga Fernandes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ocefpaf/SciPyLA_2016_tutorial"&gt;https://github.com/ocefpaf/SciPyLA_2016_tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan Ogasawara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-16:scipyla-2016/scipyla-2016-abertura.html</guid></item><item><title>Sinestesia científica - Explorando dados através da música, com DataSounds</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/sinestesia-cientifica-explorando-dados-atraves-da-musica-com-datasounds.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Arnaldo Russo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:
DataSounds é uma ferramenta Python para exploração e percepção de dados através de sons.
O método utilizado é descrito na ciência sonora como &amp;quot;sonificação&amp;quot;, utilizando a modulação de notas musicais para representação da diferença entre valores numéricos - www.datasounds.org&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Arnaldo Russo</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-16:scipyla-2016/sinestesia-cientifica-explorando-dados-atraves-da-musica-com-datasounds.html</guid></item></channel></rss>