<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ABBY: A Django app to document your A/B tests</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/abby-a-django-app-to-document-your-ab-tests.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ABBY is a Django app that helps you manage your A/B tests. The main
objective is to document all tests happening in your company, in order
to better understand which measures work and which don't. Thereby
leading to a better understanding of your product and your customer.
ABBY offers a front-end that makes it easy to edit, delete or create
tests and to add evaluation results. Further, it provides a RESTful API
to integrate directly with our platform to easily handle A/B tests
without touching the front-end. Another notable feature is the
possibility to upload a CSV file and have the A/B test auto-evaluated,
although this feature is considered highly experimental. At Jimdo, a
do-it-yourself website builder, we have a team of about 180 people from
different countries and with professional backgrounds just as diverse.
Therefore it is crucial to have tools that allow having a common
perspective on the tests. This facilitates having data informed
discussions and to deduce effective solutions. In our opinion tools like
ABBY are cornerstones to achieve the ultimate goal of being a
data-driven company. It enables all our co-workers to review past and
plan future tests to further improve our product and to raise the
happiness of our customers. The proposed talk will give a detailed
overview of ABBY, which eventually will be open-sourced, and its
capabilities. I will further discuss the motivation behind the app and
the influence it has on the way our company is becoming increasingly
data driven.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andy Goldschmidt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/abby-a-django-app-to-document-your-ab-tests.html</guid></item><item><title>Building the PyData Community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/building-the-pydata-community.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Travis Oliphant</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/building-the-pydata-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Commodity Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/commodity-machine-learning.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Mueller</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/commodity-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Conda: a cross-platform package manager for any binary distribution</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/conda-a-cross-platform-package-manager-for-any-b-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conda is an open source package manager, which can be used to manage
binary packages and virtual environments on any platform. It is the
package manager of the Anaconda Python distribution, although it can be
used independently of Anaconda. We will look at how conda solves many of
the problems that have plagued Python packaging in the past, followed by
a demonstration of its features. We will look at the issues that have
plagued packaging in the Python ecosystem in the past, and discuss how
Conda solves these problems. We will show how to use conda to manage
multiple environments. Finally, we will look at how to build your own
conda packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Ilan Schnell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/conda-a-cross-platform-package-manager-for-any-b-0.html</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Patent Data with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/exploring-patent-data-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiences from building a recommendation engine for patent search
using pythonic NLP and topic modeling tools such as Gensim.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Franta Polach</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/exploring-patent-data-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Fast Serialization of Numpy Arrays with Bloscpack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/fast-serialization-of-numpy-arrays-with-bloscpack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bloscpack [1] is a reference implementation and file-format for fast
serialization of numerical data. It features lightweight, chunked and
compressed storage, based on the extremely fast Blosc [2] metacodec and
supports serialization of Numpy arrays out-of-the-box. Recently, Blosc
-- being the metacodec that it is -- has received support for using the
popular and widely used Snappy [3], LZ4 [4], and ZLib [5] codecs, and
so, now Bloscpack supports serializing Numpy arrays easily with those
codecs! In this talk I will present recent benchmarks of Bloscpack
performance on a variety of artificial and real-world datasets with a
special focus on the newly available codecs. In these benchmarks I will
compare Bloscpack, both performance and usability wise, to alternatives
such as Numpy's native offerings (NPZ and NPY), HDF5/PyTables [6], and
if time permits, to novel bleeding edge solutions. Lastly I will argue
that compressed and chunked storage format such as Bloscpack can be and
somewhat already is a useful substrate on which to build more powerful
applications such as online analytical processing engines and
distributed computing frameworks. [1]:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Blosc/bloscpack"&gt;https://github.com/Blosc/bloscpack&lt;/a&gt; [2]:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Blosc/c-blosc/"&gt;https://github.com/Blosc/c-blosc/&lt;/a&gt; [3]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/snappy/"&gt;http://code.google.com/p/snappy/&lt;/a&gt;
[4]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/lz4/"&gt;http://code.google.com/p/lz4/&lt;/a&gt; [5]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.zlib.net/"&gt;http://www.zlib.net/&lt;/a&gt; [6]:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pytables.org/moin"&gt;http://www.pytables.org/moin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valentin Haenel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/fast-serialization-of-numpy-arrays-with-bloscpack.html</guid></item><item><title>Faster than Google? Optimization lessons in Python.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/faster-than-google-optimization-lessons-in-pytho.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lessons from translating Google's deep learning algorithm into Python.
Can a Python port compete with Google's tightly optimized C code?
Spoiler: making use of Python and its vibrant ecosystem (generators,
NumPy, Cython...), the optimized Python port is cleaner, more readable
and clocks in—somewhat astonishingly—4x faster than Google's C. This is
12,000x faster than a naive, pure Python implementation and 100x faster
than an optimized NumPy implementation. The talk will go over what went
well (data streaming to process humongous datasets, parallelization and
avoiding GIL with Cython, plugging into BLAS) as well as trouble along
the way (BLAS idiosyncrasies, Cython issues, dead ends). The quest is
also documented on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radim Řehůřek</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/faster-than-google-optimization-lessons-in-pytho.html</guid></item><item><title>Make sense of your (big) data using Elasticsearch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/honza-kral-make-sense-of-your-big-data-using.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I would like to show you a few real-life use-cases where
Elasticsearch can help you make sense of your data. We will start with
the most basic use case of searching your unstructured data and move on
to more advanced topics such as faceting, aggregations and structured
search. I would like to demonstrate that the very same tool and dataset
can be used for real-time analytics as well as the basis for your more
advanced data processing jobs. All in a distributed environment capable
of handling terabyte-sized datasets. All examples will be shown with
real data and python code demoing the new libraries we have been working
on to make this process easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Honza Král</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/honza-kral-make-sense-of-your-big-data-using.html</guid></item><item><title>Intro to ConvNets</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/intro-to-convnets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will give an introduction to the recent development of Deep Neural
Networks and focus in particular on Convolution Networks which are well
suited to image classification problems. We will also provide you with
the practical knowledge of how to get started with using ConvNets via
the cuda-convnet python library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kashif Rasul</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/intro-to-convnets.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to the Signal Processing and Classification Environment pySPACE</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/introduction-to-the-signal-processing-and-classif.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will give a basic introduction to the pySPACE framework and
its current applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pySPACE (Signal Processing And Classification Environment) is a modular
software for the processing of large data streams that has been
specifically designed to enable distributed execution and empirical
evaluation of signal processing chains. Various signal processing
algorithms (so called nodes) are available within the software, from
finite impulse response filters over data-dependent spatial filters
(e.g., PCA, CSP, xDAWN) to established classifiers (e.g., SVM, LDA).
pySPACE incorporates the concept of node and node chains of the Modular
Toolkit for Data Processing (MDP) framework. Due to its modular
architecture, the software can easily be extended with new processing
nodes and more general operations. Large scale empirical investigations
can be configured using simple text-configuration files in the YAML
format, executed on different (distributed) computing modalities, and
evaluated using an interactive graphical user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pySPACE allows the user to connect nodes modularly and automatically
benchmark the respective chains for different parameter settings and
compare these with other node chains, e.g., by automatic evaluation of
classification performances provided within the software. In addition,
the pySPACElive mode of execution can be used for online processing of
streamed data. The software specifically supports but is not limited to
EEG data. Any kind of time series or feature vector data can be
processed and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pySPACE additionally provides interfaces to specialized signal
processing libraries such as SciPy, scikit-learn, LIBSVM, the WEKA
Machine Learning Framework, and the Maja Machine Learning Framework
(MMLF).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Michael Krell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/introduction-to-the-signal-processing-and-classif.html</guid></item><item><title>IPython and Sympy to Develop a Kalman Filter for Multisensor Data Fusion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/ipython-and-sympy-to-develop-a-kalman-filter-for.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best filter algorithm to fuse multiple sensor informations is the
Kalman filter. To implement it for non-linear dynamic models (e.g. a
car), analytic calculations for the matrices are necessary. In this
talk, one can see, how the IPython Notebook and Sympy helps to develop
an optimal filter to fuse sensor information from different sources
(e.g. acceleration, speed and GPS position) to get an optimal estimate.
more: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://balzer82.github.io/Kalman/"&gt;http://balzer82.github.io/Kalman/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Balzer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/ipython-and-sympy-to-develop-a-kalman-filter-for.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/lightning-talks-7.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/lightning-talks-7.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Massively Parallel Processing with Procedural Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/massively-parallel-processing-with-procedural-pyt.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python data ecosystem has grown beyond the confines of single
machines to embrace scalability. Here we describe one of our approaches
to scaling, which is already being used in production systems. The goal
of in-database analytics is to bring the calculations to the data,
reducing transport costs and I/O bottlenecks. Using PL/Python we can run
parallel queries across terabytes of data using not only pure SQL but
also familiar PyData packages such as scikit-learn and nltk. This
approach can also be used with PL/R to make use of a wide variety of R
packages. We look at examples on Postgres compatible systems such as the
Greenplum Database and on Hadoop through Pivotal HAWQ. We will also
introduce MADlib, Pivotal’s open source library for scalable in-database
machine learning, which uses Python to glue SQL queries to low level C++
functions and is also usable through the PyMADlib package.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ronert Obst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/massively-parallel-processing-with-procedural-pyt.html</guid></item><item><title>Pandas' Thumb: unexpected evolutionary use of a Python library.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/pandas-thumb-unexpected-evolutionary-use-of-a-p.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is a description of how - against a backdrop of data-drunk tax
authorities, legal pressures on businesses to have appropriate
compliance systems in place, and the constant pressure on their law
firms to commoditise compliance services, Pandas may be about to make a
foray from its venerable financial origins into a brave new fiscal world
- and can revolutionise an industry by doing so. A case study covering
the author's development of a Pandas-based stamp duty land tax engine
(&amp;quot;ORVILLE&amp;quot;) is discussed, and the inherent usefulness of Pandas in the
world of tax analysis is explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lawyers are not famed for their mathematical ability. On the contary -
the law almost self-selects as a career choice for the
numerically-challenged. So when the one UK tax that property lawyers
generally felt comfortable dealing with (lease duty) was replaced with a
new tax (stamp duty land tax) that was both arithmetically demanding and
conceptually complex, it was inevitable that significant frustrations
would arise. Suddenly, lawyers had to deal with concepts such as net
present valuations, aggregation of several streams of fluctuating
figures, and constant integration of a complex suite of credits and
disregards. This talk is a description of how - against a backdrop of
data-drunk tax authorities, legal pressures on businesses to have
appropriate compliance systems in place, and the constant pressure on
their law firms to commoditise compliance services, Pandas may be about
to make a foray from its venerable financial origins into a brave new
fiscal world - and can revolutionise an industry by doing so. A case
study covering the author's development of a Pandas-based stamp duty
land tax engine (&amp;quot;ORVILLE&amp;quot;) is discussed, and the inherent usefulness of
Pandas in the world of tax analysis is explored.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Nyland</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/pandas-thumb-unexpected-evolutionary-use-of-a-p.html</guid></item><item><title>Panel: The challenges and frontiers of data science in Europe</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/panel-the-challenges-and-frontiers-of-data-scien.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Drake</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/panel-the-challenges-and-frontiers-of-data-scien.html</guid></item><item><title>Algorithmic Trading with Zipline</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/algorithmic-trading-with-zipline.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin 2014 - Python is quickly becoming the glue language which
holds together data science and related fields like quantitative
finance. Zipline is a BSD-licensed quantitative trading system which
allows easy backtesting of investment algorithms on historical data. The
system is fundamentally event-driven and a close approximation of how
live-trading systems operate. Moreover, Zipline comes &amp;quot;batteries
included&amp;quot; as many common statistics like moving average and linear
regression can be readily accessed from within a user-written algorithm.
Input of historical data and output of performance statistics is based
on Pandas DataFrames to integrate nicely into the existing Python
eco-system. Furthermore, statistic and machine learning libraries like
matplotlib, scipy, statsmodels, and sklearn integrate nicely to support
development, analysis and visualization of state-of-the-art trading
systems. Zipline is currently used in production as the backtesting
engine powering Quantopian.com -- a free, community-centered platform
that allows development and real-time backtesting of trading algorithms
in the web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Wiecki</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/algorithmic-trading-with-zipline.html</guid></item><item><title>Data Oriented Programming</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/data-oriented-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computers have traditionally been thought as tools for performing
computations with numbers. Of course, its name in English has a lot to
do with this conception, but in other languages, like the french
'ordinateur' (which express concepts more like sorting or classifying),
one can clearly see the other side of the coin: computers can also be
used to extract (usually new) information from data. Storage, reduction,
classification, selection, sorting, grouping, among others, are typical
operations in this 'alternate' goal of computers, and although carrying
out all these tasks does imply doing a lot of computations, it also
requires thinking about the computer as a different entity than the view
offered by the traditional von Neumann architecture (basically a CPU
with memory). In fact, when it is about programming the data handling
efficiently, the most interesting part of a computer is the so-called
hierarchical storage, where the different levels of caches in CPUs, the
RAM memory, the SSD layers (there are several in the market already),
the mechanical disks and finally, the network, are pretty much more
important than the ALUs (arithmetic and logical units) in CPUs. In data
handling, techniques like data deduplication and compression become
critical when speaking about dealing with extremely large datasets.
Moreover, distributed environments are useful mainly because of its
increased storage capacities and I/O bandwidth, rather than for their
aggregated computing throughput. During my talk I will describe several
programming paradigms that should be taken in account when programming
data oriented applications and that are usually different than those
required for achieving pure computational throughput. But specially, and
in a surprising turnaround, how the amazing amount of computational
power in modern CPUs can also be useful for data handling as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesc Alted</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/data-oriented-programming.html</guid></item><item><title>Dealing With Complexity</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/dealing-with-complexity.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jean-Paul Schmetz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/dealing-with-complexity.html</guid></item><item><title>Driving Moore's Law with Python-Powered Machine Learning: An Insider's Perspective</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/driving-moores-law-with-python-powered-machine-l.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;People talk about a Moore's Law for gene sequencing, a Moore's Law for
software, etc. This is talk is about &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; Moore's Law, the bull that
the other &amp;quot;Laws&amp;quot; ride; and how Python-powered ML helps drive it. How do
we keep making ever-smaller devices? How do we harness atomic-scale
physics? Large-scale machine learning is key. The computation drives new
chip designs, and those new chip designs are used for new computations,
ad infinitum. High-dimensional regression, classification, active
learning, optimization, ranking, clustering, density estimation,
scientific visualization, massively parallel processing -- it all comes
into play, and Python is powering it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Trent McConaghy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/driving-moores-law-with-python-powered-machine-l.html</guid></item><item><title>Exploratory Time Series Analysis of NYC Subway Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/exploratory-time-series-analysis-of-nyc-subway-da.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What questions arise during a quick model assessment? In this
hands-on-tutorial we want to cover the whole chain from preparing data
to choosing and fitting a model to properly assessing the quality of a
predictive model. Our dataset in this tutorial are the numbers of people
entering and exiting New York subway stations. Among other ways of
building a predictive model, we introduce the python package pydse (
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydse.readthedocs.org/"&gt;http://pydse.readthedocs.org/&lt;/a&gt; ) and apply it to the dataset in order to
derive the parameters of an ARMA-model (autoregressive moving average).
At the end of the tutorial we evaluate the models and examine the
strengths and weaknesses of various ways to measure the accuracy and
quality of a predictive model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felix Marczinowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/exploratory-time-series-analysis-of-nyc-subway-da.html</guid></item><item><title>Extract Transform Load using mETL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/extract-transform-load-using-metl.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;mETL is an ETL package written in Python which was developed to load
elective data for Central European University. Program can be used in a
more general way, it can be used to load practically any kind of data to
any target. Code is open source and available for anyone who want to use
it. The main advantage to configurable via Yaml files and You have the
possibility to write any transformation in Python and You can use it
natively from any framework as well. We are using this tool in
production for many of our clients and It is really stable and reliable.
The project has a few contributors all around the world right now and I
hope many developer will join soon. I really want to show you how you
can use it in your daily work. In this tutorial We will see the most
common situations: - Installation - Write simple Yaml configration files
to load CSV, JSON, XML into MySQL or PostgreSQL Database, or convert CSV
to JSON, etc. - Add tranformations on your fields - Filter records based
on condition - Walk through a directory to feed the tool - How the
mapping works - Generate Yaml configurations automatically from data
source - Migrate a database to another database&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bence Faludi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/extract-transform-load-using-metl.html</guid></item><item><title>Generators Will Free Your Mind</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/generators-will-free-your-mind.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Powell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/generators-will-free-your-mind.html</guid></item><item><title>How to Spy with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/how-to-spy-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk through what the US government has done in terms of
spying on US citizens and foreigners with their PRISM program, then walk
through how to do exactly that with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lynn Root</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/how-to-spy-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Interactive Analysis of (Large) Financial Data Sets</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/interactive-analysis-of-large-financial-data-se.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/interactive-analysis-of-large-financial-data-se.html</guid></item><item><title>Low-rank matrix approximations in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/low-rank-matrix-approximations-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low-rank approximations of data matrices have become an important tool
in machine learning and data mining. They allow for embedding high
dimensional data in lower dimensional spaces and can therefore mitigate
effects due to noise, uncover latent relations, or facilitate further
processing. These properties have been proven successful in many
application areas such as bio-informatics, computer vision, text
processing, recommender systems, social network analysis, among others.
Present day technologies are characterized by exponentially growing
amounts of data. Recent advances in sensor technology, internet
applications, and communication networks call for methods that scale to
very large and/or growing data matrices. In this talk, we will describe
how to efficiently analyze data by means of matrix factorization using
the Python Matrix Factorization Toolbox (PyMF) and HDF5. We will briefly
cover common methods such as k-means clustering, PCA, or Archetypal
Analysis which can be easily cast as a matrix decomposition, and explain
their usefulness for everyday data analysis tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Thurau</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/low-rank-matrix-approximations-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Packaging and Deployment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/packaging-and-deployment.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Travis Oliphant</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/packaging-and-deployment.html</guid></item><item><title>Parallel processing using python and gearman</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/parallel-processing-using-python-and-gearman.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When talking of parallel processing, some task requires a substantial
set-up time. This is the case of Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks
such as classification, where models need to be loaded into memory. In
these situations, we can not start a new process for every data set to
be handled, but the system needs to be ready to process new incoming
data. This talk will look at job queue systems, with particular focus on
gearman. We will see how we are using it at Synthesio for NLP tasks; how
to set up workers and clients, make it redundant and robust, monitor its
activity and adapt to demand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pedro Miguel Dias Cardoso</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/parallel-processing-using-python-and-gearman.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and pandas as back end to real-time data driven applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/python-and-pandas-as-back-end-to-real-time-data-d.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For data, and data science, to be the fuel of the 21th century, data
driven applications should not be confined to dashboards and static
analyses. Instead they should be the driver of the organizations that
own or generates the data. Most of these applications are web-based and
require real-time access to the data. However, many Big Data analyses
and tools are inherently batch-driven and not well suited for real-time
and performance-critical connections with applications. Trade-offs
become often inevitable, especially when mixing multiple tools and data
sources. In this talk we will describe our journey to build a data
driven application at a large Dutch financial institution. We will dive
into the issues we faced, why we chose Python and pandas and what that
meant for real-time data analysis (and agile development). Important
points in the talk will be, among others, the handling of geographical
data, the access to hundreds of millions of records as well as the real
time analysis of millions of data points.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giovanni Lanzani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/python-and-pandas-as-back-end-to-real-time-data-d.html</guid></item><item><title>Quantified Self: Analyzing the Big Data of our Daily Life</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/quantified-self-analyzing-the-big-data-of-our-da.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applications for self tracking that collect, analyze, or publish
personal and medical data are getting more popular. This includes either
a broad variety of medical and healthcare apps in the fields of
telemedicine, remote care, treatment, or interaction with patients, and
a huge increasing number of self tracking apps that aims to acquire data
form from people’s daily life. The Quantified Self movement goes far
beyond collecting or generating medical data. It aims in gathering data
of all kinds of activities, habits, or relations that could help to
understand and improve one’s behavior, health, or well-being. Both,
health apps as well as Quantified Self apps use either just the
smartphone as data source (e.g., questionnaires, manual data input,
smartphone sensors) or external devices and sensors such as ‘classical’
medical devices (e.g,. blood pressure meters) or wearable devices (e.g.,
wristbands or eye glasses). The data can be used to get insights into
the medical condition or one’s personal life and behavior. This talk
will provide an overview of the various data sources and data formats
that are relevant for self tracking as well as strategies and examples
for analyzing that data with Python. The talk will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessing local and distributed sources for the heterogeneous Quantified
Self data. That includes local data files generated by smartphone apps
and web applications as well as data stored on cloud resources via APIs
(e.g., data that is stored by vendors of self tracking hardware or data
of social media channels, weather data, traffic data etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homogenizing the data. Especially, covering typical problems of
heterogeneous Quantified Self data, such as missing data or different
and non-standard data formatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyzing and visualizing the data. Depending on the questions one has,
the data can be analyzed with statistical methods or correlations. For
example, to get insight into one's personal physical activities, steps
data form activity trackers can be correlated to location data and
weather information. The talk covers how to conduct this and other data
analysis tasks with tools such as pandas and how to visualize the
results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples in this talk will be shown as interactive IPython sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Schreiber</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/quantified-self-analyzing-the-big-data-of-our-da.html</guid></item><item><title>Semantic Python: Mastering Linked Data with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/semantic-python-mastering-linked-data-with-pytho.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim Berners-Lee defined the Semantic Web as a web of data that can be
processed directly and indirectly by machines. More precisely, the
Semantic Web can be defined as a set of standards and best practices for
sharing data and the semantics of that data over the Web to be used by
applications [DuCharme, 2013].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the Semantic Web is built on top of three main pillars:
the RDF (i.e., Resource Description Framework) data model, the SPARQL
query language, and the OWL standard for storing vocabularies and
ontologies. These standards allows the huge amount of data on the Web to
be available in a unique and unified standard format, contributing to
the definition of the Web of Data (WoD) [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WoD makes the web data to be reachable and easily manageable by
Semantic Web tools, providing also the relationships among these data
(thus practically setting up the “Web”). This collection of interrelated
datasets on the Web can also be referred to as Linked Data [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two typical examples of large Linked Dataset are FreeBase, and DBPedia,
which essentially provides the so called Common sense Knowledge in RDF
format. Python offers a very powerful and easy to use library to work
with Linked Data: rdflib. RDFLib is a lightweight and functionally
complete RDF library, allowing applications to access, create and manage
RDF graphs in a very Pythonic fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, a general overview of the main features provided by the
rdflib package will be presented. To this end, several code examples
will be discussed, along with a case study concerning the analysis of a
(semantic) social graph. This case study will be focused on the
integration between the networkx module and the rdflib library in order
to crawl, access (via SPARQL), and analyze a Social Linked Data Graph
represented using the FOAF (Friend of a Friend) schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is intended for an Novice level audience, assuming a good
knowledge of the Python language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valerio Maggio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/semantic-python-mastering-linked-data-with-pytho.html</guid></item><item><title>Speed Without Drag</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/speed-without-drag.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speed without drag: making code faster when there's no time to waste A
practical walkthrough over the state-of-the-art of low-friction
numerical Python enhancing solutions, covering: exhausting CPython,
NumPy, Numba, Parakeet, Cython, Theano, Pyston, PyPy/NumPyPy and Blaze.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saul Diez-Guerra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/speed-without-drag.html</guid></item><item><title>Street Fighting Trend Research</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/street-fighting-trend-research.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk shows how to tackle common tasks in applied trend research and
technology foresight from identifying a data-source, getting the data
and data cleaning to presenting the insights in meaningful
visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents a very hands-on approach for identifying research and
technology trends in various industries with a little bit of Pandas
here, NTLK there and all cooked up in an IPython Notebook. Three
examples featured in this talk are: How to find out the most interesting
research topics cutting edge companies are after right now? How to pick
sessions from a large conference program (think PyCon, PyData or Strata)
that are presenting something really novel? How to automagically
identify trends in industries such as computer vision or
telecommunications? The talk will show how to tackle common tasks in
applied trend research and technology foresight from identifying a
data-source, getting the data and data cleaning to presenting the
insights in meaningful visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Benedikt Koehler</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/street-fighting-trend-research.html</guid></item><item><title>Visualising Data through Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/visualising-data-through-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pandas &amp;amp; ggplot: quick analysis with python and friends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning the basics of pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning the basics of visualisation with ggplot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;combining the two&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the talk will be slides, the other part will be done via an
iPython-notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vincent Warmerdam</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/visualising-data-through-pandas.html</guid></item></channel></rss>