<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-sk-2019.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Automated visualization and presentation of tests results</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/automated-visualization-and-presentation-of-tests-results.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tibor Frank</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/automated-visualization-and-presentation-of-tests-results.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thousands of performance tests run by tens of Jenkins jobs generate
gigabytes of data. It is not an easy task to provide it to our audience.
But we do our best. Data visualization is not only coding in Python, it
is above all finding the best way how to transform well structured but
boring xml files to fancy and informative graphs and tables. They must
be beautiful, gratifying, logical and functional like any good design
and/or architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Automatická korekcia písaného prejavu prirodzeného jazyka s využitím znakových a kontextuálnych modelov</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/automaticka-korekcia-pisaneho-prejavu-prirodzeneho-jazyka-s-vyuzitim-znakovych-a-kontextualnych-modelov.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Mertus</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/automaticka-korekcia-pisaneho-prejavu-prirodzeneho-jazyka-s-vyuzitim-znakovych-a-kontextualnych-modelov.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banka disponuje veľkým objemom neštruktúrovaných dát. Na ich použitie je
potrebné tieto dáta očistiť. Preto vyvíjame modul na korekciu
gramatických chýb a preklepov, ktorý sa skladá z troch hlavých častí.
Prvou časťou je takzvaný &amp;quot;re-diakritizátor&amp;quot; zameraný na obnovenie
diakritiky v slove bez nej. Druhá časť je znakový model SymSpell. Ten
navrhuje možné opravy slova na základe Damerau-Levenshtein metriky.
Tretia časť využíva známy model Word2Vec na pochopenie kontextuálnych
závislostí slov v relevantnom dokumente. Vývoj modulu nie je ešte
ukončený, avšak subjektívne posúdenie modulu indikuje použiteľnosť v
špecifickom bankovom prostredí.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Intro to Blockchain with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/intro-to-blockchain-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christoph Ritzer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/intro-to-blockchain-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is structured into two parts of approximately equal length:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First an introduction to blockchains in general. Most have heard about
blockchains or bitcoin but how does it actually work and what is the
technology driving it? This talk will explain what a cryptocurrency
wallet is, how transactions are created and how they are brought
together to form blocks that build the blockchain. I will outline
differences between the most widely used implementations and the core
technological concepts behind them, like Proof-of-Work versus
Proof-of-Stake, consensus algorithms, trustless systems and the ideas
behind them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second half of the talk I draw on my experience working with
python in my professional career and give an overview of the python
ecosystem for blockhain and cryptocurrency development. I will showcase
some of the libraries and tools that exist, like btcpy and highlight
some of the pros and cons (mostly pros) of using python in this sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>MVP, is never just a MVP</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/mvp-is-never-just-a-mvp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Suryansh Tibarewala</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/mvp-is-never-just-a-mvp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MVP: Minimum Viable Product. We all follow agile product development
process, iterate fast, fail fast and in the disguise of a MVP we cut
corners to release a product to the market ASAP. In this process, their
are several compromises we make in the tech set up and the codebase to
just get it out there. These compromises more often than not always
bites us back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is what the talk is about. The assumptions which never hold,
the implementation which is never revisited, and the MVP which never
ends up being just a MVP. By the end of talk, you would know the
cautionary tale of the most common mistakes everyone makes while
developing a new product and some measures on how you can avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon SK 2019 - Aula Magna - Nedela</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aula-magna-nedela.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aula-magna-nedela.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Smart Homes + Tor = SSH [Secure Smart Home]</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/smart-homes-tor-ssh-secure-smart-home.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kalyan Dikshit</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/smart-homes-tor-ssh-secure-smart-home.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Internet of Things,” “Smart Devices,” “Smart Homes.” people are
fascinated with them and their usage. But the most important things they
tend to forget are “Security &amp;amp; Privacy”. Using Tor to divert prying eyes
away from our connected homes.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Apprentice's Enthusiastic Guide to pandas (or how to look at the world through the gentle eyes of one)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/the-apprentices-enthusiastic-guide-to-pandas-or-how-to-look-at-the-world-through-the-gentle-eyes-of-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ingrid Budau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/the-apprentices-enthusiastic-guide-to-pandas-or-how-to-look-at-the-world-through-the-gentle-eyes-of-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pandas soon realized there's no way they are going to survive the
ordeals and hardships of this world, if they didn't finally and without
the blink of an eye of hesitation pull themselves together, stop being
the lazy fluffy beings, they have long been known for and start
reorganizing their lives ASAP. They needed a fresh view over the world
and its intrinsic mechanisms, light had to be shed upon the information
they possessed about survival, in a few words, they had to start over.
This is how in the midst of the forest a high performative library was
coming to life, whose powerful toolkit would enable them a long lasting
life of happiness and joy. This long-dreamed library should import the
information they have been gathering about the world for long gone
centuries and help them look at it through different eyes. They wanted
to structure their world views and beliefs into sensible types and
categories, remove from their genes their procrastinative behavioural
patterns, drop them altogether. After laborious efforts of dealing with
missing data about their surroundings, grouping and counting the
meaningful rest, filtering the nonsensical superstitions, they could
finally and, without doubt, point out with precision, where the bamboo
sprouts were freshest, most succulent, fiber rich, absolutely
scrumptious and the moment of the year, dictated by the moon calendar,
when they are fluffiest, cosiest, most willing and irresistibly fall for
one another and cuddle up. They put all this secret survival kit into
easily understandable pictures and graphs for the dreamers out of them,
who weren't prepared to put in all the effort of learning all those
complicated symbols, just in order to survive and just wanted to admire
the sky goddess, the moon. But wait, they didn't have a name for their
grandiose library, so they just wanted to make a statement of being the
most diligent creature of them all and called it, simply and
unmistakably, pandas!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The dos and don'ts of task queues</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/the-dos-and-donts-of-task-queues.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Petr Stehlík</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/the-dos-and-donts-of-task-queues.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about our experience with Celery and intentions to switch to
RQ which failed. We'll show our setup of larger and more complex apps
than the ones presented in doc examples together with some useful tips
and tricks and how-tos on orchestrating such apps for thousands of tasks
a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Kiwi.com we heavily rely on task queues and asynchronous execution of
code to process large amounts of requests coming to our back-ends. With
the separation of our codebase to microservices, we can quickly try new
tools and different approaches to process these large volumes of
requests. The microservice we'll be talking about is making unreliable
slow 3rd party services reliable and asynchronous with a bit of business
logic sprinkled on top of it. We’ll tell a failure story of ours but
resulting in a valuable lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our services use Celery and it's the go-to tool for new services
as well but we wanted to be different with this new microservice. RQ is
the next best choice for task queues and it is presented as simpler and
more straightforward than Celery. That can definitely be true but after
3 weeks of research, development and struggling we found out the
unpleasant truth about being simple and making the right choices. We
won't talk about comparing the frameworks but rather about the approach
on how to experiment with new things in your environment. After that,
we'll present our current setup which can take upon any number of tasks.
How we orchestrate the app and continuously integrate and deploy and
what fun things await ahead of us in the development.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Think about the user</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/think-about-the-user.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hans Christian Feßl</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/think-about-the-user.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As developers, we are mainly focused on making things work. Business
logic and process analysis, reinventing the wheel and questioning every
line of code are what we do best. But when it comes to making this very
complex systems work for users, we are quickly frustrated, because it
feels like they just don't get it. As people of code, we are no longer
regular users because we understand what is going on behind the curtains
of the big show that is called a User Interface. What means, that by
default, users have a totally different experience then we developers
do. In this talk, I want to extend my lightning talk from last year to
half an hour, to give you some tips on how to get a users perspective on
the user interface you want or have to create.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Amazon Web Services - Alexa skills</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/amazon-web-services-alexa-skills.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Samuel Hopko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/amazon-web-services-alexa-skills.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alexa is Amazon’s cloud base voice service that provides natural voice
experience to end users. This opens a way to use human voice as
input/output for you applications. You can easily create
voice-controlled applications (called Alexa skills) or just voice
interface for your current products or anything you like! Tools provided
by Amazon web services (AWS) are easy to use and if used correctly, then
completely free. Once skill is done, it’s just a matter of minutes to
deploy it as high-available, auto-scaled, serverless, globally
distributed application using AWS. Then you can use Amazon Alexa Skill
store to sell your product all over the world. I would like to show you
how it works, what AWS provides to developers and how can anybody create
Alexa skills using your favorite language – Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building smarter solutions with Machine Learning, from magic to reality</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/building-smarter-solutions-with-machine-learning-from-magic-to-reality.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Laurent Picard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/building-smarter-solutions-with-machine-learning-from-magic-to-reality.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic.”
Well, Machine Learning can look like magic, but you don't need to be a
data scientist or an ML researcher to develop with ML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what about making your solution smarter without any knowledge in AI?
With pre-trained models and a few lines of code, Machine Learning APIs
can analyze your data. Moreover, AutoML techniques can now help in
getting even more specific insights tailored to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, you'll see how to transform or extract information from
text, image, audio &amp;amp; video with the latest ML APIs, how to train an
AutoML custom model, and you'll be an active player of a live demo.
Don't put your smartphone in airplane mode!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Gotchas and landmines in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/gotchas-and-landmines-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Manoj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/gotchas-and-landmines-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python may be one of the simplest and most flexible programming
languages out there, but it is still a programming language. It still
has syntax, datatypes, and some occasional dark corners. Python “warts”
are things for which people have criticised Python, typically aspects of
the language or mechanisms of its implementation, because such aspects
either expose certain surprising inconsistencies, are regarded as
omissions, or cause irritation for parts of the community in some sense.
This talk will be about common pitfalls (termed warts/landmines) that
people face using Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only pre-requisite is a basic familiarity with Python programming
language. Although it’ll be good that you have laptops with Python
already setup, it’s not required as such !&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I Don't Care About Security (And Neither Should You)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/i-dont-care-about-security-and-neither-should-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joel Lord</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/i-dont-care-about-security-and-neither-should-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember when setting up a login page was easy? It seems like nowadays
it can take weeks to start a project -- creating a signup form, a login
form, a password recovery screen, and all the validation in between. And
you haven't even started on security considerations yet. During this
presentation, the attendees will be introduced to OpenID Connect and
OAuth. They will also learn how to leverage these technologies to create
more secure applications. Most importantly, they will learn how to
delegate authorization and authentication so they can focus on their
real work and forget about all that security stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides this talk Joel is planning a workshop on building a passwordless
authentication server.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Less Obvious Things To Do With Django's ORM.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/less-obvious-things-to-do-with-djangos-orm.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Markus Holtermann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/less-obvious-things-to-do-with-djangos-orm.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django’s ORM is powerful. And it has been for ages. It only became even
more powerful over the last years. Django’s ORM can be intimidating
because it can do so many things. And it can also be confusing when
trying to find out how to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Long term IT projects</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/long-term-it-projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paweł Lewtak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/long-term-it-projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not everybody has a chance to work on new project from scratch.
Everybody has some ideas what to do for such a project so it'll be a
good one instead of legacy in a near future. During this talk I want to
share my experience and show what works for me. I'll start from project
analysis and end on deployment and beyond. I want to discuss some common
mistakes and misconceptions and hopefully give you some ideas you could
use for your own project regardless of its size. With a bit of work
some/all could be applied to legacy projects as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Nenuťte uživatele přemýšlet</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/nenutte-uzivatele-premyslet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Světlana Hrabinová</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/nenutte-uzivatele-premyslet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Myšlenka Steva Kruga &amp;quot;Nenuťte uživatele přemýšlet&amp;quot; bude hlavní inspirací
pro příspěvek, který se bude věnovat pojmům jako je UX (user
experience), UI (user interface) a použitelnost. Smyslem je poukázat na
základní principy použitelnosti a návrhu uživatelského prožitku, které
pomohou navrhovat a vytvářet intuitivní a pochopitelné služby či
uživatelská rozhraní s cílem jít svým uživatelům naproti, tedy aby
uživatelé museli dělat pouze nezbytné kroky s vynaložením co nejmenšího
úsilí.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Nucleus: an open-source library for genomics data and machine learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/nucleus-an-open-source-library-for-genomics-data-and-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Helen Li</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/nucleus-an-open-source-library-for-genomics-data-and-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nucleus is a Python library designed to make it easy to read, write, and
analyze genomics data in common bioinformatics file formats such as SAM
and VCF. In addition, Nucleus enables seamless integration with the
TensorFlow machine learning (ML) framework. Nucleus is heavily used in
DeepVariant, a state-of-the-art convolutional neural network variant
caller, and in other ML projects at Google AI Genomics. This talk will
give an overview of Nucleus, its features, and its APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>On the Edge of Leadership</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/on-the-edge-of-leadership.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mislav Cimperšak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/on-the-edge-of-leadership.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to lead a dev team with zero personal experience in people
management while still having no idea how to manage even your own time.
After several years of fairly regular software developer career path,
I've found myself in a new role that I've unconsciously put myself into.
Being a solid senior developer, management at the time agreed that I am
a good candidate for the team lead. Being promoted to a new personal
level of incompetence I felt lost and confused in my new role, but made
a pact with myself to see this one through to the end. And so it came
that for the past few years, I've been development team lead for several
teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With zero formal training, relying on my intuition and various random
pieces of advice I picked up from people smarter than me I've more or
less successfully lead my teams to their goals. On that path, I've
learned tremendously, improved myself and hopefully, my teams. I would
like to share what worked and what didn't, my emotions, my regrets, and
my wins.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon SK 2019 - Aula Magna - Sobota</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aula-magna-sobota.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aula-magna-sobota.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon SK 2019 - Aula Minor - Sobota</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aula-minor-sobota.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aula-minor-sobota.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Robot Framework – univerzálny nástroj pre automatizované testovanie</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/robot-framework-univerzalny-nastroj-pre-automatizovane-testovanie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Radoslav Kokuľa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/robot-framework-univerzalny-nastroj-pre-automatizovane-testovanie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robot Framework je open-source framework naprogramovaný v jazyku Python
určený pre automatizáciu testov a podporu test-driven developmentu.
Kompatibilita s rôznymi operačnými systémami, jednoduchá inštalácia,
zrozumiteľná syntax vhodná aj pre ľudí bez programátorských zručnosti, s
možnosťou importovať vlastné Python knižnice a moduly, a tiež ľahkou
integráciou do CI/CD serverov (napr. Jenkins) sú jeho nesporné výhody.
Vďaka množstvu dostupných knižníc je možné využiť Robot Framework na
testovanie rôznych druhov aplikácii a zariadení s využitím širokej škály
rozhraní, protokolov a dátových typov. Poskytuje taktiež možnosti
paralelného vykonávania testov alebo spúšťanie testov na vzdialených
systémoch. Neoddeliteľnou súčasťou je aj automaticky generovaný report
vo formátoch html a xml, poskytujúci prehľadné informácie o trvaní,
použitých dátach a výsledku vykonávaných testov a aj jednotlivých
krokoch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Príspevok predstaví tento nástroj na konkrétnych príkladoch testov vo
formátoch pre keyword-driven, data-driven a behaviour-driven testing,
ako aj prácu so Seleniom a REST API rozhraním.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>So you want to be an Engineer?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/so-you-want-to-be-an-engineer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Honza Král</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/so-you-want-to-be-an-engineer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software Engineering is a new field, have we figured out all the ins and
outs of how best to work in it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a lot of people the technology field has always been a semi-magical
place where engineers use their arcane knowledge to tease the secrets
from the computer and unfortunately we have bought into this myth... Let
us examine what are some of the myths surrounding out field and which
aspects might actually be useful. Is SW engineering an art or just
another skill? Is talent required? Does it even matter? What about the
10X engineer...?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be sharing some insights that I have learned from trying to
answer these questions for myself, part based on research, part on
personal opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Testing network interactions in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/testing-network-interactions-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dmitry Dygalo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/testing-network-interactions-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many modern Python applications interact with 3rd parties over network
and packages like requests and aiohttp are incredibly popular nowadays.
It makes it essential to know how to test network interactions. It is
particularly important for microservices - to connect them you need to
do network calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk from most straightforward ad-hoc solutions to more
tunable and extensible ones. You’ll learn how to approach testing
network on different isolation levels in sync and async code, take away
ideas and practices how to use with popular Python tools like responses,
pook, VCR, and pytest.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>We run huge in-memory databases in GKE and we love it!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/we-run-huge-in-memory-databases-in-gke-and-we-love-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>František Benko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/we-run-huge-in-memory-databases-in-gke-and-we-love-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We invite You on the talk about our largest scale change in history of
Exponea. We'll show you how we managed to run multi-terrabyte sharded
in- memory DBs in the environment of ephemeral containers, hundreds of
python and go workers in multiple kubernetes namespaces and several
hundred VMs in google cloud. You don't want to miss our way of
automating this system too.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What's new in Python 3.7?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/whats-new-in-python-37.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stéphane Wirtel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:pycon-sk-2019/whats-new-in-python-37.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scheduled for release in mid-June before the conference, Python 3.7 is
shaping up to be a feature-packed release! This talk will cover all the
new features of Python 3.7, including the Data Classes and the Context
Variables for the asynchronous programming with asyncio.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Day Has Only 24±1 Hours</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/a-day-has-only-24-1-hours.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miroslav Šedivý</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/a-day-has-only-24-1-hours.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only will the Sunday in the week after this PyCon.SK 2019 be one
hour shorter, but also it may steal you even more sleep because of all
your Python code that has to work smoothly during daylight saving time
changes or otherwise manipulate time zones. While correct working with
datetime objects and offsets can be mastered, you have no control of the
information on local time zones. Exclusive domain of geographers one
hundred years ago, the time zones adjustments became a toy in the hands
of governments all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short overview of Pythons datetime and pytz libraries you'll
learn how the information on time zone changes gets into your system.
We'll fly quickly around the world's over five hundred time zones, but
will also focus on the case of Slovakia and surrounding countries. Two
centuries of propaganda and chaos in thirty minutes. Maybe that will
make you want to avoid time zones in your code altogether!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ako prestať kradnúť v štátnom IT?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/ako-prestat-kradnut-v-statnom-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriel Lachmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/ako-prestat-kradnut-v-statnom-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slovensko.Digital už vyše troch rokov zasahuje do veľkých štátnych IT
projektov a informatizácie verejnej správy ako takej. Dozviete sa či to
bolo na niečo vlastne dobré, čo sa bude diať v informatizácii ďalej, čo
s tým vie urobiť bežný programátor a IT komunita. Povieme Vám niečo
bližšie o eurofondovom projekte, ktorý nám schválili za Kaliňáka a ako
tieto peniaze využívame, aby sme robili zle zlodejom konštruktívne
vylepšovali štátne IT. Povieme aj pozitívne správy o témach ako Open API
či My Data, ktoré by mohli posunúť informatizáciu tak dopredu, že nám aj
Estónci budú závidieť. Keď všetko pôjde podľa plánu mali by sa toho
dožiť nielen naše budúce vnúčatá..&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ako sa ďalej pasujeme s Python na hodinách informatiky</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/ako-sa-dalej-pasujeme-s-python-na-hodinach-informatiky.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tomáš Dudík</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/ako-sa-dalej-pasujeme-s-python-na-hodinach-informatiky.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ako sa ďalej pasujeme s Python na hodinách informatiky&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Anvil: Full-stack Web Apps with Nothing but Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/anvil-full-stack-web-apps-with-nothing-but-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Meredydd Luff</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/anvil-full-stack-web-apps-with-nothing-but-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building for the modern web is complicated and error-prone: a typical
web app requires five different languages and four or five frameworks
just to get started. Wouldn't it be nicer if we could do it all in
Python? With Anvil, you can design your page visually, write your
browser-side and server-side code in pure Python, and even set up a
built-in database in seconds. In this talk, Meredydd will walk us
through how Anvil works under the bonnet, and the challenges of building
a programming system that's easy to use without sacrificing power.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Avoiding Macro Trouble of Micro Services</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/avoiding-macro-trouble-of-micro-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/avoiding-macro-trouble-of-micro-services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any change in software architecture is a significant time investment.
Writing microservices in Python is a joy, but when you decide on it,
there is often no way back. Therefore it is always an advantage to know
what to expect in advance, not just from inspiring blog posts but also
from the harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a bunch of smooth as well as tricky microservice migrations in
the past, I would like to share typical pitfalls of choosing a framework
stack, communication protocol, conventions, and deployment process — all
covered by real projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Be a good colleague and help your Security Engineer!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/be-a-good-colleague-and-help-your-security-engineer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Števko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/be-a-good-colleague-and-help-your-security-engineer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 was the year of GDPR. Security is a shared responsibility and has
become even more important than ever before. Nevertheless, not everybody
realizes this and security incidents and problems continue to occur,
thus resulting in catastrophical consequences for your business. In this
talk, I will be sharing how one can utilize best practices to deliver
less vulnerable code by using tools to prevent security holes, how to
handle incidents from the developers’ point of view and how you can
assist your Security Engineers. By following these guidelines, you will
make your Security Engineers happy and your code more secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Controling a robotic arm with micro:bits. How to make computer science education more interesting.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/controling-a-robotic-arm-with-microbits-how-to-make-computer-science-education-more-interesting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luke Spademan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/controling-a-robotic-arm-with-microbits-how-to-make-computer-science-education-more-interesting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Captivating a group of children for a sustained period of time is
notoriously hard. I will be exporing with you how the micro:bit can be
used to engage a young audience with interactive demos and programming
activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children love to physically interact with hardware. That is what is
great about the micro:bit. It not only has built in LEDs and buttons but
can also control bigger more exciting electronics like robotic arms.
This allows for setup that gives students of all ability levels a
challenge. Students that are beginners to programming can be given a
more complete program or walk throught a worksheet that takes them
through the process of controling the device (in this case a robotic
arm) step by step. Students that have higher programming skills can be
given a more bare bones / boilerplate source file and can write code to
control the arm with less guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>EduSummit 2019 Aftermovie - PyCon SK</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/edusummit-2019-aftermovie-pycon-sk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/edusummit-2019-aftermovie-pycon-sk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EduSummit 2019 Aftermovie - PyCon SK&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>GitHub Bots: Rise of the Machines 🤖</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/github-bots-rise-of-the-machines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sviatoslav Sydorenko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/github-bots-rise-of-the-machines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, fellow human!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably spend too much time regretting that manual recurring
routines don't do themselves. Let's change this! This workshop will
empower you to automate all the things using GitHub Apps integration
type as reusable restless workers helping you overcome typical
maintainer frustrations. We'll have a walkthrough of the complete
application creation and deployment process: from creating an App entity
in the GitHub UI, to actual coding and to shipping your code via Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To participate in the hands-on, bring your laptop with Python 3.7 and
some editor on-board. You'll also need to have a GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/features/actions/signup"&gt;sign up for GitHub
Actions&lt;/a&gt; as early as
possible to try it out on the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Inovácie v meste Bratislava</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/inovacie-v-meste-bratislava.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Petra Dzurovcinova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/inovacie-v-meste-bratislava.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Čo všetko robíme v Bratislave pre inovácie a ako môžete byť súčasťou
tohto procesu?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Let's talk about MLOps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/lets-talk-about-mlops.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Barra</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/lets-talk-about-mlops.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quantity of hype around machine learning and AI is probably second
only to bitcoins and blockchains. But until a machine learning model is
deployed to production the value delivered to companies is approximately
equal to zero. Together with the common mantra that data science can't
use agile/lean frameworks or that the best software engineering
practises don't apply explains a lot about why often companies got burnt
with their data science projects and why generally they under delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLOps is here to help, the machine-learning equivalent of DevOps: it
solves the problems of implementing machine-learning in production.
During this talk I will introduce the data science lifecycle, the
concept of machine learning Ops, its characteristics, why is extremely
required, how it compares to DevOps, how it will become a required
capabilities for any DS/ML/AI Team, tools available and how you can
start with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk is a very short presentation lasting only a few minutes, given at a conference or similar forum. Several lightning talks will usually be delivered by different speakers in a single session.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning Democratization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/machine-learning-democratization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jorge Torres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/machine-learning-democratization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can't expect Machine Learning experts to be both domain experts
across various fields and also true experts in ML, it is crucial to
rethink how we build tools so that we can provide Machine Learning
capabilities to experts in various disciplines that are not necessarily
savvy in machine learning, but are experts in their own domains, so that
they can too become participants of the data science community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is divided into three sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one, dives into the importance of democratizing Machine
Learning, its objective is to demonstrate why now this is a crucial
issue to be solved and to show the risks and problems that present
themselves when Machine Learning Engineers take in the responsibility of
building predictive technologies in domains that are not necessarily
where they are the most experts on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of this talk focuses on some solutions and approaches to
challenges of democratizing Machine Learning, as well as the journey and
results we have seen at MindsDB while at this endeavor as well as what
would be new ways that the ML community can think of the next generation
of tools being built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and most extensive section of this talk, focuses on the new
issues that are born once machine Learning capabilities are on the hands
of not ML experts, more importantly, the implications of delegating the
Machine Learning machinery to a system, and what is important in order
to trust those systems. Which leads to the importance in further
developing our understanding of explainability, interpretability, and
robustness of ML.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Objavovanie VPythonu v Dudley College</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/objavovanie-vpythonu-v-dudley-college.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miroslava Šturmová</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/objavovanie-vpythonu-v-dudley-college.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;V marci 2017 dostali žiaci Strednej priemyselnej školy technickej v
Martine (SPŠT) prvýkrát príležitosť absolvovať prax v Dudley College vo
Veľkej Británii. Vďaka úspešnému projektu Erasmus+ „Turiec do Európy,
Európa do Turca“, ktorý pripravila K. A. B. A. Slovensko, sa tu
zoznámili s programovacím jazykom Python. Projekt bol úspešný aj v
školskom roku 2017/2018. Dudley College sa tak stala na dva marcové
týždne školou pre desiatich tretiakov technického lýcea SPŠT. Odborný
program bol zameraný na tvorbu efektívnych algoritmov, rozvoj logického
myslenia, grafiku a nástroj pre vytváranie 3D animácií v reálnom čase -
VPython. Svoje nadobudnuté vedomosti a praktické zručnosti odovzdali
účastníci mobility aj ďalej. Učitelia informatiky SPŠT a Gymnázia
Viliama Paulínyho Tótha (GVPT) v Martine nadviazali na úspešnú
spoluprácu z minulého roka, opäť spojili svoje sily a pripravili druhý
ročník odbornej konferencie PYTHON DAYS 2.0. V dňoch 31.5 - 1.6.2018
odzneli na GVPT zaujímavé prednášky, robilo sa veľa workshopov. Na
jednom z nich sme predstavili gymnazistom VPython a vývojové prostredie
GlowScript. Výstupy z mobility Erasmus+ tak neostali len doma, na SPŠT,
ale nadobudli oveľa širší rozmer. Na konferencii PyCON SK 2019
predstavíme toto prostredie, jeho nástroje a ukážeme práce, ktoré sme
vytvorili.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Odoo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/odoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Šedinár</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/odoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Odoo na Slovensku - game changer slovenského ERP prostredia. Chceme vám
povedať a ukázať, čo je Odoo, ako funguje, prečo je lepšie ako iné
riešenia. Ako je zameraný, aká je architektúra riešenia...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Prechod na Python u Piaristov v Nitre a niektoré tamojšie študentské projekty</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/prechod-na-python-u-piaristov-v-nitre-a-niektore-tamojsie-studentske-projekty.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Valachovič</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/prechod-na-python-u-piaristov-v-nitre-a-niektore-tamojsie-studentske-projekty.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Krátko sa podelíme o tom ako sa vyvíja prechod na Python z pascalu
(Delphi/Lazarus), čo sa nám podarilo, a aké výzvy pred nami sme
identifikovali konkrétne by sme chceli hovoriť o tom ako postupujeme pri
vývoji kurzu pripravujúceho na maturitu z informatiky kedy použijeme
programovací jazyk python vo verzii 3.X. Predstavíme projekt študentskej
učebnice pre základný kurz Pythonu - od študenta pre študentov a
študentský projekt vylepšenia zvonení na škole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pri predstavovaní študentskej učebnice bude Tomáš Kiss hovoriť o
motivácii pre túto učebnicu a spôsobe akým ju realizuje. Tiež by chcel
predostrieť výzvy, ktoré identifikuje a tiež spôsob ako budú môcť
ostatní učebnicu získať.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pri projekte o vylepšení zvonení na škole opíše Jakub stav, aký bol na
škole predtým a popíše motiváciu k zlepšeniu ako aj realizovaný systém.
Chcel by tiež poukázať na možnosti a úskalia, ktoré sa pri vývoji
zvonení vyskytli.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Programovanie s LOGO-filozofiou ako model všeobecného vzdelávania pre všetky odbory</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/programovanie-s-logo-filozofiou-ako-model-vseobecneho-vzdelavania-pre-vsetky-odbory.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juraj Hromkovič</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/programovanie-s-logo-filozofiou-ako-model-vseobecneho-vzdelavania-pre-vsetky-odbory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean Piaget prišiel s konceptom &amp;quot;learning by doing&amp;quot; s cieľom zvýšiť motiváciu a trvanlivosť vedomostí a prehĺbiť chápanie študovaných objektov vďaka vlastnej aktivite v procese učenia sa. Seymour Papert obohatil tento koncept o &amp;quot;getting things to work&amp;quot; vo svojej implementácii výučby programovania v programovacom jazyku LOGO. My sme na ETH skombinovali tento prístup s konceptom &amp;quot;critical thinking&amp;quot;, ktorý odmieta vyučovať hotové produkty vedy (fakty, modely, metódy,...), ale vyžaduje si učiť procesy ich vytvárania. Pre prípravu vzdelávania tisícky učiteľov základných a stredných škôl pre výučbu programovania, sme vyvinuli v rámci týchto výučbových konceptov prostredia na výučbu programovania, ako aj iných informatických tém a napísali k nim sériu učebníc. V tejto prednáške sa budeme venovať prostrediam TigerJython (dialekt Pythonu) a viacerým verziám jazyka LOGO (textovým i blokovým) a vysvetlíme proces ich tvorby z pohľadu potrieb výučby programovania. Predstavíme aj informatiku ako viac než 5000 rokov starú vedu a ozrejmíme jej prínos pre všeobecné vzdelanie a jej nenahraditeľnosť vo vzdelávaní budúcich generácii.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Programujeme v Pythone na strednej škole</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/programujeme-v-pythone-na-strednej-skole.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Kučera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/programujeme-v-pythone-na-strednej-skole.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rozmýšľate, čo vyučovať na seminári z programovania, ak chcete svojich
študentov naučiť ešte viac? Základnú a maturitnú úroveň programovania,
ktorú sme predstavili v minulosti, sme rozšírili o ďalšie zaujímavé
témy. V príspevku vám predstavíme, čo učíme na seminároch z
programovania. Ukážeme vám, ktorým témam sa venujeme, ako sme ich
spracovali, ktorý kontext úloh sa nám osvedčil v praxi. Tiež vám
predstavíme kompletné materiály na strednú školu. Ako aktivizovať
študentov? Aké programy vedia vytvoriť a ako tvoria seminárne práce z
programovania? Aj týmto otázkam sa budeme venovať v našom príspevku.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon SK 2019 Aftermovie</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aftermovie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-aftermovie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon SK 2019 in 2 minutes...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon SK 2019 - Edutalks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-edutalks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Various speakers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-edutalks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon SK 2019 - Edutalks&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon SK 2019 piatok - Aula Minor (Aula Minor)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-piatok-aula-minor-aula-minor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/pycon-sk-2019-piatok-aula-minor-aula-minor.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Stability with a Hockey-stick</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/stability-with-a-hockey-stick.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Filip Štefaňák</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/stability-with-a-hockey-stick.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Make fast and break things&amp;quot; used to be a popular motto at Facebook, but
at some point it needed to change. How can a fast-growing SaaS company
like Exponea handle the ever increasing need for service stability? We
will take a quick look at all the bazillion things that must be done,
panic, and talk about how they can actually be done.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Python in new space industry is not a rocket science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/using-python-in-new-space-industry-is-not-a-rocket-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Balas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/using-python-in-new-space-industry-is-not-a-rocket-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we do at Iceye and how Python is allowing us to grow fast and be
unique.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Výučba programovania pomocou tvorby hier v PyGame Zero</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/vyucba-programovania-pomocou-tvorby-hier-v-pygame-zero.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miroslav Biňas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/vyucba-programovania-pomocou-tvorby-hier-v-pygame-zero.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Výučba programovania pomocou tvorby hier v PyGame Zero&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Your flight ticket is just the tip of the iceberg!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/your-flight-ticket-is-just-the-tip-of-the-iceberg.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Martin Strýček</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/your-flight-ticket-is-just-the-tip-of-the-iceberg.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your flight ticket is just the tip of the iceberg!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>