<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/event_pycon-taiwan-2019.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Async Context Manager for Python 3.7</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/async-context-manager-for-python-37.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sammy Wen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/async-context-manager-for-python-37.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R1 13:00–13:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.7針對asyncio做了不少的改動，也是Python進化為3.7版的重要改動項目。這一次的講題想要帶大家認識在Python 3.7成為內建功能的asynccontextmanager。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在學習程式語言的最初階段，我們常常會使用到with語法，確保開啟的資源在使用完之後有確實被關閉或釋放；這在Python的世界裡，我們稱之為contextmanager。而Python 3.7也針對實作contextmanager的函式庫 -- contextlib，做了一些改動，使其支援「async with」這樣的語法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本次的演講將藉由探討asynccontextmanager的實作與應用，以及它和一般contextmanager的不同之處，讓聽眾了解Python 3.7對於非同步的重視。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gamekingga.com/pycontw2019.pdf"&gt;https://gamekingga.com/pycontw2019.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sammy Wen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently working at Sinitic Inc as a Senior Backend Engineer while studying in the University of Waterloo as a ECE graduate student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is awesome. It helps me earn a living.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Automate the Boring Stuff with Slackbot</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/automate-the-boring-stuff-with-slackbot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Takanori Suzuki</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/automate-the-boring-stuff-with-slackbot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R2 11:30–12:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, there are many tasks to repeat in the company/community.
In addition, we often use chat such as Slack for daily communication.
So, I created a chatbot([PyCon JP Bot](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pyconjp/pyconjpbot"&gt;https://github.com/pyconjp/pyconjpbot&lt;/a&gt;)) to automate various boring tasks related to holding PyCon JP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will first explain how to create a chatbot using [slackbot](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/lins05/slackbot"&gt;https://github.com/lins05/slackbot&lt;/a&gt;).
I will tell you how to registers bot's integration on Slack and how to create a simple bot in Python that responds to specific keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as a specific case, I will explain how to make a bot command to perform the following operations and technical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emoji reaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculator: SymPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karma(plusplus): Peewee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search issues, display issue details: JIRA API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create multiple issues from a template: JIRA API, Sheets Spreadsheet API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search files from Google Drive: Google Drive API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account management of G Suite(user, alias, group and member): G Suite API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitpitch.com/takanory/slides?p=20190922pycontw#/"&gt;https://gitpitch.com/takanory/slides?p=20190922pycontw#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Takanori Suzuki&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takanori is a Vice Chairperson of PyCon JP Committee(www.pycon.jp).
He is also a director of BeProud Inc.(www.beproud.jp), and his title is &amp;quot;Python Climber&amp;quot;.
Takanori held PyCon JP 2014 to 2016 as the chairperson.
Currently he teaches Python to beginners as a lecturer at Python Boot Camp(pycamp.pycon.jp) all over Japan.
In addition, he published several Python books.
Tananori plays trumpet, climbs boulder, loves Lego, ferrets and beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Doujin Activity in Japan with Ren’Py</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/doujin-activity-in-japan-with-renpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daisuke Saito</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/doujin-activity-in-japan-with-renpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R2 13:00–13:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using Ren'Py for eight years in Doujin activities. Ren'Py is Python based visual novel game engine. In the past eight years, I felt many benefits using Ren'Py. This talk demonstrates the benefits of using it. The author also describes how Ren'Py evolved from the user's point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Daisuke Saito&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daisuke Saito is a assistant professor of the School of Fundamental Science and Engineering, Waseda University in Japan. He acquired a Doctor of Engineering degree from Waseda University in Japan. His research interests include programming education and digital game-based learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>GraphQL with Graphene and Django, Laughters and Tears</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/graphql-with-graphene-and-django-laughters-and-tears.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Keith Yang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/graphql-with-graphene-and-django-laughters-and-tears.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R1 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;這不是教學。我希望為曾經使用過 web API 的人，不論是哪一種 API，都能帶來一些啟發，以及微笑。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我會先簡述一下過往用 Python 寫裸 API，到 REST API，到目前 GraphQL 的心路歷程，再展示 iCHEF 在 GraphQL 的《&lt;strong&gt;三&lt;/strong&gt;》代演進，以及一些後見之明，為來者鋪路。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;聽完應該會對 GraphQL 在 web 前後端與 mobile 的應用場景有更多的掌握，在 API 的設計與使用多一些他山之石，以及用 Graphene 與 Django 實作 GraphQL schema 時能預想到一些細節與工具。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's NOT a tutorial. Hoping it can bring some delights to people who ever used Python to call the web API, whatever kind that API is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will brief my experience of writing Python from raw API, REST API, to current GraphQL API. &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; generations of iCHEF GraphQL will be demonstrated to pave the road of followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should bring more understanding of GraphQL interaction between web frontend, backend, and mobile clients, more examples of API design &amp;amp; usage, and details of GraphQL schema implement in Graphene &amp;amp; Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Keith Yang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最近覺得邊騎室內腳踏車邊用電腦，離開臉書與 IG 的精神（神經？）生活很不賴。讓這隻小白鼠從大眾心理控制實驗學裡喘了一小口氣。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently he enjoys skateboard commute, still coffee-achemy, and indoor cycle while programming or gaming, an awesome mind vocation of leaving FB and IG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith is the founder and co-organizer of Taipei.py, largest Python user group in Taiwan, a Lead Software Engineer at iCHEF, and was Chairperson of PyCon APAC 2015. His work mostly focuses on web/backend/cloud services since 2006, and he hands on kernel tools of virtualization on hypervisors in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Artificial Intelligence in Finance</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-artificial-intelligence-in-finance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yves J Hilpisch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-artificial-intelligence-in-finance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, 09:25–10:25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programmatic availability of basically any kind of (financial) data has reshaped finance from a theory-driven to a data-driven discipline. Recent advances in AI in combination with the programmatic availability of (financial) data with further change finance to an AI-first discipline. The talk discusses several important aspects in this regard and provides concrete examples in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yves J Hilpisch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch is founder and managing partner of The Python Quants (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tpq.io"&gt;http://tpq.io&lt;/a&gt;), a group focusing on the use of open source technologies for financial data science, artificial intelligence, algorithmic trading, and computational finance. He is also founder and CEO of The AI Machine (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aimachine.io"&gt;http://aimachine.io&lt;/a&gt;), a company focused on AI-powered algorithmic trading based a proprietary strategy execution platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yves has a Diploma in Business Administration, a Ph.D. in mathematical finance and is Adjunct Professor for Computational Finance at Miami Business School (University of Miami). He is the author of four books (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://books.tpq.io"&gt;http://books.tpq.io&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial Intelligence in Finance (O’Reilly, current project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python for Finance (2018, 2nd ed., O’Reilly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listed Volatility and Variance Derivatives (2017, Wiley Finance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivatives Analytics with Python (2015, Wiley Finance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yves is the director of the first online training program leading to a University Certificates in Python for Algorithmic Trading (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://certificate.tpq.io"&gt;http://certificate.tpq.io&lt;/a&gt;) and Computational Finance (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://compfinance.tpq.io"&gt;http://compfinance.tpq.io&lt;/a&gt;). He also lectures on computational finance, machine learning and algorithmic trading at the CQF Program (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cqf.com"&gt;http://cqf.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yves is the main author of the financial analytics library DX Analytics (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dx-analytics.com"&gt;http://dx-analytics.com&lt;/a&gt;) and organizes meetups, conferences, and bootcamps about Python, artificial intelligence and algorithmic trading in London (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pqf.tpq.io"&gt;http://pqf.tpq.io&lt;/a&gt;), New York (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aifat.tpq.io"&gt;http://aifat.tpq.io&lt;/a&gt;), Frankfurt, Berlin and Paris. He has given keynote speeches at technology conferences in the United States, Europe, and Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: The Different Paths We Take as Programmers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-the-different-paths-we-take-as-programmers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tracy Osborn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-the-different-paths-we-take-as-programmers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, 15:10–16:10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone who learns Python is using it to become a back-end programmer. In this keynote, Tracy will cover her process on how she learned how to program and how she uses Python and programming in her current work, as well as why programming education can (and should) change considering all the ways we can use Python and programming in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tracy Osborn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracy Osborn is a programmer, designer, author, and entrepreneur. In 2010, she taught herself Python to launch her first startup, which lead to writing Hello Web App, a book teaching introductory Django web app development. She’s also the Program Manager at TinySeed, an accelerator program for bootstrapped businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks, Day 3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/lightning-talks-day-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/lightning-talks-day-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, 16:10–16:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;陳柏宇 - Gogoro 熱度圖的前世今生&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jaysinh Shukla - Server-sent-events (SSE) Using Django Channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James - 搬家日記&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sebastian Witowski - Productivity Tricks for Developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deimos - 自己要的素材自己做&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>你到底匯還是不匯？（當爬蟲遇上外匯…）– PyCon Taiwan 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/ni-dao-di-hui-huan-shi-bu-hui-dang-pa-chong-yu-shang-wai-hui-pycon-taiwan-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kilik Kuo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/ni-dao-di-hui-huan-shi-bu-hui-dang-pa-chong-yu-shang-wai-hui-pycon-taiwan-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R0 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;介紹外匯與其市場, 以及匯率在金融科技公司裡扮演的角色.
日常工作中, 金融交易操作者(Treasury)必須隨時監控來自多管道的資訊 透過低買高賣與遠期交易等操作將公司財務風險分擔. 今日這些資訊多數已可依靠專業軟體的輔助來獲得, 如彭博(Bloomberg), 路透(Thomson Reuters)等大型企業有能力整合來自各國權威機構或一線銀行,企業的消息, 但新創公司所面向的客戶並不全然屬於此類機構, 多數的合作對象更可能是偏向在地性質的二三線銀行, 或技術能力有相對落差的在地金融服務供應商. 此時便有機會利用 Python 程式自動化將這些對象的資訊整合, 進而強化內部企業效率.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Kilik Kuo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;改變自己先, 影響世界後.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kilik-kuo-3923a454/"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kilik-kuo-3923a454/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python and SQLs: How I Create Universal SQL CLI Client using PEP 249 standards</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/python-and-sqls-how-i-create-universal-sql-cli-client-using-pep-249-standards.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ing Wei Tang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/python-and-sqls-how-i-create-universal-sql-cli-client-using-pep-249-standards.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R2 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SQL client is ubiquitous and impossible for developers not to have one in their toolbag. However potentially there is a unforeseen situation that the developers are forbid to use SQL client to access the cloud/on-premise SQL DB. This proposal primarily addresses the issue of such scenario and provides a solution based on the hacker's mindset. In this proposal, the author will show how he tackles this pain point in his workplace, by creating a universal SQL client CLI that allows him to connect to the SQL DB in his DB cluster, hence extends this project to other SQL DB using the API standardization in PEP 249. Apart from integrating all the SQL connectors, the author also implemented standardize hotkey for all the SQL DB, by studying the internal core of the SQL standards, and retrieving SQL metadata using pure SQL queries through the hotkeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ing Wei Tang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ing Wei is the chair for PyCon MY 2019, the co-chair of PyCon MY 2018, and vice president of MyPOP. He has spoken in various PyCons, particularly in PyCon APAC 2018, as well as involving in PyCon communities actively in Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses python a lot in his daily work, especially coding the automation process and flow. During his past time, he likes to experience and perform hacking different things on operating system level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from programming language, he can also speak 5 different types of languages concurrently in one sentence. Please ask for demo if time permits.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Wait, IPython Can Do That?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/wait-ipython-can-do-that.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sebastian Witowski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/wait-ipython-can-do-that.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R0 11:30–12:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using IPython since the beginning of my adventure with Python. Over the years, I've picked up more and more tricks that it could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I would like to share some of them with you:
- Documentation with ? and ??, running shell functions in IPython, magic functions
- Profiles, startup files, configuration file, kernels, and extensions
- How to better use IPython for debugging
- How to use IPython for profiling
- Alternatives to IPython REPL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://switowski.com/python/ipython/slides/2019/07/07/wait-ipython-can-do-that.html"&gt;https://switowski.com/python/ipython/slides/2019/07/07/wait-ipython-can-do-that.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sebastian Witowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a software engineer with 7 years of experience in full stack development, operations and leading small projects.
I had worked as a DevOps at CERN for the past 6 years, but recently I have decided to move to Python consulting and trainings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I like to give talks about Python, coding and productivity. Python is my main programming language, but I don't shy away from using different languages as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>用 Python 拉近群眾與星空的距離：Astrohackers in Taiwan 社群介紹</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/yong-python-la-jin-qun-zhong-yu-xing-kong-de-ju-li-astrohackers-in-taiwan-she-qun-jie-shao.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>蘇羿豪</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/yong-python-la-jin-qun-zhong-yu-xing-kong-de-ju-li-astrohackers-in-taiwan-she-qun-jie-shao.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R0 13:00–13:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每當黑蛋仰望星空，他總幻想能伸手捕獲星星來一探其奧秘，但即便看了科普書籍及最新天文研究的新聞報導，他仍覺得離星空好遠。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;某天，黑蛋在搜尋引擎輸入&amp;quot;開放天文資料&amp;quot;，發現一個以遊戲的方式來引導玩家使用開放天文資料的網站，他就此進入了精神時光屋。在他完成「以爬說語指引蛇蛇吃星星」的任務後，收到一則來自Astrohackers-TW的訊息:
「哈囉，這是Astrohackers-TW對等級0的天文黑客們的呼召，我們在尋找潛在的天文黑客，與我們一同對抗試圖把天文資源佔為私有的邪惡勢力。接受呼召前來參加天文黑客松的成員們，將一同合作創造出有助於天文教育與研究的開源軟硬體，成為推動全民共享及再創造天文知識的一份子。以下是天文黑客松的報名資訊...」黑蛋受到感召，前往參加天文黑客松，於是黑蛋破殼了，成為等級1的天文黑客，並藉由一次又一次地協作開源天文專案，在公民天文學家之路上，持續升級。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;這是關於Astrohackers in Taiwan社群的現在及未來式...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;astrobackhacker/ByWuFL1DB#/"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;astrobackhacker/ByWuFL1DB#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 蘇羿豪&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公民天文學家/Astrohackers in Taiwan的共同創辦人/承接網站開發及資料科學相關案子的遠距工作者&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>BI 前的悲哀—那些 User 所謂的 Big(?) Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/bi-qian-de-bei-ai-na-xie-user-suo-wei-de-big-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>高振倫</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/bi-qian-de-bei-ai-na-xie-user-suo-wei-de-big-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R1 16:15–16:45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;近年來Machine Learning及Big Data相關議題襲捲於世界各地，坊間研討會、速成課程四起，台灣工商業圈也不落人後，大舉徵用相關人才，意圖導入BI (Business Intelligence)的概念，利用資料的收集與整理，規劃產生Data Model，並輔以企業的Domain know-how來進行資料分析，最後實作出加值應用或自動化決策系統。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本演講以BI前期的ETL (Extract-Load-Transform)階段為主軸，以企業中的異質(Heterogeneous)環境和非結構化資料(Unstructured Data)的收集與整理來貫穿主題，講述身為Data Engineer如何在User們對AI的天馬行空中感到哀怨，這些哀怨又與Python交織出怎樣的愛恨情仇，讓我們看下去！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bingroom/PyConTW2019/blob/master/slides.pdf"&gt;https://github.com/bingroom/PyConTW2019/blob/master/slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 高振倫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bingroom，迷途中的一個Python小書僮，由於之前Crawler寫太多，現在都在寫Parser還債。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building Data Pipelines on Apache NiFi with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/building-data-pipelines-on-apache-nifi-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shuhsi Lin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/building-data-pipelines-on-apache-nifi-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R0 13:15–14:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today's big data world, the data you need to analyze comes from diverse sources in a variety of different formats. Combining all that data and reconciling it is incredibly difficult. Based on your need, adopting a proper and manageable ETL tool can make data integration easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An open source project, Apache NiFi, is a tool to built to automate and manage the flow of data between systems. You can use NiFi to build streaming data pipelines between different data-related systems, including Apache Kafka and Apache Spark, various RDBS, and so much more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will start with introducing a concept of ETL and Apache NiFi, what it can solve, and how to use Python to enable NiFi's ability. Then, a sample demo will help you to understand how to build a streaming data pipeline with NiFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/sucitw/building-data-pipelines-on-apache-nifi-with-python"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/sucitw/building-data-pipelines-on-apache-nifi-with-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Shuhsi Lin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A data engineer and python programmer. Currently working on various data applications in a manufacturing company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research interests: IoT applications, data streaming processing, data analysis and data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Data Visualization and Machine Learning — Using Python Modules to Solve Phylogen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/data-visualization-and-machine-learning-using-python-modules-to-solve-phylogen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liting Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/data-visualization-and-machine-learning-using-python-modules-to-solve-phylogen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R2 16:15–16:45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The genome in every cell contains enormous information on how the cell would behalf. The difference between each genome results in various phenotypes. In this talk, I would first showcase how did we use python modules to extract information across different single-cell genome sequencing information from sparse and erroneous raw data. Secondly, I would demo example graphs where Python module seaborn and matplotlib aid creating novel and informative representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Liting Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liting is a PhD student in the Netherlands. She has currently started to work on the application of machine learning algorithms to understanding diseases. Other than research, she enjoys nature, music, and sharing ideas with people.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Develop Numerical Software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/develop-numerical-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yung-Yu Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/develop-numerical-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R1 13:15–14:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerical software development is a unique subject.  On one hand, programming skills and computer science are indispensable for proper implementation.  On the other hand, the understandings to the scientific or engineering problems are the foundation of the software.  The fundamental knowledge is so important that the application experts, e.g., mathematicians and scientists, often become the best programmers.  However, it is difficult to train people for the multi-disciplinary skills.  This talk will discuss how Python makes the development and training manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/yyc/develop-numerical-software-pycontw-2019"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/yyc/develop-numerical-software-pycontw-2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yung-Yu Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HPC software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Draw Me Like One of Your French Girls — Generative Models in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/draw-me-like-one-of-your-french-girls-generative-models-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Prakhar Srivastava</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/draw-me-like-one-of-your-french-girls-generative-models-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R0 11:45–12:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tl; Dr Generative models are making all the big headlines, understand what, how and most importantly why behind these esoteric algorithms. How can you start building one and why are these models the dark horse of artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yann LeCun, the man behind Convolution Neural Networks and the frontier of computer vision research, proclaimed that the future of artificial intelligence lies in unsupervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are Generative models? These are the machine learning models that can learn the hidden representation of a given dataset and then can extrapolate an accurate data point given certain conditions. If all that was jargon for you - here's a better intuitive understanding, imagine if you were given a white canvas to paint a picture of a bird, what would you do? First, you would imagine a bird and then fill in the colors. Well, Generative models do the same thing! Just with a lot of mathematics and sweet python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Prakhar Srivastava&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings to everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm Prakhar Srivastava, researcher, open source lover, and a student. I have worked on Deep learning models for 3 years now and mentor the deeplearning.ai course on Coursera. I've researched with India's leading research college, IIIT Delhi (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://midas.iiitd.edu.in/team/prakhar.html"&gt;http://midas.iiitd.edu.in/team/prakhar.html&lt;/a&gt;). I've worked as a student developer in GSoC'18 under OpenAstronomy and as a team leader at Stanford Scholar initiative. I've hosted complete lecture sessions on Deep learning in my college under IEEE. I'm currently working as a Machine learning and research intern at SocialCops, one of India's leading startups.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting Started with Sparse Modeling Using spm-image</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/getting-started-with-sparse-modeling-using-spm-image.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Takashi Someda</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/getting-started-with-sparse-modeling-using-spm-image.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R2 11:45–12:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackbox problem has been becoming a popular concern when applying machine learning in specific applications, like medical system, where a user is supposed to understand the behavior of the system. Collecting tons of data for training machine learning model is another headache especially when you newly create a system from scratch. In this talk, I introduce the data analysis approach called &amp;quot;Sparse Modeling&amp;quot; that can produce good results, even if the amount of data is small. Event Horizon Telescope project, capturing blackhole image, is one good example of this nature. It's also referred to as explainable since it can tell you which input features have a strong impact to result generated by a machine learning model. With the overview of the method, I'll show concrete code examples for common use cases like image analysis, using a Python library named spm-image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/hacarus/getting-started-with-sparse-modeling-with-spm-image"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/hacarus/getting-started-with-sparse-modeling-with-spm-image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Takashi Someda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting his master’s degree in informatics at Graduate School of Kyoto University, he started his job at Sun Microsystems as an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For about 20 years in the software industry, he has experienced several roles like software developer, technical evangelist, and data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as CTO of Hacarus, he is responsible for technical direction with strong passion toward building a creative, self-organized team like Pixer.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Deep Probabilistic Programming with Pyro</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/introduction-to-deep-probabilistic-programming-with-pyro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>柯維然</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/introduction-to-deep-probabilistic-programming-with-pyro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R0 14:10–14:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本講題將介紹深度機率語言(Deep Probabilistic Programming)的核心概念與特性，並分享如何使用Pyro來體驗深度機率語言有趣與強大之處。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyro為基於Pytorch之上所開發的深度機率語言(Deep Probabilistic Programming)，能建立複雜機率模型並使用隨機變分估計(Stochastic Variational Inference)方法於GPU上進行大規模訓練，本講題會分享實作文本分析LDA模型、變分自編碼器VAE心得。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qOIqK5MmE-b43yTYgQL7b7Opu-AmkqGGCgmvgdHhqfg/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qOIqK5MmE-b43yTYgQL7b7Opu-AmkqGGCgmvgdHhqfg/edit?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 柯維然&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;穿上制服是個菜鳥警官，忙於勤務與警政工作；脫下制服是個熱愛用數據與程式解決問題的資料戰警；目前服務於新竹市警察局，並於交通大學資訊工程研究所攻讀博士班，主要研究方向為深度生成模型、機率模型等&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;技術部落格：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://odie2630463.github.io"&gt;https://odie2630463.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Programming Language Tourism: Leave Python and see the world!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-programming-language-tourism-leave-python-and-see-the-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Ivanov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-programming-language-tourism-leave-python-and-see-the-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 09:25–10:25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming languages are places. The idea of abandoning the convenience and familiarity of your primary coding language might seem anything from tedious and inconvenient to scary and stressful. But, switching to an alternative other than your primary development language -- especially when such a challenge is not a requirement -- can be both fun and productive. You will likely grow your abilities as a developer and gain new perspective that is currently beyond your reach.
Let's push out of our comfort zone together to leave Python and voyage to a different language! We will go into details about why and how we can do that, along with some possible destinations. Upon our return, we will see -- and appreciate -- Python in a different light. Plus, we can use the justifications for our departure to entice and welcome folks from other language communities to visit us in the land of the snake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pirsquared.org/talks/pycon_tw/"&gt;https://pirsquared.org/talks/pycon_tw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Paul Ivanov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Ivanov is a member of the Jupyter Steering Council and a senior software engineer at Bloomberg LP working on IPython- and Jupyter-related open source projects. Previously, Paul worked on backend and data engineering at Disqus; was a code monkey at the Brain Imaging Center at UC Berkeley, where he worked on IPython and taught at UC Berkeley’s Python bootcamps; worked in Bruno Olshausen’s lab at the Redwood Center for Theoretical Neuroscience; and was a PhD candidate in the Vision Science program at UC Berkeley. He holds a degree in computer science from UC Davis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>利用 Python 預測風力發電量</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/li-yong-python-yu-ce-feng-li-fa-dian-liang.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>陳律閎</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/li-yong-python-yu-ce-feng-li-fa-dian-liang.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R1 14:10–14:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;可再生能源（如風力、太陽能發電等）由於其在發電過程中不會產生任何污染的特性被視為乾淨能源，在環保意識高漲的現代設備備受期待，在歐美先進國家如德國、丹麥、美國加州等更意圖將可再生能源作為該國最主要的能源來源。然而可再生能源看天吃飯、不受控制的特性也為電網營運帶來新的挑戰。所幸由於氣象預報科技的進步，可再生能源發電量以可藉由氣象預報大致預測。本演講將以風力發電為例簡述目前可再生能源預測的發展現況，以及如何利用機器學習演算法預測未來數日的逐時風力發電曲線及未來數日風力發電的發電總量。我們會介紹如何以Python讀取相關數據(如NOAA的氣象預報資料等open data)，及如何以Tensorflow打造一個預測未來風力發電量的系統。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 陳律閎&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;中興大學統計所助理教授，曾開授資料科學方法、巨量資料分析、統計學習等課程。專長為結合領域知識提取特定用途之特徵以利後續統計與機器學習演算法分析與預測。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks, Day 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/lightning-talks-day-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/lightning-talks-day-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 16:55–17:25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;高中生&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foucault – Neuroimag Pipeline in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KK – 個人發起的小小小小小社群&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josef Monje – USB Hacking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victor – 高雄發大財&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lina – My PyCon diary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Practicing Statistics in Python: Hypothesis Testing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/practicing-statistics-in-python-hypothesis-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mosky Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/practicing-statistics-in-python-hypothesis-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R1 10:50–11:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在一個產品改動實驗裡，控制組與實驗組的平均分別是 169.61 與 169.88，這樣就說明了實驗組表現得比較好嗎？還是差異是來自隨機誤差呢？在這場演講，我們會介紹如何使用假設檢定對實驗結果進行判斷，而且是以 Python 的 SciPy 函數庫，最少僅需要一行程式碼，來介紹包含 p-value、α、β、effect size、sample size 等不可或缺的假設檢定必備知識。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/mosky/hypothesis-testing-with-python"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/mosky/hypothesis-testing-with-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Mosky Liu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mosky 是個熱愛 open source 精神的 Python 工程師，也是 Pinkoi 的 Python Charmer，工作時和同事一起打造能夠買到獨特禮物的設計品購物平台。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;自從寫下人生第一支程式後，就難以忘懷以敘述為磚、邏輯為泥，堆砌出腦中藍圖的成就感，也熱愛分享自己所學，業餘時是 Python 課程講師，偶爾講點資料科學。也是數場國內外研討會的講者，包含臺灣的 PyCon、COSCUP、TEDxNTUST，以及在日本、新加坡、香港、韓國、馬來西亞等地的 PyCon。More: mosky.tw 。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Probabilistic Programming Using TensorFlow Probability</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/probabilistic-programming-using-tensorflow-probability.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Niladri Shekhar Dutt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/probabilistic-programming-using-tensorflow-probability.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R2 14:10–14:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probabilistic programming allows us to encode domain knowledge to understand data and make predictions. TensorFlow Probability (TFP) is a Python library built on TensorFlow that makes it easy to combine probabilistic models and Deep Learning. With TensorFlow 2.0, TFP can be very easily integrated into your code with very few changes and the best part - it even works with tf.keras!
This talk will teach you when, why and how to use TensorFlow probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Niladri Shekhar Dutt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate Researcher working in the field of Deep Learning and its applications in the field of Computer Vision and NLP. He was a visiting student at the University of California, Berkeley for Spring 2019, where he worked at the CITRIS Lab. He has won several hackathons including San Francisco DeveloperWeek Hackathon 2019 (America’s largest challenge-driven hackathon). His current research focuses on self-driving cars and training machine learning models with limited data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Real-Time Automatic Accompaniment Implementation in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/real-time-automatic-accompaniment-implementation-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>范斯越 Szu-Yueh Fan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/real-time-automatic-accompaniment-implementation-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R0 10:50–11:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would it be if the computer could accompany human automatically?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatic accompaniment is a research topic which is proposed 35 years ago. Nowadays, this is still a very attractive topic. e.g. a musician plays the main melody of &amp;quot;Twinkle, Twinkle Little Star&amp;quot;; the computer performs the accompaniment part adapt for the musician's tempo. That is to say, the system must be able to &amp;quot;listen to&amp;quot; musician in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will share the topic background, problem definition, the approaches I tried, and show the accompaniment result with a performer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an entry-level session, everyone is welcome to attend. It will be better if you are interested in music tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 范斯越 Szu-Yueh Fan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szu-Yueh pursues theory and engineering balanced lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He embraces complexity and uncertainty that is why he likes the probabilistic model more than the deterministic model.
He loves to be a creator that is why the generative model is more interesting to him than the discriminative model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amateur book translator, tech+music enthusiast, cellist.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sim-to-Real：用物理引擎打造能虛實轉移的機器人</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/sim-to-realyong-wu-li-yin-qing-da-zao-neng-xu-shi-zhuan-yi-de-ji-qi-ren.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jiawei Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/sim-to-realyong-wu-li-yin-qing-da-zao-neng-xu-shi-zhuan-yi-de-ji-qi-ren.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R1 11:45–12:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;深度學習技術快速進步, 我們能訓練神經網路來控制實體機器人, 但訓練過程會發生各種突發狀況, 在物理安全與經濟狀況考慮下, 先在模擬環境完成訓練再轉移到真實機器人是一種解決方法。 但是模擬環境與真實環境有許多物理落差, 速度或摩擦力等各種物理因素, 都會導致訓練好的模型轉移到真實環境的效能低落。 去年 Google Brain 透過對物理引擎的模擬過程進行參數化與隨機擾動來解決問題, 我們也透過同樣方法完成二輪平衡車控制模型的虛實轉換, 這場分享將會介紹我們如何從無到有, 在物理引擎建立 車體3D模型, 並用 Python 參數化各種物理量, 最後展示完成的機器人可以做為訓練環境, 用來訓練神經網路控制模型。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jiawei Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLDM Monday與 Kaohsiung Python社群 Co-organizer, 目前在學術單位擔任研究人員，熱衷於研究機器學習相關技術，喜歡分享相關技術，並應用在實務工作上。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Art of Inference: Practicing Bayesian Reasoning in Computer Vision Problems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/the-art-of-inference-practicing-bayesian-reasoning-in-computer-vision-problems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yen-Hsun Lin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/the-art-of-inference-practicing-bayesian-reasoning-in-computer-vision-problems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R2 10:50–11:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayesian reasoning has a long standing history than frequentist since 18th century. In this talk, I'd like to present those fancy techniques appeared in many forensic movies and TV shows. Including the restorations of noisy and scratched images, deblur the unfocoused pictures...etc. These topics are no-doubt very active in the domain of computational photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will perform plenty of vivid examples on how to achieve these goals by Bayesian reasoning and Monte-Carlo simulations together with python practicing. Alternatively, such goals can be accomplished by modern convolutional neural network (CNN) as well. I will conduct a short comparison between the traditional and modern ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience does not require to have any specific knowledge on probability theory though basic calculus will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bit.ly/2kVEIrR"&gt;https://bit.ly/2kVEIrR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yen-Hsun Lin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a theoretical physicist that is enthusiastic in revealing the mystery of our resplendent Universe. Though people often considered math is a daunting task, I always found harmony and elegance behind it. Despite the constant debate on how should we proceed the understanding of nature epistemologically or ontologically, I believe that the essence of science lies in humanity itself instead of such philosophical conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My major research includes dark matter detection, astroparticle physics and computer simulations with some side projects on computational photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will join the Institute of Physics, Academia Sinica as a Distinguished Postdoctoral Scholar this August unless surprise happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Software Engineering Part of Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/the-software-engineering-part-of-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Niño R. Eclarin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/the-software-engineering-part-of-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R2 13:15–14:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science and software engineering is getting more and more intertwined with each other. But what is the common grounds between the two? How do we define the boundaries of the two disciplines? This talk will discuss the role of python in terms of development process for software engineers working in a data science environment. We will also tackle the different aspects of software engineering in relation to working with a data science oriented team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Xos0xRyDtXKPGQ2IkN5OaEDNHsJQTSPHukrMrmayGZ8"&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Xos0xRyDtXKPGQ2IkN5OaEDNHsJQTSPHukrMrmayGZ8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Niño R. Eclarin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I'm Ninz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a software engineer in the Philippines. I've worked with several startups in the past and currently working at Hacarus(focus on backend and machine learning integration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently taking my Masters degree in Computer Science here in the Philippines. My interests are Astronomy, Physics and Cooking :P&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Lucid to Visualize Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/using-lucid-to-visualize-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yufeng Guo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-21:pycon-taiwan-2019/using-lucid-to-visualize-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R0 16:15–16:45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural networks work in &amp;quot;mysterious ways&amp;quot;, but we can now peer into some of them to see how they work. This talk focuses on a tool called Lucid, from the TensorFlow team, and aims to show some interesting examples of different ways of visualizing neural networks with the goal of improving explainability. You will come away with a bit more understanding of how neural networks &amp;quot;learn&amp;quot;, and what aspects they are &amp;quot;looking&amp;quot; at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yufeng Guo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yufeng is a Developer Advocate focusing on Cloud AI, where he is working to make machine learning more understandable and usable for all.
He is the creator of the YouTube series AI Adventures, at yt.be/AIAdventures, exploring the art, science, and tools of machine learning.
He is enjoys hearing about new and interesting applications of machine learning, share your use case with him on Twitter &amp;#64;YufengG&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>async def Serial() await Serial_connection</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/async-def-serial-await-serial_connection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jason</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/async-def-serial-await-serial_connection.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R1 11:30–12:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;用 asyncio 建構一個多並行程式，例如搭配 aiohttp 撰寫網路爬蟲來提高效率是多數人最常使用 asyncio 的部分。但假使今天切換到硬體情境，想開發一支可以針對多個不同的 serail port 裝置讀與寫的程式，如何在裝置阻塞時切換？以及如何使用 asyncio 讓硬體溝通也能多並行？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;這場演講將分享作者使用 asyncio 強大的 low-level APIs (Transport 和 Protocol) 來建構非同步框架與函式庫，並利用它來開發應用程式，讓多個使用 serial port 硬體能夠並行的溝通。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;接著就讓我們一起優雅的用 asyncio 建立一個非同步框架吧！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;Uvz_vZj7SYajJAhdNwxlFA/BJnJ2J9IH#/"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;Uvz_vZj7SYajJAhdNwxlFA/BJnJ2J9IH#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jason&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, 我是 Jason。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Build and Host Real-world Machine Learning Services from Scratch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/build-and-host-real-world-machine-learning-services-from-scratch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>曾君宇</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/build-and-host-real-world-machine-learning-services-from-scratch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 13:00–13:45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Python has become the most popular programming language for research, it is quite easy to clone the source code from state of the art machine learning projects, and then run the demos in your well-prepared local environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, is it easy to turn these demos into production-ready services? How can you make them sustainable? What actual challenges may you face?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will share a story about how we leverage the power of Python to build computer vision services for customers, and further improve these services through a self-designed machine learning pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/excusemejoe/build-and-host-realworld-machine-learning-services-from-scratch-pycontw2019"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/excusemejoe/build-and-host-realworld-machine-learning-services-from-scratch-pycontw2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 曾君宇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe (就是那個最近一直沒有好好辦台南拍的傢伙 QQ)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Click Click Boom! Bombs Over Our Mind!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/click-click-boom-bombs-over-our-mind.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>KunYu Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/click-click-boom-bombs-over-our-mind.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 13:55–14:25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re doing research about zip bomb and this talk mainly focuses on how we deal with problem and the adventures we had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We share the successful experiences if we made it. Instead we share what we’ve learnt from the progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most important of all, this is all about having fun! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qPCPRfHx3ZEoneWOxBUqUE-LswqmTo2J-Pb74NGPPeg/edit#slide=id.g5ac89a5966_0_6"&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qPCPRfHx3ZEoneWOxBUqUE-LswqmTo2J-Pb74NGPPeg/edit#slide=id.g5ac89a5966_0_6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: KunYu Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security researcher, working at InfoSec Division, Telecom Technology Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun through challenging difficulties.
Recently get heavily involved in cpython work-flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kunyu-chens-notes.rtfd.io/"&gt;http://kunyu-chens-notes.rtfd.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jun-Wei Song&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cpython Contributor, focuses on security, using Python to deal with real-world problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security Researcher at Telecom Technology Center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Founder of TWBGC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://krnick.rtfd.io/"&gt;https://krnick.rtfd.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>打造面向金融場景的中文自然語言理解引擎</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/da-zao-mian-xiang-jin-rong-chang-jing-de-zhong-wen-zi-ran-yu-yan-li-jie-yin-qing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>陳皓遠</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/da-zao-mian-xiang-jin-rong-chang-jing-de-zhong-wen-zi-ran-yu-yan-li-jie-yin-qing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R1 15:05–15:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;自然語言理解(NLU)為建構問答系統的核心。要讓智慧代理人能夠以對話的方式來協助人類完成各式各樣目標， 就需要一個具有意圖及實體識別能力的自然語言理解引擎。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在這次演講中，講者將以一個後端工程師初次踏入自然語言處理領域的姿態，介紹實作NLU模組所需要使用的NLP技術與相對應機器學習的方法，接著分享基於RasaNLU開源專案來達成目標的過程與採用此方案的優點。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最後，除了透過統計來驗證模型能力以外，也搭配Rasa Core建構一個智慧型對話代理人，跟市面上應用在金融場景的智慧客服做個比較。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/HaoYuanChen/ss-174107004"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/HaoYuanChen/ss-174107004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 陳皓遠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;熱愛利用數據、程式、演算法來解決問題的 Python Developer。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;目前任職於中國信託商業銀行數據研究發展中心，協助金融機構面對數位轉型下的挑戰。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>工業 4.0—CNC 刀具健康監測</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/gong-ye-40-cnc-dao-ju-jian-kang-jian-ce.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>張楦涵</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/gong-ye-40-cnc-dao-ju-jian-kang-jian-ce.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R1 15:45–16:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;設備連網是工業4.0重要的一環，設備連網後我們如何讀得懂設備的語言?面對大量的高頻數據如何處理?怎麼將數據應用在工業現場?這次的演講將為大家介紹如何使用Python實作上述的課題，以CNC為範例，利用信號處理方法解析高低頻數據，並比較Supervised、Unsupervised方法的應用等，同時分享sample code。內容主要提及：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;選定問題、需求及現場應用場景時常會遇到的課題&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;不同特徵建立方法的比較及選用考量&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;模型的實踐與可行性驗證&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;實作過程的議題處理&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;現場應用方法與研究方法的差異比較&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;應用的現況、瓶頸與挑戰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/HsuanHanChang/cnc-tool-health-assessment-2019-pycon"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/HsuanHanChang/cnc-tool-health-assessment-2019-pycon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 張楦涵&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我是Judy，對數據工作充滿熱情，渴望運用python讓世界更進步&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 徐仕杰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我是RD, 我寫python&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Honey, There Is a Python in My Android Phone!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ing Wei Tang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple scripting, such as Python, Bash, PHP, Perl are all embedded in modern OS. Since Android is also a linux-based OS, it is also possible to write a script. Unfortunately before SL4A arrives, it is impossible to script on Android phone. SL4A provides rich APIs that allow user to access Android intents such as GPS location, Accelerometer and etc. through scripting. Hence with those APIs, the user can build simple scripts to interact with those APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks demonstrates how android intents can be accessed using python client, hence understanding the interaction between Android and Python API inside SL4A via RPC by dissecting the source code of both Android and Python API inside SL4A. The speaker will then demonstrate how different android intents such as GPS coordinate and gyroscope through a presentation of websocket coded in Python and webapp demo using babylon.js, together with a flask application that allows user to send SMS messages through Rest APIs, using android API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ing Wei Tang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ing Wei is the chair for PyCon MY 2019, the co-chair of PyCon MY 2018, and vice president of MyPOP. He has spoken in various PyCons, particularly in PyCon APAC 2018, as well as involving in PyCon communities actively in Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses python a lot in his daily work, especially coding the automation process and flow. During his past time, he likes to experience and perform hacking different things on operating system level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from programming language, he can also speak 5 different types of languages concurrently in one sentence. Please ask for demo if time permits.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to Transform Research Oriented Code into Machine Learning APIs with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/how-to-transform-research-oriented-code-into-machine-learning-apis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tetsuya Jesse Hirata</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/how-to-transform-research-oriented-code-into-machine-learning-apis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R0 13:15–13:45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, web application engineers have more opportunities to work with data scientists than before. At the same time, they are often faced with the research-oriented code written by researchers or data scientists. In order to integrate this code with systems such as APIs, web application engineers need to additionally write the code or refactor it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk covers the gap between the research-oriented code and production code of machine learning API. What is the gap between them? How it can be implemented based on real-world python code? How can the code validate whether the dataset is correct? How can machine learning models be continuously inspected? Audiences can earn the answers to these questions from this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/tetsuya0617/how-to-transform-research-oriented-code-into-machine-learning-apis-with-python?fbclid=IwAR1cUkcCBYq6duaiWAmlEhcW4-lz6wcrISHMcK2-IYcelFJSPTwMoY6iE5E"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/tetsuya0617/how-to-transform-research-oriented-code-into-machine-learning-apis-with-python?fbclid=IwAR1cUkcCBYq6duaiWAmlEhcW4-lz6wcrISHMcK2-IYcelFJSPTwMoY6iE5E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tetsuya Jesse Hirata&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesse is a software engineer working at Classi, which is the leading EdTech company in Tokyo. He has been developing a recommender engine which can optimize appropriate learning materials according to learner's abilities. It is based on a statistical method well-known in educational psychology and implemented with python. Prior to this, he used to research the relationships between online learning behaviors and learning outcomes at the UCL Institute of Education (IOE) in the UK. His interest is in how to bridge the gap between data science and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Understanding Deep Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-understanding-deep-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>林守德 Shou-de Lin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/keynote-understanding-deep-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, 09:40–10:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence has become overwhelming popular in recent years thanks to availability of big data and the advance of machine learning based models. Among them, solutions based on the Deep Neural Network (or DNN) have produced tremendous success in various applications including computer vision, natural language processing, etc. Nevertheless, one common concern for DNN-based solutions is that they are generally very complicated and can hardly be understood by human beings. This talk focuses on a specific type of deep neural networks called recurrent neural networks (RNN). It will not only demonstrate the power of an RNN model to learn from implicit information but also explain why the overwhelming performance can be achieved given its architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: 林守德 Shou-de Lin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;林守德教授擁有台灣大學電機工程學士、密西根大學電機碩士、南加州大學計算語言學碩士學位和計算機科學博士學位，目前為國立臺灣大學資訊工程學系的教授。他創立台大的機器發明與社群網路探勘實驗室。在加入台大之前，他是羅沙拉摩斯國家實驗室的博士後研究員。林教授的研究包括機器學習和資料探勘、社群網絡分析和自然語言處理等領域。他的國際學術成就包括 2003 年 IEEE 網路智能會議最佳論文獎、2007 年 Google 研究獎、三度獲得微軟研究獎、IBM 研究獎助，2010 年及 2014 TAAI 優秀論文獎、2011 年 ASONAM 最佳論文獎，以及連續 5 年獲得美國空軍 AFOSR / AOARD 研究獎。他亦是 ACM KDD Cup 的 All Time Leader，領導或共同領導台大團隊贏得 5 次冠軍，也帶領研究團隊贏得 2016 年 WSDM Cup。他也曾獲得科技部吳大猷先生紀念獎，傑出人才基金會年輕學者研究獎，曾擔任 SIGKDD 的 senior program chair 及 ACL 的 area chair，目前是國際社群網絡探勘期刊、資訊科學與工程期刊和中文計算語言學期刊的副主編，也是科學人的「網路不打烊」單元作家之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shou-de Lin is currently a full professor in the CSIE department of National Taiwan University. He holds a BS degree in EE department from National Taiwan University, an MS-EE degree from the University of Michigan, an MS degree in Computational Linguistics and PhD in Computer Science both from the University of Southern California. He leads the Machine Discovery and Social Network Mining Lab in NTU. Before joining NTU, he was a post-doctoral research fellow at the Los Alamos National Lab. Prof. Lin’s research includes the areas of machine learning and data mining, social network analysis, and natural language processing. His international recognition includes the best paper award in IEEE Web Intelligent conference 2003, Google Research Award in 2007, Microsoft research award in 2008, 2015, 2016 merit paper award in TAAI 2010, 2014, 2016, best paper award in ASONAM 2011, US Aerospace AFOSR/AOARD research award winner for 5 years. He is the all-time winners in ACM KDD Cup, leading or co-leading the NTU team to win 5 championships. He also leads a team to win WSDM Cup 2016. He has served as the senior PC for SIGKDD and area chair for ACL. He is currently the associate editor for International Journal on Social Network Mining, Journal of Information Science and Engineering, and International Journal of Computational Linguistics and Chinese Language Processing. He is also a freelance writer for Scientific American.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks, Day 1</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/lightning-talks-day-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/lightning-talks-day-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, 16:25–16:55&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daisuke Saito – Minecraft Education and Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshida Shunsuke – PyCon JP Introduction of Useful Tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naotaka Yokoyama – Recap PyCon JP 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nikkie – Prepare PyCon JP 2019 with Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keith Yang – Test by Touchpad in Vim, Coding with AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>驢車 (Donkey Car)，一個基於 Raspberry Pi 與機器學習的自走車專案介紹 — PyCon Taiwan 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/lu-che-donkey-caryi-ge-ji-yu-raspberry-pi-yu-ji-qi-xue-xi-de-zi-zou-che-zhuan-an-jie-shao-pycon-taiwan-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>sosorry</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/lu-che-donkey-caryi-ge-ji-yu-raspberry-pi-yu-ji-qi-xue-xi-de-zi-zou-che-zhuan-an-jie-shao-pycon-taiwan-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R1 10:50‑11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donkey Car 是 Adam Conway 在 2017 年發起的專案，一開始是想做一個縮小版的自走車，因此使用 1/10 比例的 RC 車作為車體，並用 OpenCV 裡的車道跟隨技術，但他的夥伴 Will Roscoe 希望能像 Google 和 Tesla 一樣可以使用深度學習技術打造自動駕駛系統，因此很快的 Donkey Car 就加入了神經網路模型。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donkey Car 是一個開源機器學習的自走車專案，車上唯一的感測器就是相機。藉由操作 Donkey Car，我們可以將機器學習的過程跑一遍，包括訓練資料蒐集與處理、模型選擇與調整、實機訓練、測試驗證等。從無到有瞭解機器學習的原理，並操作整個過程，最後透過車輛的自走看到實際的成果。而最有趣的地方不只是機器學習的部份，我們可以自由的改裝車上的硬體或是修改車道的設計比較各項變化，這都能讓我們離真實的自駕車更靠近。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donkey Car 使用的硬體包括 Raspberry Pi、RC Car(不限)、馬達控制板和最重要的魚眼相機等。使用的軟體包括 Raspbian 系統加上 Keras/Tensorflow 神經網路，搭配 Tornado 做的 web control。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我們將分享專案的技術細節、實做上會遇到的問題與相關學習資源，希望有更多人能一起來當車友。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/raspberrypi-tw/donkey-car-raspberry-pi"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/raspberrypi-tw/donkey-car-raspberry-pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: sosorry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I'm sosorry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PEP 572: The Walrus Operator</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/pep-572-the-walrus-operator.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dustin Ingram</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/pep-572-the-walrus-operator.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R0 13:55–14:25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll learn about a highly controversial proposed change to Python syntax, the rationale for it, and the fallout as the result of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dustin Ingram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dustin is a Developer Advocate at Google, focused on supporting the Python community on Google Cloud. He's also a member of the Python Packaging Authority, maintainer of PyPI, organizer for the PyTexas conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Py 車達人</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/py-che-da-ren.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Malo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/py-che-da-ren.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R0 15:45–16:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;當我們便利的使用車輛於日常交通時，你知道車上有一台行車電腦在和它的周邊不斷通訊嗎?
當保險業者說要由你的行車資訊來決定你的保險額度、費用時，你知道除了AI在分析你的開車習慣以外，是什麼把你的車輛資訊取出來送回去的嗎?
本演講將說明行車電腦常用的CANBus協定，並使用Python語言藉此協定把車輛資訊取出上傳至雲端，讓資料科學家來分析數據。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Malo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;由機構工程師轉職的韌體工程師，對IoT的議題感到很有興趣，平時工作因為大多接觸的是較低階的硬體，因此主要使用C語言，近二年開始接觸Python語言後，開始逐步把工作上的需求轉用Python來完成，希望在社群和更多同好一起開心的探索工業控制和IoT的領域。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Profilers We Built for Efficiency</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/python-profilers-we-built-for-efficiency.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jimmy Lai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/python-profilers-we-built-for-efficiency.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 11:30–12:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve efficiency issue of our Python application. We started with cProfile to profile function call CPU cost and found it couldn't differentiate call-stacks sharing the same function calls. Asyncio makes the issue worse, since gathered functions all have the event loop as caller. We ended up build our own function call profilers:
* CPU cost profiler: CPU instructions per function call with complete call stack.
* Latency profiler with asyncio support: collect timestamp/latency per function call and yield from await.
* Profiler identifies lru_cache opportunities: functions have high cost and high hit rate of parameters/returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We share how we implemented those profilers. After this talk, you'll have learned how to:
* Build profilers by registering a callback function for function calls.
* Handle call stacks in asyncio world.
* Use different timers and traversing through call-stack.
* Implement a CPU profiler, latency profiler lru_cache opportunities profiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jimmylai/talks"&gt;https://github.com/jimmylai/talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jimmy Lai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Lai is a Software Engineer in Instagram Infrastructure. His recent interest is Python efficiency, including profiling, optimization and asyncio. He has been sharing his experiences in PyCon Taiwan since 2012. This year, he plan to share his latency efficiency experiences on large scale Python web application.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python 在 Data for Social Good 領域常見的應用</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/python-zai-data-for-social-good-ling-yu-chang-jian-de-ying-yong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ning Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/python-zai-data-for-social-good-ling-yu-chang-jian-de-ying-yong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R0 14:50–15:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data For Social Good (D4SG)是從2015年發起的一個用資料做公益的計畫，協助了超過30個NGO及公部門單位，並獲得總統府黑客松前五強，及聯發科的「智在家鄉」第一名等殊榮。在30多個專案中涵蓋影像辨識、文字探勘及資料分析，Python是常用的程式語言之一。本次Talk將分享給Python初學者在哪些情境可以如何做資料分析、機器學習來解決社會人文相關題目。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ning Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Andrew Li&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently working as a Data Engineer and Data Analyst, besides I am a cross-domain engineer.
I had experienced in various domains, such as genetic engineering, metabolic engineering, fermentation engineering, process engineering, solvent recycling engineering, composite materials engineering, and full stack developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Small-scale Infrastructure Management with Python-based Tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/small-scale-infrastructure-management-with-python-based-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>SHY</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/small-scale-infrastructure-management-with-python-based-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R1 13:00–13:45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing server infrastructures (i.e. everything below the application stack) is a lot of work. There is hardware to install, operating systems to set up, IP addresses to assign and backup the manage; at the same time, there are more to manage as the business grows. This talk will present several Python-based tools (namely cloud-init, curtin, MAAS, and Ansible) can help manage the infrastructure (even if the fleet is too small to justify huge investment in automation), and take a look at how they work under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: SHY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;目前在台大教務處擔任系統工程師&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Python Spirit Behind LED Glasses (LED 眼鏡背後的蟒蛇魂)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/the-python-spirit-behind-led-glasses-led-yan-jing-bei-hou-de-mang-she-hun.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chiung-ting Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/the-python-spirit-behind-led-glasses-led-yan-jing-bei-hou-de-mang-she-hun.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R0 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the music band &amp;quot;21 Band&amp;quot; got some fascinating LED glasses that look very good on stage. Besides the built-in pattern from the glasses, we also hacked into them and made some changes. The glasses are connected to a computer, and so is the keyboard. A program is written to detect different notes or chords, and triggers different LED patterns. In this talk we will share how it is achieved, the problem that we encountered, improvements that we made, and talk about some future works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 年，21 樂團因緣際會獲得了舞台效果十足的 LED 眼鏡。除了 LED 眼鏡內建的 pattern 之外，我們更改裝了部分的程式，讓眼鏡可以和鍵盤手的鍵盤串接，透過一個偵測程式來啟動、結束不同的 pattern。本演講將和各位分享這是如何達成的，我們碰到的問題、隔年的改善，以及未來的展望。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/yychen/livespring"&gt;https://github.com/yychen/livespring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Chiung-ting Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 愛好者，平常多使用 Django 或 Tornado 開發各式各樣專案&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The str/bytes Nightmare Before the Python 2 EOL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/the-strbytes-nightmare-before-the-python-2-eol.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kir Chou</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/the-strbytes-nightmare-before-the-python-2-eol.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 15:45–16:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the EOL of python2, let's reflect one of the most well-known nightmare: str. This talk will analyze the nightmare, and provide the treatment for it. This is the right talk for you if you have encountered UnicodeEncodeError but not knew about the root cause yet. After the talk, you will know the difference between str and bytes in both python2 and python3 and learn the cleaner way to write string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This talk will organize many previous PyCon talks with real world supporting python3 experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/ssuser2cbb78/the-strbytes-nightmare-before-python2-eol"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/ssuser2cbb78/the-strbytes-nightmare-before-python2-eol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Kir Chou&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A code monkey builds search services in Amazon jungle. This will be the 3rd year of his presence in PyCon TW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在亞馬遜做搜索服務的碼猴，今年將會是它出現在PyCon台灣的第三年。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Useful Tools to Explain ML Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/useful-tools-to-explain-ml-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jack Pan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/useful-tools-to-explain-ml-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R1 13:55–14:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;現今建立各種機器學習模型的套件很多，但是最常被詬病的是如何去解釋建立出來的機器學習模型。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尤其是若需要將模型應用到與人高度相關的行業中，如：金融業決定是否要發信用卡、醫療業協助診斷疾病等，若無法解釋模型，常會導致使用者或老闆不敢用、不相信模型之問題。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;實際上現在已經有很多工具套件來協助解釋機器學習模型。
介紹三種常用的模型，以及如何運用套件來解釋這些模型。
包含線性迴歸可以用 p-value 和係數，Tree-based 模型可以用 feature importance 和 SHAP ，最後是類神經網路的模型一樣也可以用 SHAP 來對其做解釋。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主要會以結構化資料介紹 SHAP 套件的原理以及它的應用方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jack Pan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;喜歡用Python開發的工程師。有三年以上的機器學習經驗，特別是將其運用到金融相關的問題上。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>寫個能幹的中文斷詞系統</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/xie-ge-neng-gan-de-zhong-wen-duan-ci-xi-tong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>PeterWolf</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/xie-ge-neng-gan-de-zhong-wen-duan-ci-xi-tong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 14:50–15:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我們利用語言學的中文句法原則，從零開始打造了一套中文斷詞引擎 - 文截斷詞 (Articut)，而且不只斷詞，它還能推理詞性標記。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本演講將分享一點點中文語言學 (雖然深度不足以理解程式邏輯)、我們在開發過程中遇到的有趣語料和斷詞結果 (可能會有些冷場)以及 Python3 的 Unicode 如何省下我們和字串編碼戰鬥的力氣 (還有 Python3.5 的 re 模組有什麼問題…啊啊，扯遠了)、還有看著 Articut 犯下和人類孩童一樣的語言錯誤時的感動(底特律變人嗎？)、以不同斷詞引擎處理特殊語料的修羅場 (我們對同領域的前輩還是非常尊敬的)以及最後用 SIGHAN 2005 的資料集，和其它文獻中的演算法進行良率競爭的結果。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Droidtown/PyConTW2019"&gt;https://github.com/Droidtown/PyConTW2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: PeterWolf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Droidtown Linguistic Tech. Co. (卓騰語言科技) 創辦人兼核心開發者。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;平常開發基於語言學理論的中文斷詞(NLP)、中文語意處理(NLU)、自動語音處理、語音辨識、自然語言文本解析及資料探勘的演算法及前端應用。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;是一個覺得流浪很美，卻差一點成為流浪漢的大叔。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>