<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Accelerating the SunPy Data Analysis Ecosystem with Dask</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/accelerating-the-sunpy-data-analysis-ecosystem-with-dask.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, the SunPy ecosystem, a Python solar data analysis environment, has evolved organically to serve the needs of scientists analyzing solar physics data, mostly on desktop and laptop computers. However, modern solar observatories are producing data volumes in the tens of petabytes, necessitating the need for parallelized and out-of-core computation. HelioCloud is a cloud computing environment tailored for heliophysics research and colocated with many terabytes of solar physics data. In this talk, we will show how the SunPy ecosystem, combined with Dask on HelioCloud, can be used to efficiently process high-resolution solar data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will barnes</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/accelerating-the-sunpy-data-analysis-ecosystem-with-dask.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Accelerating the Use of Public Geophysical Data for Recharging California’s Groundwater</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/accelerating-the-use-of-public-geophysical-data-for-recharging-californias-groundwater.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recharging ground aquifers is an urgent task for improving groundwater sustainability in California. Geophysical data can provide a capability to image the subsurface where the major data gap lies. However, neither data nor analytic tools required to derive subsurface information is readily accessible. We present an interactive web application that utilizes a public database, GIS capabilities and directly integrates Jupyter Notebooks and Python packages from researchers to guide recharge site location. Our demonstration showcases how this technology can contribute to improving groundwater recharge in California and how integrating the research knowledge directly into a web application can increase the impact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Seogi Kang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/accelerating-the-use-of-public-geophysical-data-for-recharging-californias-groundwater.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Accessibility best practices for authoring Jupyter notebooks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/accessibility-best-practices-for-authoring-jupyter-notebooks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you’ve written the perfect notebook, but do you know who can read it? As a notebook author you have great stories, code, and visualizations filling your work, but how often do you consider accessibility? Jupyter notebooks seem like they are for everyone, but how a notebook gets written can greatly impact how usable it is for people with disabilities. We’ve curated authoring-focused best practices for notebook content to help your notebooks be more inclusive and reach a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephannie Jimenez Gacha</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/accessibility-best-practices-for-authoring-jupyter-notebooks.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>An Introduction to Cloud-Based Geospatial Analysis with Earth Engine and Geemap</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/an-introduction-to-cloud-based-geospatial-analysis-with-earth-engine-and-geemap.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is an introduction to cloud-based geospatial analysis with Earth Engine and the geemap Python package. We will cover the basics of Earth Engine data types and how to visualize, analyze, and export Earth Engine data in a Jupyter environment using geemap. We will also demonstrate how to develop and deploy interactive Earth Engine web apps. Throughout the session, practical examples and hands-on exercises will be provided to enhance learning. The attendees should have a basic understanding of Python and Jupyter Notebooks. Familiarity with Earth science and geospatial datasets is not required, but will be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steve Greenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/an-introduction-to-cloud-based-geospatial-analysis-with-earth-engine-and-geemap.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Bayesian Statistics with Python No Resampling Necessary</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/bayesian-statistics-with-python-no-resampling-necessary.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TensorFlow Probability is a powerful library for statistical analysis in Python. Using TensorFlow Probability’s implementation of Bayesian methods, modelers can incorporate prior information and obtain parameter estimates and a quantified degree of belief in the results. Resampling methods like Markov Chain Monte Carlo can also be used to perform Bayesian analysis. As an alternative, we show how to use numerical optimization to estimate model parameters, and then show how numerical differentiation can be used to get a quantified degree of belief. How to perform simulation in Python to corroborate our results is also demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charles D Lindsey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/bayesian-statistics-with-python-no-resampling-necessary.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Better (Open Source) Homes and Gardens with Project Pythia | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/better-open-source-homes-and-gardens-with-project-pythia-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As scientists continue to embrace the Jupyter ecosystem for constructing computational narratives of their science through code, data, and rich text, they may encounter technical and community barriers to maintaining and sharing their science with new and existing audiences. We demonstrate the value of open-source science community building and getting there through reliance on the open-source Jupyter ecosystem, pre-packaged GitHub and BinderHub-based infrastructure, and documentation for creating, sharing, testing, and maintaining Pythia Cookbooks for their computational narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Drew Camron</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/better-open-source-homes-and-gardens-with-project-pythia-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Building MetPy for the Long Term</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/building-metpy-for-the-long-term.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MetPy is an open-source Python package for meteorological and atmospheric science applications, leveraging significantly many other pieces of the scientific Python stack (e.g. numpy, matplotlib, scipy, etc.). With a focus on sustainability, Metpy extensively leverages GitHub Action to try to automate as much of the software development process as possible. Sustainability also extends to the growth of the community of developers, and we have been working to try to make that sustainable as well. Here we talk about our experiences, share our successes and lessons learned with trying to build a sustainable project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan May</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/building-metpy-for-the-long-term.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Can There Be Too Much Parallelism?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/can-there-be-too-much-parallelism.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numerical Python libraries can run computations on many CPU cores with various parallel interfaces. When we simultaneously use multiple levels of parallelism, it may result in oversubscription and degraded performance. This talk explores the programming interfaces used to control parallelism exposed by libraries such as NumPy, SciPy, and scikit-learn. We will learn about parallel primitives used in these libraries, such as OpenMP and Python's multiprocessing module. We will see how to control parallelism in these libraries to avoid oversubscription. Finally, we will look at the overall landscape for configuring parallelism and highlight paths for improving the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas J. Fan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/can-there-be-too-much-parallelism.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Climate Model Evaluation Workflow Built on Jupyter Notebooks | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/climate-model-evaluation-workflow-built-on-jupyter-notebooks-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project introduces an extensible workflow used to evaluate climate model output using collections of Jupyter notebooks. The workflow supports parametrizing and batch-executing notebooks using Papermill, in conjunction with developing notebooks interactively. Additional features include integration with Dask and caching intermediate data products generated by notebooks. The final product of the workflow can automatically be built into a Jupyter book for easy presentation and shareability. While it was initially developed for climate modeling, the flexible and extensible nature of this framework makes it adaptable to any kind of data analysis work, and the presentation will highlight this capability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elena Romashkova</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/climate-model-evaluation-workflow-built-on-jupyter-notebooks-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Community-first open source: An action plan!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/community-first-open-source-an-action-plan.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Communities are at the heart of open source software and are fundamental to our projects’ long-term success. The Python ecosystem has several mature projects, that have spent years working on community initiatives. Newer projects can learn from their experiences and build stronger foundations to foster healthy communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we share a set of practices for community-first projects, including repository management, contributor pathways, and governance principles. We’ll also share real examples from our own journey transitioning a company-backed OSS project, Nebari (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nebari.dev/"&gt;https://nebari.dev/&lt;/a&gt;), to be more community-oriented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pavithra Pothina</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/community-first-open-source-an-action-plan.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Computer Vision Approach to Classifying Clouds &amp; Aerosols from Satellite Observations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/computer-vision-approach-to-classifying-clouds-aerosols-from-satellite-observations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NASA Atmosphere SIPS, located at the University of Wisconsin, is responsible for producing operational cloud and aerosol scientific products from satellite observations. With decades of satellite observations, new scientific algorithms are employing Machine Learning (ML) methods to improve processing efficiencies and scientific analyses. In preparation for future developments, we are working with NASA Atmospheric Science Teams to understand ML requirements and assist in developing new tools that will benefit both the Science Teams and the broader Open-Source Science community. This talk will step through a ML methodology being used to identify cloud types and severe aerosols.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steve Dutcher</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/computer-vision-approach-to-classifying-clouds-aerosols-from-satellite-observations.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Contributor experience: Why it matters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/contributor-experience-why-it-matters.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Behind every successful open source project is a strong contributor community. What makes these communities strong? What can you do in your OSS project to nurture a thriving contributor community? In this presentation, we will share insights from the work of the Contributor Experience Lead team (NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, and pandas) and discuss why designing and providing positive contributor experience is vital to sustainability of each individual project and the SciPy ecosystem overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melissa Weber Mendonça</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/contributor-experience-why-it-matters.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Designing user friendly APIs for the NIST Interatomic Potentials Repository</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/designing-user-friendly-apis-for-the-nist-interatomic-potentials-repository.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NIST Interatomic Potentials Repository project has developed Python APIs to support user interactions with the repository data hosted at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://potentials.nist.gov"&gt;https://potentials.nist.gov&lt;/a&gt;. The associated code is layered, starting with generic methods for JSON/XML-based data and databases, and building up to user-friendly interfaces specific to the repository. This design allows for basic users to easily explore the data and expert users to perform more complicated operations or create custom APIs for other databases. The repository APIs help users find and compare interatomic models, set up simulations, perform high throughput calculations, and access the high throughput results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lucas Hale</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/designing-user-friendly-apis-for-the-nist-interatomic-potentials-repository.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Disciplined Saddle Programming | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/disciplined-saddle-programming-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our recent work implements a domain-specific language called Disciplined Saddle Programming (DSP) in Python. It is available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cvxgrp/dsp"&gt;https://github.com/cvxgrp/dsp&lt;/a&gt;. DSP allows specifying convex-concave saddle, or minimax problems, a class of convex optimization problems commonly used in game theory, machine learning, and finance. One application for DSP is to naturally describe and solve robust optimization problems. We show numerous examples of these problems, including robust regressions and economic applications. However, this only represents a fraction of problems solvable with DSP, and we want to engage with the SciPy community to hear about further potential applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Sager Luxenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/disciplined-saddle-programming-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Effective Open Source Community Management in Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/effective-open-source-community-management-in-quantum-computing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qiskit is an open-source SDK for quantum computers, enabling developers to work with these powerful machines using a familiar python interface. First released in 2017, Qiskit has become the most popular package for quantum computing (Unitary Fund, 2022), with a thriving open-source community. As Qiskit has grown and changed, so has our approach to nurturing our community. This talk will share important lessons we’ve learnt over the years, including practical tips you can apply to your own projects. Whether you’re just starting in open-source or already manage an established community, this talk is for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abby Mitchell</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/effective-open-source-community-management-in-quantum-computing.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Emukit Python toolkit for uncertainty quantification</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/emukit-python-toolkit-for-uncertainty-quantification.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emukit is an open-source package for uncertainty quantification in Python. It provides various Bayesian methods, such as optimization, experimental design and quadrature, in a flexible unified way that leverages their commonalities. In the talk we will explain how and why Emukit was built, what are its strengths and weaknesses, how it is used today and in what scenarios one might find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrei Paleyes</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/emukit-python-toolkit-for-uncertainty-quantification.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Fast and Accurate machine learning potentials for extreme-scale simulations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/fast-and-accurate-machine-learning-potentials-for-extreme-scale-simulations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allegro and FLARE are two very different packages for constructing machine learning potentials that are fast, accurate, and suitable for extreme-scale molecular dynamics simulations. Allegro uses PyTorch for efficient equivariant potentials with state-of-the-art accuracy, while FLARE is a sparse Gaussian process potential with an optimized C++ training backend leveraging Kokkos, OpenMP, and MPI for state-of-the-art performance, and a user-friendly Python frontend. We will compare and contrast the two methods, discuss lessons learned, and show spectacular scientific applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anders Johansson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/fast-and-accurate-machine-learning-potentials-for-extreme-scale-simulations.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Fast Exploration of the Milky Way or any other n dimensional dataset | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/fast-exploration-of-the-milky-way-or-any-other-n-dimensional-dataset-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;N-dimensional datasets are common in many scientific fields, and quickly accessing subsets of these datasets is critical for an efficient exploration experience. Blosc2 is a compression and format library that recently added support for multidimensional datasets. Compression is crucial in effectively dealing with sparse datasets as the zeroed parts can be almost entirely suppressed, while the non-zero parts can still be stored in smaller sizes than their uncompressed counterparts. Moreover, the new double data partition in Blosc2 reduces the need for decompressing unnecessary data, which allows for top-class slicing speed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesc Alted</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/fast-exploration-of-the-milky-way-or-any-other-n-dimensional-dataset-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Gammapy: a Python Package for Gamma-Ray Astronomy Version v1.0</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/gammapy-a-python-package-for-gamma-ray-astronomy-version-v10.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this contribution we will present the first stable version v1.0 of Gammapy, an openly developed Python package for gamma-ray astronomy. Gammapy provides methods for the analysis of astronomical gamma-ray data, such as measurement of spectra, images and light curves. By relying on standardized data formats and a joint likelihood framework, it allows astronomers to combine data from multiple instruments and constrain underlying astrophysical emission processes across large parts of the electromagnetic spectrum. Finally we will share lessons learned during the journey towards version v1.0 for an openly developed scientific Python package.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Axel Donath</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/gammapy-a-python-package-for-gamma-ray-astronomy-version-v10.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>GraphBLAS for Sparse Data and Graphs | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/graphblas-for-sparse-data-and-graphs-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GraphBLAS solves graph problems using sparse linear algebra. We are using it to build graphblas-algorithms, a fast backend to NetworkX. python-graphblas is faster and more capable than scipy.sparse for both graph algorithms and sparse operations. If you have sparse data or graph workloads that you want to scale and make faster, then this is for you. Come learn what makes GraphBLAS special--and fast!--and how to use it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jim Kitchen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/graphblas-for-sparse-data-and-graphs-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>How can we protect vulnerable groups</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/how-can-we-protect-vulnerable-groups.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity, equity and inclusion initiatives often start with measurement - what do our communities look like today and how can we track progress against our goals? However, data collected through APIs, web scraping, surveys, interviews, inference etc. have the potential to expose more details about an individual than they were expecting, especially when aggregated across platforms and shared in public forums. This talk will discuss tactics, opportunities and challenges when collecting sensitive data in and around open source communities, while aligning with policies and regulations, respecting the right to anonymity and ensuring the safety of all members of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sophia Vargas</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/how-can-we-protect-vulnerable-groups.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>How Open Source Tools Power the Efforts of Biological Data Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/how-open-source-tools-power-the-efforts-of-biological-data-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Angela Pisco is the head of computational biology at insitro. She is passionate about extracting meaningful information from biomedical datasets and use that to improve disease understanding and drug development. She has studied Biomedical Engineering as BSc and MSc and have a PhD in Systems Biology. Her PhD work became the foundation of a new direction of thinking on why cancer develops resistance to chemotherapy, which is the major reason for treatment failure. In her postdoctoral work, she investigated the mechanisms of cellular differentiation in the skin. She developed a 3D computational model that recapitulated the observed changes in the mouse skin connective tissue and dermis during development. The combination of the mathematical analysis with experimental data led to a new understanding of how distinct fibroblast subpopulations become activated, proliferate, and deposit matrix proteins during wound healing. Before moving to insitro, she led the Data Science platform at CZ Biohub. There she made significant contributions for the whole organism cell atlas projects including the first whole mouse cell atlas, the first aging cell atlas, and Tabula Sapiens, one of the first Human Cell Atlas drafts (The Tabula Sapiens Consortium, Science 2022). She is also a founder and core member of Open Problems in Single Cell (openproblems.bio), a community effort to improve multimodal data analysis by both generating gold standard datasets and benchmarking metrics and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Angela Pisco</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/how-open-source-tools-power-the-efforts-of-biological-data-analysis.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>In Process Analytical Data Management with DuckDB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DuckDB is a novel analytical data management system. DuckDB supports complex queries, has no external dependencies, and is deeply integrated into the Python ecosystem. Because DuckDB runs in the same process, no serialization or socket communication has to occur, making data transfer virtually instantaneous. For example, DuckDB can directly query Pandas data frames faster than Pandas itself. In our talk, we will describe the user values of DuckDB, and how it can be used to improve their day-to-day lives through automatic parallelization, efficient operators and out-of-core operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Monahan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Interactive Exploration of Large-Scale Datasets with Jupyter-Scatter | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/interactive-exploration-of-large-scale-datasets-with-jupyter-scatter-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter-scatter is a scalable, interactive, and interlinked scatter plot widget for exploring datasets with up to several million data points. It focuses on data-driven visual encodings and offers two-way pan+zoom and lasso interactions. Beyond a single instance, jupyter-scatter can compose multiple scatter plots and synchronize their views and selections. Moreover, points can be connected by spline-interpolated lines. Thanks to the underlying WebGL rendering engine, spatial and color changes are smoothly transitioned. Finally, the API integrates seamlessly with Pandas DataFrames and offers functional methods that group properties by type to ease accessibility and readability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fritz Lekschas</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/interactive-exploration-of-large-scale-datasets-with-jupyter-scatter-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Introducing yt xarray</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/introducing-yt-xarray.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;yt_xarray is a new package in the scientific python ecosystem for linking yt and xarray. yt, primarily used in computational astrophysics, has gradually broadened support for scientific domains, including geoscience disciplines. Most geoscience data, however, still requires manual steps to load into yt. yt_xarray, a new xarray extension, aims to streamline communication of data from xarray to yt, providing a potentially useful tool to the many geoscience researchers already using xarray while allowing yt to leverage the distributed backends already supported by xarray. In this presentation, we will provide an overview of the usage and design of yt_xarray.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Havlin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/introducing-yt-xarray.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Open Source Contributors in Space and Time</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/keynote-open-source-contributors-in-space-and-time.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael Droettboom is a Principal Software Engineering Manager at Microsoft where he leads the CPython Performance Engineering Team. That team contributes directly to the upstream CPython project, and recently helped make Python 3.11 up to 60% faster than 3.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael has been contributing to open source for over 25 years: he is the former lead maintainer of matplotlib, a major contributor to astropy, and he is the original author of Pyodide and airspeed velocity. His work has supported such diverse applications as the Hubble and James Webb Space Telescopes, the Firefox web browser, infrared retinal imaging, and optical sheet music recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Droettboom</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/keynote-open-source-contributors-in-space-and-time.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>libyt: a Tool for Parallel In Situ Analysis with yt</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/libyt-a-tool-for-parallel-in-situ-analysis-with-yt.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the era of exascale computing, storage and analysis of large scale data have become more important and difficult. We present libyt, an open source C++ library, that allows researchers to analyze and visualize data using yt or other Python packages in parallel during simulation runtime. We describe the methods for reading adaptive mesh refinement data structure, handling data transition between Python and simulation with minimal memory overhead, and conducting analysis with no additional time penalty using Python C API and NumPy C API. We demonstrate how it solves the problem in astrophysical simulations and increases disk usage efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shin-Rong Tsai</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/libyt-a-tool-for-parallel-in-situ-analysis-with-yt.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks DAY 1 | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-1-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Little</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-1-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks DAY 2 | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto Pastor Muela</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks DAY 3 | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Axel Donath</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Long-tailed distributions in the natural and engineered world</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/long-tailed-distributions-in-the-natural-and-engineered-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Long-tailed distributions are common in natural and engineered systems; as a result, we encounter extreme values more often than we would expect from a short-tailed distribution. If we are not prepared for these &amp;quot;black swans&amp;quot;, they can be disastrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we have statistical tools for identifying long-tailed distributions, estimating their parameters, and making better predictions about rare events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I present evidence of long-tailed distributions in a variety of datasets -- including earthquakes, asteroids, and stock market crashes -- discuss statistical methods for dealing with them, and show implementations using scientific Python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Allen Downey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/long-tailed-distributions-in-the-natural-and-engineered-world.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Maintenance and Evolution of Zarr</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/maintenance-and-evolution-of-zarr.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key feature of the Python data ecosystem is the reliance on simple but efficient primitives that follow well-defined interfaces to make tools work seamlessly together (Cf. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://data-apis.org/"&gt;http://data-apis.org/&lt;/a&gt;). NumPy provides an in-memory representation for tensors. Dask provides parallelisation of tensor access. Xarray provides metadata linking tensor dimensions. Zarr provides a missing feature, namely the scalable, persistent storage for annotated hierarchies of tensors. Defined through a community process, the Zarr specification enables the storage of large out-of-memory datasets locally and in the cloud. Implementations exist in C++, C, Java, Javascript, Julia, and Python, enabling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">John Kirkham</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/maintenance-and-evolution-of-zarr.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Modern compute stack for scaling large AI/ML workloads</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/modern-compute-stack-for-scaling-large-aiml-workloads.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Existing production machine learning systems often suffer from various problems that make them hard to use. For example, data scientists and ML practitioners often spend most of their time stitching and managing bespoke distributed systems to build end-to-end ML applications and push models to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this, the Ray community has built Ray AI Runtime (Ray AIR), an open-source toolkit for building large-scale end-to-end ML applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jules S. Damji</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/modern-compute-stack-for-scaling-large-aiml-workloads.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>New CUDA Toolkit packages for Conda</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/new-cuda-toolkit-packages-for-conda.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will examine the new CUDA package layout for Conda (as included in conda-forge). Show how CUDA components have been broken out. Share how this affects development and package building. Walk through changes in the conda-forge infrastructure made to incorporate these new packages. Examine recipes using the new packages and what was needed to update them. Additionally will provide guidance on how to use these new packages in recipes or in library development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomson Comer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/new-cuda-toolkit-packages-for-conda.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Open FF: next generation force fields with open data, open software, and open science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/open-ff-next-generation-force-fields-with-open-data-open-software-and-open-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Open Force Field (OpenFF) initiative was formed to build a new generation of force fields for molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using modern data-driven techniques. Openness is one of our fundamental founding principles, and everything we produce is released openly and accessibly so that the community can validate, modify, or extend our work. Here we introduce some flagship packages in our ecosystem and the advances they have enabled in force field science and MD workflows. These include fitting custom functional forms, exploring the addition of off-site charges, and using neural networks to assign charges to protein-ligand systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeff Wagner</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/open-ff-next-generation-force-fields-with-open-data-open-software-and-open-science.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Pandera: Beyond Pandas Data Validation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/pandera-beyond-pandas-data-validation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data quality remains a core concern for practitioners of machine learning, data science, and data engineering, and in recent years specialized packages have emerged to validate and monitor data and models. However, as the open source community iterates on data frameworks – notably, highly performant entrants such as Polars – data quality libraries need to catch up to support them. In this talk, you will learn about Pandera and its journey from being a pandas-only validator to a generic tool for testing arbitrary data containers so that it can provide a standardized way of creating data validation tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Niels Bantilan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/pandera-beyond-pandas-data-validation.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Rapid prediction of Thermal Transport in Metal-Organic Frameworks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/rapid-prediction-of-thermal-transport-in-metal-organic-frameworks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metal-Organic Frameworks (MOFs) have vast potential for gas adsorption, but their practical use hinges on their ability to dissipate thermal energy generated during adsorption. Here, we performed the first high-throughput screening of thermal conductivity in over 10,000 MOFs using molecular dynamics simulations. Next, we developed a graph neural network (GNN) based model to swiftly predict the diagonal components of the thermal conductivity tensor for accelerated materials discovery. Attendees will gain insights into how GNNs can be trained to predict material tensor properties, benefiting both the materials science and machine learning communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meiirbek Islamov</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/rapid-prediction-of-thermal-transport-in-metal-organic-frameworks.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Responsible AI in Practice</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/responsible-ai-in-practice.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rumman Chowdhury is a trailblazer in the field of applied algorithmic ethics, creating cutting-edge socio-technical solutions for ethical, explainable and transparent AI. She currently runs Parity Consulting, Parity Responsible Innovation Fund, and is a Responsible AI Fellow at the Berkman Klein Center for Internet &amp;amp; Society at Harvard University. She is also a Research Affiliate at the Minderoo Center for Democracy and Technology at Cambridge University and a visiting researcher at the NYU Tandon School of Engineering. Previously, she was the director of the ML Ethics, Transparency, and Accountability team at Twitter identifying and mitigating algorithmic harms on the platform. Before that she was CEO and founder of Parity, an enterprise algorithmic audit platform company. She formerly served as Global Lead for Responsible AI at Accenture Applied Intelligence. In her work as Accenture’s Responsible AI lead, she led the design of the Fairness Tool, a first-in-industry algorithmic tool to identify and mitigate bias in AI systems. Dr. Chowdhury has been featured in international media, including the Wall Street Journal, Financial Times, Harvard Business Review, NPR, MIT Sloan Magazine among others. She was named one of BBC’s 100 Women, recognized as one of the Bay Area’s top 40 under 40, and honored to be inducted to the British Royal Society of the Arts (RSA).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rumman Chowdhury</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/responsible-ai-in-practice.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>Scientific and technical publishing with Python and Quarto</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/scientific-and-technical-publishing-with-python-and-quarto.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In research and data science, effective communication requires weaving together narrative text and code to produce elegantly formatted output. By embedding executable Python code blocks inside markdown, the open-source publishing platform, Quarto, works with Jupyter and VS Code to enable you to create these fully reproducible documents and reports with the format and styling you need. In this talk I’ll share how to get started and a few of my favorite things in Quarto including creating a manuscript, presentation and website in HTML, PDF and Word from a single source file, and creating lessons, reports, and Confluence documents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tracy Teal</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/scientific-and-technical-publishing-with-python-and-quarto.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Scientific Python: from `__init__` to `__call__`</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/scientific-python-from-__init__-to-__call__.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Scientific Python project aims to better coordinate the ecosystem and grow the community. Come hear about our recent progress and our plans for the coming year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juanita Gomez</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/scientific-python-from-__init__-to-__call__.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>SciPy Tools Plenary Day 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy is organized by NumFOCUS, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that promotes open source scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas J. Fan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-1.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>SciPy Tools Plenary Day 3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy is organized by NumFOCUS, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that promotes open source scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juan Nunez-Iglesias</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-3.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Small Town Police Accountability A Data Science Toolkit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/small-town-police-accountability-a-data-science-toolkit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will share a Python library to obtain and analyze policing data, that was developed in conjunction with community activists, data scientists, social scientists and the Small Town Police Accountability (SToPA) Research Lab. We will showcase components of the SToPA library which use Python tools such as web drivers, optical character recognition, geospatial mapping, machine learning and statistical sampling to better understand the policing landscape. The goal of this work is to present an easily replicable framework for analyzing police and community interactions with accessible on-ramps for activists, developers and researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Haensch</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/small-town-police-accountability-a-data-science-toolkit.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Subpoenas Less Scary</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/subpoenas-less-scary.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your users have entrusted their data to you. But what happens when a law enforcement government agency demands you share the data with them? We will demystify the process of receiving and responding to law enforcement’s demands for data. We demonstrate how designing around privacy can limit what needs to be shared. To make subpoenas less scary, we break them down as a technical process, and share the protections we implemented at Mozilla. If you want to understand the real-world impact of your approaches to privacy, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rebecca BurWei</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/subpoenas-less-scary.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>tfmodisco-lite: an attribution based motif discovery algorithm | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/tfmodisco-lite-an-attribution-based-motif-discovery-algorithm-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important problem in genomics is identifying the proteins that bind to DNA. Although many methods attempt to learn DNA motifs underlying protein binding as position-weight matrices (PWMs), these PWMs cannot faithfully represent real biology. For instance, a static PWM cannot describe a zinc-finger protein whose fingers can optionally include one-nucleotide spacing. TF-MoDISco is a framework for extracting motifs using attribution scores from a machine-learning model. The learned motifs and syntax overcome many of the limitations presented by PWM. I will describe the TF-MoDISco algorithm and showcase its efficient re-implementation, tfmodisco-lite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Schreiber</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/tfmodisco-lite-an-attribution-based-motif-discovery-algorithm-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Thar Be Dragons: Ethical, Legal, and Policy Challenges When Measuring Open Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/thar-be-dragons-ethical-legal-and-policy-challenges-when-measuring-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source researchers are increasingly challenged while navigating the data which open source communities inherently create when working in the open. While mining software repositories for insights into open source practices isn't new, moving beyond code analysis into ecosystems-level research does not have a clear path. This talk will outline the current ethical, legal, and policy challenges community leaders, as well as researchers in academia and industry face and the ambiguous areas decision makers should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amanda Casari</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/thar-be-dragons-ethical-legal-and-policy-challenges-when-measuring-open-source.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>The largest standardized single-cell data repository by CZ CELLxGENE Discover</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/the-largest-standardized-single-cell-data-repository-by-cz-cellxgene-discover.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy is organized by NumFOCUS, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that promotes open source scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pablo Garcia-Nieto</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/the-largest-standardized-single-cell-data-repository-by-cz-cellxgene-discover.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Tidy Geospatial Cubes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/tidy-geospatial-cubes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The open-source project, Xarray, combines labeled data structures inspired by Pandas with NumPy-like multi-dimensional arrays to provide an intuitive and scalable interface for scientific analysis. Xarray has strong user bases in the physical sciences and geospatial community. However, new users commonly struggle to fit their dataset into the Xarray model and with conceptualizing and constructing an Xarray object that makes subsequent analysis steps easy (“dataset wrangling”). We take inspiration from the “tidy data” concept for dataframes — “datasets structured to facilitate analysis” (Wickham, 2014) — and attempt a definition of tidy data for labeled array objects provided by Xarray.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deepak Cherian</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/tidy-geospatial-cubes.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>To brew, distill, &amp; mix force fields with balanced briskness, smoothness, &amp; intricacy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/to-brew-distill-mix-force-fields-with-balanced-briskness-smoothness-intricacy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Force fields (FF)—the (parametrized) mapping from geometry to energy, are a crucial component of molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, whose associated Boltzmann-like target probability densities are sampled to estimate ensemble observables, to harvest quantitative insights of the system. State-of-the-art force fields are either fast (molecular mechanics, MM-based) or accurate (quantum mechanics, QM-based), but seldom both. Here, leveraging graph-based machine learning and incorporating inductive biases crucial to chemical modeling, we approach the balance between accuracy and speed from two angles---to make MM more accurate and to make machine learning force fields faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yuanqinq Wang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/to-brew-distill-mix-force-fields-with-balanced-briskness-smoothness-intricacy.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Toward Array Interoperability in the Scientific Python Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/toward-array-interoperability-in-the-scientific-python-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The array API standard (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://data-apis.org/array-api/"&gt;https://data-apis.org/array-api/&lt;/a&gt;) is a common specification for Python array libraries, such as NumPy, PyTorch, CuPy, Dask, and JAX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This standard will make it straightforward for array-consuming libraries, like scikit-learn and SciPy, to write code that uniformly supports all of these libraries. This will allow, for instance, running the same code on the CPU and GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover the scope of the array API standard, supporting tooling which includes a library-independent test suite and compatibility layer, what work has been completed so far, and the plans going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Meurer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/toward-array-interoperability-in-the-scientific-python-ecosystem.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Ultrafast visualization of large datasets | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/ultrafast-visualization-of-large-datasets-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/fastplotlib/fastplotlib"&gt;https://github.com/fastplotlib/fastplotlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast interactive visualization remains a considerable barrier in analyses pipelines for large neuronal datasets. Here, we present fastplotlib, a scientific plotting library featuring an expressive API for very fast visualization of scientific data. Fastplotlib is built upon pygfx which utilizes the GPU via WGPU, allowing it to interface with modern graphics APIs such as Vulkan for fast rendering of objects. Fastplotlib is non-blocking, allowing for interactivity with data after plot generation. Ultimately, fastplotlib is a general purpose scientific plotting library that is useful for the fast and live visualization and analysis of complex datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kushal Kolar</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/ultrafast-visualization-of-large-datasets-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Using Linear Tracking Data to Estimate Backcountry Recreation Popularity</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/using-linear-tracking-data-to-estimate-backcountry-recreation-popularity.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geolocated data from smartphone apps are well-established resources for research. While most of that data come as points (e.g., geotagged photos), there are a growing number of apps that collect linear data from users activities (e.g., running, hiking, off-road driving). Using established ecological methods, shallow-machine learning packages, and multiprocessing we demonstrate a novel approach using mobile app data to estimate back-country recreation popularity at multiple scales. The topics covered include normalizing and thinning coordinate data, merging linear data from multiple sources, and accounting for spatial bias while preserving the integrity of the original data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David C. Folch</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/using-linear-tracking-data-to-estimate-backcountry-recreation-popularity.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Using Numba for GPU Acceleration of Neutron Beamline Digital Twins</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/using-numba-for-gpu-acceleration-of-neutron-beamline-digital-twins.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss how Numba was used to accelerate MCViNE, a software environment for building and running digital twins of neutron experiments via Monte Carlo ray tracing. Numba is an open-source JIT compiler for Python using LLVM to generate efficient machine code for CPUs and GPUs with NVIDIA CUDA. Python and Numba were used to create a GPU accelerated version of MCViNE utilizing an extensible object-oriented design that has achieved a speedup of up to 1000x over the CPU. The performance gain with Numba enables more sophisticated data analysis and impacts neutron scattering science and instrument design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Coleman Kendrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/using-numba-for-gpu-acceleration-of-neutron-beamline-digital-twins.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Using Python to accelerate sustainable aviation fuel research and development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/using-python-to-accelerate-sustainable-aviation-fuel-research-and-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy is organized by NumFOCUS, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that promotes open source scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ana Comesana</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/using-python-to-accelerate-sustainable-aviation-fuel-research-and-development.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>UXarray, a python library for unstructured climate and weather data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/uxarray-a-python-library-for-unstructured-climate-and-weather-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;UXarray aims to provide xarray-styled functionality for unstructured grid datasets. UXarray offers support for loading and representing unstructured grids by utilizing existing Xarray functionality paired with new routines that are specifically written for operating on unstructured grids. In this talk, we will present the current capabilities of the library: reading and writing of unstructured grids, reading of datasets along with basic grid operations and the need to speed up computations, integration operations along with details on speedups obtained by using Numba and python indexing. We will also demonstrate the use of this library for visualization of unstructured grids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rajeev Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/uxarray-a-python-library-for-unstructured-climate-and-weather-data.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>vak: neural network models for acoustic behavior</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/vak-neural-network-models-for-acoustic-behavior.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research on animal acoustic communication is being revolutionized by deep learning. In this talk we present vak, a framework that allows researchers in this area to easily benchmark deep neural network models and apply them to their own data. We'll demonstrate how research groups are using vak through examples with TweetyNet, a model that automates annotation of birdsong by segmenting spectrograms. Then we'll show how adopting Lightning as a backend in version 1.0 has allowed us to incorporate more models and features, building on the foundation we put in place with help from the scientific Python stack.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Nicholson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/vak-neural-network-models-for-acoustic-behavior.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>View, annotate, and analyze multi-dimensional images in Python with napari</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/view-annotate-and-analyze-multi-dimensional-images-in-python-with-napari.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;napari is an n-dimensional image viewer for Python. If you’ve ever tried plt.imshow(arr) and made Matplotlib unhappy because arr has more than two dimensions, then napari might be for you! napari will gladly display higher-dimensional arrays by providing sliders to explore additional dimensions. But napari can also: overlay derived data, such as points, segmentations, polygons, surfaces, and more; and annotate and edit these data, using standard data structures like NumPy or Zarr arrays, allowing you to seamlessly weave exploration, computation, and annotation in image analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juan Nunez-Iglesias</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/view-annotate-and-analyze-multi-dimensional-images-in-python-with-napari.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>What happens when the main maintainer of a project takes a step down?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/what-happens-when-the-main-maintainer-of-a-project-takes-a-step-down.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once a maintainer of a project decides to step down of a project, the community needs to quickly adapt to this decision. This situation can be devastating for small projects and lead to their extinction. This talk demonstrates, based on the case of poliastro, that the community is a key factor for a software to survive no matter who is leading it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jorge Martinez</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/what-happens-when-the-main-maintainer-of-a-project-takes-a-step-down.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>When and How to Try with Your Own C-Extensions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/when-and-how-to-try-with-your-own-c-extensions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the NumPy C API lets developers write C that builds or evaluates arrays, just writing C is often not enough to outperform NumPy. NumPy's usage of Single Instruction Multiple Data routines, as well as multi-source compiling, provide optimizations that are impossible to beat with simple C. This presentation offers principles to help determine if an array-processing routine, implemented as a C-extension, might outperform NumPy called from Python. A C-extension implementing a narrow use case of the np.nonzero() routine will be studied as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Ariza</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/when-and-how-to-try-with-your-own-c-extensions.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item></channel></rss>