<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Architecture of CPython, the bricks!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/architecture-of-cpython-the-bricks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contribution to CPython is really funny, you can learn how the language
is designed, but you want to know where you should start when you have a
patch to provide. In this talk, I will explain the several components of
CPython and the architecture, how is the code designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="stephane-wirtel-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stéphane Wirtel Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stéphane is Belgian software hacker, engaged and dad. Organiser of
PythonFOSDEM, &amp;#64;ThePSF Fellow, EuroPython Society Member and Member of
Association Francophone de Python and former OpenERP Core Dev (6y). He
has received a Community Service Award from the Python Software
Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think distributed, asynchronous and others interesting subjects,
he will be happy to discuss with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stéphane Wirtel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/architecture-of-cpython-the-bricks.html</guid></item><item><title>Building a HackASac</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/building-a-hackasac.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build a HackASac! Paul's been wheeling a large toolbox
around the conference. Come find out what's inside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Mullins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/building-a-hackasac.html</guid></item><item><title>CPython internals: why bother?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/cpython-internals-why-bother.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you've heard that the Python interpreter you use is called &amp;quot;CPython.&amp;quot;
It's written in C! But who cares? Why should you even bother to learn
more? Could this ever be helpful? Could it help you debug your code or
answer questions about how the language works? Thirty minutes is an
awful lot of time to spend saying &amp;quot;no, just forget about it&amp;quot;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="james-powell-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;James Powell Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James is a volunteer at NumFOCUS, the 501(c)3 non-profit that supports
and promotes open source in data science, data analytics, and scientific
computing. At NumFOCUS, he serves as an office of the board, helping to
organize the PyData conference series. He also helps run New York's
local python meetup groups, NYC Python and Learn Python NYC, and is a
past-chair and current organizer for the New York Python conference,
PyGotham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Powell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/cpython-internals-why-bother.html</guid></item><item><title>Deep learning techniques for predictive analytics using Python: Theano vs TensorFlow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/deep-learning-techniques-for-predictive-analytics-using-python-theano-vs-tensorflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predictive analytics uses statistical and machine learning techniques to
provide a best assessment of what will happen in the future.
Understanding the future can guide current decisions. This talk will
provide a quick guide on using deep learning approaches in building
predictive models in python. It will give a brief introduction to
predictive models, deep learning, Tensorflow and Thenao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="allaa-hilal-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Allaa Hilal Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allaa R. Hillal has 10+ years’ experience in Data Intelligence, IoT, and
Intelligent systems design. She has a Doctorate degree in Pattern
Analysis and Machine Intelligence from the Electrical and Computer
Engineering at University of Waterloo. Dr. Hilal has been granted
numerous prestigious awards and has also been recognized as one of the
most influential women in the M2M and IoT space by the Connected World
Magazine. She has always been a big supporter of women in Science
Technology and engineering and an active member of women engineering
chapter in the University of Waterloo over the past 9 years now. She is
also the Champion of Women in Technology peer to peer group in Waterloo
and has been working on mentoring young girls and women, of all ages,
throughout the past 3 years. She is also an adjunct assistant professor
at the University of Waterloo in the pattern analysis and Data
Intelligence lab. Currently, she holds the position of Innovation Lead
at Intelligent Mechatronic Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Allaa Hilal</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/deep-learning-techniques-for-predictive-analytics-using-python-theano-vs-tensorflow.html</guid></item><item><title>Embrace the mistake</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/embrace-the-mistake.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without mistakes, there is no knowledge. We must make wrong predictions
to learn, and we must try the impossible to break out of our
complacency. This talk will explore the key role mistakes play in our
own minds, our attempts to build AIs, and our practice as programmers.
We are going to argue that mistakes are your best friend and offer some
guidance on how to make more of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mike-c-fletcher-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mike C. Fletcher Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Fletcher is a design epistemologist (someone who studies the
formation of knowledge or belief) by training, currently running a small
programming consultancy in Toronto. He has been programming Python since
1995. He is a PSF Fellow and the maintainer of a number of Open Source
projects, including PyOpenGL, RunSnakeRun, and OpenGLContext.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mike C. Fletcher</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/embrace-the-mistake.html</guid></item><item><title>Hacker’s guide to Neural Networks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/hackers-guide-to-neural-networks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we hear buzzwords like Recurrent Neural Nets, LSTM etc.
But don't know what is all that jargon and how or why these things work,
This talk will give you a decent introduction to Neural Networks (No
boring history lessons or the typical &amp;quot;neurons in brain&amp;quot; talk), and will
give introduction for a hacker to get started with neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="anoop-thomas-mathew-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anoop Thomas Mathew Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anoop a.k.a ATM is the Co-Founder and CTO of Profoundis
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.vibeapp.co"&gt;Vibe&lt;/a&gt;), a successfully bootstrapped
company, got &lt;em&gt;acquired by `FullContact &amp;lt;http://www.fullcontact.com&amp;gt;`__&lt;/em&gt;.
Leading the development effort for the entire product handling millions
of requests every month. Vibe internally uses machine learning for the
product to work as intended. Now he works as the Head of Technology,
India at &lt;strong&gt;fullcontact.com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anoop Thomas Mathew</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/hackers-guide-to-neural-networks.html</guid></item><item><title>Hockey Night at PyCon</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/hockey-night-at-pycon.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is used across various industries to help solve various problems.
Sports Analytics, the systematic analysis of information in the context
of various sports is one field where Python is a major contributor in
competition with R. In this discussion I outline the most common uses of
Python in my work in the National Hockey League to help improve
management's decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="joshua-weissbock-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Joshua Weissbock Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh Weissbock works in the federal government by day in Victoria BC. He
has been involved in hockey analytics for the past half decade from his
early days of public researching in the hockey analytics blogosphere and
CanucksArmy.com. He has studied hockey analytics in the context of
applications for Machine Learning at the University of Ottawa and is now
applying his trade with the Florida Panthers in the National Hockey
league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joshua Weissbock</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/hockey-night-at-pycon.html</guid></item><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks in the cloud</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/jupyter-notebooks-in-the-cloud.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks provide a way to do &amp;quot;literate computing&amp;quot; where
documents contain their own live code and visualizations. And while
getting started with notebooks is easy, using cloud-based hosting like
Azure Notebooks makes it even easier to get started and share your
results. This talk will explain what notebooks are and talk about
benefits (and drawbacks) of hosting them in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brett-cannon-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Brett Cannon Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brett is part of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://azure.microsoft.com/"&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; Data
Science Tools team at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.microsoft.com/"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; where
he works on various &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/pythonengineering/"&gt;Python
engineering&lt;/a&gt;
problems. He has been a core developer of Python itself for over 13
years and mucked around with pretty much every part of Python at this
point. At this point Brett just hopes he can continue to live up to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2016/05/brett-cannon-wins-frank-%20willison-award.html"&gt;winning the 2016 Frank Willison
Award&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brett Cannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/jupyter-notebooks-in-the-cloud.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/lightning-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various lightning talks&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephane Wirtel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/lightning-talks.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Living in a land down dunder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/living-in-a-land-down-dunder.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover some common uses of dunder methods and some not so
common. It will also lightly cover the process of editing the C Python
source in order to add your own operator/dunder method combo to the C
Python interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="paul-logston-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Paul Logston Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Logston is a New York City based developer. He helps organize and
run the NYC Python, Learn Python NYC, and PyGotham events that take
place in NYC. He works at 15Five and teaches at Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Logston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/living-in-a-land-down-dunder.html</guid></item><item><title>Monty Python for pythonistas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/monty-python-for-pythonistas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of things in the python universe are named after Month Python
references - references that we python programmers may not understand,
and may not even be able to spot as jokes. I have collected some of
these and will share them with you, for your edification and amusement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sa-friend-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;sa friend Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sa friend is a designer and developer currently studying at Recurse
Center in NYC. Before that, she was the senior designer and production
director at Guild Eyewear, a start up making mass-customizable glasses.
She is also the founder of Small Talk, an Interdisciplinary Lecture
Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">sa friend</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/monty-python-for-pythonistas.html</guid></item><item><title>Mutants and immutants: the missing types</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/mutants-and-immutants-the-missing-types.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A thought experiment exploring what a symmetrical type system would look
like in Python. Mutable ints, floats, and strs? Immutable dicts? What
would they be called, how would they behave, and would they even be
useful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sye-van-der-veen-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sye van der Veen Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior Software Engineer at Zenreach. I have been marvelling at the
elegance and simplicity of Python code for over 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sye van der Veen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/mutants-and-immutants-the-missing-types.html</guid></item><item><title>Not on the shelves: what nonexistent books, tools, and courses can tell us about ourselves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/not-on-the-shelves-what-nonexistent-books-tools-and-courses-can-tell-us-about-ourselves.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of books about compilers, but only three about
writing debuggers. Spreadsheets are used more than any other statistical
tool, but version control still can't handle them. Everyone thinks we
should teach kids to program, but courses on computing education are
almost nonexistent. This talk explores why these gaps exist and what
they tell us about computing today and in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="greg-wilson-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Greg Wilson Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Wilson is the co-founder of Software Carpentry, a volunteer
organization that teaches basic computing skills to researchers in a
wide range of disciplines. He has worked for 30 years in both industry
and academia, and is the author or editor of several books on computing
(including the 2008 Jolt Award winner &amp;quot;Beautiful Code&amp;quot;) and two for
children. Greg received a Ph.D. in Computer Science from the University
of Edinburgh in 1993.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Greg Wilson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/not-on-the-shelves-what-nonexistent-books-tools-and-courses-can-tell-us-about-ourselves.html</guid></item><item><title>Overcoming life’s hurdles</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/overcoming-lifes-hurdles.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Believing in your dreams is one of the most important steps you'll take
in goal setting. While many of us can come up with things we want to
accomplish, it is the emotional connection we make with the dream by
believing in its possibility that lead us to action and accomplishments.
For Olympian Sarah Wells, this belief was mandatory to fuel her Olympic
dream after a devastating stress fracture in her leg threatened her
chance of making the team. Sarah's story is one of guts, courage and
perseverance. Audiences will leave inspired to dream big, overcome
obstacles and of course believe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sarah-wells-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sarah Wells Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Wells is a Canadian Olympian specializing in the 400m hurdles.
Recruited by her high school teacher, Sarah fell in love with the sport
of track and 15 years old and field and joined the Toronto Track club in
2005. With only 8 months of training under her belt, Sarah qualified for
her first national team and travelled to Morocco Marrakesh to represent
Canada. Since then Sarah has been a 4-time National Champion and a
7-time National Team member. In 2012, after winning the Canadian
National Championships for the 3rd time in her career, Sarah represented
Canada in the London Olympics and finished as an Olympic Semi Finalist.
Following the Olympics, Sarah continued progressing and came home a
double-medallist from the 2015 Pan-American games held in her home city
of Toronto. Sarah has overcome many obstacles in her career and has set
her sights on becoming a 2-time Olympian at the 2020 Olympics in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sarah Wells</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/overcoming-lifes-hurdles.html</guid></item><item><title>Painful serverless</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/painful-serverless.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last 2 years, serverless architecture has become a huge trend.
Amazon Lambdas is one of the first function as a service solution which
I have used since its early beginning. This talk covers the pain it can
be to set up a REST API operating AWS API Gateway &amp;amp; Lambdas, the
solutions and practices to overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hadrien-david-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Hadrien David Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hadrien is a software engineer at Dialogue.co, and is currently
developing a service for better healthcare for Canadians. Member of
Montreal Python user group, passionated about team work and open source
culture, he spends a lot of time designing software architecture and
riding his bicycle whether it rains or snows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hadrien David</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/painful-serverless.html</guid></item><item><title>Pragmatic microservices for the rest of us</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/pragmatic-microservices-for-the-rest-of-us.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will explore taking the core concepts of microservices
and building them into the architecture of a monolith in an attempt to
get the best of both worlds. This approach establishes a pragmatic
baseline architecture that can cleanly evolve to distributed
microservices when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ryan-easterbrook-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ryan Easterbrook Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan Easterbrook is a systems engineer specializing in designing and
building scalable, resilient, and highly versatile system architectures
to support a wide variety of applications from web to mobile. For the
past five years he's been working on platforms to support SaaS products
at great companies such as EventMobi and Firmex, and before that spent
two years at a startup developing the backend for social massively
multiplayer online games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Easterbrook</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/pragmatic-microservices-for-the-rest-of-us.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and the Blockchain</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/python-and-the-blockchain.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A high level presentation which will cover working with the popular
public blockchains: Bitcoin, Ethereum and Stellar with python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the presentation is that attendees will understand high
level the various popular public blockchains using python and how
potentially they could use these in their next application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="anthony-barker-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anthony Barker Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony has managed or worked on various projects using python over the
past decade and is particularly interested in leveraging python in the
financial technology (fintech) space for companies such as Bank of
Montreal and National Bank as well as start ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anthony Barker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/python-and-the-blockchain.html</guid></item><item><title>Python -&gt; Iron Python -&gt; SQL Server</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/python-iron-python-sql-server.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working with Python in a Windows environment can present some unorthodox
challenges. In one such challenge we'll explore one solution for cases
when you want to communicate with a SQL Server database and cannot use
pyodbc. The solution demonstrates how to create a small library in Iron
Python which can take advantage of the .NET CLR that is responsible for
communicating with SQL Server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="matt-mcgraw-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Matt McGraw Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After five years of working in corporate finance and business
intelligence, Matt has shifted his career focus to software development.
The Python community has played a major role in supporting the
transition and now he uses Python to help build enterprise information
systems in the automotive industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matt McGraw</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/python-iron-python-sql-server.html</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying the visual structure of written language</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/quantifying-the-visual-structure-of-written-language.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk details how a distributed application was used to
algorithmically compare pairs of Chinese characters for use in
psycholinguistic research. By programmatically representing the
structure of Chinese characters, it is possible to quantify the
similarity of two characters in the same way it is possible to quantify
the similarity of two English words by comparing their constituent
letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="nick-anderegg-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Nick Anderegg Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick is an MSc student in Cognitive Psychology at Western University,
with a primary research area in reading, phonology, and computational
psycholinguistics. He earned a BPhil degree in Linguistics and a BA
degree in Psychology from Penn State University. He's primarily
interested in understanding universal reading processes that speakers of
different languages have in common, and how cross-linguistic differences
in writing systems and phonology interact with these processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nick Anderegg</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/quantifying-the-visual-structure-of-written-language.html</guid></item><item><title>Securing Your company’s data: encryption, deletion and other best practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/securing-your-companys-data-encryption-deletion-and-other-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your company is storing customer information, then it's a safe bet
that hackers will try to steal it. What are the best practices for
securing your customer data? Covering topics such as encryption,
deletion and hiring a CISO, this talk is for developers and
entrepreneurs seeking to learn more about best practices for information
security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="elissa-shevinsky-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Elissa Shevinsky Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elissa Shevinsky is a serial entrepreneur, author, and privacy activist.
She joined her first startup (Geekcorps) in 1999, and most recently
worked on the Brave browser. Shevinsky is currently Managing Director at
Kearney Boyle &amp;amp; Associates, where she focusing on fixing one of the most
broken parts of technology - recruiting. Shevinsky is also the editor of
the critically acclaimed book, &amp;quot;Lean Out.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elissa Shevinsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/securing-your-companys-data-encryption-deletion-and-other-best-practices.html</guid></item><item><title>Simple made easy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/simple-made-easy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 30-year computing crisis rages on because it is too hard to do a
good job! Here we present a new and improved DevOps paradigm, which
makes it easy to build simple and reliable systems. This is a Software
Silver Bullet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="steve-jackson-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Steve Jackson Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an Electrical Engineer and I have been programming since 1968. CEO
of a private company for 30 years, developing and manufacturing embedded
systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steve Jackson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/simple-made-easy.html</guid></item><item><title>Sunday Morning keynote</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/sunday-morning-keynote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning something new can often spark new connections in our minds.
Very recently, I started running and focusing on fitness --
and discovered numberous revelations about programming in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll share what just six months of running has shown me
about my six years in the software industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Safia Abdalla</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/sunday-morning-keynote.html</guid></item><item><title>Using Python to power Selenium at scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/using-python-to-power-selenium-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can Python use Selenium to take command of a web browser and step it
through thousands of tests that have to run hundreds of times per day?
What anti-patterns emerge when an organization has been maintaining a
Selenium test suite for multiple years? At Dropbox, I and my co-workers
use Python to deliver test results to hundreds of other engineers. Come
learn the lessons we have learned so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brandon-rhodes-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Brandon Rhodes Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandon Rhodes works at Dropbox where he strives to deliver a
world-class Python development environment to his fellow Dropboxers. His
most popular open source projects are astronomy libraries for Python
that he has been maintaining since the late 1990s. He speaks at several
Python conferences a year, and in 2016–2017 is the Chair of the main
worldwide PyCon conference as it is held in Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brandon Rhodes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/using-python-to-power-selenium-at-scale.html</guid></item><item><title>Where we came from, what’s special about now, and where we might go</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/where-we-came-from-whats-special-about-now-and-where-we-might-go.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on interviews with leading developers of Python and with Python,
we take a look at how the Python language specification and the
reference implementation are developed. The subcommunity of core
developers not only produces a great programming language that's fun to
use, but sets the tone for a vibrant, productive, and inclusive
community of user-developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="stephen-j-turnbull-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stephen J Turnbull Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Known as the Unwelome Guest on several channels because he professes the
Dismal Science of Economics, Steve nonetheless has found a ray of light
among the zero-profit theorems: open source software and the communities
that develop, support, and use it. He teaches in Japan, where he learned
the virtues of Unicode from living in an environment with 5 different
encodings (and many nonstandard variants) in use for the same language.
He was introduced to Python development during the discussion of PEP 263
(which appropriately enough allows you to be explicit about encoding of
Python programs), when he was turned into a newt by none other than GvR
for the sin of misusing the word &amp;quot;pythonic&amp;quot;. (It got better!) He mentors
in GSoC for Systers &amp;amp; GNU Mailman, and spends what's left of his free
time fighting DMARC to make the Internet safe for mailing lists again.
He's also been know to write Emacs Lisp (ssh! it's a dirty secret!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen J Turnbull</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/where-we-came-from-whats-special-about-now-and-where-we-might-go.html</guid></item><item><title>Word! Automating a Hip-hop word of the day blog</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/word-automating-a-hip-hop-word-of-the-day-blog.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been surprised by sophisticated vocabulary used by some
hip-hop artists? With standard data science tools, I search a large
corpus of hip-hop lyrics in order to extract rhyming couplets that
include uncommon and interesting words. Using curated output from this
code, I demonstrate how to automate the creation of short text-based
posts for a hip-hop themed &amp;quot;Word of the Day&amp;quot; blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="christopher-ing-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Christopher Ing Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris is a PhD student at University of Toronto studying computational
biochemistry. He has degrees in computational physics and physics from
University of Waterloo. He has converted countless graduate students to
Python in the wake of his scientific career, not to mention, he's a
minor celebrity on Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Ing</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/word-automating-a-hip-hop-word-of-the-day-blog.html</guid></item><item><title>A concrete approach to abstractions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/a-concrete-approach-to-abstractions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstractions make things appear simple. This is one of the main concepts
behind OOP. So what is it?! This talk provides some guidelines on how to
achieve scalable abstractions and demystify some of the confusion around
it. One could say, I'll try to abstract the abstraction itself :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="terry-yanchynskyy-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Terry Yanchynskyy Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terry (Taras) is a software engineer on the Payments team at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.waveapps.com/"&gt;Wave&lt;/a&gt;. He is a co-organizer of Pycon
Canada 2016 and 2015. Before Wave, he was on the brandstem™ team at St
Joseph Communications. He also bears a few personal projects behind his
belt. His path to software engineering comes from a distant medical
degree, but he was always more fascinated by the &amp;quot;physiology&amp;quot; of the
computation. He also enjoys casual rides on his motorcycle, travelling,
and rock climbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Terry Yanchynskyy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/a-concrete-approach-to-abstractions.html</guid></item><item><title>An end to boring data with visualizations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/an-end-to-boring-data-with-visualizations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put the days of trying to decipher meaning from boring spreadsheets
behind you. Visualize data to give greater and immediate meaning to all
those numbers with Python. Explore the variety of options available for
data visualization in Python using different libraries and understand
which ones excel for what type of task. Create maps, statistical graphs
and more detailed or interactive visualization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="heather-shapiro-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Heather Shapiro Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heather Shapiro is a Technical Evangelist in Microsoft's Developer
Experience group, where she educates developers on Microsoft's new
technologies. In this role, Heather works closely with students and
developer communities across the North East to understand the newest
technologies and architectures. Prior to becoming a Technical
Evangelist, Heather completed her undergraduate degree at Duke
University and graduated in the Class of 2015. She received Bachelors of
Science in Computer Science and Statistical Science, and completed an
Honors Thesis about employing Bayesian Approaches to Understanding Music
Popularity. Heather blogs at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://microheather.com"&gt;http://microheather.com&lt;/a&gt; and tweets at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/microheather"&gt;http://twitter.com/microheather&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Heather Shapiro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/an-end-to-boring-data-with-visualizations.html</guid></item><item><title>Async tasks with Django Channels</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/async-tasks-with-django-channels.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Channels is the most exciting thing to happen to Django since, well,
Django! It is both an elegant and backwards compatible extension of the
core Django request response model to allow direct support of WebSockets
and lightweight async tasks. This talk will cover the current state of
Channels, work through an asynchronous task example, touch on deployment
and point towards other resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="albert-o-connor-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Albert O'Connor Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freelance Django developer with over 5 years over independent
contracting for business, startups and institutions. Instigator
including WatPy the Waterloo Region Python Users Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Albert O’Connor</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/async-tasks-with-django-channels.html</guid></item><item><title>Automate your data analysis testing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/automate-your-data-analysis-testing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scientific Python ecosystem has made a Python a great language for
data analysis, encouraging readable and expressive code, but data
analysts struggle with applying Python test frameworks to their data
transformation and analysis code. This talk will give a good starting
point: how to compare different versions of tabular data and turn that
into automated tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="stephen-childs-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stephen Childs Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Childs has been working with Python for the past three years,
primarily using the language for data analysis. Originally from Thunder
Bay, Ontario, Stephen has called Toronto, Vancouver, Kitchener-Waterloo,
Ottawa home. Currently he works at the University of Calgary as an
Institutional Analyst. Stephen uses Python for many aspects of the job,
but it's main use is to apply predictive models to university data.
Stephen is the founder and one of the organizers of PyData Calgary,
which promotes of the use of Python and other Open Source tools for data
analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Childs</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/automate-your-data-analysis-testing.html</guid></item><item><title>Building and managing diverse engineering teams</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/building-and-managing-diverse-engineering-teams.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it's to serve a diverse customer base or to cultivate a more
inclusive office environment, companies are ramping up efforts to hire
(and retain) diverse technical candidates. This talk covers best
practices for all steps in this process - recruiting, hiring and
retaining diverse Python engineers (and their teammates) as well as
keeping team dynamics harmonious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="elissa-shevinsky-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Elissa Shevinsky Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elissa Shevinsky is a serial entrepreneur, author, and privacy activist.
She joined her first startup (Geekcorps) in 1999, and most recently
worked on the Brave browser. Shevinsky is currently Managing Director at
Kearney Boyle &amp;amp; Associates, where she focusing on fixing one of the most
broken parts of technology - recruiting. Shevinsky is also the editor of
the critically acclaimed book, &amp;quot;Lean Out.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elissa Shevinsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/building-and-managing-diverse-engineering-teams.html</guid></item><item><title>Building the Real-time Web with Python and aiohttp</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/building-the-real-time-web-with-python-and-aiohttp.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's the real-time web? Can I build it myself? In Python? Of course
you can! This talk will help Python web developers learn how to
integrate real-time components with their existing web applications
using &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;asyncio&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;aiohttp&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="steven-seguin-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Steven Seguin Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full-stack developer at SurveyMonkey in Ottawa working on real-time and
collaboration features. Holds strong opinions about distributed systems,
functional programming, and API design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven Seguin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/building-the-real-time-web-with-python-and-aiohttp.html</guid></item><item><title>Circuit simulator for power electronics: Python power electronics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/circuit-simulator-for-power-electronics-python-power-electronics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simulating large systems with multiple power electronic converters is a
challenge due to the non-linear nature of the circuit and the necessity
to model the associated control systems with each converter. Python
Power Electronics aims to provide a free and open source solution that
can be used by both academics and industry professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="shivkumar-v-iyer-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shivkumar V. Iyer Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Power Electronics Engineer at a start-up in Kingston, ON that
develops solar microinverters. As a power electronics engineer my
primary interest is in simulating large electrical systems with multiple
power electronic converters. For this purpose, I am developing my own
free and open source circuit simulator called Python Power Electronics
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pythonpowerelectronics.com/"&gt;http://www.pythonpowerelectronics.com/&lt;/a&gt;). This circuit simulator has
been developed purely in Python and began with a blog
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pythonpowerelectronics.blogspot.ca/"&gt;http://pythonpowerelectronics.blogspot.ca/&lt;/a&gt;) and a project hosting on
SourceForge (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/pythonpowerelec/"&gt;https://sourceforge.net/projects/pythonpowerelec/&lt;/a&gt;). The
website (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pythonpowerelectronics.com/"&gt;http://www.pythonpowerelectronics.com/&lt;/a&gt;) now contains all parts
of the project including case studies and examples and also
documentation on how to use the software. My primary interest lies in
simulating power systems with renewable energy systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shivkumar V. Iyer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/circuit-simulator-for-power-electronics-python-power-electronics.html</guid></item><item><title>Creating a contemporary lending risk management system using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/creating-a-contemporary-lending-risk-management-system-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lending involves risk and in order to be a successful lender at scale
that risk needs to be mitigated. We'll be discussing how C2FO has built
a suite of risk management tools for underwriting and portfolio
management using the PyData ecosystem, rpy2 (for integrating R), and
Spyre (for building a simple web application).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="piero-ferrante-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Piero Ferrante Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piero Ferrante is the Director of Data Science at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://c2fo.com/"&gt;C2FO&lt;/a&gt;. He and his team are focused on optimizing
C2FO’s capital markets through applied machine learning and the
development of quantitative risk management systems. In the past he has
applied his expertise in healthcare, telecom, insurance, and mobile
advertising at Fortune 500 companies and startups. He holds a M.S. in
Predictive Analytics from Northwestern University, a B.S. in Finance and
Management Information Systems from the University of Delaware, and is
an adjunct professor of Text Analytics at Rockhurst University. Piero
also helps organize the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/Data-Science-KC/"&gt;Kansas City Data Science
Meetup&lt;/a&gt; and advises &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://playithealth.com/index.html"&gt;Play-it
Heath&lt;/a&gt;, a digital health
engagement solution, on algorithms and data strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piero Ferrante</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/creating-a-contemporary-lending-risk-management-system-using-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Databases 201: the power of the relational algebra and limits of the ORM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/databases-201-the-power-of-the-relational-algebra-and-limits-of-the-orm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most common understanding of databases stop at persistence and
retrieval which leaves the power of the relational database as a compute
engine under- appreciated and under-utilized. This talk is an
exploration of that computational power, the relationship of this
compute engine and the ORM, and how to leverage this power in your
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wesley-george-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Wesley George Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wesley George is Software Engineer operating out of Toronto, San
Francisco and Thunder Bay. A specialist in computer security and
cryptography, Wes was an early member at Toronto's Nymi before recently
moving to another Toronto tech startup, the financial tech company
Clearbanc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wes gets excited by challenging problems, clean solutions, power tools,
ultimate frisbee, and Python conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley George</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/databases-201-the-power-of-the-relational-algebra-and-limits-of-the-orm.html</guid></item><item><title>Extending Python with Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/extending-python-with-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted lightning-fast code, without the segfaults and
tedious boilerplate of C? Then come learn why so many Pythonistas are
excited about Rust, a new language from Mozilla. After a short
introduction to the language, we'll see how the Rust Python bindings let
us easily write elegant, safe, and high-performance extension modules,
hassle-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="samuel-cormier-iijima-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Samuel Cormier-Iijima Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samuel Cormier-Iijima is a senior engineer at SurveyMonkey. He
previously co- founded Fluidware, which grew to 80 employees before
being acquired in 2014. He is passionate about the web, cryptography,
computer science and mathematics, and contributes to a number of Python
and Rust open source projects. Samuel lives in Ottawa with his wife and
cat and plays the keys in his band, Cloud City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samuel Cormier-Iijima</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/extending-python-with-rust.html</guid></item><item><title>“Fabric”ating RESTful APIs for Linux</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/fabricating-restful-apis-for-linux.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing a HTTP-RESTful-API-based infrastructure provisioning system is
challenging. Concurrent users, race conditions, erroneous OS responses,
quota mechanisms etc. need to be wrapped up under a consistent and
responsive CRUD interface. The talk is about a few design patterns and
about the &amp;quot;lessons learnt&amp;quot; in building/operating/iterating a large scale
API-driven infra- provisioning system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sachin-agarwal-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sachin Agarwal Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="in-brief"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;In Brief&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python hacker with a day job in the infra/platform cloud space: devops
automation, monitoring, capacity planning, data mining logs,
virtualization/LXC-docker containerization, software-defined-*
(networking/storage/compute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="formal-stuff"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Formal Stuff&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="current"&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Current&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as an engineering manager for a infrastructure/platform software
development team at TD &amp;#64; Waterloo. Shameless plug - I am hiring Python
developers, especially those with infra/cloud/config management/devops
experience - in Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="previous"&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Previous&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage architect at blackberry - developer of a large scale
software-defined-storage all-flash system: Backend for 1000+ node
Cassandra cluster(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researcher at NEC Labs (Heidelberg, Germany) and Deutsche Telekom
Labs (Berlin, Germany), PhD - Boston University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sachin Agarwal</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/fabricating-restful-apis-for-linux.html</guid></item><item><title>From idea to production in 20 minutes: engineering at scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/from-idea-to-production-in-20-minutes-engineering-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shopify strives to be an ever moving company. With a strong force of
hundreds in the R&amp;amp;D team, the challenges to keep delivering and shipping
scaled accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a manual CLI that only ops could execute just a few years back, to
today’s automatic 180+ deploys a day, this talk will highlight the
different tools, processes and integrations used throughout the team
that fuels today's scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="jean-philippe-caissy-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jean-Philippe Caissy Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean-Philippe is a senior software developer at Shopify, working in
their Montreal's office. For the past 4 years, he helped organized the
local Montréal-Python user group. A seasoned Python and Ruby developer,
he likes to talk about scaling problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jean-Philippe Caissy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/from-idea-to-production-in-20-minutes-engineering-at-scale.html</guid></item><item><title>GitHub’s Deployments API: let GitHub be your deployment glue</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/githubs-deployments-api-let-github-be-your-deployment-glue.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Github's Deployments API allows Github itself to sit in the middle of
your deployment pipeline, acting as the glue needed to pull together
loosely- coupled deployment tooling. This talk will discuss how the
author used Github's Deployments API to connect a chatbot to a custom CI
server, allowing for chat-based deploys to a custom Docker-based
infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="jay-parlar-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jay Parlar Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay is a Hamilton-based software developer at Rackspace, working on
internal tools to improve the quality of life of his coworkers. He
spends his days writing JavaScript and Python, contributing both to
front-end and back-end systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He earned his Ph.D. in Software Engineering from McMaster University,
where he focused on hard real-time embedded systems and vibration
analysis, topics that have little-to-nothing to do with his current job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, Jay spends most of his time with his wife and three
kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jay Parlar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/githubs-deployments-api-let-github-be-your-deployment-glue.html</guid></item><item><title>G.Tool: a Python-based DSL for managing information security governance information</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/gtool-a-python-based-dsl-for-managing-information-security-governance-information.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security professionals don't have great tools for managing their
governance programs (audit, risk, system descriptions, etc.) and
typically need to buy very expensive tools or resort to using Excel
spreadsheets. G.Tool is an opensource python based framework that uses
pyparsing to implement a user DSL and file ORM for building your
security governance tools without writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ben-sapiro-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ben Sapiro Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the head of Security at Vision Critical (a SaaS company) and have
worked in both infosec consulting and operations since graduated from
b-school. I'm a regular contributor on the LiquidMatrix Podcast
(whenever we get around to recording it) and helps run BSidesTO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I built an internal tool (in Python) at work and it went
reasonably well to I decided so I decided to rebuild, from scratch, an
open source and generalized version of the tool to help security
professionals manage different information processes from audit
reporting to risk management and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a professional developer but I've dabbled with Python for
years. This is my first serious release in Python. Prior to this I
released an opensource tool called Binary Risk Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Sapiro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/gtool-a-python-based-dsl-for-managing-information-security-governance-information.html</guid></item><item><title>Hacking Cars with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/hacking-cars-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern cars are basically networks of computers, which control
everything from the engine to the airbags. We'll briefly cover how
vehicle networks work, then demonstrate how to access to the network
using Python and open-source hardware. Finally, we'll discuss some
attacks that can be performed on these systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Evenchick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/hacking-cars-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>High performance networking in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/high-performance-networking-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of async/await.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asyncio and uvloop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sockets, Protocols or Streams?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn by example: high-performance PostgreSQL driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="yury-selivanov-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Yury Selivanov Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yury Selivanov is an avid Python user for the last 10 years. He's a
CPython core developer since January 2013. He's one of the main
developers behind asyncio, and he authored and implemented PEP 492
(async/await) in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yury is an entrepreneur and technical leader with many years of
experience in software architecture and design. He's a partner at
MagicStack, a Toronto- based IT consultancy firm, which he co-founded in
2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yury Selivanov</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/high-performance-networking-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>How to make ** less expensive and more expressive</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/how-to-make-less-expensive-and-more-expressive.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exponentiation is the gotcha of math operators. Be it square or square
root, exp, log, tanh, or the complex roots of unity, ** has it's work
cut out. Ints, floats, fractions, and zero don't play nice with **.
Precision, accuracy, and performance aspects of Python can be revealed
by following ** thru the interpreter down to the metal. SciPy, SymPy,
and Machine Learners care, shouldn't you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="en-zyme-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;en zyme Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;en zyme has been a coder scientist for decades, traversing meteorology,
telecom, biotech, and was into data before it was big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;en zyme is the founder of Ad, Hock &amp;amp; Nimble [ a data consultancy] and of
40th Parallel Python. en zyme can be reached at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:en.zyme&amp;#64;40thparallelpython.com"&gt;en.zyme&amp;#64;40thparallelpython.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:enzyme&amp;#64;bu.edu"&gt;enzyme&amp;#64;bu.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">en zyme</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/how-to-make-less-expensive-and-more-expressive.html</guid></item><item><title>How to write maintainable code without tests</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/how-to-write-maintainable-code-without-tests.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While most people know test-driven development, in reality, not many
developers have a luxury of time to implement tests before product
delivery due to non-negotiable deadline or competitive business
opportunity. This talk will explore how to approach the problem,
technical considerations, and some useful design patterns which allows
developers to implement maintainable code before writing tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="juti-noppornpitak-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Juti Noppornpitak Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a software developer, a mathematician, a UX designer, and a
photography who is based in Toronto. I am currently with Statflo Inc. as
Senior Software Developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juti Noppornpitak</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/how-to-write-maintainable-code-without-tests.html</guid></item><item><title>Hypothesis: tests that write themselves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/hypothesis-tests-that-write-themselves.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing is generally seen as a Good Thing™ that one should do. Writing
tests that are comprehensive and cover all possibilities however can be
time- consuming, hard, or even downright impossible. Property-based
testing is one method that can help with this. This talk will introduce
the concept of property-based testing and how to do it yourself using
the Python library Hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="david-kua-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;David Kua Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David recently graduated from the undergraduate computer science program
at the University of Toronto and is not currently gainfully employed. He
has previously organized the Go Toronto meetup, the Canadian University
Software Engineering Conference (CUSEC), and is presently an organizer
of the Toronto chapter of Papers We Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Kua</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/hypothesis-tests-that-write-themselves.html</guid></item><item><title>Make some noise with Python and generate terrain</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/make-some-noise-with-python-and-generate-terrain.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will explore how seemingly simple functions can be layered together
to create complex and feature rich topological maps. Watch as each extra
layer introduces more interesting, diverse worlds which can be used as
images, in games, or as a playground for the curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="michael-mchugh-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Michael McHugh Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduced to Python a decade ago, I now work as a lead engineer at
Urban Airship. Originally from Southern Ontario, I moved to Portland,
Oregon 4 years ago. I use half a dozen languages on a weekly basis, but
Python has always been my go to for experimentation and productivity.
Owner of untold hundreds of half finished projects, seeing how far I can
push an idea is much more exciting to me than seeing something
completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael McHugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/make-some-noise-with-python-and-generate-terrain.html</guid></item><item><title>Managing large ensembles and batch execution with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/managing-large-ensembles-and-batch-execution-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many scientific applications it is necessary to run a large number of
similar experiments (i.e. ensembles). Using examples from my own
research, I will show how an Ensemble container class can be constructed
in Python to simplify many of the tedious aspects of performing large
sets of numerical experiments or simulations and to easily parallelize
batch execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="andre-r-erler-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Andre R. Erler Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andre is an early-career researcher in climate modeling and hydrology;
that means he runs climate models and hydrological models on high
performance computing facilities and analyses their output. He uses
primarily uses the scientific software stack in Python for data analysis
and visualization, but also uses Python to manage experiments with large
volumes of data (or &amp;quot;data plumbing&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andre is also interested in machine learning and the use of data science
techniques in and outside of climate science, and he is somewhat
concerned about the state of software development in science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source software, open science, the environment and sustainable
global development are the causes he cares most about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andre R. Erler</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/managing-large-ensembles-and-batch-execution-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Rub-a-dub rubber duck: don’t be afraid to debug!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scenario: You run into a bug, break your code-then you have to
figure out how to fix it. Do you want to learn what to do when your code
doesn’t work? How a rubber duck can help? This talk is for you! I’ll
present debugging strategies, how to prevent frustration, how to become
a more confident debugger, and where/how to get help. Breaking things is
the first step to learning how to fix them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="anna-ossowski-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anna Ossowski Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna is currently looking for a new people-focused role in tech. She is
a former director of the Python Software Foundation, PyCon Open
Spaces-Chair, DjangoCon US Communications Chair, and group leader of the
PyLadies Remote group. In her free time she loves speaking at
conferences and mentoring future speakers. Anna is very passionate about
diversity and community outreach and wants to encourage more women to
learn programming because it's awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</guid></item><item><title>Saturday Afternoon keynote</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/saturday-afternoon-keynote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote: Invitation to Core Developer World&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raymond Hettinger</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/saturday-afternoon-keynote.html</guid></item><item><title>Saturday Morning Keynote</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/saturday-morning-keynote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New Beginner -- Saturday Morning Keynote by Tracy Osborn&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tracy Osborn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/saturday-morning-keynote.html</guid></item><item><title>See Python, See Python Go, Go Python Go</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/see-python-see-python-go-go-python-go.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being able to run C code from Python is pretty great, but what about
running Go code from Python? Or even Python from Go? This talk will walk
through the process of executing calls between Python and Go using CFFI
bindings to bridge the two runtimes and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="andrey-petrov-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Andrey Petrov Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write a lot of open source software. My most popular projects are
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/shazow/urllib3"&gt;urllib3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/shazow/ssh-chat"&gt;ssh-
chat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like room-scale virtual reality, linux, and p2p systems. I'm a
Y-Combinator alumni and Xoogler. I am a Cat person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrey Petrov</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/see-python-see-python-go-go-python-go.html</guid></item><item><title>State of the PyVideo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/state-of-the-pyvideo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyVideo.org has undergone significant changes over the past year. It's
changed teams, infrastructure, and looks. Come hear about the progress
the PyVideo team is making and the direction in which PyVideo is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="paul-logston-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Paul Logston Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Logston is a New York City based developer. He helps organize and
run the NYC Python, Learn Python NYC, and PyGotham events that take
place in NYC. He works at 15Five and teaches at Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Logston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/state-of-the-pyvideo.html</guid></item><item><title>The art of writing wargames in Python with Kivy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/the-art-of-writing-wargames-in-python-with-kivy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of us got our start in programming, by building games and simple
apps. However creating interesting games and UIs in Python was not a
simple task especially for multiple platforms. Kivy, a cross-platform
Python UI app framework changes all that. This talk discusses the
journey of working with Kivy to develop a moderately complex strategy
game. It also contrasts to using other platforms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dorian-pula-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Dorian Pula Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dorian Pula</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/the-art-of-writing-wargames-in-python-with-kivy.html</guid></item><item><title>Version control worst practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/version-control-worst-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, everybody uses version control. But until you learn to
&lt;em&gt;misuse&lt;/em&gt; your version control system, you're missing out on ways to
minimize developer productivity and pessimize your workflow. I'll show
you 12 time-tested worst practices that will set you down the wrong path
from Day One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="greg-ward-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Greg Ward Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been using and creating open source software since before the term
&amp;quot;open source&amp;quot; was coined, and involved with the Python community since
the late nineties. I've written or contributed to several modules in the
standard library. And I've been working as a programmer for over 20
years. I don't think I've made every mistake in the book, but I've made
a lot of them, and I hope to share some of the things I have learned the
hard way and save you the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Greg Ward</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/version-control-worst-practices.html</guid></item><item><title>What kind of sorcery is OpenStack?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/what-kind-of-sorcery-is-openstack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lets clear the air about witchcraft and best practices in data center
IT. Come listen to my rants and raves about OpenStack, the software that
controls large armies of compute, storage, and networking resources. Why
does OpenStack get so much hype and so much hate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="daniel-snider-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Daniel Snider Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Snider is a former OpenStack software engineer, UOIT
undergraduate in Information Technology, IBM, and Google Summer of Code
student. He is currently a bio-tech newbie at SickKids and roboticist at
Ryerson University's R3 Robotics club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Snider</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/what-kind-of-sorcery-is-openstack.html</guid></item><item><title>What’s new in Python 3.6</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/whats-new-in-python-36.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scheduled for release in mid-December following the conference, Python
3.6 is shaping up to be a feature-packed release! This talk will cover
all the new features of note that will be making their debut in Python
3.6, with consideration to explain things so that those still on legacy
Python 2 can follow along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brett-cannon-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Brett Cannon Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brett is part of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://azure.microsoft.com/"&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; Data
Science Tools team at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.microsoft.com/"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; where
he works on various &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/pythonengineering/"&gt;Python
engineering&lt;/a&gt;
problems. He has been a core developer of Python itself for over 13
years and mucked around with pretty much every part of Python at this
point. At this point Brett just hopes he can continue to live up to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2016/05/brett-cannon-wins-frank-%20willison-award.html"&gt;winning the 2016 Frank Willison
Award&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brett Cannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/whats-new-in-python-36.html</guid></item><item><title>When the abyss gazes back: staring down Python’s surprising internals</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/when-the-abyss-gazes-back-staring-down-pythons-surprising-internals.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's fantastic until it isn't. This talk dives into some of the
surprising implementation details of CPython, then explains exactly how
they could be discovered from first principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will leave with some dangerous Python trivia, and the tools
they'll need to uncovery their own trivia when surprises strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="david-wolever-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;David Wolever Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Wolever</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/when-the-abyss-gazes-back-staring-down-pythons-surprising-internals.html</guid></item></channel></rss>