<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>tqdm - A Fast, Extensible Progress Bar for Python and CLI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/tqdm-a-fast-extensible-progress-bar-for-python-and-cli.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A demonstration of the world's most-used progress bar by its primary developer&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Casper da Costa-Luis</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-07:pydata-meetups/tqdm-a-fast-extensible-progress-bar-for-python-and-cli.html</guid><category>lightning-talks</category><category>tutorial</category><category>performance</category><category>jupyter</category><category>notebook</category><category>tqdm</category><category>progressbar</category><category>progressmeter</category><category>progress-bar</category><category>meter</category><category>rate</category><category>eta</category><category>console</category><category>terminal</category><category>time</category><category>progress</category><category>bar</category><category>gui</category><category>python</category><category>parallel</category><category>cli</category><category>utilities</category></item><item><title>Azure Machine Learning: Predict Who Survives the Titanic</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/azure-machine-learning-predict-who-survives-the-titanic.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Azure Machine Learning: Predict Who Survives the Titanic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in doing machine learning in the cloud? In this demo, Jennifer Marsman will set the stage with some information on the different types of machine learning (clustering, classification, regression, and anomaly detection) supported by Azure Machine Learning and when to use each. Then, for the majority of the session, she’ll demonstrate using Azure Machine Learning to build a model which predicts survival of individuals on the Titanic (one of the challenges on the Kaggle website). She'll talk through how she analyzes the given data and why she chooses to drop or modify certain data, so you will see the entire process from data import to data cleaning to building, training, testing, and deploying a model. You’ll leave with practical knowledge on how to get started and build your own predictive models using Azure Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Marsman is a Principal Software Development Engineer in Microsoft’s Developer Experience group, where she educates developers on Microsoft’s new technologies with a focus on data science, machine learning, and artificial intelligence. Jennifer blogs at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jennifer"&gt;http://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jennifer&lt;/a&gt; and tweets at &amp;#64;jennifermarsman.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jennifer Marsman</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:pydata-meetups/azure-machine-learning-predict-who-survives-the-titanic.html</guid></item><item><title>Scalable, Distributed, and Reproducible Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/scalable-distributed-and-reproducible-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent advances in machine learning and artificial intelligence are amazing!  Yet, in order to have real value within a company, data scientists must be able to get their models off of their laptops and deployed within a company’s data pipelines and infrastructure.  Those models must also scale to production size data. In this talk, we will implement a model locally in Python. We will then take that model and deploy both it's training and inference in a scalable manner to a production cluster with Pachyderm, an open source framework for distributed pipelining and data versioning. We will also learn how to update the production model online, track changes in our model and data, and explore our results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Whitenack (&amp;#64;dwhitena) is a Ph.D. trained data scientist working with Pachyderm (&amp;#64;pachydermIO). Daniel develops innovative, distributed data pipelines which include predictive models, data visualizations, statistical analyses, and more. He has spoken at conferences around the world (ODSC, Spark Summit, Datapalooza, DevFest Siberia, GopherCon, and more), teaches data science/engineering with Ardan Labs (&amp;#64;ardanlabs), maintains the Go kernel for Jupyter, and is actively helping to organize contributions to various open source data science projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Whitenack</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-25:pydata-meetups/scalable-distributed-and-reproducible-machine-learning.html</guid><category>machine learning</category><category>pachyderm</category></item><item><title>Attention Models For Deep Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/attention-models-for-deep-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will discuss the implementation of selective attention in deep networks. We will also talk about the pros and cons of different attention methods and provide insights and best practices. Practical implementations examples for both image processing and NLP will be presented. Finally, novel ideas for further research in the subject will be suggested.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amir Balaish</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-07:pydata-meetups/attention-models-for-deep-models.html</guid></item><item><title>Generative models &amp; Variational AutoEncoder explained</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/generative-models-variational-autoencoder-explained.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ever-increasing size of modern datasets combined with the difficulty of obtaining labeled information has made semi-supervised learning one of the problems of significant practical importance in modern data analysis. VAE offers a novel way to enforce structure on the representation surface, by doing so, it opens the possibility of employing traditional semi supervised learning techniques on the structured embedding space. In this talk I will cover how VAE impose latent space structure constraint, and how we can use it in a semi-supervised settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shai Harel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-07:pydata-meetups/generative-models-variational-autoencoder-explained.html</guid><category>semi supervised learning</category></item><item><title>Machine Learning Applied To Mice Diet &amp; Weight Gain</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/machine-learning-applied-to-mice-diet-weight-gain.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Persistent microbiome alterations modulate the rate of post-dieting weight regain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In tackling the obesity pandemic, significant efforts are devoted to the development of effective weight reduction strategies, yet many dieting individuals fail to maintain a long-term weight reduction, and instead undergo excessive weight regain cycles. The mechanisms driving recurrent post-dieting obesity remain largely elusive. Here we identify an intestinal microbiome signature that persists after successful dieting of obese mice, which contributes to faster weight regain and metabolic aberrations upon re-exposure to obesity-promoting conditions and transmits the accelerated weight regain phenotype upon inter-animal transfer. We develop a machine-learning algorithm that enables personalized microbiome-based prediction of the extent of post-dieting weight regain. Additionally, we find that the microbiome contributes to diminished post-dieting flavonoid levels and reduced energy expenditure, and demonstrate that flavonoid-based ‘post-biotic’ intervention ameliorates excessive secondary weight gain. Together, our data highlight a possible microbiome contribution to accelerated post-dieting weight regain, and suggest that microbiome-targeting approaches may help to diagnose and treat this common disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daphna Rothchild</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-07:pydata-meetups/machine-learning-applied-to-mice-diet-weight-gain.html</guid><category>obesity</category><category>microbiome</category><category>machine learning</category></item><item><title>Easy Spark: Exploiting large datasets for multi-class classification</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/easy-spark-exploiting-large-datasets-for-multi-class-classification.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apache Spark provides an interface for programming entire clusters with implicit data parallelism and fault tolerance. At first glance, it seems that getting started with programming the Hadoop eco-system is quite cumbersome, and not so user-friendly for a data scientist or a machine learning specialist. In this talk I will briefly introduce Apache Spark, and its programming paradigm. I will show how to easily execute a distributed training of the common multi-class classifiers (naïve Bayes, random forest, logistic regression), without installing a single virtual machine, virtual box or a docker. I will share my experience of managing long-term software projects which are based on the Hadoop technology for data storage, extraction and transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Victor Makarenkov</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-14:pydata-meetups/easy-spark-exploiting-large-datasets-for-multi-class-classification.html</guid></item><item><title>Generative Adversarial Networks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/generative-adversarial-networks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) are a promising framework for unsupervised learning. GANs consist of a generator and a discriminator, which learn together by pursuing competing goals. From a conceptual perspective, adversarial training is fascinating because it bypasses the need of loss functions in learning, and opens the door to new ways of regularizing (as well as fooling or attacking) learning machines. In this talk GANs basics are explained and a lot of examples of their usage are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Victoria Mazo</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-13:pydata-meetups/generative-adversarial-networks.html</guid><category>generative adversarial networks</category></item><item><title>Interactive Data Visualization in Jupyter Notebook Using bqplot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/interactive-data-visualization-in-jupyter-notebook-using-bqplot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bqplot is a Python plotting library based on d3.js that offers its functionality directly in the Jupyter Notebook, including selections, interactions, and arbitrary css customization. In bqplot, every element of a chart is an interactive widget that can be bound to a python function, which serves as the callback when an interaction takes place. This allows the user to generate full fledged interactive applications directly in the Notebook with just a few lines of Python code. In the second part of the talk, drawing examples from fields like Data Science and Finance, we show examples of building interactive charts and dashboards using bqplot and the ipywidgets framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will also cover bqplot's interaction with the new JupyterLab IDE and what we plan for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dhruv Madeka is a Quantitative Researcher at Bloomberg LP. His current research interests focus on Machine Learning, Quantitative Finance, Data Visualization and Applied Mathematics. Having graduated from the University of Michigan with a BS in Operations Research and from Boston University with an MS in Mathematical Finance, Dhruv is part of one of the leading research teams in Finance, developing models, software and tools for users to make their data analysis experience richer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dhruv Madeka</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-13:pydata-meetups/interactive-data-visualization-in-jupyter-notebook-using-bqplot.html</guid><category>bqplot</category><category>jupyter lab</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Algorithmic Trading</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/introduction-to-algorithmic-trading.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;He provides guidelines and tools to save time and money, explains how to get the data, create trading models, evaluate and trade them in Python. In addition he shows a simple submission for Numer.ai, a hedge fund of Data Scientists and a simple trading algorithm using Machine Learning for Quantopian, a platform to research and back-test various trading strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides and code: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/algonell/PyData"&gt;https://github.com/algonell/PyData&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Kreimer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-13:pydata-meetups/introduction-to-algorithmic-trading.html</guid><category>trading</category></item><item><title>Working with TensorFlow - tips learned from Spark PyData</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/working-with-tensorflow-tips-learned-from-spark-pydata.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What tips can we use with TensorFlow taken from Spark/big-data experience? Working with cloud machines, experimenting, iterating, interactive work, monitoring and visualisation. Some script goodies on github provided for working with EC2 and Jupyter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tal Franji</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:pydata-meetups/working-with-tensorflow-tips-learned-from-spark-pydata.html</guid><category>tensorflow</category></item><item><title>Taming Big Data with Jupyter and Friends</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/taming-big-data-with-jupyter-and-friends.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This month, we are excited to host Carol Willing who will be discussing the Jupyter eco-sytem.  Carol develops software, electronics, educational tutorials, and is passionate about outreach.  She is a core developer on the Jupyter Project and is a former director at the Python Software foundation.  She continues to contribute her time to OpenHatch, Systers, PyLadies San Diego, and San Diego Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carol Willing</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-02:pydata-meetups/taming-big-data-with-jupyter-and-friends.html</guid><category>jupyter</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Part 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="7%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="27%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="66%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;00:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uri Goren&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Basic Bayesian statistics for churn analysis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;08:49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ohad Zadok&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Visualization of Neural networks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;14:56&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tal perry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Recurrent neural networks in 10 minutes or less&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;26:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nathaniel Shimoni&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Model validation methods (Kaggle)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;35:20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Raphael Cohen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wow, that's awesome! Detecting emotion in call&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Uri Goren</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-16:pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-1.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Part 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="5%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="18%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="77%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;00:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Omer Sagi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sugar cane yield Prediction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Amit Aronovitch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quick visualization tool for Analysis of Shadows cast by (actual physical) Clouds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;22:02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Feather format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;28:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gidi Shperber&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Modern recommendation engine in python with LightFM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;37:29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alon Nir&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pandas tips and tricks (Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alonnir/PyData-TLV-Talk"&gt;https://github.com/alonnir/PyData-TLV-Talk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Omer Sagi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-16:pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-2.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Fraud detection challenges and data skepticism using LIME</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/fraud-detection-challenges-and-data-skepticism-using-lime.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shir presents the story of developing a machine learning model which automatically approves factoring deals, the challenges in the model training, evaluation and interpretation including a mysterious problem in the model creation and the details of its final solution. In addition she discusses data leakage, overfitting and a cutting-edge framework for model explanations (LIME).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shir Meir Lador</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-01-05:pydata-meetups/fraud-detection-challenges-and-data-skepticism-using-lime.html</guid></item></channel></rss>