<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sriram Vamsi Ilapakurthy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sriram-vamsi-ilapakurthy.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-08T16:15:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python in Hardware &amp; Embedded Systems: A Deep Dive</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2023/Python_in_Hardware_Embedded_Systems_A_Deep_Dive.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-08T16:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-08T16:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sriram Vamsi Ilapakurthy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-08:/pybay-2023/Python_in_Hardware_Embedded_Systems_A_Deep_Dive.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Python in Hardware &amp;amp; Embedded Systems: A Deep Dive&amp;quot; offers a comprehensive exploration of Python's growing influence in the realm of embedded systems, challenging the traditional dominance of languages like C. Beginning with specialized Python implementations such as MicroPython and CircuitPython, the talk illuminates Python's capability to interface with the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Python in Hardware &amp;amp; Embedded Systems: A Deep Dive&amp;quot; offers a comprehensive exploration of Python's growing influence in the realm of embedded systems, challenging the traditional dominance of languages like C. Beginning with specialized Python implementations such as MicroPython and CircuitPython, the talk illuminates Python's capability to interface with the physical world, from sensors to actuators. As we delve into robotics, attendees will discover Python's role in sensor fusion, computer vision, and advanced robotic applications. The discourse also sheds light on real-world Python-driven innovations, from drones to wearables, while addressing performance and memory challenges. Concluding with development tools and debugging techniques, this talk serves as both a testament to Python's versatility and a guidebook for its effective deployment in embedded contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2023"></category></entry></feed>