<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brad-nielsen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Teaching OOP using Python (Progressing from GameMaker to Pygame)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/teaching-oop-using-python-progressing-from-gamemaker-to-pygame.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brad Nielsen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-24:pycon-au-2018/teaching-oop-using-python-progressing-from-gamemaker-to-pygame.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teaching students Object-Oriented Programming(OOP) is challenging but invaluable. Due to its abstract nature, OOP is best taught in a fun and practical context such as game design. This talk will examine the progression of teaching OOP using the drag-and-drop interface of Game Maker to using Pygame.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Integrating Python within a School Context</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/integrating-python-within-a-school-context.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brad Nielsen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/integrating-python-within-a-school-context.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brad Nielsen
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/185/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/185/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Python is an ideal first programming language for secondary school students due to the simplicity of its syntax, its enforced code formatting, and the extensibility of the language. Introducing Python to a school however, takes planning, an incremental approach, and modification to existing curriculum plans based on experience. In this presentation, you will be given an overview of how a high school has introduced Python through years 8-12. You will also learn about various Python packages and environments that can be of benefit to a school including: Python Turtle, Grok Learning, Pygame, Flask, and PythonAnywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Flask and Python Anywhere in the Classroom</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/using-flask-and-python-anywhere-in-the-classroom.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brad Nielsen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/using-flask-and-python-anywhere-in-the-classroom.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flask is a python web server and web framework that makes server-side
programming using Python easy. Flask has less 'magic' than Django and
therefore makes server requests and responses easier to understand for
students. Python Anywhere is a cloud server that allows you to easily
set up a live Flask or Django application. Students can develop and
debug code online without the hassle of installing and configuring their
development environments. This session will look at how Flask and Python
Anywhere was used in the classroom with a year 12 student cohort.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>