<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Invisible Work of Maintaining &amp; Sustaining Open Source Software</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/the-invisible-work-of-maintaining-sustaining-open-source-software.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open-source software has become critical infrastructure for many sectors, including academic research, industry, governments, non-profits, activism, and more. However, the work of maintaining these projects is no small feat, particularly given the many different kinds of work expected of maintainers. In this talk, I share findings and insights from our team’s ongoing mixed-method research into the maintenance of open-source software in and beyond scientific computing, which is based on ethnographic interviews with maintainers and stakeholders, as well as quantitative analyses of code repositories. In particular, I discuss the often-invisible work that maintainers do to support their projects, and how invisible work intersects with other relevant issues to the sustainability of OSS projects, including funding models, governance, diversity &amp;amp; inclusion, and burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stuart Geiger</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/the-invisible-work-of-maintaining-sustaining-open-source-software.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Community sustainability in Wikipedia a review of research and initiatives</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/community-sustainability-in-wikipedia-a-review-of-research-and-initiatives.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia relies on one of the world’s largest open collaboration communities. Since 2001, the community has grown substantially and faced many challenges. This presentation reviews research and initiatives around community sustainability in Wikipedia that are relevant for many open source projects, including issues of newcomer retention, governance, automated moderation, and marginalized groups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stuart Geiger</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/community-sustainability-in-wikipedia-a-review-of-research-and-initiatives.html</guid></item><item><title>Governing Open Source Projects at Scale: Lessons from Wikipedia's Growing Pains</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/governing-open-source-projects-at-scale-lessons-from-wikipedias-growing-pains-staurt-geiger-sc.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stuart Geiger</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/governing-open-source-projects-at-scale-lessons-from-wikipedias-growing-pains-staurt-geiger-sc.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>wikipedia</category></item></channel></rss>