<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_harinarayan-krishnan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python's role in VisIt</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/pythons-role-in-visit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cyrus Harrison</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/pythons-role-in-visit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;VisIt is an open source, turnkey application for scientific data
analysis and visualization that runs on a wide variety of platforms from
desktops to petascale class supercomputers. This talk will provide an
overview of Python’s role in VisIt with a focus on use cases of scripted
rendering, data analysis, and custom application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is the foundation of VisIt’s primary scripting interface, which
is available from both a standard python interpreter and a custom
command line client. The interface provides access to all features
available through VisIt’s GUI. It also includes support for macro
recording of GUI actions to python snippets and full control of
windowless batch processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Python has always played an important scripting role in VisIt, two
recent development efforts have greatly expanded VisIt’s python
capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We recently enhanced VisIt by embedding python interpreters into our
data flow network pipelines. This provides fine grained access,
allowing users to write custom algorithms in python that manipulate
mesh data via VTK’s python wrappers and leverage packages such as
numpy and scipy. Current support includes the ability to create
derived mesh quantities and execute data summarization operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now support custom GUI development using Qt via PySide. This
allows users to embed VisIt’s visualization windows into their own
python applications. This provides a path to extend VisIt’s existing
GUI and for rapid development of streamlined GUIs for specific use
cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of this work is to evolve Python into a true peer to
our core C++ plugin infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work performed under the auspices of the U.S. Department of Energy
by Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory under Contract
DE-AC52-07NA27344 (LLNL- ABS-552316).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="visualization"></category></entry></feed>