<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Daniel Beck</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daniel-beck.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-28T15:30:00+01:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Deprecation Warning: documenting your software’s last days</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/deprecation-warning-documenting-your-softwares-last-days.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-28T15:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T15:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Beck</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-28:/pycon-uk-2017/deprecation-warning-documenting-your-softwares-last-days.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apologies for the poor quality video, the camera was unattended and the autofocus was being confused by something in the room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could happen to you: your project is canceled, your team is “reorganized”, or your company is closing its doors. Some or all of your software, service, or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apologies for the poor quality video, the camera was unattended and the autofocus was being confused by something in the room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could happen to you: your project is canceled, your team is “reorganized”, or your company is closing its doors. Some or all of your software, service, or API may not be long for this world. What will you say to the people using it? In this talk, you’ll learn how to cope when it’s time to break bad news to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re deprecating significant features or shutting down entirely, you still have a chance to make life better—or at least a little less worse—for the people who have come to rely on your work. In this talk, you’ll learn how to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cope with a stressful situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plan your shutdown communications to make sure no users get left behind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;let your users down easy with the appropriate voice, tone, and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From your initial announcement to your software's last day, you’ll learn how to say goodbye in a way that’s good for you and your soon-to-be-former users.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon UK 2017"></category></entry><entry><title>Checklist the Docs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2016/checklist-the-docs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Beck</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:/write-the-docs-europe-2016/checklist-the-docs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The aviation industry has made flying long distances at high speeds one
of the safest ways to travel. How did they do it? In part with the help
of the humble but effective checklist! In this talk, you’ll learn to
adapt the checklist practices of high-risk environments, like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The aviation industry has made flying long distances at high speeds one
of the safest ways to travel. How did they do it? In part with the help
of the humble but effective checklist! In this talk, you’ll learn to
adapt the checklist practices of high-risk environments, like flight
decks and operating rooms, to avoid mistakes and improve your
documentation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever missed an important step that you’ve done a hundred times
before, or are you worried that you might someday? Or have you ever
repeatedly made the same, avoidable mistake? A well-designed checklist
might help you avoid errors large and small and increase confidence in
your workflow. In this talk, you’ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to write a checklist that you’ll actually want to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to choose the right time and place to follow your checklist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to extend your checklists with automation or teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by research and practices in aerospace safety (such as “ Human
Factors of Flight Deck Checklists: The Normal Checklist” by Degani &amp;amp;
Wiener), medical safety (such as “The Checklist Manifesto” by Atul
Gawande), and cognitive psychology (such as “Human Error” by James
Reason), this talk will guide you through the process of making and
using checklists in the day-to-day work of creating documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what distinguishes a checklist from a to-do list to developing
checklist habits, you’ll learn how to use checklists to help you write
the docs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Europe 2016"></category></entry></feed>