<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Maxim Danilov</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hidden gems of Django Admin</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/hidden-gems-of-django-admin.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Django Admin Panel is a complex and bad-documented tool in the Django that can greatly speed up development if you start to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Isn't it easier for us to write our Backend?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will answer: “No, it’s not easier!”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven years of insights and discoveries in my report.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxim Danilov</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-19:/djangocon-us-2022/hidden-gems-of-django-admin.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>Ultimative session about hidden gems of Django Admin</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/ultimative-session-about-hidden-gems-of-django-admin.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/ultimative-session-about-hidden-gems-of-django-admin"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/ultimative-session-about-hidden-gems-of-django-admin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django Admin Panel is a complex and bad-documented tool in the Django that can greatly speed up development if you start to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Isn’t it easier for us to write our Backend?” I will answer: “No, it’s not easier!”. 8 years of insights and discoveries in my Talk. Here i want talk about multiple admin sites, ModelAdmins possibilities, object state versioning and app configs as completely forgotten hidden power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxim Danilov</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/ultimative-session-about-hidden-gems-of-django-admin.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>An alternative view on the OpenAPI documentation.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/an-alternative-view-on-the-openapi-documentation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2B on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative view on the OpenAPI documentation. by Maxim Danilov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/an-alternative-view-on-the-openapi-documentation"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/an-alternative-view-on-the-openapi-documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documenting Python project endpoints is a real challenge in API development. Poor readability, versioning, and lack of authentication information - this all reduce the usability of existing OpenAPI documentation. The different libraries offers us a good start for autogenerated OpenAPI documentation for our endpoints, but in this talk we will discuss an alternative way to auto generated documentation for our APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxim Danilov</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/an-alternative-view-on-the-openapi-documentation.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>What are you yield from?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/what-are-you-yield-from.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many developers avoid using generators. For example, many well-known python libraries use lists instead of generators. The generators themselves are slower than normal list loops, but their use in code greatly increases the speed of the application. Let's discover why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxim Danilov</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/what-are-you-yield-from.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item><item><title>Django FTL: Resolving Bottlenecks on the Path to High Performance</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2024/django-ftl-resolving-bottlenecks-on-the-path-to-high-performance.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raw Django doesn't take the first places when comparing the performance of Python web frameworks. However, it can be pretty fast if we identify the bottlenecks and find ways to avoid them. Comparing performance and implementation complexity before and after gives us an understanding of which features should be implemented and what can be skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django framework offers a beautiful collection of diverse tools that are easy to understand, set up, and start working with. However, after some time, appearing disadvantages of the framework's features may increase the complexity of the development process and fatally reduce project performance. While the new version of Django successfully improves the developers effictivity, the task to improving performance requires a good understanding of how Django works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will review the most significant performance-reducing factors in Django and provide examples of how to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of the talk from a 10,000-feet view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django vs. other faster frameworks: reviewing architectural differences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request-Response Flow: Identifying elements that can be easily omitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forms and Data validation: Balancing flexibility and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The quickest methods for data serialization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debunking myths about async-await productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire and Forget: FTL Client-Server Communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving Time to First Byte (TTFB). Less known Responce classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewing other utilities to expedite our project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By comparing performance before and after, every developer attending this talk can decide which advice to implement in their own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxim Danilov</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-11-03:/pycon-fr-2024/django-ftl-resolving-bottlenecks-on-the-path-to-high-performance.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2024</category></item></channel></rss>