<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Alejandro Saucedo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alejandro-saucedo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning Pipelines with Python &amp; Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:/europython-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide key insights on the learnings I have obtained
throughout my career building &amp;amp; deploying machine learning systems in
critical environments across several sectors. I will provide a deep dive
on how to build scalable and distributed machine learning data pipelines
using Airflow with a Celery backend …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide key insights on the learnings I have obtained
throughout my career building &amp;amp; deploying machine learning systems in
critical environments across several sectors. I will provide a deep dive
on how to build scalable and distributed machine learning data pipelines
using Airflow with a Celery backend. I will also compare Airflow with
other technologies available out there and how it differentiates, such
as Luigi, Chronos, Pinball, etc. If you attend the talk, you will obtain
an understanding on the solid fundamentals of Airflow, together with its
caveats and walk-arounds for more complex use-cases. As we proceed with
the examples, I will cover the challenges that you will run into when
scaling Machine Learning systems, and how Airflow can be used to address
these using a manager-worker-queue architecture for distributed
processing with Celery. By the end of this talk you will have the
knowledge required to build your own industry-ready machine learning
pipelines to process data at scale, and I will provide further reading
resources so people are able to implement the knowledge obtained almost
right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>The state of Machine Learning Operations in 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-state-of-machine-learning-operations-in-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/the-state-of-machine-learning-operations-in-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of the key challenges and trends in
the productization of machine learning systems, including concepts such
as reproducibility, explainability and orchestration. The talk will also
provide a high level overview of several key open source tools and
frameworks available to tackle these issues …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of the key challenges and trends in
the productization of machine learning systems, including concepts such
as reproducibility, explainability and orchestration. The talk will also
provide a high level overview of several key open source tools and
frameworks available to tackle these issues, which have been identifyed
putting together the Awesome Machine Learning Operations list
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/EthicalML/awesome-machine-learning-operations"&gt;https://github.com/EthicalML/awesome-machine-learning-operations&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The key concepts that will be covered are:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Reproducibility&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Explainability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Orchestration of models&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reproducibility piece will cover key motivations as well as
practical requirements for model versioning, together with tools that
allow data scientists to achieve version control of model+config+data to
ensure full model lineage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explainability piece will contain a high level overview of why this
has become an important topic in machine learning, including the high
profile incidents that tech companies have experienced where undesired
biases have slipped into data. This will also include a high level
overview of some of the tools available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the orchestration piece will cover some of the fundamental
challenges with large scale serving of models, together with some of the
key tools that are available to ensure this challenge can be tackled.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2019"></category><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Deep Learning"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Meditations on First Deployment: A Practical Guide to Responsible Development</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/meditations-on-first-deployment-a-practical-guide-to-responsible-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/meditations-on-first-deployment-a-practical-guide-to-responsible-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the impact of software increasingly reaches farther and wider, our professional responsibility as developers becomes more critical to society. The production systems we design, build and maintain often bring inherent adversities with complex technical, societal and even ethical challenges. The skillsets required to tackle these challenges require …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the impact of software increasingly reaches farther and wider, our professional responsibility as developers becomes more critical to society. The production systems we design, build and maintain often bring inherent adversities with complex technical, societal and even ethical challenges. The skillsets required to tackle these challenges require us to go beyond the algorithms, and require cross-functional collaboration that often goes beyond a single developer. In this talk we introduce intuitive and practical insights from a few of the core ethics themes in software including Privacy, Equity, Trust and Transparency. We cover their importance, the growing societal challenges, and how organisations such as The Institute for Ethical AI, The Linux Foundation, the Association for Computer Machinery, NumFocus, the IEEE and the Python Software Foundation are contributing to these critical themes through standards, policy advise and open source software initiatives. We finally will wrap up the talk with practical steps that any individual can take to get involved and contribute to some of these great open initiatives, and contribute to these critical ongoing discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Ethics"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Real Time Stream Processing for Machine Learning at Massive Scale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/real-time-stream-processing-for-machine-learning-at-massive-scale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/real-time-stream-processing-for-machine-learning-at-massive-scale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processing Massively Parallel Stream of Data with Python (+ Kafka, SKlearn, SpaCy and Seldon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical insight on how to build scalable data streaming machine learning pipelines to process large datasets in real time using Python and popular frameworks such as Kafka, SpaCy and Seldon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processing Massively Parallel Stream of Data with Python (+ Kafka, SKlearn, SpaCy and Seldon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical insight on how to build scalable data streaming machine learning pipelines to process large datasets in real time using Python and popular frameworks such as Kafka, SpaCy and Seldon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be covering a case study performing automated content moderation on Reddit comments in real time. Our dataset will consist of 200k reddit comments from /r/science, 50,000 of which have been removed by moderators. We will be handling the stream data in a Kubernetes cluster, and the stream processing will be handled using the stream processing library Kafka. We will be running the end-to-end pipeline in Kubernetes with various components legeraging SKLearn, SpaCy and Seldon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will then dive into fundamental concepts on stream processing such as windows, watermarking and checkponting, and we will show how to use each of these frameworks to build complex data streaming pipelines that can perform real time processing at scale by building, deploying and monitoring a machine learning model which will process production incoming data..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we will show best practices when using these frameworks, as well as a high level overview of tools that can be used for monitoring in-depth.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="ASYNC / Concurreny"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category><category term="Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)"></category></entry><entry><title>Production ML Monitoring: Outliers, Drift, Explainers &amp; Statistical Performance</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/production-ml-monitoring-outliers-drift-explainers-statistical-performance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/production-ml-monitoring-outliers-drift-explainers-statistical-performance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Production ML Monitoring: Outliers, Drift, Explainers &amp;amp; Statistical Performance
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Session Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lifecycle of a machine learning model only begins once it's in production. In this talk we provide a practical deep dive on best practices, principles, patterns and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Production ML Monitoring: Outliers, Drift, Explainers &amp;amp; Statistical Performance
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Session Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lifecycle of a machine learning model only begins once it's in production. In this talk we provide a practical deep dive on best practices, principles, patterns and techniques around production monitoring of machine learning models. We will cover standard microservice monitoring techniques applied into deployed machine learning models, as well as more advanced paradigms to monitor machine learning models with Python leveraging advanced monitoring concepts such as concept drift, outlier detector and explainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll dive into a hands on example, where we will train an image classification machine learning model from scratch using Tensorflow, deploy it, and introduce advanced monitoring components as architectural patterns with hands on examples. These monitoring techniques will include AI Explainers, Outlier Detectors, Concept Drift detectors and Adversarial Detectors. We will also be understanding high level architectural patterns that abstract these complex and advanced monitoring techniques into infrastructural components that will enable for scale, introducing the standardised interfaces required for us to enable monitoring across hundreds or thousands of heterogeneous machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benefits to ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will benefit the ecosystem by providing cross-functional knowledge, bringing together best practices from data scientists, software engineers and DevOps to tackle the challenge of machine learning monitoring at scale. During this talk we will shed light into best practices in the python ecosystem that can be adopted towards production machine learning, and we will provide a conceptual and practical hands on deep dive which will allow the community to both, tackle this issues and help further the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Secure Python ML: The Major Security Flaws in the ML Lifecycle</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/secure-python-ml-the-major-security-flaws-in-the-ml-lifecycle.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/secure-python-ml-the-major-security-flaws-in-the-ml-lifecycle.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Secure Python ML: The Major Security Flaws in the ML Lifecycle (and how to avoid them) - presented by Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every phase across the end-to-end machine learning lifecycle exposes a plethora of security risks that often go unnoticed by machine learning practitioners …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Secure Python ML: The Major Security Flaws in the ML Lifecycle (and how to avoid them) - presented by Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every phase across the end-to-end machine learning lifecycle exposes a plethora of security risks that often go unnoticed by machine learning practitioners. In this talk we uncover the most critical (and common) security risks in the machine learning lifecycle, covering in-depth concepts as well as practical examples of ways in which these can be exploited as well as resolved and mitigated (analogous to the OWASP Top 10 industry standard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the talk we will be using a hands on example, where we will be training, packaging and deploying a model from scratch, outlining key risk areas for each step together with tools and practices that can be used to mitigate these risks. By the end of this talk, machine learning practitioners will have a robust intuition of the importance of security best practices throughout the machine learning lifecycle, together with tools and frameworks that can help mitigate undesirable outcomes due to security flaws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operation and maintenance of large scale production machine learning systems has uncovered new challenges which have required fundamentally different approaches to that of traditional software. The area of security in MLOps has seen a rise in attention as machine learning infrastructure expands to further critical usecases across industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we introduce the conceptual and practical topics around MLSecOps that data science practitioners will be able to adopt or advocate for. We will also provide an intuition on key security challenges that arise in production machine learning systems as well as best practices and frameworks that can be adopted to help mitigate security risks in ML models, ML pipelines and ML services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover a practical example showing how we can secure a machine learning model, and showcasing the security risks and best practices that can be adopted during the feature engineering, model training, model deployment and model monitoring stages of the machine learning lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits to the ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide practitioners with the intuition and tools to secure production machine learning systems, as well as further the discussion around best practices reinforcing SecOps into MLOps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will provide best practices on a critical area of machine learning operations which is of paramount importance in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The State of Production Machine Learning in 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the number of production machine learning use-cases increase, we find ourselves facing new and bigger challenges where more is at stake. Because of this, it's critical to identify the key areas to focus our efforts …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the number of production machine learning use-cases increase, we find ourselves facing new and bigger challenges where more is at stake. Because of this, it's critical to identify the key areas to focus our efforts, so we can ensure our machine learning pipelines are reliable and scalable. In this talk we dive into the state of production machine learning, and we will cover the concepts that make production machine learning so challenging, as well as some of the recommended tools available to tackle these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>A practical guide towards explainability and bias evaluation in ML</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-belarus-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-explainability-and-bias-evaluation-in-ml.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-16:/pycon-belarus-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-explainability-and-bias-evaluation-in-ml.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon Belarus 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Secure ML: Automated Security Best Practices in Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/secure-ml-automated-security-best-practices-in-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-12:/pycon-de-2022/secure-ml-automated-security-best-practices-in-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Machine Learning &amp;amp; Stats
As data science capabilities scale, the core concept of security becomes growingly critical. In this talk we will introduce the security challenges and solutions for data science practitioners relevant to each of the phases of the machine learning lifecycle, and we …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Machine Learning &amp;amp; Stats
As data science capabilities scale, the core concept of security becomes growingly critical. In this talk we will introduce the security challenges and solutions for data science practitioners relevant to each of the phases of the machine learning lifecycle, and we will provide a practical set of best practices and frameworks that can be adopted to ensure a relevant level of security is present in the multiple stages of the machine learning lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/APTWQS"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/APTWQS&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2022"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConDE"></category><category term="pyconde2022"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="pydataberlin2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The State of Production Machine Learning in 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/the-state-of-production-machine-learning-in-2023.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the number of production machine learning use-cases increase, we find ourselves facing new and bigger challenges where more is at stake. Because of this, it's critical to identify the key areas to focus our efforts, so we can ensure our machine learning pipelines are reliable and scalable. In …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the number of production machine learning use-cases increase, we find ourselves facing new and bigger challenges where more is at stake. Because of this, it's critical to identify the key areas to focus our efforts, so we can ensure our machine learning pipelines are reliable and scalable. In this talk we dive into the state of production machine learning in the Python Ecosystem, and we will cover the concepts that make production machine learning so challenging, as well as some of the recommended tools available to tackle these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover key principles, patterns and frameworks around the open source frameworks powering single or multiple phases of the end-to-end ML lifecycle, incluing model training, deploying, monitoring, etc. We will be covering a high level overview of the production ML ecosystem and dive into best practices that have been abstracted from production use-cases of machine learning operations at scale, as well as how to leverage tools to that will allow us to deploy, explain, secure, monitor and scale production machine learning systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning Pipelines with Python &amp; Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:/pycon-hk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning and data pipelines in Python. I will
cover practical presentation that will build from the basics of Airflow,
and show how it is possible to build scalable and distributed machine
learning data pipelines using …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning and data pipelines in Python. I will
cover practical presentation that will build from the basics of Airflow,
and show how it is possible to build scalable and distributed machine
learning data pipelines using a distributed architecture with a
producer- consumer backend using Celery. I will provide insights on some
of the key learnings I have obtained throughout my career building
machine learning systems, as well as caveats and best practices
deploying scalable data pipelines systems in production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon HK 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>Industrial Data Pipelines with Python and Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2018/industrial-data-pipelines-with-python-and-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-22:/pycon-russia-2018/industrial-data-pipelines-with-python-and-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/strong&gt; , Eigen Technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.ru/2018/en/program/content/Alejandro/"&gt;**Industrial Data Pipelines with Python and
Airflow**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning / data pipelines using Airflow. This
will consist of a practical presentation that will build from the basics
of Airflow, and show how it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/strong&gt; , Eigen Technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.ru/2018/en/program/content/Alejandro/"&gt;**Industrial Data Pipelines with Python and
Airflow**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning / data pipelines using Airflow. This
will consist of a practical presentation that will build from the basics
of Airflow, and show how it is possible to build scalable and
distributed machine learning data pipelines using a distributed
architecture with a Celery backend. I will provide insights on some of
the key learnings I've obtained throughout my career building &amp;amp;
deploying machine learning systems in critical environments across
several sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Russia 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning: Building scalable distributed machine learning pipelines with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-building-scalable-distributed-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:/pycon-sk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-building-scalable-distributed-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk would provide useful and practical understanding on how to
build industry-ready machine learning models in python through
distributed, horizontally-scalable architectures. I will include why and
when these architectures are required, best practices, caveats,
technologies to use them, and a practical implementation using celery +
rabbitmq.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon SK 2018"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="celery"></category><category term="rabbitmq"></category></entry><entry><title>Industrial ML - Overview of the technologies available to build scalable machine learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2018/industrial-ml-overview-of-the-technologies-available-to-build-scalable-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-08:/pydata-berlin-2018/industrial-ml-overview-of-the-technologies-available-to-build-scalable-machine-learning.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide useful and practical understanding on how to
build industry-ready machine learning pipelines in python through
distributed, horizontally-scalable architectures. This talk will also go
into detail on the motivations for such architectures, the technologies
required, best practices, caveats and practical use-cases in industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>A practical guide towards algorithmic bias and explainability in machine learning.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-algorithmic-bias-and-explainability-in-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/pydata-london-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-algorithmic-bias-and-explainability-in-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Undesired bias in machine learning has become a worrying topic due to the numerous high profile incidents. In this talk we demystify machine learning bias through a hands-on example. We'll be tasked to automate the loan approval process for a company, and introduce key tools and techniques from latest …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Undesired bias in machine learning has become a worrying topic due to the numerous high profile incidents. In this talk we demystify machine learning bias through a hands-on example. We'll be tasked to automate the loan approval process for a company, and introduce key tools and techniques from latest research that allow us to assess and mitigate undesired bias in our machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData London 2019"></category></entry></feed>