<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A "Supremely" Light introduction to Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/a-supremely-light-introduction-to-quantum-computing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quantum Computing is here and now, and its uses for solving real-world
problems is getting nearer. This talk will give you the tools to
understand the main concepts of Quantum Information, and even perform
your first steps by running your own programs on real hardware using
Qiskit and Rigetti Forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantum Computing is one of the most disruptive and fast-paced
disciplines of the present time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Data Science practitioners, understanding the main elements of the
new paradigm (Superposition, measurement, entanglement, Qubits, etc) can
be a daunting task. In this talk, we will walk through all these
concepts and will use Python to understand and probe them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will focus on direct and math-light examples, with accompanying
python code examples illustrating the differences between simulating the
quantum world ideally, an then observing introduced error of running
code in the noisy environment of real IBM and Rigetti's devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outline of the talk is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for a new kind of computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum phenomena and how it can be used for computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum circuits and algorithms: Manipulating quantum data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulating and real hardware running of Python-based examples
(Qiskit, Rigetti Forest SDK, Pennylane)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rodolfo Bonnin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/a-supremely-light-introduction-to-quantum-computing.html</guid></item><item><title>A (Very Gentle) introduction to Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-cordoba-2019/a-very-gentle-introduction-to-quantum-computing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quantum Computing is here and now, and its uses for solving real-world problems is getting nearer. This talk will help you to grasp the fundamental concepts and tools you need to start working in this amazing new field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rodolfo Bonnin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-27:pydata-cordoba-2019/a-very-gentle-introduction-to-quantum-computing.html</guid><category>quantum computing</category></item><item><title>Computer Vision: An (Un?)Expected Journey, with Keras and Tensorflow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2018/computer-vision-an-unexpected-journey-with-keras-and-tensorflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A hands-on tutorial which will allow you to practice and finally train
cutting-edge Deep Learning models, covering the most active and demanded
skills in the field: Image Classification, Feature detection and Image
Segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rodolfo Bonnin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-27:pydata-london-2018/computer-vision-an-unexpected-journey-with-keras-and-tensorflow.html</guid></item></channel></rss>