<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Alex Bozarth</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alex-bozarth.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Customizing JupyterLab using extensions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/customizing-jupyterlab-using-extensions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Bozarth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:/pydata-austin-2019/customizing-jupyterlab-using-extensions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab provides data scientists a singular work environment for notebooks, file editing, and more. Designed to be extendable, JupyterLab allows developers to create new features and improve upon built-in functionality. In this session we will go over JupyterLab extensions and how they can be used to customize JupyterLab for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab provides data scientists a singular work environment for notebooks, file editing, and more. Designed to be extendable, JupyterLab allows developers to create new features and improve upon built-in functionality. In this session we will go over JupyterLab extensions and how they can be used to customize JupyterLab for your use case.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Austin 2019"></category><category term="jupyter lab"></category></entry><entry><title>Developing Extensions for JupyterLab</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/developing-extensions-for-jupyterlab.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Martha Cryan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/developing-extensions-for-jupyterlab.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab is a web-based user interface for scientists and developers for exploration, analysis, and visualization. JupyterLab provides a Jupyter notebook editor, code editor, code console, terminal, debugger, and more as core extensions. Users can write and distribute extensions as Python packages to add new components or customize and extend …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab is a web-based user interface for scientists and developers for exploration, analysis, and visualization. JupyterLab provides a Jupyter notebook editor, code editor, code console, terminal, debugger, and more as core extensions. Users can write and distribute extensions as Python packages to add new components or customize and extend the capabilities of existing components in JupyterLab. For example, users can install extensions that provide a new file viewer or editor, display data with custom visualizations inside notebooks or code consoles, or interact with external services and version control. Extensions can add items to the main menu, status bar, command palette, notebook metadata panel, activity launcher, side bars, context menus, toolbars, and keyboard shortcuts. Extensions can also provide new autocomplete results, custom themes, custom settings, and custom ipywidgets. Extensions can also provide extension points for other extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will guide attendees through creating basic extensions and show how extensions can interact with core components in JupyterLab. We'll use the new extension distribution system introduced in JupyterLab 3.0, which enables users to easily install extensions as Python packages. Attendees are expected to be comfortable with coding in javascript/typescript (or willing to pick it up fairly quickly). Attendees are encouraged to come with an extension idea that they’d like to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marthacryan/developing-extensions-tutorial"&gt;https://github.com/marthacryan/developing-extensions-tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>