<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mona Obedoza</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mona-obedoza.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Project TEDDY (Text-based Early Distress Detector for Youth)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/project-teddy-text-based-early-distress-detector-for-youth.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mona Obedoza</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/project-teddy-text-based-early-distress-detector-for-youth.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mona Obedoza, a high schooler, tech enthusiast, and aspiring AI engineer, presented &amp;quot;Project Teddy,&amp;quot; a text-based early distress detector for youth. As a passionate coder and AI advocate, she developed Teddy using Python and tools like Google Colab and Streamlit. The project aims to help teachers identify mental health …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mona Obedoza, a high schooler, tech enthusiast, and aspiring AI engineer, presented &amp;quot;Project Teddy,&amp;quot; a text-based early distress detector for youth. As a passionate coder and AI advocate, she developed Teddy using Python and tools like Google Colab and Streamlit. The project aims to help teachers identify mental health concerns in student essays, flagging potential issues for guidance counselors. Mona detailed her process of data gathering, AI model training, and web deployment, emphasizing the importance of AI in early intervention. She encouraged schools to implement Teddy and expressed her ongoing commitment to using technology for positive change, while also promoting coding education for girls through hackathons and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyLadiesCon 2023"></category></entry></feed>