<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Michał Gałka</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Script your application - integrating Python with C applications - Michał Gałka</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2017/script-your-application-integrating-python-with-c-applications-michal-galka.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Gałka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-18:/pycaribbean-2017/script-your-application-integrating-python-with-c-applications-michal-galka.html</guid><category>PyCaribbean 2017</category></item><item><title>Micropython Gotchas - Michal Galka</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2018/micropython-gotchas-michal-galka.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michal Galka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-17:/pycaribbean-2018/micropython-gotchas-michal-galka.html</guid><category>PyCaribbean 2018</category></item><item><title>Micropython Gotchas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2019/micropython-gotchas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all somehow get the feeling that MicroPython is not quite the Python we know. During the talk, I’ll show what the “not quite” actually means. I'll present a set of different issues I stumbled upon when working with different MicroPython powered boards ranging from memory constraints to API calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2019.pycon-au.org/talks/micropython-gotchas"&gt;https://2019.pycon-au.org/talks/micropython-gotchas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Aug  4 14:50:00 2019 at C3.4 &amp;amp; C3.5&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Gałka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-04:/pycon-au-2019/micropython-gotchas.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2019</category></item><item><title>Creating USB gadgets with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/creating-usb-gadgets-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;USB is with us for 26 years. Connecting USB devices to our computers,
TVs, phones and many other devices became as natural as breathing.
Throughout these years several mechanism have been developed in Linux to
facilitate the process of creating USB devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'd like to take you to the other end of the USB plug and
show you how to &lt;strong&gt;create your own USB device with Python&lt;/strong&gt;. I'll take
you through the process of turning RaspberryPi Zero into a USB keyboard.
I'll show you how to use Python to interact with Linux system internals.
We'll find out how to use Python to facilitate and automate the process
of device creation and configuration. Finally, I'll present the
implementation of the logic of a Linux based USB keyboard-like device in
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Gałka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/creating-usb-gadgets-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Vodka powered by Whiskeyberry PI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/vodka-powered-by-whiskeyberry-pi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would you like to talk with someone but even your dog doesn’t want to listen to you? Would you love to have a drink but you are too tired to prepare one? Your problems are solved! During this presentation, you will find out how to build your own Bartender who talks with you and what is the most important serves drinks for you! All that you need is Amazon Alexa, simple Python Flask application, Raspberry PI and few pumps. I will go through all the steps starting from the creation of Bartender service with Amazon Alexa, development of Flask application with Bartender logic, deployment on Raspberry PI and connection with pumps. In the end, the most active participants will be allowed to talk with Bartender and ask for drinks prepared from local whiskey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will briefly introduce an audience with existing voice assistants and explain why I choose Amazon Alexa to build Bartender. Base on examples I will show what is the flow of requests and responses using selected assistant. I will say how it can be used for the purpose of this great project! I will briefly guide the audience through the process of creating Bartender skill in Amazon Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I will tell how to build a Python application for serving the drinks. I will show example source code using Flask-Ask library which wraps Amazon API and makes life easier. With only a few lines of code we will create full-value Bartender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least part of my presentation will be dedicated to Raspberry PI which is responsible for serving the ingredients of drinks. I will explain how to connect and control the pumps. I will show example source code for serving the drinks according to defined recipes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maciej Polańczyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:/pygotham-2018/vodka-powered-by-whiskeyberry-pi.html</guid><category>PyGotham 2018</category></item><item><title>Micropython Gotchas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/micropython-gotchas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all somehow feel that MicroPython is not quite the Python we know. During the talk I'll show you what the &amp;quot;not quite&amp;quot; actually means. I'll present a few cases I stumbled upon when connecting a small thermal printer to different MicroPython powered boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video Copyright belongs to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Gałka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-09:/pylondinium-2018/micropython-gotchas.html</guid><category>PyLondinium 2018</category></item></channel></rss>