<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kelly Schuster-Paredes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kelly-schuster-paredes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Education Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/education-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Reina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/education-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Education Panel - presented by Chris Reina, Kelly Schuster - Paredes, Aimée Fagan, Keith Quille &amp;amp; Sarah-Jayne Carey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Python: a panel discussion with perspectives from teachers, academics, makers and enthusiasts. Why is Python appealing in education? What tools and resources work well? What can the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Education Panel - presented by Chris Reina, Kelly Schuster - Paredes, Aimée Fagan, Keith Quille &amp;amp; Sarah-Jayne Carey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Python: a panel discussion with perspectives from teachers, academics, makers and enthusiasts. Why is Python appealing in education? What tools and resources work well? What can the Python community do to help teachers &amp;amp; policy makers? Join us for an engaging and insightful discussion with a fascinating panel of experts, Dr Keith Quille, Kelly Schuster-Paredes, Chris Reina and Sarah-Jayne Carey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Learn Python Like a 12-Year Old</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/learn-python-like-a-12-year-old.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kelly Schuster - Paredes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/learn-python-like-a-12-year-old.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the way to adulthood, we often lose that sense of wonder, enjoyment, and playfulness that we had as kids in our favorite school subjects. As adults, we can become better learners ourselves when we examine how kids learn coding with Python. In this session, we’ll talk about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the way to adulthood, we often lose that sense of wonder, enjoyment, and playfulness that we had as kids in our favorite school subjects. As adults, we can become better learners ourselves when we examine how kids learn coding with Python. In this session, we’ll talk about making thinking and coding visible, to the brain science behind how we learn new things, to the importance of playfulness in learning. We will share a variety of helpful tips to improve your learning whether you are new to Python or an experienced coder.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category></entry></feed>