<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Yusuf Sale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_yusuf-sale.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Is the Volume of a Credal Set a Good Measure for Epistemic Uncertainty?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/is-the-volume-of-a-credal-set-a-good-measure-for-epistemic-uncertainty.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yusuf Sale</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/is-the-volume-of-a-credal-set-a-good-measure-for-epistemic-uncertainty.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Is the Volume of a Credal Set a Good Measure for Epistemic Uncertainty?&amp;quot;
Yusuf Sale, Michele Caprio, Eyke Hüllermeier
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/sale23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/sale23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Adequate uncertainty representation and quantification have become imperative in various scientific disciplines, especially in machine learning and artificial intelligence. As an alternative …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Is the Volume of a Credal Set a Good Measure for Epistemic Uncertainty?&amp;quot;
Yusuf Sale, Michele Caprio, Eyke Hüllermeier
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/sale23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/sale23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Adequate uncertainty representation and quantification have become imperative in various scientific disciplines, especially in machine learning and artificial intelligence. As an alternative to representing uncertainty via one single probability measure, we consider credal sets (convex sets of probability measures). The geometric representation of credal sets as d-dimensional polytopes implies a geometric intuition about (epistemic) uncertainty. In this paper, we show that the volume of the geometric representation of a credal set is a meaningful measure of epistemic uncertainty in the case of binary classification, but less so for multi-class classification. Our theoretical findings highlight the crucial role of specifying and employing uncertainty measures in machine learning in an appropriate way, and for being aware of possible pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/482-oral-slides.pdf"&gt;https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/482-oral-slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Quantifying Aleatoric and Epistemic Uncertainty in Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/quantifying-aleatoric-and-epistemic-uncertainty-in-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lisa Wimmer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/quantifying-aleatoric-and-epistemic-uncertainty-in-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Quantifying Aleatoric and Epistemic Uncertainty in Machine Learning: Are Conditional Entropy and Mutual Information Appropriate Measures?&amp;quot;
Lisa Wimmer, Yusuf Sale, Paul Hofman, Bernd Bischl, Eyke Hüllermeier
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/wimmer23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/wimmer23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The quantification of aleatoric and epistemic uncertainty in terms of conditional entropy and mutual information …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Quantifying Aleatoric and Epistemic Uncertainty in Machine Learning: Are Conditional Entropy and Mutual Information Appropriate Measures?&amp;quot;
Lisa Wimmer, Yusuf Sale, Paul Hofman, Bernd Bischl, Eyke Hüllermeier
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/wimmer23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/wimmer23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The quantification of aleatoric and epistemic uncertainty in terms of conditional entropy and mutual information, respectively, has recently become quite common in machine learning. While the properties of these measures, which are rooted in information theory, seem appealing at first glance, we identify various incoherencies that call their appropriateness into question. In addition to the measures themselves, we critically discuss the idea of an additive decomposition of total uncertainty into its aleatoric and epistemic constituents. Experiments across different computer vision tasks support our theoretical findings and raise concerns about current practice in uncertainty quantification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/374-oral-slides.pdf"&gt;https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/374-oral-slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2023"></category></entry></feed>