<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Anush Elangovan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_anush-elangovan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Accelerating AI: How AMD and PyTorch Drive Innovation with Seamless Day-0 Support and High Performance</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/accelerating-ai-how-amd-and-pytorch-drive-innovation-with-seamless-day-0-support-and-high-performance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anush Elangovan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/accelerating-ai-how-amd-and-pytorch-drive-innovation-with-seamless-day-0-support-and-high-performance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this keynote presentation, we explore the robust collaboration between AMD and PyTorch that is propelling advancements in artificial intelligence and machine learning. Discover how AMD's commitment to Day-0 PyTorch support ensures that PyTorch users benefit from cutting-edge performance enhancements and out-of-the-box compatibility. We delve into the technical synergies …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this keynote presentation, we explore the robust collaboration between AMD and PyTorch that is propelling advancements in artificial intelligence and machine learning. Discover how AMD's commitment to Day-0 PyTorch support ensures that PyTorch users benefit from cutting-edge performance enhancements and out-of-the-box compatibility. We delve into the technical synergies that make AMD hardware an ideal choice for PyTorch frameworks, showcasing real-world examples of accelerated workflows and breakthrough AI applications. Join us to learn how this dynamic partnership is enabling researchers, developers, and data scientists to push the boundaries of innovation and achieve unprecedented results in their AI projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>