<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Everything you wanted to know about Toastmasters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2018/everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-toastmasters.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tana Franko</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-08:write-the-docs-portland-2018/everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-toastmasters.html</guid><category>lightning talk</category></item><item><title>Continuous Annoyment: Bringing More Zen to a Hectic Writing Environment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/continuous-annoyment-bringing-more-zen-to-a-hectic-writing-environment.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tana Franko
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbztc/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbztc/&lt;/a&gt;
The hectic pace of documentarian tasks is only accelerating these days, spurred on by things like continuous deployment and tools that enable a new, higher level of collaboration. These changes bring not only unprecedented opportunities but also unprecedented challenges.
Today&amp;amp;#39;s technical communicators need to adapt to cope with this change. In this talk, Tina the Tech Writer is back, now leading a team of writers. The team has been almost too successful at proving the value of documentation. Facing a mountain of urgent requests for documentation coverage, potential writer burnout, and attrition, she puts her hedgehog brain skills to practical application on a plan to bring the team to new levels of engagement, happiness, and value -- all while learning to say no when appropriate. It&amp;amp;#39;s all about balance. Tina will share results from her team&amp;amp;#39;s experiment, while outlining a way you can design your own plan to balance any set of challenges and opportunities you&amp;amp;#39;re facing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tana Franko</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:write-the-docs-2016/continuous-annoyment-bringing-more-zen-to-a-hectic-writing-environment.html</guid></item><item><title>Elevating the Hedgehog: Creativity in Tech Writing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2015/elevating-the-hedgehog-creativity-in-tech-writing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tana Franko
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2015/writethedocs/sdmwxf/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2015/writethedocs/sdmwxf/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp;quot;People who hope to thrive in the Conceptual Age must understand the connections between diverse, and seemingly separate, disciplines.&amp;amp;quot; So says Daniel Pink in his book, A Whole New Mind: Why Right-Brainers Will Rule the Future. In this talk, I assert that tech writers are a natural fit to help their organizations transition from the Information Age to the Conceptual Age. I&amp;amp;#39;ll also give and seek ideas on how we as writers can apply Pink&amp;amp;#39;s six aptitudes -- storytelling, empathy, design, humor, games, and finding meaning -- to make our work more fulfilling, if not more competitive.
The key underlying message for those who attend this talk is: YOU are a designer. Even if you haven&amp;amp;#39;t traditionally seen yourself in this role, writers are information designers who serve a unique, user-focused and holistic function on development teams. By recognizing that fact, and opening up space in your work life for creativity, you can have an even bigger impact and a more fulfilling career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tana Franko</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-19:write-the-docs-2015/elevating-the-hedgehog-creativity-in-tech-writing.html</guid></item></channel></rss>