<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Roboto Framework for Test Code Coverage for cloud services.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/roboto-framework-for-test-code-coverage-for-cloud-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test case design is an important phase of software testing life cycle
where test cases are identified. Designing test cases for cloud
solutions requires a different approach from traditional application
oriented testing. The quality which is multidimensional will include
more attributes like network resiliency, fault recovery, reliability and
availability when it comes to cloud-based solutions. If such aspects
when not encompassed through test development framework, it will lead to
high chances of defect leakage in production in an agile mode of
delivery. We propose a strategy to design the test cases which traverse
across different levels of testing to find gaps using the Roboto
framework with Python. The solution provides the teams and the product
owners to get a picture of what is getting tested and how much of
coverage is done. The data can be used in team release discussions to
build confidence in the tests that gets executed as part of that
release. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/robotframework/robotframework"&gt;https://github.com/robotframework/robotframework&lt;/a&gt; Testing
performed for features in a product is diverse and can be widely
categorized into functional, non-functional like reliability, fault
injections etc. Though developing test cases for functional changes is
achievable, arriving at test cases for non-functional requirements is
challenging in the given two-week sprint cycle of agile, and so leads to
defect leakage. Some vital modules in a project would have been running
in production for years and would have different sets of teams working
at different periods. Quantifying test code coverage and quality only by
a number of test cases per feature does not suffice as testing is
multidimensional and has to span across different levels. Measuring and
improving the test code coverage is the challenge generally faced by
product teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">khushbu parakh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/roboto-framework-for-test-code-coverage-for-cloud-services.html</guid><category>quality-assurance</category><category>Functional Testing</category><category>Python</category><category>testing</category><category>robustness</category><category>integration</category><category>automation</category><category>framework</category><category>deployment</category><category>google-cloud</category></item><item><title>Solidarity of Systers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/solidarity-of-systers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have created a web application that provides a stand to women's to share their story. So that government organization helps them to file cases. They will also be provided legal help through SMS or E-mail portal after sign- up. It's a Normal Django App. Codechef and AAP uses an open source forum to discuss things, So I am using that in this app. Use of PostgreSQL 9.6.1 for the database. Federated knOwledge eXtraction Framework for RDF extraction from text based on Ensemble Learning.
So this application help's us highlighting how one can learn about the different ways to use the power of Django to impact billions of people in the world. What happens here is the victim has to report the same thing to many people. When she goes to Police station, to the doctor, to her lawyer, she was being told to narrate the same story to everyone in the court and many other places like lawyers, doctors... This is the most quintessential problems women faces. In police station also she needs to report it to many people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many women who have been stigmatized feel as though they are transforming from a whole person to a tainted one. They feel different and devalued by others. We can have a common place where we can ask a set of questions to her, once she will answer that we can send the set to all the concerned people. She will just ask their numbers or Mail ID's and click on a button in our web app and write the mail id or number and our web app will send the information to all intended person. A common platform, where women being anonymous will be able to share about experiences that they had. Inside some company, about some person. They will enter the story, location, gender, and some more specific things while writing their story. Based on that we will generate a map, as many plots as possible. Another woman can simply search for that location or company and can find what all bad things happen there. She can request the writer contact or mail, we will then send a mail asking the writer if we can leak and try to setup a connection between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Khushbu Parakh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/solidarity-of-systers.html</guid></item></channel></rss>