<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Should I develop my own DS library? Maybe.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/should-i-develop-my-own-ds-library-maybe.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever entertained the idea of developing your own library for data science related tasks to be used among your team or organization? If so, phrases like 'don't recreate the wheel' also probably came to mind. This talk will address compelling arguments on both sides of the topic while telling the story of why we at Aetna ultimately decided to do just that and what we learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piero Ferrante</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/should-i-develop-my-own-ds-library-maybe.html</guid></item><item><title>Creating a contemporary lending risk management system using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/creating-a-contemporary-lending-risk-management-system-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lending involves risk and in order to be a successful lender at scale
that risk needs to be mitigated. We'll be discussing how C2FO has built
a suite of risk management tools for underwriting and portfolio
management using the PyData ecosystem, rpy2 (for integrating R), and
Spyre (for building a simple web application).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="piero-ferrante-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Piero Ferrante Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piero Ferrante is the Director of Data Science at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://c2fo.com/"&gt;C2FO&lt;/a&gt;. He and his team are focused on optimizing
C2FO’s capital markets through applied machine learning and the
development of quantitative risk management systems. In the past he has
applied his expertise in healthcare, telecom, insurance, and mobile
advertising at Fortune 500 companies and startups. He holds a M.S. in
Predictive Analytics from Northwestern University, a B.S. in Finance and
Management Information Systems from the University of Delaware, and is
an adjunct professor of Text Analytics at Rockhurst University. Piero
also helps organize the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/Data-Science-KC/"&gt;Kansas City Data Science
Meetup&lt;/a&gt; and advises &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://playithealth.com/index.html"&gt;Play-it
Heath&lt;/a&gt;, a digital health
engagement solution, on algorithms and data strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piero Ferrante</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/creating-a-contemporary-lending-risk-management-system-using-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Creating a Contemporary Lending Risk Management System Using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/creating-a-contemporary-lending-risk-management-system-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lending involves risk and in order to be a successful lender at scale that risk needs to be mitigated. We'll be discussing how C2FO has built a suite of risk management tools for underwriting and portfolio management using the PyData ecosystem, rpy2 (for integrating R), and Spyre (for building a simple web application).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering a sophisticated in-house risk management solution for a commercial lending platform doesn't necessarily need to involve millions of lines of low-level code, clunky desktop applications, fancy front-end development, or messy spreadsheets. That is, so long as the problem is approached objectively and the solutions are evaluated critically.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piero Ferrante</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/creating-a-contemporary-lending-risk-management-system-using-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Creating a Contemporary Risk Management System Using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/creating-a-contemporary-risk-management-system-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lending involves risk and in order to be a successful lender at scale that risk needs to be mitigated. We'll be discussing how C2FO has built a suite of risk management tools for underwriting and portfolio management using the PyData ecosystem, rpy2 (for integrating R), and Spyre (for building a simple web application).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piero Ferrante</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-28:pydata-chicago-2016/creating-a-contemporary-risk-management-system-using-python.html</guid><category>management</category></item></channel></rss>