<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tim Schilling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tim-schilling.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>You got that nice tech salary, now what?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/you-got-that-nice-tech-salary-now-what.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Schilling</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-24:/djangocon-us-2024/you-got-that-nice-tech-salary-now-what.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talking about finances is awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several things I'd rather talk about with a group of strangers before finances. However, I believe that as a part of the tech community, there's a moral responsibility to make sound personal financial decisions because you earn a comfortable salary. I have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talking about finances is awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several things I'd rather talk about with a group of strangers before finances. However, I believe that as a part of the tech community, there's a moral responsibility to make sound personal financial decisions because you earn a comfortable salary. I have made several mistakes along my career, and I'm probably still making some. The goal here is to make it a bit easier for us to have these conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the first in my family to graduate from college. One of my parents attended some college. They knew how to balance a budget, and they knew to max your employer's 401k matching program. Beyond that, there wasn't much of a plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't have any financial literacy when I entered the tech industry. In fact, I fell prey to a corporate insurance provider, bought an insurance-investment type product and contributed to it for years! I've left money in my savings account because I was scared of the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk you will have a basic understanding of:
- The importance of planning, budgeting and saving
- Where to put your savings
- Maximizing employer contributions
- How to evaluate an index fund&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>