<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Karen Jex</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_karen-jex.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to keep your database happy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2023/how-to-keep-your-database-happy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Karen Jex</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-23:/pycon-uk-2023/how-to-keep-your-database-happy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;5 simple things you can put in place to make sure you have a database that runs smoothly and performs well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't want to spend too much time looking after your database; you've got better things to do with your time. You do, however, want your database to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;5 simple things you can put in place to make sure you have a database that runs smoothly and performs well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't want to spend too much time looking after your database; you've got better things to do with your time. You do, however, want your database to run smoothly and perform well. Fortunately, there are a few simple things that you can do to make sure your database ticks along nicely in the background.
I've put together my top 5 tips, based on things that have been useful to me as a DBA and as a database consultant. These are things you can put in place, without too much effort, to make sure your database works well. The focus will be on PostgreSQL, but most of the tips are also relevant to other databases.
You'll come away with some simple ways to keep your database happy, leaving you free to concentrate on developing your application.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon UK 2023"></category></entry></feed>