<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fitting Many Dimensions into One: The Promise of Hierarchical Indices for Data Beyond Two Dimensions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/fitting-many-dimensions-into-one-the-promise-of-hierarchical-indices-for-data-beyond-two-dimensions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent versions of Pandas have warned users of the imminent deprecation
of the Panel, Panda’s name-sake data structure for storing
three-dimensional data. This talk will examine the tradeoffs in
performance and interface between two types of Panel alternatives: using
hierarchical indices in Pandas and StaticFrame, or using true
n-dimensional arrays in NumPy or xarray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will aid those working in data science and related fields by
examining the tradeoffs between working with data in true
multidimensional data structures (i.e., NumPy and xarray) versus working
with hierarchical index implementations on one- or two-dimensional data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immediate point of departure is Pandas imminent deprecation of the
Panel: for Pandas users who have used the Panel, this talk will
illustrate how to transition away from the Panel and the tradeoffs in
Panel alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain how hierarchical indices work by comparing two
implementations: the Pandas MultiIndex and the StaticFrame
IndexHierarchy. The StaticFream IndexHierarchy offers a new, independent
implementation of hierarchical indices that deviates from Pandas in
significant ways: the index is literally composed of other index
objects, permitting usage of specialized index types (such as datetime
indices), efficient memory usage of shared immutable objects, and the
enforcement of a strict tree graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After demonstrating how hierarchical indices can support higher
dimensional data in one or two-dimensional arrays, the power and
flexibility of selecting and slicing data with hierarchical indices will
be demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will close with performance analysis, isolating the overhead of
using hierarchical indices over true multi-dimensional array
representations, and comparing the performance of selection, slicing,
grouping, and function application of hierarchical data in NumPy,
xarray, Pandas and StaticFrame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at both beginners, new to hierarchical indices, and
more advanced users interested in interface design and performance
tradeoffs. Basic familiarity with NumPy and Pandas is expected. Audience
members will leave with a better understanding of how hierarchical
indices work, and what tradeoffs are made when using them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Ariza</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:pydata-la-2019/fitting-many-dimensions-into-one-the-promise-of-hierarchical-indices-for-data-beyond-two-dimensions.html</guid></item><item><title>StaticFrame: An Immutable Alternative to Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2018/staticframe-an-immutable-alternative-to-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;StaticFrame provides Pandas-like data structures that enforce
immutability. StaticFrame narrows and refines Pandas-style interfaces,
which, when combined with immutability, reduces opportunities for error.
In addition, StaticFrame offers a range of new and powerful iterators
for function application with built-in concurrency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Ariza</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-23:pydata-la-2018/staticframe-an-immutable-alternative-to-pandas.html</guid></item></channel></rss>