<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_anusua-trivedi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>An example of Predictive Analytics: Building a Recommendation Engine using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/an-example-of-predictive-analytics-building-a-recommendation-engine-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anusua Trivedi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-26:pydata-seattle-2015/an-example-of-predictive-analytics-building-a-recommendation-engine-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recommendation systems are needed to locate appropriate data on same topic or on similar topics of interest. In this talk, I will describe a recommender system framework for PubMed articles. I will present the background and motivation for these recommendation systems, and discuss the implementations of this PubMed recommendation engine with codes and examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular features of Big Data is predictive analytics. Predictive analytics is a form of business intelligence gathering. Far from the latest business buzzword, predictive analytics is a set of techniques that have become fundamental to the business strategies. In this tutorial, we will cover an example of predictive analytics through implementing a recommendation engine using python. A recommendation engine (sometimes referred to as a recommender system) is a tool that lets algorithm developers predict what a user may or may not like among a list of given items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very common now a day to have access to large amount of data on similar or related topics. Recommendation systems are needed to locate appropriate data on same topic or on similar topics of interest. In this talk, I will describe a recommender system framework for PubMed articles. PubMed is a free search engine that primarily accesses the MEDLINE database of references and abstracts on life-sciences and biomedical topics. The proposed recommender system produces two types of recommendations – i) content-based recommendation and (ii) recommendations based on similarities with other users' search profiles. The first type of recommendation, viz., content-based recommendation, can efficiently search for material that is similar in context or topic to the input publication. The second mechanism generates recommendations using the search history of users whose search profiles match the current user. In the talk I will present the background and motivation for these recommendation systems, and discuss the implementations of this PubMed recommendation system using python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/PyData/an-example-of-predictive-analytics-building-a-recommendation-engine-using-pythonanusua-trivedi"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/PyData/an-example-of-predictive-analytics-building-a-recommendation-engine-using-pythonanusua-trivedi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Transfer Learning and Finetuning Deep Convolution Neural Network</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/transfer-learning-and-finetuning-deep-convolution-neural-network.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anusua Trivedi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/transfer-learning-and-finetuning-deep-convolution-neural-network.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016
Anusua Trivedi | Transfer Learning and Finetuning Deep Convolution Neural Network on Different Domain Specific Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a method to apply a pre-trained deep convolution neural network (DCNN) on images to improve prediction accuracy. We use a pre-trained DCNN on two very different domain specific datasets, and apply fine-tuning to transfer the learned features to the prediction. Our approach improves prediction accuracy on both domain-specific datasets, compared to state-of-the-art approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we propose prediction techniques using deep learning on different types of images datasets – medical images and fashion images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show how to build a generic deep learning model, which could be used with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fluorescein angiographic eye image to predict Diabetic Retinopathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fashion image to predict the clothing type in that image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a method to apply a pre-trained deep convolution neural network (DCNN) on images to improve prediction accuracy. We use an ImageNet pre-trained DCNN and apply fine-tuning to transfer the learned features to the prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use this fine-tuned model on two very different domain specific datasets. Our approach improves prediction accuracy on both domain-specific datasets, compared to state-of-the-art Machine Learning approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>