<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Julia Signell</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hacking Dask: Diving Into Dask's Internals</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/hacking-dask-diving-into-dasks-internals.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dask is a popular Python library for scaling and parallelizing Python code on a single machine or across a cluster. It provides familiar, high-level interfaces to extend the PyData ecosystem (e.g. NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn) to larger-than-memory or distributed environments, as well as lower-level interfaces for parallelizing custom algorithms and workflows. In this tutorial we’ll cover more advanced features of Dask like task graph optimization, the worker and scheduler plugin system, how to inspect the internal state of a cluster, and more. Attendees should walk away with a deeper understanding of Dask’s internals, an introduction to more advanced features, and ideas of how they can apply these features effectively to their own data intensive workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bourbeau</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/hacking-dask-diving-into-dasks-internals.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>Making interactive visualizations easy, inside and outside of notebooks - Julia Signell</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2018/making-interactive-visualizations-easy-inside-and-outside-of-notebooks-julia-signell.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julia Signell</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-16:/pydata-dc-2018/making-interactive-visualizations-easy-inside-and-outside-of-notebooks-julia-signell.html</guid><category>PyData DC 2018</category></item><item><title>Data-centric exploration using intake, dask, hvplot, datashader, panel, and binder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-centric-exploration-using-intake-dask-hvplot-datashader-panel-and-binder.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discovering a new dataset is exciting, but it can also be daunting. How will you read it? Will it fit in memory? What meaning can be derived? Can you share that with others? This talk describes an opinionated method of data exploration going from data ingestion to dashboard deployment and showing how everything comes together into a complete and repeatable workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julia Signell</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:/pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-centric-exploration-using-intake-dask-hvplot-datashader-panel-and-binder.html</guid><category>PyData New York City 2019</category></item><item><title>Visualize any Data Easily, from Notebooks to Dashboards</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/visualize-any-data-easily-from-notebooks-to-dashboards.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial you will see how to visualize and communicate your data easily and effectively using Python tools. You'll learn how to use Panel to lay out your existing plots with widgets to make apps in the notebook or as deployed dashboards, hvPlot to make your Pandas or Xarray .plot() API calls return interactive, explorable plots, HoloViews and GeoViews to help you explore multidimensional data naturally without having to build a plot for each combination or sample of the data space, and Datashader to visualize even the very largest datasets faithfully in a web browser. See pyviz.org for links to all these tools and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bednar</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/scipy-2019/visualize-any-data-easily-from-notebooks-to-dashboards.html</guid><category>SciPy 2019</category><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Dask Tutorial: The PyData Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/dask-tutorial-the-pydata-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dask is a flexible library for parallel computing in Python. Dask provides high-level interfaces to extend the PyData ecosystem to larger-than-memory or distributed environments, as well as lower-level interfaces to customize workflows. This tutorial will be a data-oriented, hands-on, workshop that will show new users how to scale NumPy and pandas via the Dask Array and Dask DataFrame collections, and how to use the interactive diagnostic tools to understand their computational performance. It will also cover the low-level Dask Delayed and Futures interfaces, and introduce cluster deployments. No previous Dask experience is required, though knowledge of Python basics and familiarity with NumPy and pandas is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dask/dask-tutorial"&gt;https://github.com/dask/dask-tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalia Clementi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/dask-tutorial-the-pydata-ecosystem.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item></channel></rss>