<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_miguel-vaz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Financial Risk Management: Analytics and Aggregation with the PyData stack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/financial-risk-management-analytics-and-aggregation-with-the-pydata-stack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Vaz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-20:pydata-london-2015/financial-risk-management-analytics-and-aggregation-with-the-pydata-stack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Bokeh, Pandas and a bit of Apache Spark to address the
flexibility, performance / data volume requirements of standard
financial risk management processes. Examples in the talk illustrate
the model calibration and backtesting processes of a market risk
model (VaR Filtered Historical Simulation), which quantifies possible
future losses arising from market price movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Financial institutions regularly estimate possible portfolio losses
arising from (future) changes in the market values of their assets, e.g.
using the Value at Risk (VaR) metric. We show a VaR model using Filtered
Historical Simulation and illustrate some of the usual processes for
calibrating, validating and analysing these models, such as calibration
and backtesting. Although the model is relatively simple, the challenges
posed by their different requirements - flexibility, data volume,
performance - inevitably lead to many shortcuts and complexity. With the
ultimate goal of managing this complexity, we explore and evaluate, with
concrete coded examples, the PyData (e.g. Pandas, Bokeh) and Apache
Spark frameworks from a practitioner's point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Networks meet Finance in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/networks-meet-finance-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Vaz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/networks-meet-finance-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will talk about network models in finance, and walk through real data and very visual examples using the pydata toolset - pandas, bokeh, pandas, networkx, ipywidgets. Special focus will be given to correlation networks, with applications to market characterization and portfolio risk management (as done in Pozzi 2013) using the latest available market data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of the 2008 Lehman and the subsequent European debt crisis, it became clear that both financial industry and regulators had underestimated the degree of interconnectedness and interdependency across financial assets and institutions. This type of information is especially well represented by network models, which had first gained popularity in computer science, biology and social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of network models in finance is already providing insight into the structure of the financial world and the economy. Network models are proving to be useful tools for providing early-warning signals of systemic risk (e.g. Squartini 2013), measuring liquidity and concentration risk, identifying sectors from time-series correlations (e.g. Fenn 2011) as well as insights into finding diversified baskets of assets in the classical investment framework (e.g. Pozzi 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will provide an overview of some of the aforementioned work, and walk through (real data) examples using the pydata toolset. Special focus will be given to the study of correlation networks, with applications to portfolio risk management as in (Pozzi 2013) using the latest available market data. The examples make heavy use of pandas, bokeh, pandas, networkx, ipywidgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pandas"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="networkx"></category><category term="ipywidgets"></category></entry></feed>