<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sound Modelling - parametric methods and deep learning representations to create and shape audio</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/sound-modelling-parametric-methods-and-deep-learning-representations-to-create-and-shape-audio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sound in digital form for years is in the loop of steps: record, mix,
edit, playback and listen. Some creative ones did create synthetic
speech and music with affordable tools. Now both computation and data
resources available made synthesis and sound shaping possible using
parametric, physical methods or with the latest deep learning
representation models. Discover the theory and code to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound in digital form for years is in the loop of steps: record, mix,
edit, playback and listen. Some creative ones did create synthetic
speech and music with affordable tools. Now both computation and data
resources available made synthesis and sound shaping possible using
parametric, physical methods or with the latest deep learning
representation models. Discover the theory and code to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Techniques like deep learning can now create a whole set of basic audio
processing functions - filtering, equalization, compression - are
becoming available to model too. They can also extract latent
representation and make it be controlled to produce real sound. One can
create his own replica for specific guitar amplifier sound or try to
find parameters that produces unique audio for film or game sound
effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take a quest to find out how to model sound by exploring and
running experiments with python code. The experiment consists of three
main parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploration how to get audio data and represent it using equations
and recent deep learning models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis by visualization, clustering .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mimicking real vibrations by approximation using parametric physical
models .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab DNN models to make them speak, play and sing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I will describe the model used, present the code the
results that perform audio out of the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, at the end of this talk you will have learned (I hope) how
deal with sound signals and that it may be combined to create music or
just bizarre, wacky sounds&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pawel Cyrta</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-12:pydata-warsaw-2019/sound-modelling-parametric-methods-and-deep-learning-representations-to-create-and-shape-audio.html</guid></item></channel></rss>