<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Gokul Prabagaren</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modeling Financial Data In Cassandra To Serve Real Time + Batch Workloads</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2021/modeling-financial-data-in-cassandra-to-serve-real-time-batch-workloads.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Modeling Financial Data In Cassandra To Serve Real Time And Batch Workloads At Same Time&amp;quot; by: Gokul Prabagaren
This talk will explain how we have modeled customer rewards data in CapitalOne using Apache Cassandra to serve Real time microservice based workloads ( Customer accessing their rewards online ) and batch Apache Spark workloads ( Customer statements ) at same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CapitalOne being Tech Company in Banking business, we are 100% Cloud operated Company. All our workloads are Cloud Native. This talk covers one of such use case which will explain how we have modeled customer rewards data in CapitalOne using Apache Cassandra to serve Real time microservice based workloads and batch Apache Spark workloads at same time. When customer accesses their Rewards from web or Customer receives their Rewards in Statements the Cassandra table we modeled plays a central role and services both the different workloads at same time. This talk will cover how Cassandra data is used by Spring based microservice and Spark based batch workload. I am part of team which designed and developed this application ground up and serving millions of customers now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2021 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2021.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gokul Prabagaren</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-03-22:/python-web-conf-2021/modeling-financial-data-in-cassandra-to-serve-real-time-batch-workloads.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2021</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2021</category></item><item><title>Challenges of Spark Application Coexisting with NoSQL Databases</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/challenges-of-spark-application-coexisting-with-nosql-databases.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CapitalOne is the first US bank to exist out of on-premises and moved completely on Cloud. Over this process of modernizing our application in CapitalOne Card Rewards, we developed ground up custom transactions processing application on open source technologies like Spark, Mongo, Cassandra etc. This application currently processes millions of customer transactions daily providing them millions of miles, cash and points everyday. In process of building our application, we came across many challenging issues to have Spark application process data from MongoDB and Cassandra backend to serve customers. This talk is going to focus on few of those issues, what is the impact of those issue and how to mitigate them. The following are list of issues this talk will focus on:
* How Cassandra Key sequence is important and how it impacts in querying
* How Cassandra batching helps and works well with Spark partitions
* Importance of Cassandra Data Modeling and its implications after MVP/Deployment
* How to manage Mongo Connection (at JVM level)
* Implications of using MongoSpark connector on its Partitioner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the issues highlighted are faced by us in our application. This talk will focus on what are these issues in Spark/Mongo/Cassandra app environment and how to mitigate them. Anyone using Spark apps with Mongo and Cassandra databases as backend can benefits from this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gokul Prabagaren</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/challenges-of-spark-application-coexisting-with-nosql-databases.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>