<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vodka powered by Whiskeyberry PI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/vodka-powered-by-whiskeyberry-pi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would you like to talk with someone but even your dog doesn’t want to listen to you? Would you love to have a drink but you are too tired to prepare one? Your problems are solved! During this presentation, you will find out how to build your own Bartender who talks with you and what is the most important serves drinks for you! All that you need is Amazon Alexa, simple Python Flask application, Raspberry PI and few pumps. I will go through all the steps starting from the creation of Bartender service with Amazon Alexa, development of Flask application with Bartender logic, deployment on Raspberry PI and connection with pumps. In the end, the most active participants will be allowed to talk with Bartender and ask for drinks prepared from local whiskey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will briefly introduce an audience with existing voice assistants and explain why I choose Amazon Alexa to build Bartender. Base on examples I will show what is the flow of requests and responses using selected assistant. I will say how it can be used for the purpose of this great project! I will briefly guide the audience through the process of creating Bartender skill in Amazon Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I will tell how to build a Python application for serving the drinks. I will show example source code using Flask-Ask library which wraps Amazon API and makes life easier. With only a few lines of code we will create full-value Bartender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least part of my presentation will be dedicated to Raspberry PI which is responsible for serving the ingredients of drinks. I will explain how to connect and control the pumps. I will show example source code for serving the drinks according to defined recipes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maciej Polańczyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pygotham-2018/vodka-powered-by-whiskeyberry-pi.html</guid></item><item><title>Mock it right! A beginner’s guide to world of tests and mocks.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyparis-2017/mock-it-right-a-beginners-guide-to-world-of-tests-and-mocks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main goal of this presentation is to make beginner audience familiar
with mocks and patches. I will say what are the best practices and what
kind of mistakes, done by many developers, may be avoided so the dragons
will not come. During this presentation I will prepare mock-it-o drink
as a prize.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maciej Polańczyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-12:pyparis-2017/mock-it-right-a-beginners-guide-to-world-of-tests-and-mocks.html</guid></item><item><title>Mock it right! A beginner’s guide to world of tests and mocks.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/mock-it-right-a-beginners-guide-to-world-of-tests-and-mocks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main goal of this presentation is to make beginner audience
familiar with mocks and patches but there is a chance that more
experienced ones will also find something new for themselves.
Presentation shows the common use cases when developing unit tests. I
will say what are the best practices when working with mocks and
patches and what kind of mistakes, done by many developers, may be
avoided so the dragons will not come. During this presentation I will
prepare mock-it-o drink as a prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will briefly introduce an audience with the topic of unit
testing. Then I will show a simple code which will be tested during
the presentation. It covers all common use cases of writing unit
tests which are usage of mocks, patches and their side effects. In
the end I will show a template of unit test which will be extended
according to our needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I will say what is a mock, and what are the benefits of using
it. Why it is better than any Dummy class implemented for purpose of
unit tests and, what is the most important and sometimes forgotten by
experienced developers, how to create the best mock, which involves
using spec_set and spec to protect us from dragons when interface of
mocked class changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least part of my presentation will be dedicated to
patches. I will explain when and how patches should be used (how to
use side_effect, patch properties and environment variables).
Finally, I will say how to avoid common mistakes when working with
patches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maciej Polańczyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-10:europython-2017/mock-it-right-a-beginners-guide-to-world-of-tests-and-mocks.html</guid></item></channel></rss>