<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyCon UK 2017 - John Pinner Awards</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/pycon-uk-2017-john-pinner-awards.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicholas Tollervey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/pycon-uk-2017-john-pinner-awards.html</guid></item><item><title>Getting Meaning from Scientific Articles</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/getting-meaning-from-scientific-articles.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bibliography process means every scientist regularly has to go
through a lot of published articles in parallel to her/his research. The
aim is to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;know what other researchers are doing: they might be ahead
of you, they might have proven your project is a dead end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get some context to interpret your research results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using specialised search engines can be inefficient if you don't use
the &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; keywords. Researcher also tend to find bibliography
boring so it would be interesting to automate part of the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I'll answer the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can Python machine learning libraries (nltk, scikit-learn) be used
to determine whether a research article is worth reading?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll use the TF-IDF measure to identify frequent topics appearing in
specific scientific articles and train a classifier to distinguish
between relevant and non-relevant articles depending and someone's
interests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Éléonore Mayola</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-20:pydata-london-2015/getting-meaning-from-scientific-articles.html</guid></item><item><title>Telling stories with data: from analysis to web visualisations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/telling-stories-with-data-from-analysis-to-web-visualisations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When analysing datasets one usually creates static visualisations. But wouldn't it be nice to use the same project to share interactive web visualisations without learning new tools. Altair is a Python API using JSON to build visualisations in a Jupyter notebook or in the browser. My talk will take the audience through using Altair to analyse a dataset and generate web based visualisations with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Éléonore Mayola</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/telling-stories-with-data-from-analysis-to-web-visualisations.html</guid><category>altair</category></item></channel></rss>