<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hayley-denbraver.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-04T13:55:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Engineering Ethics and Open Source Software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/engineering-ethics-and-open-source-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T13:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T13:55:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-us-2019/engineering-ethics-and-open-source-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems that every week there is a news story that prompts software
developers to think about the ethical implications of their work. As
individuals, teams, and communities we need to consider the impact of
the code we write. But what about code that we are using, but did not
create?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Open Source Software factor into this equation? OSS is used
across the industry, but is written and maintained primarily by
volunteers. What are best practices for maintainers, contributors,
individual users, and companies who incorporate open source into their
work? How can we protect ourselves and our users, while still benefiting
from the innovation and collaboration of open source software?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Recursion, Fractals, and the Python Turtle Module</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2019/recursion-fractals-and-the-python-turtle-module.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-23:pycascades-2019/recursion-fractals-and-the-python-turtle-module.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recursion can be a difficult thing to grasp at first. This talk will teach the basics of recursion, using fractals drawn by the python turtle module to help attendees 'see' how recursion works. Additionally, fractals are super cool and the turtle module is fun for all ages!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2019.pycascades.com/talks/recursion-fractals-and-the-python-turtle-module/"&gt;https://2019.pycascades.com/talks/recursion-fractals-and-the-python-turtle-module/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Welcome to Jurassic Park: Where Chaos and Engineering Ethics Collide</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/welcome-to-jurassic-park-where-chaos-and-engineering-ethics-collide.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-03:north-bay-python-2018/welcome-to-jurassic-park-where-chaos-and-engineering-ethics-collide.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who would believe that theme park filled with genetically engineered
dinosaurs could have failed? Fragile software and the lead developer’s
deeply unethical behavior played a huge role in the downfall of this
amazing park. This talk will explore the relationship between
engineering ethics, chaos, and building resilient systems. Expect to
laugh, cry, and learn to build a better park.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>We Are 3000 Years Behind: Let's Talk About Engineering Ethics</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/we-are-3000-years-behind-lets-talk-about-engineering-ethics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/we-are-3000-years-behind-lets-talk-about-engineering-ethics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your apartment building where you wake up. The water you drink. The car
you drive. The road on which you drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first hour of your day, you rely on the work of several distinct
branches of engineering, whose practitioners are licensed and
accountable to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second hour of your day, you may sit down at your desk to write
code that dozens, hundreds, thousands, millions of people interact with
in some way–but what do they know about you, your intentions, and your
training?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A licensed Civil Engineer turned software developer will talk through
how her former field approached ethics–something they have been
iterating on for more than 3000 years. She will discuss how lessons
learned from other engineering professions could apply to software, and
where our industry may need a new approach to ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>We Are 3000 Years Behind: Let's Talk About Engineering Ethics</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/we-are-3000-years-behind-lets-talk-about-engineering-ethics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pygotham-2018/we-are-3000-years-behind-lets-talk-about-engineering-ethics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your apartment building where you wake up.
The water you drink.
The car you drive.
The road on which you drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first hour of your day, you rely on the work of several distinct branches of engineering, whose practitioners are licensed and accountable to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second hour of your day, you may sit down at your desk to write code that dozens, hundreds, thousands, millions of people interact with in some way--but what do they know about you, your intentions, and your training?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A licensed Civil Engineer turned software developer will talk through how her former field approached ethics--something they have been iterating on for more than 3000 years. She will discuss how lessons learned from other engineering professions could apply to software, and where our industry may need a new approach to ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Recursion, Fractals, and the Python Turtle Module</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/recursion-fractals-and-the-python-turtle-module.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/recursion-fractals-and-the-python-turtle-module.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand recursion you must first understand recursion.
Alternatively, you could come to a talk that will demonstrate the basics
of recursion, using fractals drawn by the python turtle module!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are fractals? Fractals are psychedelic designs that appear
basically the same regardless of scale. They also appear all over
nature–consider how a tree trunk and branches is similar in structure to
branches and twigs or how a wave is made of mini waves. Best of all,
fractals can be constructed using recursive functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the turtle module? It is part of the standard python library
that can be used to draw amazing things and is commonly used as a tool
for learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come for the recursion, stay for the amazing fractals, and leave knowing
that no turtles were harmed in the making of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is suitable for all python enthusiasts. Those who love
mathematics will love this talk. Advanced developers will learn more
about a tool that can be used to teach people to code. There is
something for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - 2016-06-01</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-06-01.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-01:pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-06-01.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry></feed>