<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tornado in Depth</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/tornado-in-depth.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] O Vilaplana - 3 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tornado is a non-blocking light-weight web server and framework. There’s
been many introductory talks about it, and it’s time to look deeper into
it: not just what Tornado does, but how it does it and what can we learn
from it when designing our own concurrent systems. We’ll cover each
topic in two parts: first we’ll see how to use a certain feature in our
applications; then, we’ll dig into Tornado’s source code to see how it
really works. How much time we’ll spend in the “how to use” will depend
on the audience’s knowledge of Tornado. Getting Started: quickly get a
simple Tornado application up and running. We’ll keep digging into,
changing and poking this Application for most of the talk. An
Application Listens: what an Application is, how does Tornado start it
and how does it process its requests. Application and IOLoop: we’ll look
at how the IOLoop receives the connections from the users and passes
them on to the Applications. Scheduled Tasks: we’ll see how to schedule
tasks and how the IOLoop will run them. Generators: we’ll learn to use
generators to handle the responses of our asynchronous calls, and how
they work with the IOLoop. Websockets: how to use them and how they
work. IOStream: how do Tornado’s non- blocking sockets work. Database:
how to use non-blocking sockets to connect to a MySQL or MongoDB
database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">O Vilaplana</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-04:europython-2012/tornado-in-depth.html</guid></item></channel></rss>