<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Productionizing your ML code seamlessly</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/productionizing-your-ml-code-seamlessly.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science and Machine Learning are hot topics right now for Software
Engineers and beyond. There are a lot of python tools that allow you to
hack together a notebook to quickly get insight on your data, or train a
model to predict or classify. Or you might have inherited some data
wrangling and modeling {Jupyter/Zeppelin} notebook code from someone
else, like the resident data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code works on test data, when you run the cells in the right order
(skipping cell 22), and you believe that the insight gained from this
work would be a valuable game changer. But now how do you take this
experimental code into production, and keep it up-to-date with a regular
retraining schedule? And what do you need to do after that, to ensure
that it remains reliable and brings value in the long term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be the questions this talk will answer, focusing on 2 main
themes: What does running an ML model in production involve? How to
improve your development workflow to make the path to production easier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will draw examples from real projects at Yelp, like migrating
a pandas/sklearn classification project into production with pyspark,
while aiming to give advice that is not dependent on specific
frameworks, or tools, and is useful for listeners from all backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauris Jullien</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/productionizing-your-ml-code-seamlessly.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Productionizing your ML code seamlessly</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/productionizing-your-ml-code-seamlessly.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science and Machine Learning are hot topics right now for Software
Engineers and beyond. And there are a lot of python tools that allow you
to hack together a notebook to quickly get insight on your data, or
train a model to predict, or classify. Or you might have inherited some
data wrangling and modeling {Jupyter/Zeppelin} notebook code from
someone else, like the resident data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code works on test data, when you run the cells in the right order
(skipping cell 22), and you believe that the insight gained from this
work would be a valuable game changer. But now how do you take this
experimental code into production, and keep it up-to-date with a regular
retraining schedule? And what do you need to do after that, to ensure
that it remains reliable and brings value in the long term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be the questions this talk will answer, focusing on 2 main
themes: 1. What does running an ML model in production involve? 2. How
to improve your development workflow to make the path to production
easier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will draw examples from real projects at Yelp, like migrating
a pandas/sklearn classification project into production with pyspark,
while aiming to give advice that is not dependent on specific
frameworks, or tools, and is useful for listeners from all backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauris Jullien</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/productionizing-your-ml-code-seamlessly.html</guid></item><item><title>Verified fakes with OpenAPI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/verified-fakes-with-openapi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lauris Jullien&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;herrbot_DE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a backend engineer &amp;#64;Yelp in Hamburg for 3 years. Before that I was working with robots &amp;#64;Aldebaran Robotics. And before that I was doing my own startup :) I like clean APIs, all you can do with data, and as a good French, wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to test code that depends on external services. Often such services are mocked, but with time, it can be challenging to keep these mocks up to date. Verified fakes can solve this problem, and we will see how to set them up using OpenAPI and python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your code depends on an external (third-party) service, testing it can be challenging. It may be expensive, slow or unreliable to call that service in tests. A classic approach is to mock such service or its network calls. But then the challenge becomes keeping the mocks up to date with the third-party services. Using verified fakes allows us to replace a service while guaranteeing that it stays up to date. This can be achieved in different ways: using recent network recordings (e.g. vcrpy), running a test suite against the mock and the real service to compare the results, or relying on an API contract like OpenAPI, or avro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAPI* is a specification that documents how a service API works and enforces it by validating requests and responses for the service. We can then check the mocks against the OpenAPI specification to make sure they are up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will explain how to set up such verified fakes with OpenAPI, and present a new open-source library, pyramid_mock_server. Here are the 3 main focuses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick introduction on OpenAPI and how to use it with bravado, the python OpenAPI client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to set up Verified Fakes: using pyramid_mock_server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usage &amp;#64;Yelp: usage of fakes and OpenAPI for unit tests, acceptance tests, and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk focuses on OpenAPI, but the learnings and methodology can be extended to any other API specification languages (or python web frameworks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OpenAPI initiative is a cross-vendor consortium focused on creating, evolving and promoting a vendor neutral description format for APIs. As an open governance structure under the Linux Foundation, its members include Google, IBM, Atlassian and PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauris Jullien</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/verified-fakes-with-openapi.html</guid><category>use-case</category><category>python</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Asynchronous network requests in a web application</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lauris Jullien - Asynchronous network requests in a web application
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing  asynchronous calls from within an endpoint in a web app
can be desirable but hard to achieve.
This talk will explore different solutions for this (running Twisted
event loop, Co-Routines, Asyncio, …) and how well they play with the
different parallelization models of common WSGI web servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the more and more popular SOA paradigm, it’s common for services to
have to compose responses with resources from many different services.
Everyone’s first idea will probably be to call each service
synchronously with your favorite python HTTP library. This
unfortunately doesn’t scale well and tens of successive network calls
will make your endpoints painfully slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One solution is to parallelize these network calls. If you are already
using an asynchronous web app (such as Tornado or Twisted), more
asynchronous in your asynchronous shouldn’t be much of a challenge.
But if you chose not to dive into the madness of chained Deferred
calls, and used a standard prefork/threaded WSGI web server (such as
Gunicorn or uWSGI) to run your Django/Flask/Pyramid application, you
might find yourself wondering how to manage these asynchronous calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore different solutions (running Twisted event
loop, Co-Routines, Asyncio, …) and how well they play with the
different parallelization models of WSGI web servers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauris Jullien</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application.html</guid></item></channel></rss>