<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_umit-mert-cakmak.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Recent advancements in NLP and Deep Learning: A Quant's Perspective</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/recent-advancements-in-nlp-and-deep-learning-a-quants-perspective.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Umit Mert Cakmak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/recent-advancements-in-nlp-and-deep-learning-a-quants-perspective.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a gold-rush among hedge-funds for text mining algorithms to
quantify textual data and generate trading signals. Harnessing the power
of alternative data sources became crucial to find novel ways of
enhancing trading strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the proliferation of new data sources, natural language data became
one of the most important data sources which could represent the public
sentiment and opinion about market events, which then can be used to
predict financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk is split into 5 parts;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is a quant and how do they use NLP?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How deep learning has changed NLP?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s get dirty with word embeddings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performant deep learning layer for NLP: The Recurrent Layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using all that to make money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="who-is-a-quant-and-how-do-they-use-nlp"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Who is a quant and how do they use NLP?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quants use mathematical and statistical methods to create algorithmic
trading strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to recent advances in available deep learning frameworks and
datasets (time series, text, video etc) together with decreasing cost of
parallelisable hardware, quants are experimenting with various NLP
methods which are applicable to quantitative trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we will get familiar with the brief history of text
mining work that quants have done so far and recent advancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-deep-learning-has-changed-nlp"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. How deep learning has changed NLP?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, data representation and modeling methods are vastly
improved. For example when it comes to textual data, rather than using
high dimensional sparse matrices and suffering from curse of
dimensionality, distributional vectors are more efficient to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, I will talk about distributional vectors a.k.a. word
embeddings and recent neural network architectures used when building
NLP models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lets-get-dirty-with-word-embeddings"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Let’s get dirty with word embeddings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models such as Word2vec or GloVe helps us create word embeddings from
large unlabeled corpus which represent the relation between words, their
contextual relationships in numerical vector spaces and these
representations not only work for words but also could be used for
phrases and sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, I will talk about inner workings of these models and
important points when creating domain-specific embeddings (e.g. for
sentiment analysis in financial domain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="performant-deep-learning-layer-for-nlp-the-recurrent-layer"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Performant deep learning layer for NLP: The Recurrent Layer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs) can capture and hold the information
which was seen before (context), which is important for dealing with
unbounded context in NLP tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) networks, which is a special type of RNN,
can understand the context even if words have long term dependencies,
words which are far back in their sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will compare LSTMs with other deep learning
architectures and will look at LSTM unit from a technical point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-all-that-to-make-money"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Using all that to make money&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial news, especially if it’s major, can change the sentiment among
investors and affect the related asset price with immediate price
corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, what’s been communicated in quarterly earnings calls might
indicate whether the price of share will drop or increase based on the
language used. If the message of the company is not direct and featuring
complex sounding language, it usually indicates that there’s some shady
stuff going on and if this information extracted right, it’s a valuable
trading signal. For similar reasons, scanning announcements and
financial disclosures for trading signals became a common NLP practice
in investment industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, I will talk about the various data sources that
researchers can use and also explain common NLP workflows and deep
learning practices for quantifying textual data for generating trading
signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will end with summary with application architecture in case anyone
would like to implement similar systems for their own use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="nlp"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="Keras"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="spaCy"></category><category term="nltk"></category></entry></feed>