<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Rick Ratzel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rick-ratzel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>New CUDA Toolkit packages for Conda</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/new-cuda-toolkit-packages-for-conda.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomson Comer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/new-cuda-toolkit-packages-for-conda.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will examine the new CUDA package layout for Conda (as included in conda-forge). Show how CUDA components have been broken out. Share how this affects development and package building. Walk through changes in the conda-forge infrastructure made to incorporate these new packages. Examine recipes using …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will examine the new CUDA package layout for Conda (as included in conda-forge). Show how CUDA components have been broken out. Share how this affects development and package building. Walk through changes in the conda-forge infrastructure made to incorporate these new packages. Examine recipes using the new packages and what was needed to update them. Additionally will provide guidance on how to use these new packages in recipes or in library development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>No-Code-Change GPU Acceleration for Your Pandas and NetworkX Workflows</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/no-code-change-gpu-acceleration-for-your-pandas-and-networkx-workflows.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vyas Ramasubramani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/no-code-change-gpu-acceleration-for-your-pandas-and-networkx-workflows.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With datasets growing in both complexity and volume, the demand for more efficient data processing has never been higher. Pandas and NetworkX, the go-to Python libraries for tabular and graph data processing, are very popular for their ease of use and flexibility. However, they often struggle to keep pace …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With datasets growing in both complexity and volume, the demand for more efficient data processing has never been higher. Pandas and NetworkX, the go-to Python libraries for tabular and graph data processing, are very popular for their ease of use and flexibility. However, they often struggle to keep pace with the demands of large-scale data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces new open-source GPU accelerators from the NVIDIA RAPIDS project for Pandas and NetworkX, and will demonstrate how you can enable them for your workflows to experience massive speedups – up to 150x in pandas and 600x in NetworkX – without code changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>