<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hao-jin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Accelerate your NumPy Data Science Workloads and Deep Learning Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/accelerate-your-numpy-data-science-workloads-and-deep-learning-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hao Jin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:pydata-la-2019/accelerate-your-numpy-data-science-workloads-and-deep-learning-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll cover creation of a multilayer perceptron model
using gluon and MXNet’s new NumPy-compatible functions, a port of the
classic NumPy with GPU accelerations and additional features for deep
learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the code snippets shown during the talk are available at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/haojin2/PyData-LA-Demo"&gt;https://github.com/haojin2/PyData-LA-Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diving into deep learning requires understanding bulky new frameworks,
which significantly increases the adoption curve for data scientists in
industry. In this talk, we’ll cover creation of a multilayer perceptron
model using gluon and MXNet’s new NumPy-compatible functions, a port of
the classic NumPy with GPU accelerations and additional features for
deep learning. These open source tools will give you a working
foundation for building out more complicated models for real
applications with faster performance and less hassle.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Accelerate large-scale machine learning with NP on MXNet</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/accelerate-large-scale-machine-learning-with-np-on-mxnet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hao Jin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/accelerate-large-scale-machine-learning-with-np-on-mxnet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we’ll introduce NP on MXNet, a drop-in replacement library of official numpy for accelerating your workloads and opening your models to even more possibilities. The session will introduce the key features of NP on MXNet and give a demo how to build a machine learning model with this new package.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Machine-Learning"></category></entry></feed>