<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stefan-behnel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Get up to speed with Cython 3.0</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/get-up-to-speed-with-cython-30.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/get-up-to-speed-with-cython-30.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processing lots of data, in need of more speed, or struggling to make
use of native code? The Cython compiler for Python solves all of these
problems in a pythonic way, by compiling Python code to optimised C
code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cython [1] has a very long history of faithfully helping users to solve
their Python performance problems and integrating native code into
Python in production critical settings, while stimulating somewhat less
confidence with its 0.x versioning scheme. For the next Cython version,
a stable 3.0 release, we are planning to clean up several historically
grown issues in the language to make the Cython compiler more friendly
for modern Python users to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will show how Cython can be used for compiling and
speeding up Python code, using fast native data structures and
libraries. I will then give an overview of the changes that are on their
way for the 3.0 release and how they will affect the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cython.org"&gt;https://cython.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="C-Languages"></category><category term="Compiler and Interpreters"></category><category term="Cython"></category><category term="Performance"></category><category term="Programming"></category></entry><entry><title>Cython to speed up your Python code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/cython-to-speed-up-your-python-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/cython-to-speed-up-your-python-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt; is not only a very fast and comfortable
way to talk to native code and libraries, it is also a widely used tool
for speeding up Python code. The Cython compiler translates Python code
to C or C++ code, and applies many static optimisations that make Python
code run visibly faster than in the interpreter. But even better, it
supports static type annotations that allow direct use of C/C++ data
types and functions, which the compiler uses to convert and optimise the
code into fast, native C. The tight integration of all three languages,
Python, C and C++, makes it possible to freely mix Python features like
generators and comprehensions with C/C++ features like native data
types, pointer arithmetic or manually tuned memory management in the
same code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk by a core developer introduces the Cython compiler by
interactive code examples, and shows how you can use it to speed up your
real-world Python code. You will learn how you can profile a Python
module and use Cython to compile and optimise it into a fast binary
extension module. All of that, without losing the ability to run it
through common development tools like code checkers or coverage test
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Infrastructure"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="Parallel Programming"></category></entry><entry><title>Cython to speed up your Python code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/cython-to-speed-up-your-python-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/cython-to-speed-up-your-python-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt; is not only a very fast and comfortable
way to talk to native code and libraries, it is also a widely used tool
for speeding up Python code. The Cython compiler translates Python code
to C or C++ code, and applies many static optimisations that make Python
code run visibly faster than in the interpreter. But even better, it
supports static type annotations that allow direct use of C/C++ data
types and functions, which the compiler uses to convert and optimise the
code into fast, native C. The tight integration of all three languages,
Python, C and C++, makes it possible to freely mix Python features like
generators and comprehensions with C/C++ features like native data
types, pointer arithmetic or manually tuned memory management in the
same code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk by a core developer introduces the Cython compiler by
interactive code examples, and shows how you can use it to speed up your
Python code. You will learn how you can profile a Python module and use
Cython to compile and optimise it into a fast binary extension module.
All of that, without losing the ability to run it through common
development tools like static analysers or coverage test tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lift your Speed Limits with Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/fosdem-2018/lift-your-speed-limits-with-cython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-03:fosdem-2018/lift-your-speed-limits-with-cython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast native code for Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cython compiler is the most widely used static compiler for Python. It is used to speed up Python code and to extend the CPython runtime with fast native extension modules that process huge amounts of data all around the world. This talk by one of the core developers gives a quick intro into the compiler, the language, and some of its main applications in the Python big-data ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cython is not just a Python compiler or a native code wrapping tool, but also a programming language in its own right that mixes the Python language with C and C++ data types. The fact that you can simply drop Python code into it and compile it gives a very low entry level into performance optimisation by statically compiling your critical code and then tuning it into fast C to make it run faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will guide you through some examples where the compilation of regular Python code leads to faster execution, and present ways how to make the code run much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="cython"></category></entry><entry><title>Cython to the Rescue</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2018/cython-to-the-rescue.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-03:pycon-cz-2018/cython-to-the-rescue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You just found that C library which solves that huge problem you have. It solves it completely, it's so fast, it's old, rock solid and well tested – and difficult to use, because it has that real-world, well aged C-API. Maybe even C++. So, you want to use it from Python, but there's no wrapper yet? Or worse, the existing wrapper is auto-generated and feels clumsy, slow and just as ugly to work with as C?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give Cython a try! It's the fastest way to make Python talk (to) native code, and a pleasure to work with as a general programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Intro to Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2017/intro-to-cython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-31:euroscipy-2017/intro-to-cython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You've probably heard of Cython as a tool for fast data processing. Well, it's more than that. Over the years, the Cython compiler has become a major pillar in the Python ecosystem, helping Python users all over the world to crunch their data, write fast and portable native code, and integrate native libraries into their Python workflow. Several excellent projects from the scientific Python world chose Cython to allow &amp;quot;normal people&amp;quot; to write and maintain efficient code for complex scientific algorithms, whenever Python itself comes to its limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I will present the Cython compiler and quickly show how to speed up code with it, how to talk to native code, and a couple of more things that you might want to try out with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Cython"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting Native with Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2016/getting-native-with-cython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-30:pycon-de-2016/getting-native-with-cython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cython is not only an excellent and widely used tool to speed up computational Python code, it’s also a very comfortable way to talk to native code and libraries. The Cython compiler translates Python code to C or C++ code, and supports static type annotations to allow direct use of C/C++ data types and functions. The tight integration of all three languages makes it possible to freely mix Python features like generators and comprehensions with C/C++ features like native data types, pointer arithmetic or manually tuned memory management in the same code.
This talk by a core developer introduces the Cython compiler by interactive code examples and presents recent enhancements in the language that continue to make Cython the best choice for the development of fast and portable Python extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Get Native with Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2015/get-native-with-cython-euroscipy-2015-stefan-behnel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-05:euroscipy-2015/get-native-with-cython-euroscipy-2015-stefan-behnel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cython is not only an excellent and widely used tool to speed up computational Python code, it’s also a very comfortable way to talk to native code and libraries. This tutorial by a Cython core developer introduces the Cython programming language and its compiler and leads the participants all the way from their first Python extension to an efficient integration with native C/C++ code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Get native with Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/get-native-with-cython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-05:europython-2015/get-native-with-cython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stefan Behnel - Get native with Cython
[EuroPython 2015]
[21 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Cython][1] is not only an excellent and widely used tool to speed up computational Python code, it's also a very comfortable way to talk to native code and libraries. The Cython compiler translates Python code to C or C++ code, and supports static type annotations to allow direct use of C/C++ data types and functions. The tight integration of all three languages makes it possible to freely mix Python features like generators and comprehensions with C/C++ features like native data types, pointer arithmetic or manually tuned memory management in the same code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk by a core developer introduces the Cython compiler by
interactive code examples and presents recent enhancements in the
language that continue to make Cython the best choice for the
development of fast and portable Python extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Examples used in presentation as &lt;strong&gt;[IPython/Jupyter][3]&lt;/strong&gt;
or &lt;strong&gt;[HTML][2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org/"&gt;http://cython.org/&lt;/a&gt;
[2]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consulting.behnel.de/ep/2015/ep15-cython.ipynb"&gt;http://consulting.behnel.de/ep/2015/ep15-cython.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;
[3]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consulting.behnel.de/ep/2015/ep15-cython.html"&gt;http://consulting.behnel.de/ep/2015/ep15-cython.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Fast Async Code with Cython and AsyncIO</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/fast-async-code-with-cython-and-asyncio.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-28:europython-2016/fast-async-code-with-cython-and-asyncio.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stefan Behnel - Fast Async Code with Cython and AsyncIO
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/fast-async-code-with-cython-and-asyncio"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/fast-async-code-with-cython-and-asyncio&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use the new async/await language feature to write
asynchronous code in Python and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org/"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt;. See how to benefit from
the excellent low-level features that Cython provides to speed up or
parallelise your code, interface natively with external C/C++ code,
and achieve better responsiveness and lower latency also in mostly I/O
bound applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has recently seen a fresh development boost around asynchronous
applications, triggered by the addition of the asyncio library and the
new async/await language features in Python 3.5, but coming from a
world of well established tools like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twistedmatrix.com/"&gt;Twisted&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.tornadoweb.org/"&gt;Tornado&lt;/a&gt;.
The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org/"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt; compiler, which compiles Python code to C, has
accompanied and influenced this development. It provides full language
support for async/await under all Python versions starting from 2.6,
as well as native interoperability with existing Python code and the
new Python coroutines in Python 3.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benchmarks show that, while fully compatible, Cython compiled
coroutines perform about 2-3x better than the same code executed in
Python, but they additionally allow to interface natively with
external C/C++ code, release the GIL, do parallel computation, and
much more. All of this extends the applicable zone for asynchronous
applications dramatically and can lead to better responsiveness and
lower latency also for mostly I/O bound applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This joined talk by an async I/O expert and one of the Cython core
developers explains how to write code with async/await in Python and
Cython, and shows how to benefit from the excellent low-level features
that Cython provides on top of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Cython Compiler for Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/the-cython-compiler-for-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/the-cython-compiler-for-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cython compiler is the most widely used static compiler for Python.
It is used to speed up Python code and to extend CPython with fast
native extension modules that process huge amounts of data all around
the world. This talk by one of the core developers gives an intro to
using the compiler and an overview of its major features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cython compiler is the most widely used static compiler for Python.
The code it generates is used in countless critical applications that
process huge amounts of data world wide. Cython has two major use cases:
to compile Python code into fast native extension modules, and to
connect native code to the CPython runtime. The main goal of the Cython
project is to make it easy for users to manually optimise their Python
code to make it run at C speed. This talk by one of the core developers
will give an intro to using the compiler and an overview of its major
features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline will be more or less as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cython: intro to the project and the compiler (4 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compiling Python code&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to do it and what you get (3 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a tiny bit of distutils (2 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static typing and Cython extensions to the Python language&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static typing in Cython language syntax (3 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static typing in pure Python syntax (2 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why Cython's type system is cool and what users need to know about
it (8 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cython for optimising Python code (5 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quick intro: talking to native C/C++ code in Cython&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using external C APIs (4 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using external C++ APIs (3 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to build and link in distutils (2 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes on ways to wrap large C-APIs (1 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quick overview: special features for high-performance code&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NumPy integration and memory views, fused types, parallel loops in
all brevity (3 min.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>lxml - schnelles XML mit Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2011/lxml-schnelles-xml-mit-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-07:pycon-de-2011/lxml-schnelles-xml-mit-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Überblick über die XML-Bibliothek lxml, das flinke Schweizer
Taschenmesser zur XML-Verarbeitung.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Cython - das Beste aus Python und C</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2011/cython-das-beste-aus-python-und-c.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-06:pycon-de-2011/cython-das-beste-aus-python-und-c.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Überblick über die Programmiersprache Cython, die die Leichtigkeit von
Python mit der Performance von C kombiniert.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Schneller ohne C++</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/schneller-ohne-c.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-11-01:pycon-de-2012/schneller-ohne-c.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Sichtbarkeit von C++ in der Software-Entwicklung ist auch in ihrem
33. Jahr noch enorm. In vielen Bereichen, z.B. im Ingenieursumfeld und
im Embedded-Bereich wird schon aus Tradition mit C und C++ entwickelt,
oft ohne den Blick auf Alternativen. Eingespielte Entwicklerteams und
große, über lange Zeit gewachsene Code-Basen lassen einen Umstieg
unmöglich erscheinen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In diesem Vortrag werde ich die Frage stellen, warum C und C++ so große
Verbreitung besitzen, trotz der hohen Anforderungen an
Entwicklererfahrung und der aufwändigen und fehleranfälligen Entwicklung
mit diesen Sprachen. Dabei zeigt sich Python als ganz natürliche
Ergänzungssprache, die sich leicht mit bestehenden Code integriert und
in vielen Bereichen die Entwicklung dank des Paretoprinzips merklich
beschleunigt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python erlaubt sowohl eine schnelle prototypische Umsetzung neuer
Anforderungen als auch die Integration anspruchsvoller Features durch
die breite Funktionalität in der Standardbibliothek und den nahezu
allumfassenden Fundus an Bibliotheken. Das Spektrum geht dabei von
einfachen Skripten über Test-Unterstützung und Web-Frontends bis hin zu
Finanzanwendungen, Bildverarbeitung und zur performancekritischen
Analyse gigantischer Datenmengen aus Tiefseesensoren und
Radioteleskopen.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="c++"></category><category term="entwicklungskosten"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="sprachintegration"></category></entry><entry><title>Schnelle Schleifen mit Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/schnelle-schleifen-mit-cython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-31:pycon-de-2012/schnelle-schleifen-mit-cython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keine PyCon(-DE) ohne Cython, die de-facto Standarderweiterungssprache
für Python. Diesmal geht es um ein paar neuere Spracherweiterungen zur
Python- Syntax, die den Cython-Compiler besonders attraktiv für
High-Performance- Computing machen: Parallele Schleifen mit OpenMP,
effizientes Slicing mit Memory-Views und generische Funktionen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt; ist eine Programmiersprache, die die
Sprache Python um zusätzliche Features ergänzt. Sie macht das Schreiben
von schnellen Erweiterungsmodulen für CPython und das Anbinden von
externen nativen Bibliotheken (C/C++/Fortran/...) so einfach wie Python
selbst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag gibt einen kurzen Einblick in Cython und speziell in die
Optimierung von schleifenbasierten Algorithmen über NumPy Arrays, mit
denen große Datenmengen effizient verarbeitet werden können. Dazu werden
Memory- Views verwendet, die mit Version 0.16 in Cython Einzug gehalten
haben. Hinzu gesellen sich parallele Schleifen, sowie generische
Funktionen, die es dem Compiler erlauben, einmal geschriebenen Code für
verschiedene native Datentypen zu optimieren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eine ausführliche Version dieses Vortrags mit entsprechenden Übungen
wird zusätzlich als Tutorial angeboten.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Cython mit PyPy - das Beste aus drei Welten</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/cython-mit-pypy-das-beste-aus-drei-welten.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-30:pycon-de-2012/cython-mit-pypy-das-beste-aus-drei-welten.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Programmiersprache Cython (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org"&gt;http://cython.org&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;Web- Seite des
Cython-Projekts&amp;quot;) ist das de-facto Standard-Tool um CPython um nativen
Code zu erweitern. Die Python-ähnliche Sprache macht schon seit einigen
Jahren das Schreiben von schnellen Erweiterungsmodulen für CPython und
das Anbinden von externen nativen Bibliotheken (C/C++/Fortran/...) so
einfach wie Python selbst und gleichzeitig so effizient wie C. Davon
profitiert besonders das weite Feld des High-Performance-Computing in
Python (NumPy/SciPy/Sage/...), aber auch zahllose andere Bereiche, die
eine effiziente Verarbeitung großer Datenmengen und die Anbindung von
nativen Bibliotheken an die Programmiersprache Python benötigen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die neueste Version des Cython-Compilers bietet erstmals auch
Unterstützung für PyPy an, eine alternative Python-Implementierung, die
vor allem durch ihren schnellen JIT-Compiler von sich reden macht.
Dadurch kann einmal mit Cython geschriebener und in C übersetzter Code
sowohl in CPython als auch in PyPy verwendet werden. So wird es
beispielsweise möglich, in einer einzigen Code-Basis effiziente
Anbindungen externer Bibliotheken für beide Laufzeitumgebungen zu
entwickeln.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag von einem der Cython Core-Entwickler erklärt, welche
Fallstricke dabei noch auf Benutzerseite zu erwarten sind und gibt
Hilfestellungen beim Schreiben von Cython-Code, der sowohl in CPython
als auch in PyPy funktioniert.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lupa - LuaJIT in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/lupa-luajit-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-17:pycon-de-2013/lupa-luajit-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der Python-Interpreter hat den Ruf, eine ausgereifte und grandios
einfach zu verwendende dynamische Sprache und Laufzeitumgebung zu
bieten, die für jede noch so &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://xkcd.com/413/"&gt;exotische
Anforderung&lt;/a&gt; eine Lösung bereit hält.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ein oft genanntes Manko ist jedoch die begrenzte Performance des
Interpreters für stark algorithmisch geprägte, kritische Teile von
Anwendungen. Insbesondere hochdynamischer und generierter Code kommt
hier schnell an seine Grenzen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auf der anderen Seite existiert mit LuaJIT2 eine sehr schnelle
JIT-kompilierte Laufzeitumgebung der dynamischen Programmiersprache Lua,
die bereits so manche Performance-Rekorde gebrochen hat und sich durch
ihre geringe Größe leicht in andere Programme einbinden lässt. Das große
Manko von Lua ist jedoch das Fehlen von Standard-Bibliotheken, die
extrem begrenzten Sprach-Features und der daraus resultierende hohe
Aufwand bei der Entwicklung größerer Anwendungen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/scoder/lupa"&gt;Lupa&lt;/a&gt; steht eine Verbindung der
beiden Programmiersprachen bereit, die es ermöglicht, aus Python heraus
Lua-Code auszuführen und direkt mit diesem zu kommunizieren und Daten
auszutauschen. So kann der größte Teil einer Anwendung in Python
implementiert werden, und einzelne Aufgaben können von der schnellen
LuaJIT-Umgebung übernommen werden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag stellt das Projekt vor und gibt Einblicke in die
Integration der beiden Programmiersprachen.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lua"></category><category term="luajit"></category><category term="lupa"></category></entry><entry><title>XML generieren mit lxml</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/xml-generieren-mit-lxml.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-16:pycon-de-2013/xml-generieren-mit-lxml.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lxml.de/"&gt;lxml&lt;/a&gt; ist der Platzhirsch unter den XML-Tools für
Python. Über das übliche Parsen hinaus bietet es auch einige schöne
Möglichkeiten, XML-Dokumente effizient zu generieren. Der Vortrag bietet
eine Einführung in die Teile von lxml, die das Erzeugen von XML einfach
und übersichtlich machen.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lxml"></category><category term="xml"></category></entry><entry><title>Cython für schnelleren Python-Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/cython-fur-schnelleren-python-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Behnel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-15:pycon-de-2013/cython-fur-schnelleren-python-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org"&gt;Cython-Compiler&lt;/a&gt; ist mehr als nur ein Weg,
Erweiterungsmodule for CPython zu schreiben. Durch die statische
Übersetzung von reinem Python-Code öffnen sich neue Möglichkeiten, den
Code vielfach zu beschleunigen. Anhand einiger Beispiele wird gezeigt,
wie durch Profiling und gezielte manuelle Optimierung auch reiner
Python-Code von statischer Kompilierung profitieren kann, ohne dabei das
Ökosystem der CPython-Laufzeitumgebung verlassen zu müssen.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="compiler"></category><category term="cython"></category><category term="optimierung"></category></entry></feed>