<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Marco Rosa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Protecting hardcoded credentials in public source code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/protecting-hardcoded-credentials-in-public-source-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protecting hardcoded credentials in public source code - PyCon Italia
2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardcoding credentials in source code is a known bad practice, but it is
still happening every day, even on public platforms like GitHub.
Credential Digger is an open source scanning tool that can help
developers find and remediate to their exposed credentials with a low
false positive rate. Github is now widely adopted in the software
development industry as internal and external code hosting, sharing and
versioning platform. Even if this platform offers advanced code control
features it remains exposed to security weaknesses. In this talk we will
discuss about Github security concepts and introduce an SAP Open Source
tool called Credential Digger used to scan Git platforms (GitHub,
GitLab, BitBucket, etc.) in order to identify hardcoded credentials
(Passwords, API Keys, Secret Keys, Tokens, personal information,
internal domains, etc.). Compared to other secret scanners in the
market, Credential Digger is able to identify passwords with a low false
positive rate. Thanks to a NLP model we trained for this purpose, we can
identify when passwords are fake and when they are real. Together with
Credential Digger, we also work on a real time Github Organization
monitor that analyzes permanently the new commits on the projects of a
team, and alerts the owner when a potential secret is shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Marco Rosa&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Rosa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/protecting-hardcoded-credentials-in-public-source-code.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>open source</category><category>security</category></item></channel></rss>