<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Erick Martins Ratamero</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_erick-martins-ratamero.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Expanding the OME ecosystem for imaging data management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/expanding-the-ome-ecosystem-for-imaging-data-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erick Martins Ratamero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/expanding-the-ome-ecosystem-for-imaging-data-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image analysis is ubiquitous across many areas of biomedical research, resulting in terabytes of image data that must be hosted by both research institutions and data repositories for sharing and reproducibility. Common solutions for data hosting are required to improve interoperability and accessibility of bioimage data, while maintaining the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image analysis is ubiquitous across many areas of biomedical research, resulting in terabytes of image data that must be hosted by both research institutions and data repositories for sharing and reproducibility. Common solutions for data hosting are required to improve interoperability and accessibility of bioimage data, while maintaining the flexibility to address each institution's unique requirements regarding sharing and infrastructure. OMERO is an open-source solution for image data management which can be customized and hosted by individual institutions. OMERO runs a server-based application with web browser and command line options for accessing and viewing image data, based on the widely used OME data model for microscopy data. Multiple OMERO deployments might be used to provide core delivery, facilitate internal research, or serve as a public data repository. The omero-cli-transfer package facilitates data transfer between these OMERO instances and provides new methods for importing datasets. Another open-source package, ezomero, improves the usability of OMERO in a research environment by providing easier access to OMERO's Python interface. Along with existing OMERO plugins built for other analysis and viewing software, this positions OMERO to be a hub for image storage, analysis, and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>