<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Humanities to Tech: How a Religion PhD came to be learning Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/from-humanities-to-tech-how-a-religion-phd-came-to-be-learning-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lauren Bernauer
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/93/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/93/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Despite studying Physics, Chemistry, and the compulsory Maths at High School, I ended up in a Arts degree at University, and from there majored in Studies in Religion and History and continued on to do postgraduate research degrees in Religion. But along the way I became employed in IT and since completing my PhD have been teaching myself Python (among other things). However all these years in the Humanities have resulted in a particular way of approaching learning, one that is not entirely helpful to learning programming. In addition to this, there is also how I can make my new skills relevant to all those years of research and study?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is going to be about my own journey from a STEM high school student, to a humanities researcher, and then to IT, and what I have learnt along the way. It is also about why (I think) teaching children about computers and programming is incredibly important. And also, what I am doing, and planning to do with my new found Python skills in relation to my PhD and potential further research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauren Bernauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/from-humanities-to-tech-how-a-religion-phd-came-to-be-learning-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>