<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_adrien-treuille.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Turn Python Scripts into Beautiful ML Tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/turn-python-scripts-into-beautiful-ml-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adrien Treuille</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-03:pydata-la-2019/turn-python-scripts-into-beautiful-ml-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will discuss the use of internal machine learning tooling
in real self-driving car projects. We'll download a human-annotated
image dataset from the Udacity Self-Driving Car Project and discuss how
stakeholders would approach this data in a real company. Finally we will
live-code an app using Streamlit to semantically search and visualize
the dataset and run models against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've all seen poor tooling slow down data science and machine learning
projects. In fact, most projects develop their own unique ecosystem of
bug- ridden and unmaintainable internal tools to analyze data, often
through a patchwork of Jupyter Notebooks and Flask apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this workshop, we'll discover a new workflow to write ML tools as
Python scripts using Streamlit, the first app framework for ML
engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part one will be a whirlwind tour of Streamlit, creating apps, UIs, and
data caches. Then we'll download a human-annotated image dataset from
the Udacity Self-Driving Car Project and explore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part two will be about product management. We'll discuss how
stakeholders would approach this data in a real self-driving car
project. How would a machine learning engineer or product manager want
to understand this data? We'll then live-code a Streamlit app to
facilitate their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part three will get nerdier! We'll integrate an object detection model
(YOLO v3) into our app to explore the potential tooling benefits from
interactive inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the workshop you will have (1) a beautiful demo to show
off to friends, and (2) a new weapon to tackle tooling problems in your
own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the GitHub: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/streamlit/demo-self-driving"&gt;https://github.com/streamlit/demo-self-driving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>