<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Accelerating AI development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2017/accelerating-ai-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.pydata.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData is an educational program of NumFOCUS, a 501(c)3 non-profit organization in the United States. PyData provides a forum for the international community of users and developers of data analysis tools to share ideas and learn from each other. The global PyData network promotes discussion of best practices, new approaches, and emerging technologies for data management, processing, analytics, and visualization. PyData communities approach data science using many languages, including (but not limited to) Python, Julia, and R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData conferences aim to be accessible and community-driven, with novice to advanced level presentations. PyData tutorials and talks bring attendees the latest project features along with cutting-edge use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joseph Sirosh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-06:pydata-seattle-2017/accelerating-ai-development.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Keynote- Clouded Intelligence</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/keynote-clouded-intelligence.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Seattle 2015
Several exciting trends are driving the birth of the intelligent cloud. The vast majority of world’s data is now connected data resident in the cloud. The majority of world’s new software is now connected software, also resident in or using the cloud. New cloud based Machine Learning as a Service platforms help transform data into intelligence and build cloud-hosted intelligent APIs for connected software applications. Face analysis, computer vision, text analysis, speech recognition, and more traditional analytics such as churn prediction, recommendations, anomaly detection, forecasting, and clustering are all available now as cloud APIs, and far more are being created at a rapid pace. Cloud hosted marketplaces for crowdsourcing intelligent APIs have been launched. In this talk I will review what these trends mean for the future of data science and show examples of revolutionary applications that you can build using cloud platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joseph Sirosh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-25:pydata-seattle-2015/keynote-clouded-intelligence.html</guid></item></channel></rss>