<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lydia Gibson</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lydia-gibson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How the R for Data Science (R4DS) Online Learning Community Made Me a Better Student</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/how-the-r-for-data-science-r4ds-online-learning-community-made-me-a-better-student.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lydia Gibson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/how-the-r-for-data-science-r4ds-online-learning-community-made-me-a-better-student.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through my participation in R4DS Online Learning Community, I have advanced my R and data science skills, making me a better student than I otherwise would have been through just my studies. As a non-traditional MS Statistics student with an undergraduate background in economics, I had absolutely no experience …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through my participation in R4DS Online Learning Community, I have advanced my R and data science skills, making me a better student than I otherwise would have been through just my studies. As a non-traditional MS Statistics student with an undergraduate background in economics, I had absolutely no experience with the R programming language prior to pursuing my Master's degree. In July 2021, with hopes of getting a headstart on learning R before beginning my degree program, I joined the R4DS Slack Workspace. Along with helping to improve my programming skills, R4DS has connected me with scholarships, mentorship, and other opportunities, and I think that it would be beneficial for other students to know about this great resource.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>