<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fully Automated Behavioral Experiments on Cultural Transmission through Crowdsourcing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/fully-automated-behavioral-experiments-on-cultural-transmission-through-crowdsourcing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The logistics of in-laboratory experiments on cultural evolution, social learning, cooperation, and collective decision-making drive experiment designs towards simple population structures, small groups, and limited interaction between participants. Here we describe Dallinger, a software-based tool that automates large-scale experiments on cultural transmission through crowdsourcing. The tool handles the full experimental pipeline from participant recruitment through data management, enabling experiments that are efficient, reproducible, and unprecedented in their complexity and scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlos de la Guardia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/fully-automated-behavioral-experiments-on-cultural-transmission-through-crowdsourcing.html</guid></item><item><title>nbgrader - A Tool for Creating and Grading Assignments in the Jupyter Notebook</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/nbgrader-a-tool-for-creating-and-grading-assignments-in-the-jupyter-notebook.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As usage of the Jupyter notebook in scientific computing becomes increasingly ubiquitous, so too does its presence in classrooms. In this talk, I will describe &lt;em&gt;nbgrader&lt;/em&gt;, a tool developed by and for instructors to create and grade rich, interactive assignments in the notebook. On its own, nbgrader provides functionality for creating assignments and then for both automatic and manual grading of submissions. When combined with JupyterHub, it supports the full grading pipeline: creating assignments, releasing them to students, collecting submissions, grading, and generating personalized feedback. To demonstrate the use of nbgrader, I will walk the audience through the basics of the tool, and then outline two example workflows: one using standalone nbgrader, and one using nbgrader with JupyterHub. In doing so, I will illustrate to instructors how they can create their own assignments in the notebook using nbgrader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Hamrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:scipy-2017/nbgrader-a-tool-for-creating-and-grading-assignments-in-the-jupyter-notebook.html</guid><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>nbgrader</category></item><item><title>Teaching with IPython:Jupyter Notebooks and JupyterHub</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/teaching-with-ipythonjupyter-notebooks-and-jupyterhub.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Hamrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/teaching-with-ipythonjupyter-notebooks-and-jupyterhub.html</guid></item><item><title>Reproducible, One Button Workflows with the Jupyter Notebook &amp; Scons</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/reproducible-one-button-workflows-with-the-jupyter-notebook-scons-scipy-2016-jessica-hamrick.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to develop analysis code in the Jupyter notebook, while managing complex dependencies between analyses? In this talk, I will introduce nbflow, which is a project that integrates a Python-based build system (SCons) with the Jupyter notebook, enabling researchers to easily build sophisticated,
complex analysis pipelines entirely within notebooks while still maintaining a &amp;quot;one-button workflow&amp;quot; in which all analyses can be executed, in the correct order, from a single command. I will show how nbflow can be applied to existing analyses and how it can be used to construct an analysis pipeline stretching the entire way from data cleaning, to computing statistics, to generating figures,
and even to automatically generating LaTeX commands that can be used in publications to format results without the risk of copy-and-paste error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Hamrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/reproducible-one-button-workflows-with-the-jupyter-notebook-scons-scipy-2016-jessica-hamrick.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>workflow</category><category>nbflow</category></item><item><title>Games for Science: Creating interactive psychology experiments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/games-for-science-creating-interactive-psycholog.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to play video games while also contributing to
science? In psychology experiments developed by myself and Peter
Battaglia, participants are immersed in an interactive 3D world which is
experimentally well-controlled, yet also extremely fun. This talk will
explain how we created these &amp;quot;game-like&amp;quot; experiments in Python using the
Panda3D video game engine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Hamrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-13:pycon-us-2014/games-for-science-creating-interactive-psycholog.html</guid></item></channel></rss>