<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Denise Williams</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>When Your SME Ghosts You: Using GenAI to Build a Database Documentation Agent</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/when-your-sme-ghosts-you-using-genai-to-build-a-database-documentation-agent.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been handed a mystery database and told, “You’ll figure it
out”... with no documentation, no SME, and no time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, I’ll share how I turned a frustrating (and very
relatable) real-world problem into a capstone project for Kaggle's Gen
AI 5 Day Intensive Course with Google: building a GenAI-powered Database
Documentation Agent using Python, SQLite, and the Gemini API — aka what
I like to call my SME Ghost Protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll walk through how I used GenAI to automatically generate natural
language summaries, answer ad-hoc schema questions, and create entity
relationship diagrams — even when human help wasn't available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll dive into the challenges of working with GenAI as a &amp;quot;coding
partner,&amp;quot; designing prompts like communication plans, and lessons
learned the hard way about iteration, hallucination, and debugging when
you're flying solo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect live demos, practical takeaways, a little workplace sarcasm, and
ideas for how you can launch your own SME Ghost Protocol — because
sometimes, GenAI is the only teammate who shows up.👻&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Denise Williams</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-27:/pyohio-2025/when-your-sme-ghosts-you-using-genai-to-build-a-database-documentation-agent.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2025</category></item></channel></rss>