<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Kari Jordan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Carpenter's Approach to Teaching Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/florida-pycon-2017/a-carpenters-approach-to-teaching-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using evidence from Data and Software Carpentry’s training impact
surveys, this presentation explores training as a way to onboard
individuals to use Python. Attendees will walk away with a perspective
on training approaches and a feeling of empowerment to build a diverse
Python community through training. The only prerequisite knowledge you
need is your own desire to achieve equity in the Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kari Jordan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-07:/florida-pycon-2017/a-carpenters-approach-to-teaching-python.html</guid><category>Florida PyCon 2017</category></item><item><title>Black Hair and Data Science Have More in Common Than You Think</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/black-hair-and-data-science-have-more-in-common-than-you-think.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science is often difficult to define because of its many intersections, including statistics, programming, analytics, and other domain knowledge. Would you believe it if I told you Black hair and data science have much in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for those considering learning about, studying, or pursuing data science. In it, Dr. Kari L. Jordan draws parallels between approaches to caring for Black hair and approaches to learning data science. We start with the roots and end by picking the right tools and products to maintain our coiffure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kari Jordan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/black-hair-and-data-science-have-more-in-common-than-you-think.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Experience Building Local Communities of Open Source Practices Users through The Carpentries' Membership Program</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/experience-building-local-communities-of-open-source-practices-users-through-the-carpentries-membership-program.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Carpentries, an open source project that develops training and instructing resources for researchers, has developed a membership program that is key to our sustainability and mission. This program creates communities of open source practices at organisations around the world and supports the open materials and forums of The Carpentries. We have learned from our various successes and challenges, continue to assess the effectiveness of this program, and are preparing for the challenges of adapting this program to be effective in our rapidly growing and diversifying community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kari Jordan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/scipy-2019/experience-building-local-communities-of-open-source-practices-users-through-the-carpentries-membership-program.html</guid><category>SciPy 2019</category></item></channel></rss>