<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daniel-chen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Introduction to Data Processing in Python with Pandas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/introduction-to-data-processing-in-python-with-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/introduction-to-data-processing-in-python-with-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a tutorial for beginners on using the Pandas library in Python for data manipulation. We will go from the basics of how to load and look at a dataset in pandas (python) for the first time, and begin the process of preparing data for analysis. The topics covered are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load and look at slices and views of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groupby aggregates to summarize data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidy and reshape data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write functions and apply them to data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plotting data using Seaborn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encode dummy variables to prepare for analysis and model fit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitting a model using sklearn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this tutorial, you should have a solid foundation on working with datasets in Python. The last topic of encoding dummy variables segues into using other libraries, such as scikit-learn and statsmodels to fit models on your data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Pandas is for Everyone</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/pandas-is-for-everyone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-01:pycon-us-2019/pandas-is-for-everyone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Science and Machine learning have been synonymous with languages
like Python. Libraries like Numpy and Pandas have become the de facto
standard when working with data. The DataFrame object provided by Pandas
gives us the ability to work with heterogeneous unstructured data that
is commonly used in &amp;quot;real world&amp;quot; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New learners are often drawn to Python and Pandas because of all the
different and exciting types of models and insights the language can do
and provide, but are awestruck when faced with the initial learning
curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial aims to guide the learner from using spreadsheets to using
the Pandas DataFrame. Not only does moving to a programming language
allow the user to have a more reproducible workflow, but as datasets get
larger, some cannot even be opened in a spreadsheet program. The goal is
to have an absolute beginner proficient enough with Pandas that they can
start working with data in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover how to load and view our data and introduce what Dr.
Hadley Wickham has coined &amp;quot;tidy data&amp;quot;. Tidy data is an important concept
because the process of tidying data will fix a host of data problems
that are needed to perform analytics. We then cover functions and
applying methods to our data with a focus on data cleaning, and how we
can use the concept of split-apply-combine (groupby) to summarize or
reduce our data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we cover the role of Pandas in analysis packages such as scikit
learn. The tutorial will end with a fitted model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to get people familiar with Python and Pandas so they can
learn and explore many other parts of the Python ecosystem (e.g., scikit
learn, dask, seaborn, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Pandas for Data Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/pandas-for-data-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:scipy-2017/pandas-for-data-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are audio issues with this video that cannot be fixed. We recommend listening to the tutorial without headphones to minimize the buzzing sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorial information may be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/"&gt;https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Science and Machine learning have been synonymous with languages like Python. Libraries like numpy and Pandas have become the de facto standard when working with data.
The DataFrame object provided by Pandas gives us the ability to work with heterogeneous unstructured data that is commonly used in &amp;quot;real world&amp;quot; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New learners are often drawn to Python and Pandas because of all the different and exciting types of models and insights the language can do and provide, but are awestruck when faced with the initial learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial aims to guide the learner from using spreadsheets to using the Pandas DataFrame.
Not only does moving to a programming language allow the user to have a more reproducible workflow, but as datasets get larger, some cannot even be opened in a spreadsheet program. The goal is to have an absolute beginner proficient enough with Pandas that they can start working with data in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover how to load and view our data. Then, some basic methods to do quick visualizations of our data for exploratory data analysis. We will then work on combining and working multiple datasets (concatenating and merging), and introduce what Dr. Hadley Wickham has coined &amp;quot;tidy data&amp;quot;. Tidy data is an important concept because the process of tidying data will fix a host of data problems that are needed to perform analysis. We then cover functions and applying methods to our data with a focus on data cleaning, and how we can use the concept of split-apply-combine (groupby) to summarize or reduce our data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we cover the basics of string manipulation and how to use it to clean data before briefly covering the role of Pandas in analysis packages such as scikit learn. The tutorial will with a fitted model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to get people familiar with Python and Pandas so they can learn and explore many other parts of the Python ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pandas"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2017-07-12</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-12.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Meurer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:scipy-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-12.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks 2017-07-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="12%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="23%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="65%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Start&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Speakers&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;1:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Aaron Meurer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctr&lt;/strong&gt;
- We built a better tool to push from TravisCI to
GitHub Pages&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;6:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Daniel Chen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SciPy 2017 Notes&lt;/strong&gt;
- A github repo (scipy_2017_notes) of links and
tutorial information from this conference.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;7:15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Allen Downey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical Modeling in Python&lt;/strong&gt;
- tinyurl,.com/modsimpy; writing a book and am looking
for simple models to teach students.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;8:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Oliver Zeigermann&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do Convolutional Neural Networks &amp;quot;See&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;
- Techniques to visualize feature detection in the
Insight neural network.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;14:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Sebastian Raschka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screenlamp&lt;/strong&gt;
- We made Hypothosis pipeline builder for experimental
biologists, with database filtering steps.  Based on
BioPandas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;20:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Theodore Lindsay
and Floris van
Breugel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FigureFirst&lt;/strong&gt;
- Make it easy to use MatPlotLib and Inkscape to build
beautiful scientific figures.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;26:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;Pamela Wu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SynthPy:  Real Answers for Fake Data&lt;/strong&gt;
-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;31:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Nick Murphy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PlasmaPy&lt;/strong&gt;
- Beginning a community developed Python package for
plasma physics.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;34:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Scott Collis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Py-ART&lt;/strong&gt;
- Python ARM Radar Toolkit, exposing world of radar
meteorology to SciPy stack.  Taking comments on our
roadmap.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;36:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Bill Spotz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Jupyter to make Citations&lt;/strong&gt;
- The journey of using Jupyter notebooks to add real
citations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;42:15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Jose Felipe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test support in Jupyter/Ipython through cell&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;magics&lt;/strong&gt;
- Starting with iPython/Unittests, make unittesting in
cells&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;47:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Scott Cole&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burrito Data Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;
- Specialized Visualization and data collection
profiles in the quest for better burittos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Pandas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/introduction-to-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-14:pydata-carolinas-2016/introduction-to-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial aims to expose future data analysis with the Python
Pandas library. The tutorial is meant for absolute beginners to Pandas
and Python as a programming language. We will begin with loading
tabular data and various ways to calculate summary statistics and
visualize data. Next, we will learn various ways to join multiple
datasets, and how we can work with missing values etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the tutorial is to expose users to Pandas for data
analysis and move users into a more reproducible analysis workflow
compared to spreadsheet programs. The tutorial will begin with loading
in tabular data and various ways to view columns and rows of data. The
initial part of the tutorial will show users how to load in data and
quickly create descriptive statistical plots. Next, we will cover more
of pandas internal data structures. This will cover some fundamental
knowledge about Python as a programming language, mainly object
methods. Finally, before showing users basic data cleaning examples,
we will cover data visualizations using matplotlib, seaborn, and
pandas itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next section of the tutorial will show learners how to assemble
and merge multiple datasets, and how to work with missing values.
Lastly, before we get to fitting models, I will go over how to recode
variables for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose is to show users how to use Pandas, and not how to
fit machine learning models. However, I show a simple model at the end
so users see how data cleaning and analysis all fit together in a
workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python useRs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/python-users.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/python-users.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the most recent IEEE language rankings, R is now the 5th most popular language. It is the only domain specific language in the top 5, behind the general-purpose languages C, Java, Python, and C++, respectively. It is common for data science teams to work in multiple languages and for the Pythonista, a working knowledge in R is useful for collaboration, analysis, and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be better to extend a simple analysis in R than passing around CSV files. Even worse, there might be a new analysis package that only exists in R, or certain bits infrastructure are already implemented in R and it needs to incorporate a bit of Python analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>