<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nicholas-kridler.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Sirbarksalot Bark Detection in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2017/sirbarksalot-bark-detection-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicholas Kridler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-06:pydata-seattle-2017/sirbarksalot-bark-detection-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dachshunds are notorious barkers and my dogs are no exception. Using a spare webcam, the Facebook Messenger API, and some python code, I built a simple app for sending notifications when my dogs are barking. In this talk, I'll cover the methodology and some surprising things I learned about my dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have two dachshunds, Cody and Caylee. Cody in particular loves to bark and we do a lot to mitigate his barking when we are home. However, when we are at work, we have no idea how much barking he is inflicting on our neighbors. Out of curiosity for his daytime barking habits, I built an app that listens for barks and then sends a notification on Facebook. In this talk, I'll go over the methodology for bark detection from sample collection to creating a bark classifier. Then I will go over the basic structure of the app and the Facebook API component. Lastly, I'll discuss some interesting things I've learned about my dogs,&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Year of Pyxley: My First Open Source Adventure</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/a-year-of-pyxley-my-first-open-source-adventure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicholas Kridler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-28:pydata-chicago-2016/a-year-of-pyxley-my-first-open-source-adventure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I created my first Flask-powered web application utilizing React.js and D3. I refactored it into reusable components and released it as Pyxley. In this talk, I’ll introduce the basics of Pyxley and discuss what has and hasn’t worked. More importantly, I’ll talk about what it’s like to maintain an open-source project for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="adventure"></category><category term="Open Source"></category></entry></feed>