<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_shioulin-sam.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Learning with Limited Labeled Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/learning-with-limited-labeled-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shioulin Sam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/learning-with-limited-labeled-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supervised machine learning requires large labeled datasets - a prohibitive
limitation in many real world applications. What if machines could learn
with fewer labeled examples? This talk explores and demonstrates an
algorithmic solution that relies on collaboration between humans and
machines to label smartly, and shows product possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to teach machines with examples is a powerful capability, but it
hinges on the availability of vast amounts of data. The data not only needs
to exist, but has to be in a form that allows relationships between input
features and output to be uncovered. Creating labels for each input feature
fulfills this requirement, but is an expensive undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classical approaches to this problem rely on human and machine
collaboration. In these approaches, engineered heuristics are used to
smartly select the “best” instances of data to label, in order to reduce
cost. A human steps in to provide the label. The model then learns from this
smaller labeled dataset. Recent advancements have made these approaches
amenable to deep learning, enabling models to be built with limited labeled
data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we explore algorithmic approaches that drive this capability,
and provide practical guidance for translating this capability into
production. We provide intuition for how and why these algorithms work by
demoing and describing how we built a working prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>