<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_piotr-dyba.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2017-07-13</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vitalii Vokhmin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:europython-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks
EuroPython 2017 - 2017-07-13 - Anfiteatro 2&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>CyberSecurity.bootcamp()</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/cybersecuritybootcamp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Piotr Dyba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-11:europython-2017/cybersecuritybootcamp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyber-security is a critical part of all distributed applications. By
understanding and implementing proper security measures, you guard
your own resources against malicious attackers as well as provide a
secure environment for all relevant parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the talk is to show starting points on how to improve
security in python applications by destroying a few servers during
the presentation. It will provide the most important information and
will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threat modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common attack vectors on Python applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why python is not vulnerable to some kinds of attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is eval so dangerous?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving server deployment and security management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated security testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pentesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is a CISO and why is cyber-security awareness in the company so important nowadays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic knowledge of networking, python and REST is advised.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>With modern_peripherals: Python and Flask</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2015/with-modern_peripherals-python-and-flask.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Piotr Dyba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-16:pycon-pl-2015/with-modern_peripherals-python-and-flask.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Auto-scrolling sites, glance-following ads, and gesture friendly web pages are coming! Over the last few years three products emerged that enable interaction with computer in a new way: Myo Armband, Leap Motion Controller and EyeTribe. The Myo Armband is a device that uses the electrical activity in your muscles to wirelessly control your computer, phone, and tablet, which is especially useful when your hands are “tied” or dirty. This device will be used to navigate through the presentation. The Leap Motion Controller tracks both hands in front of the screen. From a web developer’s perspective, both devices allows us to use gestures, previously restricted to touch devices, on desktops. EyeTribe is an affordable eye-tracking device. The talk will briefly cover setting up SDKs and python wrappers, and then focus on possible uses in daily life, business and, of course, web app development. Code examples will be included. In addition, the trade-offs between processing this new type of input data in the client versus processing input on the server will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>with modern_peripherals: Python and Flask</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/with-modern_peripherals-python-and-flask.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Piotr Dyba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-02:europython-2015/with-modern_peripherals-python-and-flask.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Piotr Dyba - with modern_peripherals: Python and Flask
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with modern_peripherals:     Python and Flask&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auto-scrolling sites, glance-following ads, and gesture friendly web
pages are coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years three products  emerged that enable
interaction with computer  in a new way: Myo Armband, Leap Motion
Controller and EyeTribe. The Myo Armband is a device that uses the
electrical activity in your muscles to wirelessly control your
computer, phone, and tablet, which is especially useful when your
hands are &amp;quot;tied&amp;quot; or dirty.  This device will be used to navigate
through the presentation. The Leap Motion Controller tracks both hands
in front of the screen.  From a web developer’s perspective, both
devices allows us to use gestures, previously  restricted to touch
devices, on desktops. EyeTribe is an affordable eye-tracking device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will briefly cover setting up SDKs and python wrappers, and
then focus on possible uses in daily life, business and, of course,
web app development. Code examples will be included. In addition, the
trade-offs between processing this new type of input data in the
client versus processing input on the server will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>