<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dave-stokes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>MySQL 8—A New Beginning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2017/mysql-8-a-new-beginning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Stokes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-19:pytexas-2017/mysql-8-a-new-beginning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MySQL 5.7 is great but MySQL 8 is a major redesign. It will have a true data dictionary which means you can have millions of tables within a schema. Windowing Functions, CTEs, roles, multi plane character support, and more important changes. Plus learn what happened to MySQL 6 and MySQL 7.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>MySQL 5.6</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/mysql-5-6.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Stokes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-03:djangocon-us-2013/mysql-5-6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MySQL 5.6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday 11:30 a.m.--12:15 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Novice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL is the ubiquitous web database but many developers are unaware of
new features found in the later releases. This session will cover
improvements in the optimizer, Global Transactions IDs, dynamic DDL, and
more. Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL is the ubiquitous web database but many developers are unaware of
new features found in the later releases. This session will cover the
advancements MySQL has made in version 5.6 and show how these new
features can make your life easier. See how Global Transaction IDs and
simple Python scripts (MySQL Utilities) can be used to replicate slave
servers from a master and provide automatic fail over if the master
dies. Discover how the improved optimizer provides better performance,
handles sub-queries, and provides more tuning possibilities. New dynamic
table definitions make schema changes less onerous. Discover how a NoSQL
interface via memcached provides key/value pair access to data and SQL
access. The new performance schema provides more insights into system
tuning to eek out the last bit of performance. All that and more in less
than an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>