<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mongi Ben Gaid</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mongi-ben-gaid.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Chalk’it: an open-source framework for rapid web applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/chalkit-an-open-source-framework-for-rapid-web-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mongi Ben Gaid</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/chalkit-an-open-source-framework-for-rapid-web-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chalk'it is an open-source framework that transforms Python scripts into distributable web app dashboards. It utilizes drag-and-drop widgets to establish an interface linked to a dataflow connecting Python code and various data sources. Chalk'it supports multiple Python graphics libraries, including Plotly, Matplotlib and Folium for interactive mapping and visualization …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chalk'it is an open-source framework that transforms Python scripts into distributable web app dashboards. It utilizes drag-and-drop widgets to establish an interface linked to a dataflow connecting Python code and various data sources. Chalk'it supports multiple Python graphics libraries, including Plotly, Matplotlib and Folium for interactive mapping and visualization. The framework operates entirely in web browsers using Pyodide. In our presentation, we will showcase Chalk'it, emphasizing its primary features, software architecture, and key applications, with a special focus on geospatial data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>