<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lilian anonymous</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lilian-anonymous.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Creating the Next Generation of Billionaires-Part 3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/creating-the-next-generation-of-billionaires-part-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lilian anonymous</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/creating-the-next-generation-of-billionaires-part-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating the Next Generation of Billionaires-Part 3
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By lil anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our generation of young people in school (aged 5-18) have noticed the connection between Computer pRogramming, Technology, Bitcoinsm Success and Billionaires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mass young people are clamouring to master the skill of Computer …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating the Next Generation of Billionaires-Part 3
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By lil anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our generation of young people in school (aged 5-18) have noticed the connection between Computer pRogramming, Technology, Bitcoinsm Success and Billionaires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mass young people are clamouring to master the skill of Computer pRogramming. It has been dubbed the ‘4th’ R’ (computer pRogramming) along with Reading, wRiting and aRithmetic. So, governments worldwide have launched initiatives to have it taught in schools from Kindergarten to all the way to high school. And now young people are successfully mastering this skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, not wishing to be left out of these exciting modern developments; the mums’ and dads’ of these young people are also expressing an interest to master this skill. The mums’ and dads’ would like to be a position to help their children in this subject. Hence, I have started a free online simple course on this topic for mums’ and dads’.
This talk will describe a case study whereby Computer Programming (Python) was introduced for the first time to a group of adults, the mums’ and dads’ of school age children. The talk will include descriptions of the various teaching methodologies &amp;amp;amp; the outcomes; the challenges &amp;amp;amp; joys involved; &amp;amp;amp; the similarities and dissimilarities between teaching the parents and their children.  The talk will conclude with helpful suggestions, on how to proceed in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry></feed>