<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Taehyun Lee</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_taehyun-lee.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>DFD(Documentation-First Development) with FastAPI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/dfddocumentation-first-development-with-fastapi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Taehyun Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/dfddocumentation-first-development-with-fastapi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DFD(Documentation-First Development) with FastAPI by Taehyun Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/dfd-documentation-first-development-with-fastapi"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/dfd-documentation-first-development-with-fastapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many software engineers, particularly web developers, recognize the critical importance of documentation for efficient collaboration. Yet, the challenge of maintaining up-to-date documentation remains a pervasive issue, often due …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DFD(Documentation-First Development) with FastAPI by Taehyun Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/dfd-documentation-first-development-with-fastapi"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/dfd-documentation-first-development-with-fastapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many software engineers, particularly web developers, recognize the critical importance of documentation for efficient collaboration. Yet, the challenge of maintaining up-to-date documentation remains a pervasive issue, often due to human errors such as failing to update documentation after changes in the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation introduces the philosophy of Documentation-First Development (DFD), a methodology I advocate for that leverages the code-based OpenAPI documentation generation capabilities of the FastAPI framework. I will discuss methods to embody this philosophy, including the use of a sub-application pattern to segregate API documents and the application of generic types for crafting reusable custom response models. Additionally, I will address the limitations of traditional approaches to API documentation and demonstrate how FastAPI, in conjunction with Pydantic, offers a more effective solution by automatically keeping documentation synchronized with the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation aims to enlighten attendees on the benefits of the FastAPI framework and provide practical insights into creating precise and well-maintained API documentation. It is designed for audiences interested in enhancing their documentation practices and those curious about the advantages of employing FastAPI for web development projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry></feed>