<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Kartikay Khandelwal</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynote: PyTorch Technical Deep Dive</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/keynote-pytorch-technical-deep-dive.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote: PyTorch Technical Deep Dive - Piotr Bialecki, NVIDIA; Peng Wu, Will Constable, Kartikay Khandelwal &amp;amp; Mengtao (Martin) Yuan, Meta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Deep Dive provides an update on PyTorch development since last conference and dives into the key new features coming in PyTorch 2.5 and beyond.  We will explore how advancements across a number of PyTorch features combine to better support the full model development lifecycle across training, fine-tuning, and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piotr Bialecki</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/keynote-pytorch-technical-deep-dive.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category></item><item><title>Welcome to the PyTorch Ecosystem for LLM Fine-tuning Mini Summit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/welcome-to-the-pytorch-ecosystem-for-llm-fine-tuning-mini-summit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As open-source LLMs have become more capable, a substantial ecosystem has developed around the fine-tuning of these models. A thriving community of researchers, developers, practitioners and hobbyists has emerged which focuses on topics ranging from memory efficiency, parameter-efficient fine-tuning and quantization to performance at scale and reproducible evaluations. The goal of this mini-summit is to bring this community together to discuss ideas, share knowledge and build connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda features a keynote from Joe Spisak on the state of the Llama ecosystem followed by invited talks from the founders of Axolotl, Unsloth and torchtune. We conclude the summit with a riveting discussion on what’s next for LLMs, fine-tuning and the PyTorch ecosystem with a fabulous panel of experts - Tim Dettmers (author of bitsandbytes and QLoRA), Hailey Schoelkopf (maintainer of LM Eval Harness at EleutherAI), Aakanksha Chowdhery (Lead author on PaLM and Gemini) and Alexis Conneau (Research Lead at OpenAI)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kartikay Khandelwal</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/welcome-to-the-pytorch-ecosystem-for-llm-fine-tuning-mini-summit.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category></item></channel></rss>