<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why our products and communities need our empathy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2019/why-our-products-and-communities-need-our-empathy.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sasha Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-10:pydata-amsterdam-2019/why-our-products-and-communities-need-our-empathy.html</guid><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>The Secret Society of Happiness</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/the-secret-society-of-happiness.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happiness and our search for it is important but complicated. However,
we can learn much from each other. Being our authentic selves and
allowing ourselves to grow, gains us skills to help others too. In this
talk, we’ll learn about helping ourselves and guiding others towards
happiness for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness and our own search for it have deep impacts on our entire
lives. But important as it is, it’s also incredibly complicated. We each
carry our own baggage, and the things that make us happy are not
constants. However, we can learn so much from each other in a community,
and can have a tremendous impact on each other’s happiness in how we
shape our communities and interactions - though not always in the most
obvious ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the barriers to our happiness are actually created by ourselves,
and those can be the hardest the overcome. But by being our authentic
selves and facing up to our fears, we can gain the confidence to do what
is needed. And growing in this process ourselves, we gain so many skills
in helping others in their journeys as well. Embracing those journeys
and skills in our community will make it a happier and more inclusive
space for all, which fosters growth in ourselves and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently put literally every aspect of my life upside down in my own
search for happiness, and will share from my personal story and stories
of others about the lessons learned, in a way that many of us will
recognise. We’ll also talk about how each of us in a community has
opportunities to bring happiness to others, which in the end will
contribute to our own happiness too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous responses to this talk included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Took me a decade to understand what this speaker is presenting
gracefully and meaningfully in a handful of minutes.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Been waiting for this talk for months and it has not disappointed.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Such a strong, emotional and impactful opening keynote.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“This speaker is like the purest person ever!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Thank you for being inspiring and honest.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Hard truth. Touching chords.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I should have worn waterproof makeup.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1799"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1799&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sasha Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/the-secret-society-of-happiness.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Write the Docs Prague 2018</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-prague-2018/introduction-to-write-the-docs-prague-2018.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mikey Ariel</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-10:write-the-docs-prague-2018/introduction-to-write-the-docs-prague-2018.html</guid></item><item><title>Helping communities &amp; products thrive by fostering empathy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a fundamental part of human interaction. When we communicate
by email or at conferences, or indirectly, when we create products,
events, or do a talk. However, our understanding of other people is full
of error, and worse, bias. This can lead us to make communities and
products that work poorly for people that are different from ourselves,
introduce confusion and misunderstanding, exclude people
unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our communities are an opportunity to learn as well. To embrace
our diversity, and expand our understanding of other people’s worlds. To
gain understanding of other people’s situations, experiences and
emotions, which can be dramatically different to ours. And how we can
use this to create both products and communities which work great not
only for ourselves, but also those that we more easily forget about. As
creators in tech we have such tremendous power to create change, but
merely our best intentions will not be enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how and why we sometimes have such difficulty to
understand others, and how others can have difficulty to understand us.
We’ll talk about why other people’s experiences, emotion and perceptions
can be so different. Both for the world as a whole, but also with the
speaker’s personal experiences. Finally, we’ll cover specific ways for
us to understand others better, and associated pitfalls, to make our
communities and products happy, inviting and supportive places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sasha Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html</guid><category>empathy</category><category>diversity</category><category>community</category></item><item><title>The Code of Conduct is here for you</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/the-code-of-conduct-is-here-for-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many open source communities have now adopted Codes of Conduct. Django adopted one in 2013, the since then Django Software Foundation has had a Code of Conduct committee. The committee deals with CoC violations on e.g. mailing lists, aggregates reports from conferences, can check speaker lists against CoC reports and provide general advice and support. Django events tend to have their own CoC with their own CoC team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone in the wider tech community is fond of Codes of Conduct. However, a lot of this reluctance is rooted in misunderstanding about what this actually entails, and what the committee and teams actually do in both their active and reactive roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why this talk will give a peek behind the scenes of the work of the CoC committee and CoC teams, how incidents are actually handled with various real life examples, and how this leads to a better community for everyone. Including you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sasha Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-28:pycon-uk-2017/the-code-of-conduct-is-here-for-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Everything I always wanted to know about crypto, but never thought I’d understand</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2018/everything-i-always-wanted-to-know-about-crypto-but-never-thought-id-understand.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many years, I had entirely given up on ever understanding the slightest thing about cryptography. The amount required to understand even the most basic part seemed entirely dazzling. However, I’ve since learned it’s not nearly as hard as I thought to understand many of the important concepts.And this is what I want to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this talk, you don’t need to know anything about cryptography, and almost no math knowledge. You’ll gain an understanding of what the different components are and how they interact. And learn to get a grasp of how a system works, without necessarily understanding the details of each individual part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll take you through some of the underlying design principles of modern applications of cryptography. We’ll talk about what we’re trying to accomplish, which parts are involved, and how to prevent and understand common vulnerabilities. This will help you to make better choices when you implement cryptography in your products and will improve your understanding of how crypto is applied to things you already use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sasha Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-03:pycon-cz-2018/everything-i-always-wanted-to-know-about-crypto-but-never-thought-id-understand.html</guid></item></channel></rss>