<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Computing in the Undergraduate Meteorology Curriculum at Millersville Univ</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/scientific-computing-in-the-undergraduate-meteoro.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific computing is an important aspect of the undergraduate
meteorology curriculum at Millersville University. All students take a
course in Fortran, and many take additional courses in Python and
atmospheric numerical modeling. This presentation discusses how
scientific computing is incorporated into the curriculum, and why
Fortran and Python were chosen as the languages to be taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific computing is integrated into the undergraduate meteorology
curriculum at Millersville University. The curriculum guidelines
published by the American Meteorological Society specifically address
scientific computing in undergraduate atmospheric sciences curricula,
stating that students should gain “experience using a high-level
structured programming language (e.g., C, C++, Python, MATLAB, IDL, or
Fortran).” This is addressed at Millersville via the
programming-specific courses are ESCI 282 – &lt;em&gt;Fortran Programming for the
Earth Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, and ESCI 386 – &lt;em&gt;Scientific Programming, Analysis and
Visualization with Python&lt;/em&gt;. There are also additional courses in which
the students are required to use scientific computing as part of their
assignments. Examples of these courses are ESCI 445 – &lt;em&gt;Numerical
Modeling of the Atmosphere and Oceans&lt;/em&gt;, and ESCI 390 – &lt;em&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the university’s computer science department teaches
programming courses in Java, this is not very applicable to our
students’ needs for scientific programming. We therefore teach our own
programming courses in-house. The required programming course taken by
all students is the Fortran course, which teaches them the elements of
programming. This is many students’ first exposure to programming. Most
then follow-on by taking the Python course. In the Python course,
scientific data analysis and visualization are stressed, using the
Scientific Python, Numerical Python, and Matplotlib libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the elective numerical modeling course, students are required to
write programs for finite-difference solutions to various 1-D and 2-D
partial differential equations relevant to modeling the fluid dynamics
of the atmosphere. They may program in any language of their choosing,
but the majority of students choose Python, even if they have no prior
experience with it. This is because of Python’s intuitive syntax and
ease of use. In the elective remote sensing course students are
introduced to and use IDL/ENVI for display and analysis of remote
sensing imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 2012 the current Python course was instead taught as a course
in IDL. The transition was made for several reasons. The primary reason
was the limited market and usage of IDL compared to more pervasive
languages such as MATLAB and Python. Many students would not have access
to IDL once they graduate. Also, Python is gaining traction in usage in
the atmospheric and oceanic sciences, and is not proprietary like IDL
and MATLAB, so students will have access to it no matter where they find
employment or graduate school opportunities. The high cost of
maintaining an institutional IDL license is also an issue that the
university must address annually, and it times of lean budgets it
becomes an attractive target for elimination. The IDL course is still on
the books, but there are no immediate plans for upcoming offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex DeCaria</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/scientific-computing-in-the-undergraduate-meteoro.html</guid><category>education</category><category>meteorology</category></item></channel></rss>