<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>El Efecto Mariposa de Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2019/el-efecto-mariposa-de-python.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-31:pycon-latam-2019/el-efecto-mariposa-de-python.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>¡Escuincla babosa!: Creating a telenovela script in three Python deep learning frameworks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/escuincla-babosa-creating-a-telenovela-script-in-three-python-deep-learning-frameworks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telenovelas are beloved for their over the top drama and intricate plot
twists. In this talk, we’ll review popular telenovelas to synthesize a
typical telenovela arc and use it to train a deep learning model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would a telenovela script look like as imagined by a neural
network? To answer this question, we’ll examine three Python deep
learning frameworks - Keras, PyTorch, and TensorFlow - to determine the
process of translating a telenovela into a neural network and ultimately
determine which one will be best for the task at hand. Be prepared for
amor, pasiòn, and y el misterioso!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/escuincla-babosa-creating-a-telenovela-script-in-three-python-deep-learning-frameworks.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Keynote. Now Is Better Than Never: What the Zen of Python can teach us about Data Ethics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2018/keynote-now-is-better-than-never-what-the-zen-of-python-can-teach-us-about-data-ethics.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-07:pycon-es-2018/keynote-now-is-better-than-never-what-the-zen-of-python-can-teach-us-about-data-ethics.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Interview Lorena Mesa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-colombia-2018/interview-lorena-mesa.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-09:pycon-colombia-2018/interview-lorena-mesa.html</guid></item><item><title>Your model is bias, but so is your data. The case for ethics in data science.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-colombia-2018/your-model-is-bias-but-so-is-your-data-the-case-for-ethics-in-data-science.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-09:pycon-colombia-2018/your-model-is-bias-but-so-is-your-data-the-case-for-ethics-in-data-science.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>¡Escuincla babosa!: Creating a telenovela script with a neural network</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/escuincla-babosa-creating-a-telenovela-script-with-a-neural-network.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telenovelas, Spanish soap operas, are beloved for their over the top
drama (el drama es real) and complicated twists and turns. In this talk,
we'll look at some of the most popular telenovelas in recent years to
devise a common arch for a telenovela. Using this formula, we'll
determine if a recurring neural network is able to successfully produce
a telenovela script. If so, what would a telenovela&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-03:north-bay-python-2018/escuincla-babosa-creating-a-telenovela-script-with-a-neural-network.html</guid></item><item><title>Now is better than Never: What the Zen of Python can teach us about Data Ethics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2018/now-is-better-than-never-what-the-zen-of-python-can-teach-us-about-data-ethics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We Pythonistas welcome newcomers with the wisdom of Tim Peter's &amp;quot;import
this&amp;quot;. The Zen of Python gives us general aphorisms on how to write
Python and how to be a good Pythonista by offering loose guidelines that
promotes discussion. What lessons can it teach us about Data Ethics? As
data practitioners Now is Better than Never to define what our community
will and won't do as it comes to data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-29:pyohio-2018/now-is-better-than-never-what-the-zen-of-python-can-teach-us-about-data-ethics.html</guid></item><item><title>Is that ham in my spam? A novice's inquiry into Naive Bayes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-jamaica-2016/is-that-ham-in-my-spam-a-novices-inquiry-into-naive-bayes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supervised learning, machine learning, classifiers, big data! What in the world are all of these things? As a beginning programmer the questions described as “machine learning” questions can be mystifying at best. #pyconjamaica2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will define the scope of a machine learning problem, identifying an email as ham or spam, from the perspective of a beginner (non master of all things “machine learning&amp;quot;) and show how Python can help us simply learn how to classify a piece of email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin we must ask, what is spam? How do I know it “when I see it”? From previous experience of course! We will provide human labeled examples of spam to our model for it to understand the likelihood of spam or ham. This approach, using examples and data we already know to determine the most likely label for a new example, uses the Naive Bayes classifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model will look at the words in the body of an email, finding the frequency of words in both spam and ham emails and the frequency of spam and ham. Once we know the prior likelihood of spam and what makes something spam, we can try applying a label to a new example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this exercise we will see at a basic level what types of questions machine learning asks, learn to model “learning” with Python, and understand how learning can be measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016"&gt;https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016&lt;/a&gt; the PyCon Jamaica 2016 technology conference for Python software developers was held (November 17 - 18, 2016).  The conference was immediately followed by the Great Python Scavenger Hunt &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016/scavenger-race"&gt;https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016/scavenger-race&lt;/a&gt;. Our conferences are open to beginners, experts and non-programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-18:pycon-jamaica-2016/is-that-ham-in-my-spam-a-novices-inquiry-into-naive-bayes.html</guid><category>bayes</category></item><item><title>Using Django, Docker, and Scikit-learn to Bootstrap Your Machine Learning Project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2017/using-django-docker-and-scikit-learn-to-bootstrap-your-machine-learning-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US 2017 -  Using Django, Docker, and Scikit-learn to Bootstrap Your Machine Learning Project by Lorena Mesa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproducible results can be the bane of a data engineer or data scientist’s existence. Perhaps a data scientist prototyped a model some months ago, tabled the project, only to return to it today. It’s now when they notice the inaccurate or lack of documentation in the feature engineering process. No one wins in that scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll walk through how you can use Django to spin up a Docker container to handle the feature engineering required for a machine learning project and spit out a pickled model. From the version controlled Docker container we can version our models, store them as needed and use scikit-learn to generate predictions moving forward. Django will allow us to easily bootstrap a machine learning project removing the downtown required to setup a project and permit us to move quickly to having a model ready for exploration and ultimately production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning done a bit easier? Yes please!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/using-django-docker-and-scikit-learn-to-bootstrap-your-machine-learning-project/"&gt;https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/using-django-docker-and-scikit-learn-to-bootstrap-your-machine-learning-project/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-14:djangocon-us-2017/using-django-docker-and-scikit-learn-to-bootstrap-your-machine-learning-project.html</guid></item><item><title>Is that spam in my ham?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/is-that-spam-in-my-ham.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lorena Mesa - Is that spam in my ham?
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/is-that-spam-in-my-ham"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/is-that-spam-in-my-ham&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning programmers or Python beginners may find it overwhelming to
implement a machine learning algorithm. Increasingly machine learning
is becoming more applicable to many areas. This talk introduces key
concepts and ideas and uses Python to build a basic classifier - a
common type of machine learning problem. Providing some jargon to help
those that may be self-educated or currently learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervised learning, machine learning, classifiers, big data! What in
the world are all of these things? As a beginning programmer the
questions described as &amp;quot;machine learning&amp;quot; questions can be mystifying
at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will define the scope of a machine learning problem,
identifying an email as ham or spam, from the perspective of a
beginner (non master of all things &amp;quot;machine learning&amp;quot;) and show how
Python can help us simply learn how to classify a piece of email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin we must ask, what is spam? How do I know it &amp;quot;when I see it&amp;quot;?
From previous experience of course! We will provide human labeled
examples of spam to our model for it to understand the likelihood of
spam or ham. This approach, using examples and data we already know to
determine the most likely label for a new example, uses the Naive
Bayes classifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model will look at the words in the body of an email, finding the
frequency of words in both spam and ham emails and the frequency of
spam and ham. Once we know the prior likelihood of spam and what makes
something spam, we can try applying a label to a new example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this exercise we will see at a basic level what types of
questions machine learning asks, learn to model &amp;quot;learning&amp;quot; with
Python, and understand how learning can be measured.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-28:europython-2016/is-that-spam-in-my-ham.html</guid></item><item><title>Is that spam in my ham? A novice's inquiry into classification.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2015/is-that-spam-in-my-ham-a-novices-inquiry-into-c.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervised learning, machine learning, classifiers!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Help?&lt;/em&gt; In this
talk I define a problem, identifying an email as spam, from the
perspective of a beginner and show how Python can help us learn to
classify. We will translate knowing spam &amp;quot;when I see it&amp;quot; into a basic
model and use a Naive Bayes classifier to determine if email is spam. We
will train our classifier with examples and practice!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-01:pyohio-2015/is-that-spam-in-my-ham-a-novices-inquiry-into-c.html</guid><category>talk</category></item></channel></rss>