<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stefano-zacchiroli.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Software Heritage: The Great Library of (Python) Source Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2018/software-heritage-the-great-library-of-python-source-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Dandrimont</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-fr-2018/software-heritage-the-great-library-of-python-source-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.softwareheritage.org"&gt;Software Heritage&lt;/a&gt; is a non-profit
initiative whose goal is to become the most comprehensive archive of
publicly accessible source code in the world, together with its full
development history. The project archive already contains more than 4.5
billion source code files, more than 1 billion commits, coming from
almost a hundred million software projects. It is a modern time Great
Library of Source Code, growing daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Software Heritage
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forge.softwareheritage.org/diffusion/"&gt;stack&lt;/a&gt; is entirely
written in Python and supports archiving git repositories, subversion
repositories, mercurial repositories, Debian source packages, as well as
arbitrary archives (zip files, tarballs…) released by upstream authors.
Everything gets stored in a common, fully deduplicated data model,
allowing unified access to all archived content, regardless of the
original means of distribution. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://archive.softwareheritage.org/"&gt;The archive front-
end&lt;/a&gt;, built upon the Django
framework, allows people to browse the contents of the archive and
download snapshots of source code that may have disappeared upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While initially focused on archiving collaborative development forges
such as GitHub, BitBucket, and GitLab, Software Heritage also supports
archiving traditional software distributions, such as GNU/Linux
distributions, and language-specific ecosystems. As an acknowledgement
of the importance of the Python community for us, we are proud to
announce the archival of PyPI into Software Heritage. This presentation
will give a brief overview of the Software Heritage project and then
drill down through the technical details of the integration with PyPI.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>