<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ezio-melotti.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Capire le codifiche e Unicode</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/capire-le-codifiche-e-unicode.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/capire-le-codifiche-e-unicode.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="pep393"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="unicode"></category><category term="encodings"></category></entry><entry><title>Python on Mars</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-on-mars.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/python-on-mars.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="pytango"></category><category term="space suit tango"></category><category term="tango"></category><category term="mars"></category><category term="scientific-computing"></category><category term="neural network"></category><category term="space suit"></category></entry><entry><title>Python su Marte</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-su-marte.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/python-su-marte.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="tango"></category><category term="scientific-computing"></category><category term="pytango"></category><category term="neural network"></category><category term="tuta spaziale"></category></entry><entry><title>Understanding Encodings</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/understanding-encodings.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/understanding-encodings.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="pep393"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="unicode"></category><category term="encodings"></category></entry><entry><title>A journey into the Chinese language with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/a-journey-into-the-chinese-language-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/a-journey-into-the-chinese-language-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese language includes over 200 radicals used to form over 40
thousands characters that can be combined to create almost 100 thousands
words. Then there are tones, classifiers, homophones, multiple
pronunciations for each character, traditional and simplified variants,
different kind of romanization… it’s no wonder that Chinese is
considered one of the most difficult languages to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However Chinese is actually pretty easy and during this talk you will
learn more about this beautiful language and how I’ve been learning it
with the help of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Human-languages"></category><category term="data-mining"></category><category term="Chinese"></category></entry><entry><title>V-ERAS: Un ambiente virtuale per l'esplorazione planetaria</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/v-eras-un-ambiente-virtuale-per-lesplorazione-planetaria.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-25:pycon-italia-2014/v-eras-un-ambiente-virtuale-per-lesplorazione-planetaria.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European MaRs Analogue Station for Advanced Technologies Integration (ERAS -- www.erasproject.org) is a program spearheaded by the Italian Mars Society (IMS) which main goal is to provide an effective test bed for field operation studies in preparation for manned missions to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preliminarily to ERAS construction, IMS has started the development of an immersive Virtual Reality (VR) simulation of the Station (V-ERAS). The major advantage of such virtualization isthat it will be possible to undertake training sessions with a crew that can interact with its future environment before the actual station is built. This way a more effective design of the station and associated missions and a strong reduction of costs could be obtained. The main objective of this activity will be the achievement of adequate fidelity simulations and validation of the data obtained during the training sessions so that they can be used for the design of the station itself. Many ergonomics and human factors will be considered in the virtual model in order to be verified and validated before the actual ERAS habitat construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development effort is currently divided in three main activities: • ERAS Station simulation using an appropriate game engine supporting a virtual reality headset • Upper body and hands gestures tracking • Integration of an omnidirectional treadmill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant part of the software development associated to V-ERAS will be undertaken by international students within the Google Summer of Code 2014 (GSoC) program were IMS participate as mentor organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final goal will be the construction of a classroom in which four (or six, depending on the targeted crew size) VR stations will be installed and the definition of appropriate crew rotations in which different training sessions are performed. The availability of a single VR station prototype is targeted for September 2014 and multi-user integration, able to support four stations, should be ready for October/November 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is the language of choice for the project, and the presentation will explain how is it used.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Understanding Encodings</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2011/understanding-encodings.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-17:pycon-finland-2011/understanding-encodings.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2011/pycon-finland/sgybb/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2011/pycon-finland/sgybb/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with Unicode and encodings might be confusing, but every
developer must know how they work.
Even if the full Unicode standard is actually quite complex, only a
few basic concepts are really necessary to work with Python and
Unicode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the differences between Unicode strings and bytes;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how encodings are used to store characters;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the differences between different encodings;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to understand Unicode-related errors;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to explain these concept.
Best practices for using Unicode, the current status of Unicode in
Python 2 and 3, and the plans for the future (e.g. PEP393 - Flexible
string representation) will also be discussed.
The talk is suitable for both new developers that are not yet familiar
with Unicode and for experienced developers that want to understand
better what's going on under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Capire i decoratori</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2016/capire-i-decoratori.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:pycon-italia-2016/capire-i-decoratori.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>The development process of Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/the-development-process-of-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/the-development-process-of-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Ezio Melotti - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an open source language, where everyone can contribute, and
thanks to Mercurial now it's even easier. With this talk I want to
unveil what happens &amp;quot;behind the scenes&amp;quot; of CPython and how you can get
involved and be part of the open source community that allows Python to
be one of the most popular programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the workflow of the CPython development;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to get a clone of Python;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use Mercurial to do all the most common operations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the structure of the main CPython repository;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what other are repositories are used;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use the bug tracker to report and find bugs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use remote Mercurial repos to contribute code;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what tools are used;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to get in touch with the core developers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are the plans for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="contribute"></category><category term="cpython"></category><category term="mercurial"></category><category term="workflow"></category></entry><entry><title>V-ERAS-14: Una missione di esplorazione marziana in realtà virtuale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-una-missione-di-esplorazione-marziana.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-09:pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-una-missione-di-esplorazione-marziana.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;European MaRs Analogue Station for Advanced Technologies Integration
(ERAS) è un programma guidata dall’Italian Mars Society (IMS), il cui
obiettivo principale è fornire un ambiente di test per studiare
operazioni sul campo in preparazione a una missione su Marte. Prima
della sua costruzione, IMS ha iniziato lo sviluppo di una simulazione
immersiva in realtà virtuale (VR) della stazione ERAS (V-ERAS). Il setup
iniziale di V-ERAS si basa sui seguenti elementi chiave: - Simulazione
della stazione ERAS usando un virtual reality headset - Full body
tracking - Integrazione con un treadmill omnidirezionale - Supporto per
il monitoraggio della salute dei membri della crew - Supporto per utenti
multipli Fin dall’inizio, Python è stato una delle tecnologie chiave che
ci ha permesso di sviluppare il sistema, grazie anche a un team
internazionale di studenti che hanno partecipato con l’IMS a Google
Summer of Code. Nel Dicembre 2014, quattro astronauti virtuali hanno
condotto per una settimana un programma di simulazioni immersive in
realtà virtuale durante la prima missione V-ERAS (V-ERAS-14). La
presentazione mostrerà i risultati della missione V-ERAS-14,
integrandoli con il ruolo che Python ha avuto nel supportare
l’infrastruttura del progetto.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>V-ERAS-14: A Virtual Reality Mars Exploration Mission (in English)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-a-virtual-reality-mars-exploration-mis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-a-virtual-reality-mars-exploration-mis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation reports on the outcomes of the V-ERAS-14 Mission while
focusing on the integral role played by the Python language in
supporting the project infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European MaRs Analogue Station for Advanced Technologies Integration
(ERAS) is a program spearheaded by the Italian Mars Society (IMS), whose
main goal is to provide an effective test bed for field operation
studies in preparation for human missions to Mars. Preliminarily to its
construction, IMS has started the development of an immersive Virtual
Reality (VR) simulation of the ERAS Station (V-ERAS). The initial V-ERAS
setup has been based on the following key elements: - ERAS Station
simulation using an appropriate game engine supporting a virtual reality
headset - Full body tracking - Integration of an omnidirectional
treadmill - Support for the crew members’ health monitoring -
Multiplayer Support Since the beginning, Python has been one of the key
technologies that allowed us to develop the system, also thanks to a
team of international students that participated with the IMS to Google
Summer of Code. In December 2014, four virtual astronauts have conducted
a sustained program of immersive virtual reality simulations during the
first week-long V-ERAS Mission (V-ERAS-14). The presentation will report
on the outcomes of the V-ERAS-14 Mission while fusing on the transversal
role played by the Python language in supporting the project
infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>