<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mark Bynens</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mark-bynens.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Mastering the Art of Adopting R and Python: Innovative Strategies for Effective Change Management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/mastering-the-art-of-adopting-r-and-python-innovative-strategies-for-effective-change-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Bynens</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/mastering-the-art-of-adopting-r-and-python-innovative-strategies-for-effective-change-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mastering the Art of Adopting R and Python: Innovative Strategies for Effective Change Management' is more than just a presentation; it's a roadmap to navigate the complexities to integrate R and Python into our daily operations in a world that never slows down. Through an in-depth look at some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mastering the Art of Adopting R and Python: Innovative Strategies for Effective Change Management' is more than just a presentation; it's a roadmap to navigate the complexities to integrate R and Python into our daily operations in a world that never slows down. Through an in-depth look at some real-world examples from Janssen R&amp;amp;D moving towards R and Python, we will show you how it's done. This isn't just theory; it's practical, actionable advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we embark on a journey to weave R and Python into the fabric of our organization, let's keep these insights and strategies at the forefront. Together, we can redefine what it means to be adaptable and resilient in an ever-changing world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>