<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Shafqat Farhan Ahmed</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_shafqat-farhan-ahmed.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Level Up Your Django Performance: Identifying and Taming N+1 Queries</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/level-up-your-django-performance-identifying-and-taming-n1-queries.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mohammad Ahtasham ul Hassan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-24:/djangocon-us-2024/level-up-your-django-performance-identifying-and-taming-n1-queries.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, attendees will embark on a journey to understand and overcome the notorious N+1 query problem in Django development. The session will begin with an exploration of the importance of performance optimization in Django applications, emphasizing the critical role of efficient database queries in achieving robust …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, attendees will embark on a journey to understand and overcome the notorious N+1 query problem in Django development. The session will begin with an exploration of the importance of performance optimization in Django applications, emphasizing the critical role of efficient database queries in achieving robust and scalable web solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will delve into the intricacies of the N+1 query problem, unraveling its origins and impact on application performance. Through real-world examples and case studies, attendees will gain a deeper understanding of how N+1 queries manifest and the detrimental effects they can have on Django applications, such as increased latency, decreased throughput, and degraded user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the presentation will focus on practical solutions to mitigate the N+1 query problem and optimize Django code for enhanced performance. Attendees will learn how to identify N+1 queries in their projects and understand the underlying causes behind them. We will explore a range of techniques and best practices for resolving N+1 queries, including lazy loading, prefetching, and leveraging Django's ORM features such as select_related and prefetch_related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the attendees will discover how to utilize debugging tools and techniques, including the Django Debug Toolbar and SQL logging, to diagnose and address N+1 query issues effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the presentation draws to a close, we'll leave attendees with a thought-provoking question: &amp;quot;Why do some experts caution that fixing certain N+1 queries could potentially hurt performance?&amp;quot; This question invites attendees to delve deeper into the complexities of performance optimization and encourages further research and exploration into the nuanced considerations of optimizing database queries in Django applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the presentation, attendees will be equipped with actionable insights and practical skills to:
Identify and diagnose N+1 queries in their Django projects.
Implement effective solutions to optimize application performance and eliminate performance bottlenecks.
Utilize debugging tools and techniques to pinpoint and resolve N+1 query issues efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation is designed for Django developers of all experience levels, from beginners to seasoned professionals. Whether you're new to Django or a seasoned veteran, join us to deepen your understanding of Django performance optimization and elevate your development skills to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>