<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>I've Been Awaiting for an URL Like You</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/ive-been-awaiting-for-an-url-like-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The [InterPlanetary File System (IPFS)](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ipfs.io/"&gt;https://ipfs.io/&lt;/a&gt;) is a peer-to-peer hypermedia protocol to make the web faster, safer, and more open.  It's one of the leading open projects in the decentralization space, and Python developers should be able to use libraries that support the API protocol.  The best way to interact with a network protocol like IPFS in Python is to utilize the asynchronous asyncio library that comes with Python 3.  This talk will cover the basics of how asyncio and IPFS work, and will then take deep dive on what it was like to convert the InterPlanetary File System Python 2 library to async enabled Python 3.  The talk will cover suggestions around when a conversion to asyncio may be useful, and when it may not be recommended.  General practices for code refactoring and Python 3 upgrades will be covered as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Muller</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-05:pygotham-2018/ive-been-awaiting-for-an-url-like-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Don't Overreact: Moving from Twisted to Asyncio</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/dont-overreact-moving-from-twisted-to-asyncio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk covers the basics of the Twisted and Asyncio libraries for asynchronous I/O and then delves into an experience porting the Kademlia distributed hash table (DHT) library from Twisted to Asyncio.  The talk will start with a high level discussion of asynchronous I/O and describe some example cases where it might be useful.  Concrete examples in both Twisted and Asyncio will be provided to demonstrate two different approaches to asynchronous libraries.  Then, in the primary focus of the talk, the process, challenges, and lessons from converting a complex library from Twisted to Asyncio will be covered.   This will include covering cases when a conversion should and shouldn't be undertaken, along with advice for anyone who wants to convert an existing library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Muller</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/dont-overreact-moving-from-twisted-to-asyncio.html</guid></item><item><title>Untangling Twisted: How We Scaled a Python Service for Online Publishers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/untangling-twisted-how-we-scaled-a-python-servic.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At OpBandit, we built a Python Twisted service that renders different
versions of news content for rendering on top publishers across six
countries. At a high level, whenever a reader requests a page on a
publisher's website, our service selects from various versions of
headlines and photos to deliver the collection of versions that we think
a user is most likely to click. This requires decision making on the fly
for each request with hard requirements for speed and reliability. This
talk will cover how we used Twisted to scale our service to provide
hundreds of millions of optimized pages / month for readers, as well as
what it's like to attempt to scale real-time data science recommendation
algorithms within Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Muller</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/untangling-twisted-how-we-scaled-a-python-servic.html</guid></item></channel></rss>