<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Guide to Modern Hyperparameter Tuning Algorithms</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/a-guide-to-modern-hyperparameter-tuning-algorithms.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern deep learning model performance is very dependent on the choice
of model hyperparameters, and the tuning process is a major bottleneck
in the machine learning pipeline. In this talk, we will overview modern
methods for hyperparameter tuning and demonstrate how to use Tune, a
scalable hyperparameter tuning library. Tune is completely open source
at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tune.io"&gt;http://tune.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will target intermediate to advanced data scientists and
researchers familiar with deep learning. The talk will first motivate
the need for advancements in hyperparameter tuning methods. The talk
will then overview standard methods for hyperparameter tuning: grid
search, random search, and bayesian optimization. Then, we will motivate
and discuss cutting edge methods for hyperparameter tuning:
multi-fidelity bayesian optimization, successive halving algorithms
(HyperBand), and population-based training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will then present a overview of Tune, a scalable hyperparameter
tuning system from the UC Berkeley RISELab, and demonstrate about how
users can leverage cutting edge hyperparameter tuning methods
implemented in Tune to quickly improve the performance of standard deep
learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Richard Liaw</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/a-guide-to-modern-hyperparameter-tuning-algorithms.html</guid></item></channel></rss>