<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_allie.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Real Time Bidding Models in Computational Advertising</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/real-time-bidding-models-in-computational-advertising.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-17:pybay-2019/real-time-bidding-models-in-computational-advertising.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
The talk provides an overview of the ad tech ecosystem, in particular how ad slots are dynamically populated by way of user behavioral targeting each time a webpage loads. It should be interesting for developers as well as data scientists who are looking to learn about the applications of machine learning in computational advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In particular, we will explore how DSPs (demand side platforms) optimize ad campaigns for advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus will be on how CTR (click-through-rates) are optimized via real-time-bidding (RTB) models. We will discuss modeling challenges such as how best to handle categorical or imbalanced training data. You will come away with a deeper understanding of the system design trade-offs and be able to deploy models at scale in your own work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Allie is a data scientist at Even.com, a fintech company based in Oakland whose mission is to end the paycheck-to-paycheck cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to Even, Allie worked as an engineer and first data scientist at early-stage startups in the consulting, sales tech, and ad tech space in the Bay area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>