<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Real world Graphene - lessons learned from building a GraphQL API on top of a large Django project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-on-top-of-a-large-django-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphene is currently the most popular framework for building a GraphQL
in Python and it’s also an obvious choice for adding a GraphQL layer to
Django applications. Over the course of a year, we successfully built an
API with about 50 queries and over 100 mutations on top of existing
Django project (Saleor), but we also learned some hard lessons and had
to overcome several shortcomings of the framework along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’d like to share some practical tips to overcome the most
common problems that a Django developer might face when building an
optimized and maintainable API with Graphene, such as: - using useful
abstractions to build queries and mutations faster - optimizing database
queries in a graph - structuring a large Graphene project - unified
error handling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to bring up a few limitations of the framework that we
discovered as we were working on the project and then end the talk with
the most important benefits that adoption of GraphQL brings to modern
web applications development - both for the backend and frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: - Intermediate knowledge of Django - Familiarity with API
design and concepts in terms of web development - Basic knowledge of
GraphQL or interest in it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the talk would be of great value to anyone working with a
Graphene framework and those who want to know more about building
GraphQL in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All code examples in the presentation would be based on Saleor
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mirumee/saleor"&gt;https://github.com/mirumee/saleor&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1644"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1644&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marcin Gębala</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-on-top-of-a-large-django-project.html</guid><category>API Design</category><category>e-commerce</category><category>graphql</category><category>open-source</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Real world Graphene: lessons learned from building a GraphQL API - Marcin Gębala - PyCon Israel 2019</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-marcin-gebala-pycon-israel-2019.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marcin Gębala</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-06-03:pycon-israel-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-marcin-gebala-pycon-israel-2019.html</guid></item></channel></rss>