<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HiPy - Python for High School Students</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2014/hipy-python-for-high-school-students-pycon-apa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ever progressing technology is no doubt beneficial to mankind.
However, the current inventions derived from new technology is not
thorough enough to cover the needs of more focused groups. More
importantly, students often find themselves hard to go beyond passively
receiving information and stretch their own ability to become active
drivers of positive change by channeling curriculum to real life. This
is where innovation and creation of tailored applications set in. This
talk, by a group of three students from Dunman High School, Singapore,
serves to allow people to better understand the needs of high school
students and how Python can be used to benefit them. Examples based on
the authors' personal observations and experiences together with
illustration of procedures and real-time demonstration will be presented
to show how Python can be thoughtfully utilized as an inventive
computational thinking and practical problem solving tool to enrich the
lives of students. Through our sharing, we would like to inspire more
ideas on developing Python applications of close relevance to students
and hopefully, encourage more students to use Python to actively improve
their school experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nie Shuyue: New learner of Programming. Studying for Python since 2013
and learned a bit of Java and HTML. Had some hands on projects using
mainly Python and tried using Python with Google App Engine and Pygame.
It is fun to learn Python. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu Chenmu: 2005 -2007 Learning BASIC 2012 - Learning Python, C++ and
Java Study art for 4 years, good at graphic design, web design and UI
design. Has experience in both competitive programming and mobile
application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Song Kai: 2006 - 2007 Learning BASIC 2008 - 2011 Learning PASCAL 2012 -
Learning C++ 2013 - Learning Python Has experience in both competitive
programming (algorithm based) and application development. Hopes to make
good combination of both aspects of coding to bring more convenience to
people’s daily life. Some Python projects done:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://elijahsk.pythonanywhere.com/"&gt;http://elijahsk.pythonanywhere.com/&lt;/a&gt; (Flask based)
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dessert.program"&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dessert.program&lt;/a&gt; (Pygame
based, in collaboration with Shuyue) &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dhstreasurerkit.appspot.com"&gt;http://dhstreasurerkit.appspot.com&lt;/a&gt;
(GAE based)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others: We have one female presenter Shuyue and through this
presentation, we would like to encourage more female students to try
Python and bravely voice out their own experiences. All three of us are
Year 6 (Grade 12) students from Dunman High School, Singapore. Last year
we have been through Project Work where systematic report and
interactive oral presentation are the main focus of learning. We are
confident that we can give the audience an engaging presentation
experience. We have good ability to converse in Mandarin, hence are able
to reach out to a broader / more local audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nie Shuyue</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-13:pycon-apac-2014/hipy-python-for-high-school-students-pycon-apa.html</guid></item></channel></rss>