<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Making Python More Fun for Everyone</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2013/making-python-more-fun-for-everyone.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We spent the first part of our careers developing products and managing
software teams at IBM, Dell, and Texas Instruments. After moving to
Singapore, we each found are way into the education space and found
ourselves teaching Python to a variety of audiences. We developed our
first Python game for a friend of ours who was teaching computer science
in a local high school. Since then, it has been a continual journey to
see how fun we could make learning python before our now 10-year old
daughter was ready to pickup the keyboard and start helping out. In this
talk, we will talk about where our journey started, where we are today,
and where we hope to be in the near future. We will discuss the
Tournament-based Teaching methodology that we developed to increase
student preparation, in-class engagement, and peer-based learning. Then
we will talk about our research in to using mobile devices such as the
iPad to help students practice reading and working with python to gain
confidence before moving on to writing code. We will discuss our latest
family project where we have worked with our children to create a fun
python quest to encourage learners around the world to practice their
python for just a few minutes more each week. Then looking forward, we
will talk about our latest research in to pair-based programming
assignments, pair-programming tournaments, team-based logic
competitions, encouraging more girls to try programming, and the goal to
frame programming as a very healthy habit. Our hope is that this talk
will be interesting for educators looking to increase student engagement
and interest, for managers looking for fun ways to increase the
productivity of their development teams, and for parents looking for
additional ways to enable their children to experiment with python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Boesch</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-07:pycon-au-2013/making-python-more-fun-for-everyone.html</guid></item></channel></rss>