<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Critical Incidents: a guide for developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/critical-incidents-a-guide-for-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As developers we know (too well) there’s no such thing as bug-free software.
Whether you work in a small or big production software, incidents are
inevitable and being prepared is key. How would you handle, for example, a
database outage if it happened now? Or a critical bug that is affecting half
of your users?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigating in crisis mode is never easy, but having a great company culture
and recovery plan gives you guidance and mitigates damage. In this talk, I
will share some success cases, such as GitLab database outage recovery, and
my personal experience as a project manager overcoming a critical incident
in a subscription system built with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can you do to prepare your team? When should you enter crisis mode? How
to assemble a recovery plan? To answer these and other questions, I will
provide a step-by-step guide, from an Modern Agile perspective, starting
with the bug discovery, and handling the client’s expectations, through the
data recovery, until your incident postmortem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lais Varejão</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-05:pygotham-2018/critical-incidents-a-guide-for-developers.html</guid></item><item><title>Salvando Grandes Projetos</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2017/salvando-grandes-projetos.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lais Varejão</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:python-brasil-2017/salvando-grandes-projetos.html</guid></item><item><title>Defining a customizable boilerplate using Django, React and Bootstrap</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/defining-a-customizable-boilerplate-using-django-react-and-bootstrap.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you are a beginner or experienced developer, setting up the initial environment of a project can be a time-consuming task. A common solution for this problem is the use of boilerplates. Not only they reduce the setup time, but also assure strict guidelines are followed. However, most of the available boilerplates cover only one part of the problem - front or back end - and integrations are required to suit your specific needs. So, why not define your own full stack boilerplate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll share my experience and present the development process of a customizable Django, React, Bootstrap 4 with Python 3 and webpack project boilerplate. The design decisions, possible configurations and positive impacts of it's application in a production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lais Varejao</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/defining-a-customizable-boilerplate-using-django-react-and-bootstrap.html</guid></item><item><title>Definindo um Boilerplate Customizável usando Django, React e Bootstrap</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2016/definindo-um-boilerplate-customizavel-usando-django-react-e-bootstrap.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tanto para desenvolvedores iniciantes como para os mais experientes, configurar o ambiente inicial de um projeto pode consumir bastante tempo. Uma abordagem comum para solucionar esse problema é a utilização de boilerplates. Essa abordagem não só reduz o tempo inicial, como garante uma padronização dos projetos. A maioria das soluções disponíveis, entretanto, cobrem somente uma parte do problema - frontend ou backend - e integrações são sempre necessárias. Então, por que não definir o seu próprio boilerplate fullstack?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nessa talk será apresentado o processo de construção de um boilerplate fullstack, flexível e customizável para Django, React e Bootstrap utilizando npm e webpack. Serão detalhadas as decisões de design, as possibilidades de configuração e customização e os impactos positivos de sua aplicação.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lais Varejão</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-13:python-brasil-2016/definindo-um-boilerplate-customizavel-usando-django-react-e-bootstrap.html</guid></item></channel></rss>