<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_busra-koken.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Automating Distributed Tasks with Ansible in the Cloud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2016/automating-distributed-tasks-with-ansible-in-the-cloud.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Büşra Köken</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-12:pycon-sk-2016/automating-distributed-tasks-with-ansible-in-the-cloud.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a powerful automation, configuration management tool written
in python. In this talk, you are going to see how Ansible works, how
easy it is to get started and make your configuration management
automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to show you a case study that covers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating a Hadoop cluster in the cloud - digitalocean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;running a Big Data job on the Hadoop cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;destroying the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All above is done with Ansible remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, you are going to leave the room with an intro knowledge of
Ansible and be excited about starting of your new project with it!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I love being Pythonic</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/i-love-being-pythonic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Busra Koken</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pycon-uk-2016/i-love-being-pythonic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Busra Koken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python seems like an executable pseudo code. It has unique strengths and charms that can be hard to grasp. Programmers familiar with other languages may try to write Python as if it’s C++, Java, or whatever they know best. It’s important for everyone to know—the Pythonic—way to do the most common things in Python. Python philosophy suggests to be explicit, to choose simple over complex, and to maximise readability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I am going to share my story of switching from a C-family language to Python. What Pythonic thinking means here is that understanding python implementations, dynamic language structure, supported programming styles, data structures and functional extensions. The more you learn the strength of Python language the more you enjoy coding.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>