<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Gordon Shotwell</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_gordon-shotwell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Diversify Your Career with Shiny for Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/diversify-your-career-with-shiny-for-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gordon Shotwell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/diversify-your-career-with-shiny-for-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago my company made a sudden shift from R to Python which was quite bad for my career because I didn't really know Python. The main issue was that I couldn't find a niche that allowed me to use my existing knowledge while learning the new …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago my company made a sudden shift from R to Python which was quite bad for my career because I didn't really know Python. The main issue was that I couldn't find a niche that allowed me to use my existing knowledge while learning the new language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiny for Python is a great niche for R users because none of the Python web frameworks can do what Shiny can do. Additionally, almost all of your knowledge of the R package is applicable to the Python one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of the Python web application landscape and articulate what Shiny adds to this landscape, and then go through the five things that R users need to know before developing their first Shiny for Python application.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>