<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ramón Corominas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ramon-corominas.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>What a screen reader can teach you about remote Python debugging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/what-a-screen-reader-can-teach-you-about-remote-python-debugging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ramón Corominas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/what-a-screen-reader-can-teach-you-about-remote-python-debugging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/what-a-screen-reader-can-teach-you-about-remote-python-debugging"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/what-a-screen-reader-can-teach-you-about-remote-python-debugging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NVDA screen reader is a Python application packaged with Py2exe, along with C++ extensions for low-level system access and improved performance. Its functionality can be expanded through addons that are also written in Python, which …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/what-a-screen-reader-can-teach-you-about-remote-python-debugging"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/what-a-screen-reader-can-teach-you-about-remote-python-debugging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NVDA screen reader is a Python application packaged with Py2exe, along with C++ extensions for low-level system access and improved performance. Its functionality can be expanded through addons that are also written in Python, which makes the ability to debug both the core and addon code highly desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, debugging code within an embedded or packaged Python environment can be quite challenging, especially if you are a visually impaired programmer trying to debug your own screen reader, since hitting a breakpoint will freeze the tool you rely on for computer access!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, I will demonstrate how I addressed this challenge by leveraging Microsoft's debugpy library for remote debugging. I will showcase how this technique can be used to debug Python applications running within an embedded Python environment, regardless of the host language. Additionally, I will explore its applicability in debugging applications running on different operating systems or environments than the one where you prefer to use your debugging IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry></feed>