<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python in Viral Bioinformatics Research</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/python-in-viral-bioinformatics-research.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The field of bioinformatics -- using computer technology to store,
process and analyze biological data -- is relatively new, but is
expanding rapidly. Many free and commercial tools, both online and
stand-alone, are available. This presentation will describe the approach
and tools developed in our research group at the University of the
Witwatersrand. Although we research hepatitis B virus, many of the tools
can be used with any biological sequence data (DNA, RNA or amino acids).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools cover several aspects of typical laboratory research,
including tools to process sequence data, automate analyses and report
variations in sequences. The tools were developed to be quick,
lightweight solutions, which could easily be used routinely by
researchers without extensive computer skills. Many of the tools have
been developed in direct response to a specific need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics covered will include the design approach (online, CGI-scripts, no
frameworks) and the reasons for this approach, as well as the experience
of working as the only bioinformaticist in a wet laboratory. Mention
will also be made of other resources, such as R and SQL, in addition to
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of the tools have been described in published papers. The tools
are all freely available online
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hvdr.bioinf.wits.ac.za/tools"&gt;http://hvdr.bioinf.wits.ac.za/tools&lt;/a&gt;)
and source code for most of the tools is available via GitHub at the
following address:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/DrTrevorBell"&gt;https://github.com/DrTrevorBell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Trevor Bell</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/python-in-viral-bioinformatics-research.html</guid></item></channel></rss>