<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mark-fink.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Awesome CLI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/awesome-cli.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Fink</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/awesome-cli.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to get user input from your command line program?
Or maybe color the output a bit? Or do you want to write an immersive
terminal application like top, or even vim? Then you need to speak a bit
of terminal! This talk describes how to talk to your terminal from
scratch and goes on to show why the Python library prompt-toolkit is so
awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terminal emulators we run so many of our programming tools in are
more powerful than we give them credit for, and the key to that power is
understanding the interface. This talk will cover terminal colors and
styles, writing to arbitrary portions of the screen, handling signals
from the terminal, determining the terminal’s dimensions and scrollback
buffer behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terminal programming can get hairy, especially if you want to support
multiple platforms like Mac, Linux and Win; along the way we’ll deal
with encoding issues, automatisation issues and look into 4 decades’ of
terminal communication. By gaining a deeper understanding of these
issues, we’ll be able to choose from the abstractions over them offered
by Python libraries like Blessings, prompt-toolkit, asciimatics etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="terminal"></category><category term="prompt-toolkit"></category><category term="cli"></category><category term="command-line"></category></entry><entry><title>open source performance test harness for Ajax applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2011/open-source-performance-test-harness-for-ajax-app.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Fink</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-07:pycon-de-2011/open-source-performance-test-harness-for-ajax-app.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing AJAX applications is hard because of its asynchronous nature of
request processing. Performance testing of those applications is even
harder for the very same reasons. Since 2009 we have seen a dramatic
increase in adoption of the AJAX technology. Now it is time to upgrade
our test harness, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Agile testing in the large</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/agile-testing-in-the-large.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Fink</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-31:pycon-de-2012/agile-testing-in-the-large.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Im Vortrag &amp;quot;Agile testing in the large&amp;quot; nutze ich wieder OpenSource
Tools die leider nicht alle in Python implementiert sind, jedoch
hervorragend geeignet sind, um u.a. Python Webapplikationen zu testen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortrag erläuterte das Testen moderner Web-Anwendungen und gliedert
sich so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Einleitung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kleine Entwickler-Tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mittlere und große Entwickler-Tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance Testing mit Selenium2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themen exploratory Testing und Performance Testing bleiben absichtlich
unbehandelt.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="testing"></category></entry></feed>