<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Stephannie Jimenez Gacha</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stephannie-jimenez-gacha.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Inclusive and accessible scientific computing in the Jupyter Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/inclusive-and-accessible-scientific-computing-in-the-jupyter-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephannie Jimenez Gacha</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/inclusive-and-accessible-scientific-computing-in-the-jupyter-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard about accessibility?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3, 2, 1 ….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have heard the term accessibility before in a particular context, but have you thought about how accessibility fits within the open source development? In this talk, we will dive into the efforts to make Jupyterlab and Jupyter interfaces …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard about accessibility?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3, 2, 1 ….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have heard the term accessibility before in a particular context, but have you thought about how accessibility fits within the open source development? In this talk, we will dive into the efforts to make Jupyterlab and Jupyter interfaces accessible to a broader audience of users, including those users requiring assistive technologies. We will discuss ongoing efforts around robust accessibility testing framework for projects in the Jupyter ecosystem, addressing critical accessibility issues in Jupyterlab and developing documentation focused on best practices for accessibility compliance and disability inclusion. And, more importantly, how you can participate in making open source more accessible to all, whatever your role is: user, contributor, maintainer, advocate or any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the talk, the attendees will be able to:
1. Have a basic understanding of accessibility and how it ties to open source software such as Jupyterlab.
2. Learn about current efforts to make Jupyterlab more accessible.
3. Get resources for learning more about accessibility and to engage with the accessibility efforts in the Jupyter ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Apis: Standardization of N-dimensional arrays and dataframes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/data-apis-standardization-of-n-dimensional-arrays-and-dataframes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephannie Jimenez Gacha</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-11:/pycon-de-2022/data-apis-standardization-of-n-dimensional-arrays-and-dataframes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Stephannie Jimenez Gacha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: PyData &amp;amp; Scientific Libraries Stack
We would like to introduce the consortium of Data APIs, where we will be presenting our motivation, objectives and progress of the standardization process after one year of activity. We will dive into a small history lesson of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Stephannie Jimenez Gacha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: PyData &amp;amp; Scientific Libraries Stack
We would like to introduce the consortium of Data APIs, where we will be presenting our motivation, objectives and progress of the standardization process after one year of activity. We will dive into a small history lesson of the current state of the Python data and scientific ecosystem and understand the current fragmentation of the APIs. Then, we will start discussing the efforts of standardization for N-dimensional arrays and dataframes. Finally. we will talk about the roadmap for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/BMFVFG"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/BMFVFG&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2022"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConDE"></category><category term="pyconde2022"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="pydataberlin2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Accessibility best practices for authoring Jupyter notebooks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/accessibility-best-practices-for-authoring-jupyter-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephannie Jimenez Gacha</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/accessibility-best-practices-for-authoring-jupyter-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you’ve written the perfect notebook, but do you know who can read it? As a notebook author you have great stories, code, and visualizations filling your work, but how often do you consider accessibility? Jupyter notebooks seem like they are for everyone, but how a notebook gets …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you’ve written the perfect notebook, but do you know who can read it? As a notebook author you have great stories, code, and visualizations filling your work, but how often do you consider accessibility? Jupyter notebooks seem like they are for everyone, but how a notebook gets written can greatly impact how usable it is for people with disabilities. We’ve curated authoring-focused best practices for notebook content to help your notebooks be more inclusive and reach a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>