<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Keith Martin Machina</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_keith-martin-machina.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Efficient Path Planning for Search and Rescue Missions Using Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2024/efficient-path-planning-for-search-and-rescue-missions-using-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Keith Martin Machina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-27:/pyohio-2024/efficient-path-planning-for-search-and-rescue-missions-using-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Utilizing the Python programming language and the Tkinter library, I
propose to develop a simulated robotic application tailored for search
and rescue missions. Central to this endeavor is the integration of a
neural network, trained on pertinent search and rescue data, to
effectively guide the robotic agent towards areas …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Utilizing the Python programming language and the Tkinter library, I
propose to develop a simulated robotic application tailored for search
and rescue missions. Central to this endeavor is the integration of a
neural network, trained on pertinent search and rescue data, to
effectively guide the robotic agent towards areas with a high
probability of locating survivors. The neural network's computations
yield a dynamic cost map, which takes into account both traversal costs
and the priority of various regions within the search area. This cost
map serves as a comprehensive tool, continuously furnishing the robotic
agent with insights into the search region and optimizing its search
strategy. Importantly, this approach is conceived to address challenges
inherent in reinforcement learning, such as the lack of a global view
and the need to balance multiple objectives in search and rescue
mission.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2024"></category></entry></feed>