<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Shin Dong-hyun</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Django ORM that understands and uses SQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/django-orm-that-understands-and-uses-sql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most web developers manage data persistence using ORMs such as SQLAlchemy and Django ORM rather than writing SQL directly. ORM connects objects and relational databases. Using ORM, developers can perform DML in programming languages ​​without writing SQL. Since data is handled through object-oriented code, code readability is improved and productivity is enhanced. Also, since the database and code base are loosely connected through abstraction, it can flexibly respond to infrastructure changes. In addition, ORM provides additional features such as lazy-loading and caching to reduce unnecessary queries. However, ORM does not have only advantages. The more complex the data being queried, the more inconvenient ORM can be. This is because the limitations of ORM prevent the full functionality of SQL from being utilized. ORMs that are used without properly understanding the operating principles create very inefficient queries. Therefore, it is very important to understand the characteristics of SQL and know the operating principles of ORM so that you can query correctly. Let's learn how to properly use Django ORM by understanding the characteristics of SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shin Dong-hyun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-02:/pycon-korea-2022/django-orm-that-understands-and-uses-sql.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2022</category><category>Web Service</category></item><item><title>Python Domain Driven Design</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/python-domain-driven-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to develop software that keeps up with the pace of rapidly changing technologies and growing services, we need to pursue a clear, maintainable, and highly scalable design methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain-Driven Design (DDD) is a proven software development methodology that focuses on understanding and modeling core business domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will guide you through the basic concepts of DDD and learn how to implement DDD using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shin Dong-hyun
I am a backend developer who mainly uses Python web frameworks. I strive to become a person who provides better value to the world through technology. I am interested in software design and system architecture. I run a technology blog (qu3vipon.com).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shin Dong-hyun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/python-domain-driven-design.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>