<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Arnab Mondal</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_arnab-mondal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>C-MI-GAN : Estimation of Conditional Mutual Information using MinMax formulation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/c-mi-gan-estimation-of-conditional-mutual-information-using-minmax-formulation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Arnab Mondal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/c-mi-gan-estimation-of-conditional-mutual-information-using-minmax-formulation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;C-MI-GAN : Estimation of Conditional Mutual Information using MinMax formulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnab Mondal (IIT Delhi)*; Arnab  Bhattacharjee (IIT Delhi); Sudipto Mukherjee (University of Washington); Himanshu Asnani (TIFR); Sreeram Kannan (University of Washington); Prathosh A P (Indian Institute of Technology Delhi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimation of information theoretic quantities such as mutual information and its …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;C-MI-GAN : Estimation of Conditional Mutual Information using MinMax formulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnab Mondal (IIT Delhi)*; Arnab  Bhattacharjee (IIT Delhi); Sudipto Mukherjee (University of Washington); Himanshu Asnani (TIFR); Sreeram Kannan (University of Washington); Prathosh A P (Indian Institute of Technology Delhi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimation of information theoretic quantities such as mutual information and its conditional variant has drawn interest in recent times owing to their multifaceted applications. Newly proposed neural estimators for these quantities have overcome severe drawbacks of classical $k$NN-based estimators in high dimensions. In this work, we focus on conditional mutual information (CMI) estimation by utilizing its formulation as a textit{minmax} optimization problem. Such a formulation leads to a joint training procedure similar to that of generative adversarial networks. We find that our proposed estimator provides better estimates than the existing approaches on a variety of simulated datasets comprising linear and non-linear relations between variables. As an application of CMI estimation, we deploy our estimator for conditional independence (CI) testing on real data and obtain better results than state-of-the-art CI testers.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>