<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_phil-roth.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Examining Malware with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/examining-malware-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phil Roth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-09:scipy-2015/examining-malware-with-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Time Series Analysis for Network Security</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/time-series-analysis-network-security.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phil Roth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-10:scipy-2014/time-series-analysis-network-security.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Endgame seeks to develop products that allow customers to gain
visibility into their networks and discover anomalies. I will describe
how Endgame brings together various Python packages (scipy, pandas,
statsmodels, kairos, etc...) in order to collect, record, and then
analyze time series that are collected from network security data feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will describe how Endgame has brought together many
different Python tools in order to solve the problem of detecting
outliers in network security data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in this process is collecting and storing the metrics
that will form a time series. Here, I will describe how Endgame plugs
into the flow of network data and then stores that data. (Python
packages: elasticsearch, pyspark, kairos)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is applying a Fourier transform in order to classify time
series that exhibit daily and weekly patterns. This information is
especially useful in deciding how to characterize a time series's past
behavior and thus judge how unusual new data is. (Python package: numpy)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, exponentially weighted moving averages and standard deviations
are calculated in different ways depending on how the time series was
classified. For example, if strong daily patterns are present, the data
is stacked by daily time bin and moving averages are calculated within
each time bin. Corrections for weekend and weekday behavior are also
applied if necessary. Autoregressive moving average models are also used
and the performance of each algorithm is gauged and compared (Python
packages: pandas, scikits.statsmodels).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result of this process is a list of outliers and their
severity. Further algorithms will judge what outliers are serious enough
to present to users.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>