<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The KBase Narrative Bioinformatics for the 99%</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/the-kbase-narrative-bioinformatics-for-the-99.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The KBase Narrative builds on the IPython Notebook to provide a
multi-user, virtualized Bioinformatics Laboratory Notebook that brings
Experimental/Wetlab Biologists, students and the bio-curious into the
world of Computational Biology. Tools for genome annotation,
visualization, metabolic modeling and more are made available in a
collaborative and educational web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computional Biology and Experimental Biology are two specialities that
would deeply benefit from more interaction - computationalists need
access to data, biologists in wetlabs need computational tools. The
KBase Narrative is a computerized laboratory notebook that puts the
power of the KBase predictive biology platform into the hands of
experimentalists and students. KBase provides cluster computation,
analysis and modeling pipelines, large public datasets and a &amp;quot;pluggable&amp;quot;
architecture for future services. The Narrative is an interface enabling
the sharing of data, approaches and workflows on KBase. It also serves
as a teaching tool and publishing platform, allowing other scientists
and students to observe and reproduce the processes that led to the
published result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KBase Narrative is based on the IPython Notebook, extended in the
following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notebooks are stored in a remote object store that enables
versioning, provenance and sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for multiple users has been added, based on OAuth
authentication against a &amp;quot;cloud&amp;quot; authentication service (Globus
Online)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A framework for dynamically building form inputs for services using
Python introspection and the IPython Traitlets package (a version of
Traits) and displaying the output in JS visualization widgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Docker based provisioning system that builds and tears down
sandboxed IPython Notebook servers on demand, providing a scalable,
reasonable safe and easy to use environment for running hosted
IPython notebooks with much smaller overhead than VM's&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A heavily modified user interface that has been designed to support
computational biology workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current KBase Narrative was developed over the span of roughly 6
months by a small team of developers and user interface experts - the
short time scale was possible due to the huge amount of functionality
already provided by the IPython Notebook, and taking advantage of the
productivity and power of the Python language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Rihl</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/the-kbase-narrative-bioinformatics-for-the-99.html</guid><category>bioinformatics</category></item></channel></rss>