<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Carlos Kidman</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_carlos-kidman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Testing ML Systems: More than just accuracy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/testing-ml-systems-more-than-just-accuracy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Kidman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/testing-ml-systems-more-than-just-accuracy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing ML Systems: More than just accuracy - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zillow lost millions because they didn’t have proper MLOps or testing
processes. They relied on the training metrics, like accuracy, but
Software Quality goes beyond that. I will cover different testing types,
techniques, and concepts that you can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing ML Systems: More than just accuracy - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zillow lost millions because they didn’t have proper MLOps or testing
processes. They relied on the training metrics, like accuracy, but
Software Quality goes beyond that. I will cover different testing types,
techniques, and concepts that you can apply to make high-quality ML
Systems. As ML/AI systems are becoming more prevalent, the need for
setting quality standards and testing practices has become crucial.
Testing these models goes beyond validation metrics like accuracy,
precision, and recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, quality attributes like model Behaviors, Usability, and
Fairness need to be tested and measured using exploratory and automated
strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll cover some of the risks and biases that can happen
throughout the MLOps pipeline, demonstrate a few techniques to test a
model’s behaviors and fairness, and apply them against some real-world
scenarios and state-of-the-art models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end, you will have new ideas and techniques that you can use to
test your own ML/AI systems and approach these quality attributes from a
customer’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Carlos Kidman&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Italia 2022"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="testing"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing Machine Learning Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/testing-machine-learning-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Kidman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/testing-machine-learning-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As ML/AI systems are becoming more prevalent, the need for setting quality standards and testing practices has become crucial. Testing these models goes beyond validation metrics like accuracy, precision, and recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, quality attributes like model Behaviors, Usability, and Fairness need to be tested and measured using exploratory …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As ML/AI systems are becoming more prevalent, the need for setting quality standards and testing practices has become crucial. Testing these models goes beyond validation metrics like accuracy, precision, and recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, quality attributes like model Behaviors, Usability, and Fairness need to be tested and measured using exploratory and automated strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll cover some of the risks and biases that can happen throughout the MLOps pipeline, demonstrate a few techniques to test a model's behaviors and fairness, and apply them against some real-world scenarios and state-of-the-art models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end, you will have new ideas and techniques that you can use to test your own ML/AI systems and approach testing these quality attributes from a user's perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category></entry></feed>