<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alon-nir.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Getting an Edge with Network Analysis with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/getting-an-edge-with-network-analysis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alon Nir</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-15:pycon-uk-2018/getting-an-edge-with-network-analysis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Networks are all around us. While Facebook and Twitter are the obvious
examples, every time we shake hands, drive from point A to B, push code
to GitHub, check out a meetup or rate a show on IMDB, we’re
participating in network activity. People, places, things and even ideas
are inter-connected in innumerable networks, and these can have a great
(yet sometimes inconspicuous) impact on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to introduce members of the audience to
network analysis and its importance, and give them the basic building
blocks for applied network analysis with Python (using the friendly
NetworkX library). I hope this talk will encourage audience members to
consider network analysis approaches in their line of work/research and
intrigue them to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will weave theory and practice, discussing topics in graph
theory as we’re seeing them in practice during hands on analysis of a
real-life network. Topics covered include: types of graphs (undirected,
directed, multi and bipartite), structures in graphs (triangles,
cliques, connected components), node importance (centrality measures,
PageRank), graph topology and high-level graph descriptions. Practical
applications of these topics will be emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the limited time compared to the breadth of the topic, the focus
would lean towards intuitive understanding of concepts and seeing them
in practice, over deep theoretical formulations and hardcore
mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be given from a data scientist’s perspective with touches
of social sciences flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - Part 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Omer Sagi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-16:pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="5%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="18%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="77%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;00:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Omer Sagi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sugar cane yield Prediction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Amit Aronovitch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quick visualization tool for Analysis of Shadows cast by (actual physical) Clouds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;22:02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Feather format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;28:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gidi Shperber&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Modern recommendation engine in python with LightFM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;37:29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alon Nir&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pandas tips and tricks (Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alonnir/PyData-TLV-Talk"&gt;https://github.com/alonnir/PyData-TLV-Talk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry></feed>