<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Dvir Dukhan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Pattern: Machine Learning Natural Language Processing meets VR/AR</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/the-pattern-machine-learning-natural-language-processing-meets-vrar.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pattern: Machine Learning Natural Language Processing meets VR/AR
[EuroPython 2021 - Interactive session - 2021-07-28 - Argument-Clinic [Interactive]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alexander Mikhalev, Dvir Dukhan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open-source project &amp;quot;The Pattern&amp;quot; is the platform to inspire collaboration for building modern natural language processing tools and techniques and making them practically useful for end-users. In this session, I will walk through creating 3 Machine Learning NLP pipelines and deploying them using Redis and Redis Modules: RedisGears, RedisGraph and RedisAI.
The first pipeline demonstrates how to use traditional NLP techniques, such as the Aho-Corasic algorithm to build a knowledge graph from medical literature using a medical thesaurus (UMLS).
The second pipeline demonstrates how to build and deploy BERT Question/Answering model and create API for text to speech interface. Leveraging Redis Cluster sharding and capturing Redis Gears &amp;quot;keymiss&amp;quot; event to trigger processing of BERT QA in RedisAI.
The third pipeline demonstrates how to deploy Google's T5 (text to text transfer transformers) to build summary of each article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Mikhalev</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/the-pattern-machine-learning-natural-language-processing-meets-vrar.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item></channel></rss>