<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kelley-robinson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>A Tale of Two Factors: A Deep Dive into Two Factor Authentication</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/a-tale-of-two-factors-a-deep-dive-into-two-factor-authentication.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kelley Robinson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-05:pygotham-2019/a-tale-of-two-factors-a-deep-dive-into-two-factor-authentication.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us as we explore the modern landscape of Two Factor Authentication
(2FA). This talk will discuss the history of authentication, why 2FA is a
necessary security layer, and introduce the different types of factors
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll dive into a detailed comparison of methods like SMS, Soft Tokens, Push
Authentication, and YubiKeys. From cryptographic security strength to user
experience, we will break down the benefits and downsides for the different
methods and provide guidance for choosing the right methods for your
business. Finally, the session will walk through example Python code for
implementing time-based one time passcodes (Soft Tokens) like you see in
apps like Google Authenticator, Authy, or Duo.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>2FA, WTF</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/2fa-wtf.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kelley Robinson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-04:north-bay-python-2018/2fa-wtf.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may recognize Two-factor Authentication (2FA) as an additional
safeguard for protecting accounts, but do you really know how it works?
This talk will show you how to implement One Time Passwords (including
what's happening under the hood of those expiring tokens). You'll learn
the different approaches to implementing 2FA and have a better
understanding of what's right for your application.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>2FA, WTF?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/2fa-wtf.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kelley Robinson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/2fa-wtf.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Practical Cryptography</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/practical-cryptography.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kelley Robinson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-05:pygotham-2018/practical-cryptography.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From TLS to authentication, &amp;quot;crypto&amp;quot; is used for a lot more than just currencies. In 2018 security should be part of every engineer's toolkit and cryptography is a foundation we can master together. This talk will dive into modern cryptography, the math behind how it works, and its everyday use cases. By looking at the origins of cryptography we'll follow the progression of methods and algorithms as humans and computers evolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll leave understanding the difference between symmetric and asymmetric cryptography, why you would have a public and private key, and how those get used in a variety of applications. We'll look at how to encrypt and decrypt data using Python's &lt;cite&gt;cryptography&lt;/cite&gt; library and discuss the reasons you should never roll your own crypto. This will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be a talk about bitcoin, but will dive into how cryptography helps secure anonymous transactions and keeps your identity and data safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>