<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>TelApy a Python module to compute free surface flows and sediments transport in geosciences</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/telapy-a-python-module-to-compute-free-surface-flows-and-sediments-transport-in-geosciences.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is focused on the application of TelApy module
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opentelemac.org"&gt;www.opentelemac.org&lt;/a&gt;). TelApy aims to
provide a Python wrapper of TELEMAC-MASCARET API (Application Program
Interface). The goal of TelApy is to have a full control on the
simulation while running a case. For example, it must allow the user to
stop the simulation at any time step, get values of some variables and
change them. In order to make this possible, a Fortran structure called
instantiation was developed with the API. It contains a list of strings
pointing to TELEMAC variables. This gives direct access to the physical
memory of variables, and allows therefore to get and set their values.
Furthermore, changes have been made in TELEMAC-MASCARET main subroutines
to make hydraulic cases execution possible time step by time step. It is
useful to drive the TELEMAC-MASCARET SYSTEM APIs using Python
programming language. In fact, Python is a portable, dynamic,
extensible, free language, which allows (without imposing) a modular
approach and object oriented programming. In addition of benefits of
this programming language, Python offers a large amounts of
interoperable libraries. The link between various interoperable
libraries with TELEMAC-MASCARET SYSTEM APIs allows the creation of an
ever more efficient computing chain able to more finely respond to
various complex problems. Therefore, the TelApy module has the ambition
to enable a new way of use for the TELEMAC-MASCARET system. In
particular one can think about high performance computing for the
calculation of uncertainties, optimization, code coupling and so on. The
objectives of this talk is to present some examples of the TelApy module
in the case of Uncertainty Quantification, Optimization, Reduced Order
Model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TelApy a Python module to compute free surface flows and sediments
transport in geosciences and examples of how it is used to inter-operate
with other Python libraries for Uncertainty Quantification,
Optimization, Reduced Order Model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yoann Audouin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/telapy-a-python-module-to-compute-free-surface-flows-and-sediments-transport-in-geosciences.html</guid></item></channel></rss>