<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tim-grossmann.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>About going Open-Source</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/about-going-open-source.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Großmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/about-going-open-source.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will start of talking about why &amp;quot;working for free&amp;quot; became an important
part of the developer culture all around the world and talk about why
companies should try to share as many tools as possible. I'll give some
examples of tools that were open sourced and got immense traction
leading to the projects growing with an intense speed. I'll try to take
away the &amp;quot;fear&amp;quot; of open sourcing tools that cost ten of thousands of
dollars to create. Then I'll describe how my journey with open source
looks like and start talking about how you can get your feet into
contributing to known projects. After that I will close off with some
hints on doing and contributing to open source projects that worked out
great for me. They will also get an impression on what opportunities
will show up if they put some of their time into doing OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience can be mixed, but it's way more interesting for people that
are either new to programming or have never worked with open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, some of the listeners would leave the presentation
with the motivation and hard goal to start with OS as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Business &amp; Start-Ups"></category></entry><entry><title>Automating Instagram with Python and Selenium</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/automating-instagram-with-python-and-selenium.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Großmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/automating-instagram-with-python-and-selenium.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk about using Selenium and Python for social media
automation you will get some insights into growing your own open
source projects into tools that really get used and maintained by a
community. You will get an idea of what pitfalls you have to face
when working with something as fast changing as Instagram and how to
best tackle this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll  learn what the &amp;quot;Page Object&amp;quot; design pattern is, what it is
useful for and why we use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course we will also talk about OpenSource and why it's important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the talk will be based on my article on InstaPy published at
the freeCodeCamp publication on Medium:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.freecodecamp.com/my-open-source-instagram-bot-got-me-2-500-real-followers-for-5-in-server-costs-e40491358340"&gt;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/my-open-source-instagram-bot-got-me-2-500-real-followers-for-5-in-server-costs-e40491358340&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, who is this talk suited for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're just starting out with python, are interested in automation
or simply like to see a fun and interesting little open source
project, I'd love to see you at my talk and hear your ideas and
opinions about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>