<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jothir Adithyan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Time Made Easy: Simplify Date and Time Handling with Python's Pendulum</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2B on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pendulum is a Python package for working with dates, times, and timezones. It offers a simple and intuitive API for common date/time operations and provides advanced functionality for dealing with more complex scenarios. Some of the interesting points of Pendulum include support for leap years, time zones, and daylight saving time, as well as a fluent API for creating and modifying dates and times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Pendulum is its support for time zones. The library comes with a comprehensive list of time zones, and it can automatically adjust dates and times to the local time zone of a given location. Additionally, Pendulum can handle time zone conversions with ease, making it easy to work with date/time data across different time zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pendulum also provides a powerful API for creating and modifying dates and times. With its fluent interface, developers can create and manipulate dates and times using a natural, human-readable syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abhinand C</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Tackling Thread Safety in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/tackling-thread-safety-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tackling Thread Safety in Python by Jothir Adithyan, Adarsh Divakaran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/tackling-thread-safety-in-python"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/tackling-thread-safety-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thread safety is often overlooked when we start with Python for developing simple scripts. But the hidden monster will be unleashed when we try to run non-thread safe code in a multithreaded setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss the problems which can happen when seemingly good code is run in a multithreaded environment. We will walk over the concept of race coditions, how Python’s GIL currently affects multithreading and will cover steps to fix thread unsafe code using synchronization primitives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jothir Adithyan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/tackling-thread-safety-in-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>