<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Stand Back!: Building a scientific computing lab on public clouds with Pytho</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stand Back!: Building a scientific computing lab on public clouds with Pytho</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2022/stand-back-building-a-scientific-computing-lab-on-public-clouds-with-pytho.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a citizen scientist, you want to learn more, but you’re hitting the limits of your computer. In this live demo, we’ll use Python to build a data lab on a public cloud. We’ll use that infrastructure to explore public data, and we’ll learn a bit more about “the cloud” along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Laura Santamaria
As a Developer Advocate at Pulumi, Laura Santamaria loves to learn and explain how things work, bridging the gaps in engineering disciplines. She is a cohost for The Hallway Track podcast, an organizer for DevOpsDays Texas and DevOpsDays Austin, and a co-host for Cloud Austin and Austin DevOps. Previously, Laura worked as a developer advocate at LogDNA and a software developer at Rackspace where, among other things, she owned Deconst, an open-source documentation delivery platform, and MC’ed Rackspace’s internal technical conference. Apart from work, she taught Python for Women Who Code Austin for many years and has been a returning program committee member for Open Source Summit. Outside of tech, Laura runs, plays with her dogs, throws discs, and watches clouds—the real kind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stand Back!: Building a scientific computing lab on public clouds with Pytho</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-21:/pytexas-2022/stand-back-building-a-scientific-computing-lab-on-public-clouds-with-pytho.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2022</category></item></channel></rss>