<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ben-nuttall.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Astro Pi: Python on the International Space Station</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/astro-pi-python-on-the-international-space-station.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-13:pycon-uk-2019/astro-pi-python-on-the-international-space-station.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and the European Space Agency put two Raspberry Pi computers augmented with sensor boards and camera modules on the International Space Station in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Astro Pi: Python on the International Space Station</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/astro-pi-python-on-the-international-space-station.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/astro-pi-python-on-the-international-space-station.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and the European
Space Agency put two Raspberry Pi computers augmented with sensor boards
and camera modules on the International Space Station in 2015. Every
year we run a series of competitions for kids in schools around Europe
to design science experiments using the available sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission Zero is a low-barrier challenge where students can run a 1
minute Python program in space to display a message to the astronauts.
They have access to the sensors for conditional logic but cannot record
data or take photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission Space Lab is a more involved challenge, including planning an
experiment, writing and testing code which will run for 3 hours in
space, either studying life in space or life on earth (which includes
taking photos of Earth out of the ISS window). MSL teams get to keep the
data and photo they record in their experiment and are to write a report
analysing their findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small tech team at the Raspberry Pi Foundation maintain the operating
system used in flight and work in collaboration with ESA and partners to
keep the operation of the Pis running smoothly on the ISS LAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as sharing details of the OS maintenance and devops for the
Astro Pis, I'll share photos taken from space and show findings from
student experiments using opencv, tensorflow, scikit-learn, ephem and
more.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Data"></category><category term="Education"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="OpenCV"></category><category term="Raspberry PI"></category></entry><entry><title>Programming paradigms for physical computing and IoT</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/programming-paradigms-for-physical-computing-and-iot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-18:pycon-uk-2018/programming-paradigms-for-physical-computing-and-iot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A look at the GPIO Zero library for Raspberry Pi yields the blueprint
for a Pythonic API for programming the behaviour of interconnected
devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;GPIO Zero provides a multi-paradigm programming interface to GPIO
devices:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- procedural (polling)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- procedural (blocking)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- event-driven (callbacks)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- declarative&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with simple scripts to control LEDs and buttons on a breadboard,
learn to prototype ideas and move on to declaring interaction between
more advanced devices in the home and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These options for device programming, along with the extensibility of
the library, provide the means to program complex behaviour using simple
Pythonic code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Programming paradigms for physical computing and IoT</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/programming-paradigms-for-physical-computing-and-iot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/programming-paradigms-for-physical-computing-and-iot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A look at the GPIO Zero library for Raspberry Pi yields the blueprint
for a Pythonic API for programming the behaviour of interconnected
devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPIO Zero provides a multi-paradigm programming interface to GPIO
devices: - procedural (polling) - procedural (blocking) - event-driven
(callbacks) - declarative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with simple scripts to control LEDs and buttons on a breadboard,
learn to prototype ideas and move on to declaring interaction between
more advanced devices in the home and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These options for device programming, along with the extensibility of
the library, provide the means to program complex behaviour using simple
Pythonic code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>piwheels: a faster Python package repository for RaspberryPi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/piwheels-a-faster-python-package-repository-for-raspberrypi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-29T16:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-29T16:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/piwheels-a-faster-python-package-repository-for-raspberrypi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;piwheels is a Python package repository providing Python wheels natively compiled for the Raspberry Pi's ARM architecture. It solves the problem that &amp;quot;pip install&amp;quot; can take a long time to build packages implemented in C. Wheels are a general solution to this problem, but PyPI does not currently allow maintainers to upload ARM platform wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote some tooling for automating the building of all 115,000+ packages on PyPI, including all version releases, which totals up to over 750,000 package builds, monitoring the build status and logging the output.in a database, and providing the wheels in a pip-compatible web server. Raspberry Pi users can now &amp;quot;pip install&amp;quot; from this server (a Raspberry Pi) and get pre-built Python wheels, which take just seconds to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first build run I completed was on a Raspberry Pi in my living room: I built the latest version of every package (110k). Then, in order to build all versions of all packages (750k), I moved the project to a cluster of 20 Raspberry Pis in a data centre.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="piwheels"></category></entry><entry><title>Physical computing with Raspberry Pi and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/physical-computing-with-raspberry-pi-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:europython-2017/physical-computing-with-raspberry-pi-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi Foundation is working to put the power of digital
making in the hands of people all over the world, and is well known
for its series of small, cheap single board computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi runs a well supported Linux distro based on Debian,
which ships with a variety of programming tools and educational
software. Python is the main supported language on the platform, used
in many educational resources, and many Python libraries exist for
making the most of the Pi platform with other devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi Foundation mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi hardware specs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspbian desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPIO pins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPIO Zero (Python library)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picamera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astro Pi (ESA space mission) &amp;amp; Sense HAT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More HATs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pi projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2017-07-13</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vitalii Vokhmin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:europython-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks
EuroPython 2017 - 2017-07-13 - Anfiteatro 2&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Python and Raspberry PiPhysical computing, GPIO, HATs and IoT with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/fosdem-2017/python-and-raspberry-piphysical-computing-gpio-hats-and-iot-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-05:fosdem-2017/python-and-raspberry-piphysical-computing-gpio-hats-and-iot-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing Python developers to the world of physical computing and IoT using Python on the Raspberry Pi.There's great fun to be had using the Pi's GPIO pins to connect with the real world for home automation and IoT projects. Python libraries like GPIO Zero, Picamera and Sense HAT provide a simple interface to GPIO devices, HATs and more.I will demonstrate the possibilities and show the power of Python in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Physical computing with Python and Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2016/physical-computing-with-python-and-raspberry-pi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-04:pycon-russia-2016/physical-computing-with-python-and-raspberry-pi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi Foundation is a UK charity which creates low-cost, high-performance computers that people use to learn, solve problems and have fun. Through our educational programmes we work to put the power of digital making into the hands of people all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Python on the Raspberry Pi, it's easy to start creating physical computing projects, and to experiment and tinker with add-ons and accessories from lights and buzzers to environmental sensors and robotics. This ease of access was accelerated with the creation of a new minimal boilerplate library called GPIO Zero, of which I am the primary author. In this talk I'll talk about the Foundation's work in education, share some great Pi projects, give a taster of how to get started in physical computing and dive into the technical innards of the GPIO Zero library. As well as a learning tool, the Pi is commonly used in home automation projects and industrial applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyPi (not that one) - Python on the RaspberryPi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2014/pypi-not-that-one-python-on-the-raspberrypi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-20:pycon-uk-2014/pypi-not-that-one-python-on-the-raspberrypi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presented by: Ben Nuttall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting Python projects on Raspberry Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Projects on the Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2015/python-projects-on-the-raspberry-pi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-18:pycon-uk-2015/python-projects-on-the-raspberry-pi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is the most popular language in the Raspberry Pi community. Also
with the Raspberry Pi, it's easy to do physical computing directly from
Python code - rather than usual embedded hardware engineering in C or
Assembler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’ll show examples of computing projects that use Python on
the Raspberry Pi and demonstrate the sort of code used in such projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be an informative session with learning possibilities to give
those new to Python on the Raspberry Pi a chance to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Nuttall is the Education Developer Advocate at the Raspberry Pi
Foundation in Cambridge, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Physical computing with Python and Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/physical-computing-with-python-and-raspberry-pi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-07:europython-2015/physical-computing-with-python-and-raspberry-pi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ben Nuttall - Physical computing with Python and Raspberry Pi
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
[Education Summit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Raspberry Pi, it's easy to do physical computing directly
from Python code - rather than usual embedded hardware engineering in
C or Assembler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll show examples of physical computing projects that
use Python on Raspberry Pi and demonstrate the sort of code  used in
such projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical computing with Python is very popular in education - as it's
so engaging, and more interesting than printing to the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be an informative session with learning possibilities to
give those new to physical computing a change to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Pioneering the Future of Computing Education</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/pioneering-the-future-of-computing-education.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/pioneering-the-future-of-computing-education.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How the Raspberry Pi Foundation are leading the way in the computing in
schools revolution by providing affordable open and connectable hardware
to people of all levels of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have an education team, we're pushing forward with creating
resources and training teachers to help deliver modern computing
education around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All our learning resources are Creative Commons licensed and available
on GitHub. We write materials that match the UK computing curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm Ben, from Raspberry Pi. I do development and outreach for the
Foundation and I work with the rest of the education team to help make
learning through computer science, coding and hardware hacking more
accessible to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I explain the Raspberry Pi story: its mission - the reason
the Pi exists; what happened before release - getting the board in to
production; what happened in the first two years - the community birth
and growth; and what's coming next - education focus, new hardware and
improved software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is the main language used (and advocated by us) in education with
Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're creating learning resources to match up with the new UK computing
curriculum, where we teach young people programming and computer science
concepts with Python on Pi, and help teachers deliver quality material
in the classroom to work towards the objectives the curriculum sets out
to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Raspberry Pi we open up possibilities for connecting to the real
world in an accessible way using the powerful, high level and human
read/write -able language of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We work closely with the community: hobbyists organising Raspberry Jam
events; educators teaching with Raspberry Pi; the software communities
and their contributions - and we welcome any interested parties to get
involved with helping us provide for the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Python Programming in Science Education</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2014/keynote-python-programming-in-science-education.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-22:euroscipy-2014/keynote-python-programming-in-science-education.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>