<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Andrey Lushnikov &amp; Max Schmitt</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andrey-lushnikov-max-schmitt.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Playwright Comes to Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/playwright-comes-to-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrey Lushnikov &amp; Max Schmitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/playwright-comes-to-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Andrey Lushnikov. I’m a Principal Engineer at Microsoft, former Chrome DevTools engineer and Chrome Puppeteer technical lead with over 11 years of experience in software engineering. Today, I’m a member of the Playwright core team. Playwright was first released in 2020 and has …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Andrey Lushnikov. I’m a Principal Engineer at Microsoft, former Chrome DevTools engineer and Chrome Puppeteer technical lead with over 11 years of experience in software engineering. Today, I’m a member of the Playwright core team. Playwright was first released in 2020 and has been dominating JavaScript cross-browser testing ever since. Now, Playwright comes to Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome, Firefox &amp;amp; Safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows, Linux &amp;amp; MacOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unmatched functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beautiful built-in tooling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free &amp;amp; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too good? Come see yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll spend an imaginary month with Playwright for Python. On day 1, we’ll set up reliable, cross-browser, end-to-end tests using Playwright for Python in less than 60 seconds. On day 3, we’ll learn how to easily author end-to-end tests using Playwright codegen feature. On day 7, we’ll debug our first test using Playwright Inspector. On day 30, we’ll use Playwright Tracing to analyze a test that fails exclusively on CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, we’ll also learn about the framework’s unique APIs and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the journey, you’ll be comfortable to start using Playwright for Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>