<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jason Mancuso</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The ChatGPT Privacy Tango: Dancing with Data Security and Large Language Models (Sponsor: Cape Privacy)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/the-chatgpt-privacy-tango-dancing-with-data-security-and-large-language-models-sponsor-cape-privacy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the world of AI and natural language processing, privacy and utility
often find themselves engaged in a delicate dance. As users attempt to
leverage the power of Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT for
sensitive or confidential data, they face the challenge of maintaining
privacy without compromising the value these models bring. Enter the
&amp;quot;ChatGPT Privacy Tango&amp;quot; – a metaphor for the intricate steps needed to
balance these competing interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk, we'll delve into a system we've designed to help users
navigate the Privacy Tango, striking a balance between preserving
privacy and maximizing utility with ChatGPT and LLMs. We'll discuss the
significance of protecting personally identifiable information (PII) and
maintaining data security while still enjoying the advantages of
AI-powered language models. Additionally, we'll cover the pros and cons
of this approach and touch on alternative systems that we've considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you to join us as we explore the fascinating interplay of data
privacy, secure enclaves, and PII removal, shedding light on the path
towards more privacy-aware applications with Large Language Models. By
the end of our session, you'll be better prepared to dance the ChatGPT
Privacy Tango, armed with the knowledge and tools needed to safeguard
sensitive information while harnessing the power of ChatGPT and LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Mancuso</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/the-chatgpt-privacy-tango-dancing-with-data-security-and-large-language-models-sponsor-cape-privacy.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>