<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sanket Singh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sanket-singh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>When gRPC met Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/when-grpc-met-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sanket Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/when-grpc-met-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - When gRPC met Python - presented by Sanket Singh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gRPC is one of the most new breakthroughs in the world of client server interaction. Using gRPC our client can directly make a call to a server on a different machine as if it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - When gRPC met Python - presented by Sanket Singh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gRPC is one of the most new breakthroughs in the world of client server interaction. Using gRPC our client can directly make a call to a server on a different machine as if it were a local object. gRPC has low latency, high scalability and supports multiple use cases for distributed system. We can even build mobile clients which can communicate to a cloud server. gRPC uses Protocol Buffers which is an open source mechanism for serializing structured data, which makes payloads faster, smaller and simpler. In this talk we will try to understand how can we get started with gRPC in Python. grpcio package of python will be used for the demonstration of the examples and we will cover basics of gRPC as well. We will build a basic gRPC service and define protocol buffers for it. Demonstration of how a client and a server can be made through gRPC and how can they communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>When gRPC Met Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/when-grpc-met-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sanket Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/when-grpc-met-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When gRPC Met Python - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we can have a tool that helps us to do intelligent load
balancing or What if we can do selective compression of the data and
extremely fast and light weight transfer of data? Then let me introduce
gRPC, the technology …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When gRPC Met Python - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we can have a tool that helps us to do intelligent load
balancing or What if we can do selective compression of the data and
extremely fast and light weight transfer of data? Then let me introduce
gRPC, the technology that helps us to do all of this and how can we
integrate gRPC with Python. gRPC is one of the most new breakthroughs in
the world of client server interaction. Using gRPC our client can
directly make a call to a server on a different machine as if it were a
local object. gRPC has low latency, high scalability and supports
multiple use cases for distributed system. We can even build mobile
clients which can communicate to a cloud server. gRPC uses Protocol
Buffers which is an open source mechanism for serialising structured
data, which makes payloads faster, smaller and simpler. In this talk we
will try to understand how can we get started with gRPC in Python.
grpcio package of python will be used for the demonstration of the
examples and we will cover basics of gRPC as well. We will build a basic
gRPC service and define protocol buffers for it. Demonstration of how a
client and a server can be made through gRPC and how can they
communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sanket Singh&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Italia 2022"></category><category term="distributed systems"></category><category term="scaling"></category></entry></feed>