<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>nmrglue: a Python Module for Working with NMR Data.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/nmrglue-a-python-module-for-working-with-nmr-dat.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy is a key analytical
technique in the biomedical field, finding uses in drug discovery,
metabolomics, and imaging as well as being the primary method for the
determination of the structures of biological macromolecules in
solution. In the course of a modern NMR structural or dynamic study of
proteins and other biomolecules, experiments typically generate multiple
gigabytes of 2D, 3D and even 4D data sets which must be collected,
processed, analyzed, and visualized to extract useful information. The
field has developed a number of software products to perform these
functions, but few software suites exist that can perform all of the
tasks which a typical scientist requires. For example, it is not
uncommon for NMR data to be collected using software provided by the
spectrometer vendor, processed and visualized using software from the
NIH, and analyzed using software from a University, collaborator or
developed in house. Complicating this process is the lack of a standard
format for storing NMR data; each software program typically uses its
own format for data storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nmrglue is an open source Python module for working with NMR data which
acts as the &amp;quot;glue&amp;quot; to tie together existing NMR programs, and can be
used to rapidly develop new NMR processing, analysis or visualization
methods. With nmrglue, spectral data from a number of common NMR file
formats can be accessed as numpy arrays. This data can be sliced,
rearranged or modified as needed and written out to any of the supported
file formats for later use in existing NMR software programs. In this
way, nmrglue can act as the &amp;quot;glue&amp;quot; to tie together NMR workflows which
employ existing NMR software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, nmrglue can be used in conjunction with other scientific
python libraries to rapidly test, prototype, and develop new methods for
processing, analyzing, and visualizing NMR data. The nmrglue package
provides a number of common NMR processing functions, as well as
implementation of scientific routines which may be of interest to other
Python projects including peak pickers, multidimensional lineshape
fitting routines, linear prediction functions, and a bounded least
squares optimization. These functions together, with the ability to
read, write and convert between a number of common file formats, allow
developers to harness nmrglue for established routines while focusing on
the novel portion of the new method being created. In addition, the
numerical routines in numpy and scipy can be used to further speed this
process. If these packages are used with the Ipython shell and
matplotlib, a robust, interpreted environment for exploring and
visualizing NMR data can be created using only open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nmrglue is distributed under the New BSD license. Documentation,
tutorials, examples, and downloadable install files and source code are
available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/nmrglue/"&gt;http://code.google.com/p/nmrglue/&lt;/a&gt;. Despite a limited
exposure in the scientific field, nmrglue is already used in a number of
university research labs and portions of the package have been adapted
for use in VeSPA, a software suite for magnetic resonance spectroscopy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jonathan J. Helmus</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/nmrglue-a-python-module-for-working-with-nmr-dat.html</guid><category>Computational Bioinformatics</category></item></channel></rss>