<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 13:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A New Era in Python Governance</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/a-new-era-in-python-governance.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In July of 2018, Guido van Rossum stepped down as “Benevolent Dictator
for Life” of Python. In December, Python core developers voted on a new
governance structure to guide Python going forward. This talk explores
what’s changing and how it may impact the Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on analysis of the relevant PEPs and other documentation, and
strengthened via a series of interviews with core developers and other
community leaders, we’ll cover Python governance past, present and
future. Particular care will be taken to explain why the core developers
chose the governance model they did, what the new system entails, and
how community members can participate in it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shauna Gordon-McKeon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-us-2019/a-new-era-in-python-governance.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Beyond Django Basics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/beyond-django-basics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finished with the official Django getting started guide, and not sure what to do next?  This tutorial has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll extend the blog built in the official guide, using a variety of slightly more advanced Django features.  Topics to be covered include: extending the in-built user model, using the in-built login system, enhancing forms, using view mixins and overriding view methods, and changing up your database backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each extension, we'll talk about not just how to use these features but also &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you'd want to use them.  We'll conclude by talking about other Django features you may want to learn about as you grow more proficient with this versatile framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shauna Gordon-McKeon</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/beyond-django-basics.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Open Source for Newcomers and the People Who Want to Welcome Them</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/open-source-for-newcomers-and-the-people-who-want.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source can be fun and rewarding, but it can also be intimidating.
This talk addresses some of the biggest technical and psychological
barriers to contributing, from the perspective of both the newcomers who
want to overcome them and the maintainers who want to remove them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shauna Gordon-McKeon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-11:pycon-us-2015/open-source-for-newcomers-and-the-people-who-want.html</guid></item></channel></rss>