<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vyas-ramasubramani.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>freud: A Software Suite for High Throughput Analysis of Nanoscale Simulation Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/freud-a-software-suite-for-high-throughput-analysis-of-nanoscale-simulation-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bradley Dice</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/freud-a-software-suite-for-high-throughput-analysis-of-nanoscale-simulation-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improvements in high-performance particle-based computer simulations demand a commensurate increase in the performance of analysis codes. We address this need with freud, a Python library containing TBB-parallelized C++ routines for various analysis techniques. All inputs and outputs are NumPy arrays, enabling integration with the scientific Python ecosystem. In addition to standard analyses used in molecular simulation, freud implements novel methods for tasks such as characterizing local order. Used in conjunction with simulation software like HOOMD-blue, freud can dynamically analyze simulations on-the-fly, allowing users to study phase transition kinetics and other complex phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>signac: A Python Framework for Data and Workflow Management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/signac-a-python-framework-for-data-and-workflow-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vyas Ramasubramani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/signac-a-python-framework-for-data-and-workflow-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computational studies in physics, chemistry, and materials science are
frequently characterized by well-parameterized but constantly evolving
data schemas. Poor management of these dynamic schemas can significantly
impede computational research. Our talk showcases the signac framework,
an open- source Python package designed for simple data and workflow
management, particularly in high performance computing environments. The
framework's flexible data model allows easy adaptation into pre-existing
file-based workflows while also providing critical database
functionality such as filtering, searching, and grouping data. signac
also provides tools to develop complex workflows operating on its data
spaces, enabling the simple, efficient, and reproducible execution of
computational studies.Presenter(s): Speaker: Vyas Ramasubramani,
University of Michigan Author: Carl Adorf, University of Michigan
Author: Paul M. Dodd, University of Michigan Author: Bradley Dice,
University of Michigan Author: Sharon C. Glotzer, University of Michigan&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>