<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aaron-iles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Command line programs for busy developers by Aaron Iles</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/command-line-programs-for-busy-developers-by-aaro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Iles</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-07:pycon-au-2014/command-line-programs-for-busy-developers-by-aaro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Command line interface tools are the new web framework. In addition to
the Python standard library's getopt, optparse and argparse there is a
bewildering array of packages available on the Python Packaging Index.
Packages like Click, Cliff, Docopt, Invoke all provide different
mechanics for creating command line applications. When all you want to
do is expose a command line and get back to creating functionality, it’s
hard to know which alternative to reach for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will have two parts, the first half will be a brief
survey of popular modules. Strengths, weaknesses and design philosophies
will be compared by creating command line processing for the same
example program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half will go into more depth on a specific package, Begins.
This package was authored by the presenter to minimise the disruption
developers experience when breaking flow to implement command line
processing. The audience will be shown how a single line of code can
create a complex command line interface. It will also be shown how a
handful of decorators from the Begins API can eliminate boilerplate code
and create powerful, complex applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>