<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Margaret Fero</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_margaret-fero.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>What Not To Document And Why</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2024/what-not-to-document-and-why.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Margaret Fero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-29:/north-bay-python-2024/what-not-to-document-and-why.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re hopefully all on board with writing documentation for our projects. However, especially with the rise of supply-chain attacks, there are some aspects of our projects that we really shouldn’t document, and should instead remediate as vulnerabilities. If we do document these aspects of a project, it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re hopefully all on board with writing documentation for our projects. However, especially with the rise of supply-chain attacks, there are some aspects of our projects that we really shouldn’t document, and should instead remediate as vulnerabilities. If we do document these aspects of a project, it may help someone compromise the project itself or our users. In this talk, you will learn why some aspects of documentation may help attackers more than users, how to recognize those aspects in your own projects, and what to do when you encounter such an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="North Bay Python 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Key Security Considerations for Publishing Your First Mobile App with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2025/key-security-considerations-for-publishing-your-first-mobile-app-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Margaret Fero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-27:/north-bay-python-2025/key-security-considerations-for-publishing-your-first-mobile-app-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Margaret Fero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/RXNUR7"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/RXNUR7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you already have a successful app you’re thinking of packaging for mobile for the first time, or maybe you’re going from concept to native app. Either way, there are a handful of security and privacy considerations to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Margaret Fero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/RXNUR7"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/RXNUR7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you already have a successful app you’re thinking of packaging for mobile for the first time, or maybe you’re going from concept to native app. Either way, there are a handful of security and privacy considerations to keep in mind for both your and your users’ safety as you package applications for Android and iOS. In this talk, we’ll go over some key considerations for iOS, for Android, and shared by both major US app stores. After this talk, you’ll have a straightforward checklist to cover the most important security and privacy aspects of app packaging and distribution so you can focus on the fun parts of your app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Apr 27 14:15:00 2025 at Reis River Ranch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="North Bay Python 2025"></category></entry></feed>