<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Martina Ivanicova</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Don't fix bad data, do this instead</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/dont-fix-bad-data-do-this-instead.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — North Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't fix bad data, do this instead by Martina Ivanicova&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/don-t-fix-bad-data-do-this-instead"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/don-t-fix-bad-data-do-this-instead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a time where GenAI is quickly growing in popularity, along with prescriptive analytics and online ML models, the question is raised whether we still need to care about data quality? We strongly believe that the answer is yes, and even more so than before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our expectations of data are high, and this often leads to frustrations when reality does not meet these expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pursuit of data quality, expectations must be grounded in reality. It is often the case that a gap exists between anticipated outcomes and the actual data reality, which leads to frustration and mistrust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk delves into pragmatic strategies that can be employed to bridge this gap.  The talk  will discuss both the technical  (hard) and cultural  (soft) measures implemented to uphold these standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration tests serve as a proactive barrier, preempting the violation of data contracts, unlike reactive data quality checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritisation is crucial; a product-centric mindset is key when evaluating the balance between resource investment and potential gain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data quality management is requiring both hard and soft measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a data scientist, software engineer, product manager, or data engineer? Join us in this discussion; data quality concerns us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martina Ivanicova</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/dont-fix-bad-data-do-this-instead.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>