<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building real time applications with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/building-real-time-applications-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of Channels, real time web has become much easier
to work with in Django. It’s now possible to build real time
applications with much less effort in managing the idiosyncrasies of the
async programming and a lot of batteries are included. Starting with a
brief introduction to Channels, we will see how to build a real time
application, both on the Django and the frontend side and how easy it’s
to start experimenting with it. The talk has a very hands-on approach,
to allow the attendees to experiment with the proposed solution and
approach and starting immediately building their own real time
applications with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/building-real-time-applications-with-django.html</guid><category>web</category><category>javascript</category><category>websockets</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Building real time applications with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/building-real-time-applications-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of Channels, real time web has become much easier to work with in Django: discover how you can easily create yours with Django!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of Channels, real time web has become much easier to work with in Django. It’s now possible to build real time applications with much less effort in managing the idiosyncrasies of the async programming and a lot of batteries are included. Starting with a brief introduction to Channels (targeting version 2.0), we will see how to build a real time application, both on the Django and the frontend side and how easy it’s to start experimenting with it. The talk has a very hands-on approach, to allow the attendees to experiment with the proposed solution and approach, and starting immediately building their own real time applications with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iacopo Spalletti&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-23:djangocon-europe-2018/building-real-time-applications-with-django.html</guid></item><item><title>Real Time Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/swiss-python-summit-2018/real-time-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of Channels, real time web has become much easier to work with in Django. It’s now possible to build real time applications with much less effort in managing the idiosyncrasies of the async programming and a lot of batteries are included. Starting with a brief introduction to Channels, we will see how to build a real time application, both on the Django and the frontend side and how easy it’s to start experimenting with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-16:swiss-python-summit-2018/real-time-django.html</guid></item><item><title>L'Italia, Python e la chimera dell'Agile</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/litalia-python-e-la-chimera-dellagile.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sono quasi certo che il proverbio “tra il dire e il fare c’è di mezzo
il mare” lo abbiano inventato pensando alle metodologie agili. Forse
in USA o in Svezia ci riescono davvero, ma in Italia? Possiamo dire
di essere agili quando di test ne facciamo “ un po’ “, i task degli
sprint li decide il cliente e il contratto prevede un budget fissato
e una deadline prestabilita? E com’è la situazione tra i pythonisti?
Ne parliamo con Marco Beri, Iacopo Spalletti, Roberto Bettazzoni e
Peter Bittner in un panel dove siete tutti invitati a partecipare e
condividere casi di successo e scheletri nell’armadio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/litalia-python-e-la-chimera-dellagile.html</guid></item><item><title>Closing ceremony</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/closing-ceremony.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Closing remarks thanks to everyone&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/closing-ceremony.html</guid></item><item><title>Testing applications for django CMS</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2015/testing-applications-for-django-cms.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing applications integrated with django CMS can be complex with a
lot of boilerplate code and some dark corners This talk will try to make
it clearer and easier to write tests and will present tools to reduce
the effort and the boilerplate&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-20:pycon-uk-2015/testing-applications-for-django-cms.html</guid></item><item><title>Django CMS in the real time web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/django-cms-in-the-real-time-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django CMS in the real time web: how to mix CMS, websockets, REST for a fully real time experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lacopo Spalletti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CMS websites are usually kind of boring: get a request, pick data from storage, stamp them on a template and return to the client. This is less and less suitable for the current web experience, and more advanced and flexible architecture are needed: what if we mix the best CMS for Django with the real time web technologies? We'll end up with the best of both worlds: this talk will show how to use a few applications and techniques to achieve this goal. I'll show how to integrate django CMS with django channels, a REST API and an Angular JS client in a fully featured SPA managed by django CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pycon-uk-2016/django-cms-in-the-real-time-web.html</guid></item><item><title>CMS Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/iacopo-spalletti-tom-dyson-daniele-procida-cms-at.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-31:djangocon-europe-2015/iacopo-spalletti-tom-dyson-daniele-procida-cms-at.html</guid></item><item><title>DjangoBeer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/iacopo-spalletti-djangobeer-at-djangocon-europe.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-24:djangocon-europe-2015/iacopo-spalletti-djangobeer-at-djangocon-europe.html</guid></item><item><title>DjangoCMS Best Practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/djangocms-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ci sono almeno tre feature di django 1.8 / 1.9 che mi entusiasmano. Non
sono sono i template multipli o la possibilità di utilizzare i campi
specializzati di postgres. Qualcuna di esse magari non finirà nemmeno
nelle release notes. Ad alcune di esse ho collaborato direttamente e
descriverò la mia esperienza nel contribuire a Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-09:pycon-italia-2015/djangocms-best-practices.html</guid></item></channel></rss>