<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tom Mock</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Github Copilot integration with RStudio, it's finally here!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/github-copilot-integration-with-rstudio-its-finally-here.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk closes issue #10148, &amp;quot;Github Copilot integration with RStudio&amp;quot;, the most upvoted feature request in RStudio's history. Code generating AI tools like Github Copilot‚ promise an &amp;quot;AI pair programmer that offers autocomplete-style suggestions as you code&amp;quot;. For the first time, we'll show a native integration of Copilot into RStudio, helping to build on that promise by providing AI-generated &amp;quot;ghost text&amp;quot; autocompletion with R and other languages. I'll also provide a comparison of Copilot's &amp;quot;ghost text&amp;quot; to a chat-style interface in RStudio via the {chattr} package from the Posit MLVerse team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the most of these new features, I'll walk through some examples of how sharing additional context, comments, code, and other &amp;quot;prompt engineering&amp;quot; can help you go from code-generating AI tools that feels like an annoying backseat driver to an experienced copilot. We'll close with a robust end-to-end example of how these new RStudio integrations and packages can help you be a more productive developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Mock</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/github-copilot-integration-with-rstudio-its-finally-here.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Introducing Positron, a new data science IDE</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/introducing-positron-a-new-data-science-ide.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Positron is a next-generation data science IDE that is newly available to the community for early beta testing. This new IDE is an extensible tool built to facilitate exploratory data analysis, reproducible authoring, and publishing data artifacts. Positron currently supports these data workflows in either or both Python and R and is designed with a forward-looking architecture that can support other data science languages in the future. In this session, learn from the team-building Positron about how and why it is designed the way it is, what will feel familiar or new coming from other IDEs, and whether it might be a good fit for your own work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julia Silge</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/introducing-positron-a-new-data-science-ide.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>