<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_roberto-colistete-jr.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Scientific MicroPython on Microcontrollers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/scientific-micropython-on-microcontrollers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Colistete Jr</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-10:scipy-2018/scientific-micropython-on-microcontrollers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MicroPython (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://micropython.org/"&gt;http://micropython.org/&lt;/a&gt;) is a FOSS implementation of Python
3 optimised to run on microcontrollers with MHz and tens of Kbytes of
RAM. After a introduction about MicroPython, this tutorial will be a
interactive hands-on using microcontroller boards running MicroPython,
one for each attendee, practicing some scientific tools to process data
from sensor boards, then publish the sensor data on web server running
on the microcontroller or on IoT Cloud. The goal is to show MicroPython
and microcontrollers are also plataforms for scientific computing
applied to Physical Computing (sensors and actuators) and IoT (Internet
of Things). All hardware (microcontroller boards, sensor boards, jumper
cables) will be provided by the presenter. Please bring a micro USB
cable and a computer. Basic familiarity with Python 3 and terminal tools
is required.Presenter(s): Speaker: Roberto Colistete Jr, Federal
University of Espirito Santo, Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Scientific MicroPython on Microcontrollers and IoT</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/scientific-micropython-on-microcontrollers-and-iot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Colistete Jr</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:scipy-2017/scientific-micropython-on-microcontrollers-and-iot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MicroPython is a implementation of Python 3 optimised to run on a microcontroller with MHz and greater than= 10 Kbytes of RAM. But even with these hardware constraints, scientific MicroPython is already available and practical. I will present MicroPython from the perspective of users and developers, demonstrating scientific usage of MicroPython on some boards connected to sensors and Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>