<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Heiner Tholen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_heiner-tholen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A concrete guide to time-series databases with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/a-concrete-guide-to-time-series-databases-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Heiner Tholen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/a-concrete-guide-to-time-series-databases-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We evaluated time-series databases and complementary services to stream-process sensor data. In this talk, our evaluation will be presented. The final implementation will be shown, alongside python-tools we've built and lessons learned during the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding time-series data is essential to handle automatically generated data, be it from server …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We evaluated time-series databases and complementary services to stream-process sensor data. In this talk, our evaluation will be presented. The final implementation will be shown, alongside python-tools we've built and lessons learned during the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding time-series data is essential to handle automatically generated data, be it from server logs, IoT devices or any other continuous measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to handle the large amounts of incoming data from concrete mixing trucks, we evaluated a number of time-series databases as well as services to stream-process the data. For all of those decisions a key question was, of course, how well any of these tools integrate with our existing, all-Python backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right angle on time-series data will help you move tons of data with little engineering effort. In this talk, you'll learn from our practical experiences of choosing and implementing a time-series database in a Python context. You'll go away with a better understanding of how you can efficiently store, analyse and exploit streaming data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category><category term="Time Series"></category></entry></feed>