<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vm-vicky-brasseur.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The human nature of failure &amp; resiliency</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/the-human-nature-of-failure-resiliency.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>VM (Vicky) Brasseur</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/the-human-nature-of-failure-resiliency.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Projects fail in droves. Systems hiccup and hours of downtime follows. Screws fall out all the time; the world is an imperfect place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talk a lot about building resilient systems, but all systems are (at least for now) built by humans. Humans who have been making the same types of mistakes for thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because failure happens doesn’t mean we can’t do our best to prevent it or—at the very least—to minimize the damage when it does. As a matter of fact, embracing failure can be one of the best things you do for your system. Failure is a vital part of evolution. By learning to love failure we learn how to take the next step forward. Ignoring or punishing failure leads to stagnation and wasted potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk distills 3000 pages of failure research into 40 minutes of knowledge about the human factors of failure, how it can be recognised, and how you can work around it to create more resilient systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk the audience will have an awareness of the most common psychological reasons for mistakes and failures and how to develop systems and processes to protect against them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="failure"></category><category term="resiliency"></category></entry><entry><title>Passing the Baton: Succession planning for your project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/passing-the-baton-succession-planning-for-your-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>VM (Vicky) Brasseur</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-06:pycon-au-2017/passing-the-baton-succession-planning-for-your-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While sharing of and collaborating on software has been around as long as there's been code, the open source concept and movement only came into being in the late 1990s. There are many who remember a time before open source. Of those, most helped to shape the philosophy, laws, governance, and policies which are the foundation of the free and open source movement we enjoy today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what happens when these people decide to retire? Who will carry the baton and lead the movement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully these people are still with us, helping to craft and lead FOSS, but there are very few younger individuals among their ranks. As we look at the next horizon for FOSS, we must consider who will take us there. While we have these founders in our midst, we must take the time to do succession planning for free and open source leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Succession planning: what it is &amp;amp; why we need it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What new leaders must know &amp;amp; learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steps we can take to develop the FOSS leaders of the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Business of Community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/the-business-of-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>VM (Vicky) Brasseur</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/the-business-of-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While community management and developer relations are gaining acceptance, many companies still don't know how these efforts can benefit not only the communities of the open source projects on which their business relies but also their productivity and profitability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll look at community from a business perspective, including the effect community can have on an organization's bottom line. Although there are communities everywhere, I'll approach the topic—meaning, communities, their members, and their contributors—from a free/open source perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business reasons for supporting a community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metrics for gauging community management success from the business' perspective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting started in community management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risks of community management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Have It Your Way: Maximizing Drive-Thru Contributions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/have-it-your-way-maximizing-drive-thru-contributions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>VM (Vicky) Brasseur</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/have-it-your-way-maximizing-drive-thru-contributions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;VM (Vicky) Brasseur
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/118/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/118/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
They drop by, they fix their particular problem, they leave. They're the drive-through contributor. While, yes, we all would prefer that these people stick around and join the community, there's no denying that a good drive-thru contribution adds value to your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong argument can be made that the more drive-thru contributors your project has, the healthier the project process and ecosystem. It shows that you've set up a process which is easy to understand, easy to follow, and which makes it easy to contribute. In a situation like that, it increases the opportunities for new contributors to become new community members and everyone is a winner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Methods for maximizing drive-thru contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall advantages of those methods for your project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An argument for using number of drive-thru contributions as a metric for project health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>