<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sin-seok Seo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sin-seok-seo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>From Jupyter Notebooks to a Python Package: The Best of Both Worlds</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/from-jupyter-notebooks-to-a-python-package-the-best-of-both-worlds.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sin-seok Seo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/from-jupyter-notebooks-to-a-python-package-the-best-of-both-worlds.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2A on 2023-07-19]
https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/from-jupyter-notebooks-to-a-python-package-the-best-of-both-worlds

A Jupyter notebook is quite handy for rapid REPL (Read-Eval-Print-Loop) style tasks such as exploratory data analysis and data science. However, we would feel deficiencies in proper SW engineering supports at some point as the notebook grows …&lt;/pre&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2A on 2023-07-19]
https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/from-jupyter-notebooks-to-a-python-package-the-best-of-both-worlds

A Jupyter notebook is quite handy for rapid REPL (Read-Eval-Print-Loop) style tasks such as exploratory data analysis and data science. However, we would feel deficiencies in proper SW engineering supports at some point as the notebook grows to have larger and more complicated code. It is because the Jupyter notebook lacks several important features including code sharing, refactoring support, version control and advanced editing. Fortunately, traditional full-fledged IDEs, such as _VS Code_ or _PyCharm,_ are available at hand and they support these lacking features very well. Then, why don’t we take advantage of the best of both worlds?

In this beginner-level hands-on talk, I will demonstrate how to transform Jupyter notebook workflows to a proper Python package using _VS Code._ I will also introduce several basic but essential refactoring recommendations. By doing so, you can use the package for several notebooks and even share with your colleagues and friends.

This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/pre&gt;</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry></feed>