<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Machine Learning with Imbalanced Data Sets</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/machine-learning-with-imbalanced-data-sets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classification algorithms tend to perform poorly when data is skewed
towards one class, as is often the case when tackling real-world
problems such as fraud detection or medical diagnosis. A range of
methods exist for addressing this problem, including re-sampling,
one-class learning and cost-sensitive learning. This talk looks at
these different approaches in the context of fraud detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classification algorithms tend to perform poorly when data is skewed
towards one class. Real-world examples include fraud detection, medical
diagnosis and oil spill detection, where the class of interest is
generally the minority class. A key assumption built into many
classification algorithms is that maximising accuracy is the goal;
however, when positive instances account for only 1% of the data set in
question, an accuracy of 99% doesn’t quite cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common practice to address the problem with imbalanced data sets is to
rebalance them artificially using a range of sampling techniques.
However, one-class learning and cost-sensitive learning algorithms are
growing in popularity. This talk looks at different approaches to
tackling the problem of imbalanced classes in the context of fraud
detection, as have recently been explored by the GoCardless data team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalie Hockham</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/machine-learning-with-imbalanced-data-sets.html</guid></item></channel></rss>