<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Vincent Gonguet</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vincent-gonguet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Meta Llama 3 and the Future of Responsible AI Development</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/meta-llama-3-and-the-future-of-responsible-ai-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Spencer Whitman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/meta-llama-3-and-the-future-of-responsible-ai-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As AI models become increasingly powerful and pervasive, trust and safety have become top priorities. Join us for a timely talk on Llama 3, our latest foundation model, and the cutting-edge trust and safety models and tools we've developed to ensure responsible AI development. In this talk, we'll dive …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As AI models become increasingly powerful and pervasive, trust and safety have become top priorities. Join us for a timely talk on Llama 3, our latest foundation model, and the cutting-edge trust and safety models and tools we've developed to ensure responsible AI development. In this talk, we'll dive into: •The advancements of Llama 3 and its applications •Our innovative trust and safety approaches, including toxicity detection and mitigation •The open-source tools and resources we're sharing to empower the community Discover how Meta is pushing the boundaries of trust and safety and learn how you can integrate these solutions into your own projects. Let's build a safer, more responsible AI future together!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>