<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sarah Day</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sarah-day.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Copy That: Helping your Users Succeed with Effective Product Copy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/copy-that-helping-your-users-succeed-with-effective-product-copy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Day</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:/write-the-docs-2016/copy-that-helping-your-users-succeed-with-effective-product-copy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Day
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzrz/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzrz/&lt;/a&gt;
In this talk, I’ll discuss my adventures learning to write effective product copy for web and mobile apps. I’m a passionate believer that app copy is a magical panacea for bad user experience. When presented effectively, good copy decreases …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Day
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzrz/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzrz/&lt;/a&gt;
In this talk, I’ll discuss my adventures learning to write effective product copy for web and mobile apps. I’m a passionate believer that app copy is a magical panacea for bad user experience. When presented effectively, good copy decreases nearly every problem your users face, including frustration, ignorance, and workflow obstruction.
I’ll cover the following points in more detail:
How unified naming conventions can decrease user stress and make engineers’ jobs easier.
How effective in-app help guides users through complex workflows.
How to present context-based education, rather than comprehensive education. * One tricky field needs a sensible name, or even one good tooltip, not a link to a help center article that only has two lines about that one tricky field.
How effective app copy is a free way to introduce and reaffirm your product’s brand and voice.
How effective app copy increases user retention in your app, and decreases frustration and fear.
App copy is documentation for people who don’t know your knowledge base exists.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs 2016"></category></entry><entry><title>Starting from Scratch: Finding and Hiring Junior Writers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2018/starting-from-scratch-finding-and-hiring-junior-writers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Day</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-08:/write-the-docs-portland-2018/starting-from-scratch-finding-and-hiring-junior-writers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our team has the classic documentation problem--a huge backlog of work
and not enough writers. Enter the documentation internship program,
which connected us with junior and aspiring technical writers and got us
headcount fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will teach you how we recruited, interviewed, and hired
inexperienced writers, and taught …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our team has the classic documentation problem--a huge backlog of work
and not enough writers. Enter the documentation internship program,
which connected us with junior and aspiring technical writers and got us
headcount fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will teach you how we recruited, interviewed, and hired
inexperienced writers, and taught them the basics of technical writing…
all without damaging our velocity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll focus specifically on how our job pitch got us applicants from a
wide array of backgrounds, from screenwriters to college students, how
we made sense of the answers we got through an unpredictable set of
interviews, and how we onboarded writers with strong skills and
aptitude, but no real-world experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Portland 2018"></category></entry></feed>