<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why should kids learn to code and how can we help?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/why-should-kids-learn-to-code-and-how-can-we-help.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 21st Century, computers are ubiqitous, but too many young people are passive consumers of technology. We need to shift understanding from consumers, to users, to creators of content in order to prepare young people for the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright belongs to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cat Lamin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-09:pylondinium-2018/why-should-kids-learn-to-code-and-how-can-we-help.html</guid></item><item><title>Stereotypes, role models and learning to code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/stereotypes-role-models-and-learning-to-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why role models matter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be about the impact of having positive role models in the
world of coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeing reports highlighting that girls aren't
interested in coding, in particular numbers drop off during teen years
and in this talk we will discuss why and how we can help. We will
explore the importance of role models, not just to girls, but to other
minority groups and think about ways that we, as a community, can work
together to promote positive role models in the world of coding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cat Lamin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-15:pycon-uk-2018/stereotypes-role-models-and-learning-to-code.html</guid></item><item><title>You don't have to be mad to work here but it helps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/you-dont-have-to-be-mad-to-work-here-but-it-helps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mental health is a taboo subject right? We don't talk about it right? It's embarrassing or something to keep a secret right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn't it about time that changes? Mental health concerns clearly exist within the Coding Community of which Python Community is part of and it's about time we talked about it in an honest and frank manner. We suffer from depression, anxiety, bipolar, ASD, self-harming, imposter syndrome and much, much more, but when it's all behind closed doors, everything becomes so much worse, so let's talk about our mental health and how we can help and support each other to cope when those little brain-gremlins yell abuse from our shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cat Lamin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 11:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/you-dont-have-to-be-mad-to-work-here-but-it-helps.html</guid></item><item><title>Friday Education Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/friday-education-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a panel of four experts answering pre-submitted questions from the assembled audience under the guidance of a chairperson. Audience participation will be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a student learning Python? Do you teach using Python? Perhaps you support teachers or create educational resources? You may even be a parent with a perspective on how your own children are taught programming! Our panel of experts would love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think &amp;quot;Question Time&amp;quot; on BBC1 at 10:30pm on a Thursday and you have a pretty good idea of what it will be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Pope (Chair)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel is a hobbyist games programmer and two-time winner of the Pyweek games programming contest. He is author of Pygame Zero and adventurelib, both educational games frameworks for Python. He works for Two Sigma, a NYC hedge fund, from London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carrie Anne Philbin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carrie Anne Philbin is an award winning Computing &amp;amp; ICT Teacher, Author and YouTuber. Currently working as Director of Education for the Raspberry Pi Foundation to put the power of computing and digital making into the hands of people all over the world. She also volunteers on the board for Computing At School and as a Fellow of the Python Software Foundation. Alongside her work in formal education in the UK, Carrie Anne also hosts a Computer Science series on popular educational YouTube channel Crash Course and creates technology tutorials on her own channel the Geek Gurl Diaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cat Lamin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former UK primary school teacher and real-life geek girl, Cat is enthusiastic about getting teachers and children interested in coding and computing. She is a Raspberry Pi Certified Educator, CAS Master Teacher and Google Certified Educator; in her spare time, she performs in for an amateur theatre group, Q2 Players. Recent work has included work for the National STEM centre, travelling to Brazil to train elementary school teachers in basic computational thinking and computer science as well as working part-time for pi-top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cat also founded Coding Evening for teachers, a network of social events to encourage teachers and community members to get together and share best practice for computing teaching. She runs Raspberry Jam events in Wimbledon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kushal Das&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kushal Das is a developer of SecureDrop at Freedom of the Press Foundation. He is a long time contributor to various upstream Free Software projects including the Fedora project. He is a core developer of CPython, and also a director of the Python Software Foundation. For the last 10 years he has been organizing online summer training to help people to become upstream contibutors, and wrote an online book to help in the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Crick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Crick is Professor of Computer Science &amp;amp; Public Policy and Deputy Director of Innovation at Cardiff Metropolitan University. His interests sit at the research/policy interface, solving data-driven and computationally-intensive problems, as well as science/innovation policy, public service innovation, STEM education and skills/infrastructure for the digital economy. In 2013, he chaired the Welsh Government’s review of the ICT curriculum and chaired the development of a Digital Competence Framework for all schools in 2016. He was recently announced as the chair of the new National Network for Excellence in Science &amp;amp; Technology. He is Vice-President of BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT, Chair of CAS Wales and a non-executive director of Dŵr Cymru/Welsh Water. Twitter: &amp;#64;ProfTomCrick&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Pope</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/friday-education-panel.html</guid></item><item><title>PyCon UK 2017 - John Pinner Awards</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/pycon-uk-2017-john-pinner-awards.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicholas Tollervey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/pycon-uk-2017-john-pinner-awards.html</guid></item><item><title>Why do kids need to code and how can we help?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/why-do-kids-need-to-code-and-how-can-we-help.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cat Lamin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about the issues facing teachers today with the introduction of the new computing curriculum. I want to talk about my own experiences in the primary classroom and how people in the Python community can help and support teachers to achieve the best they can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cat Lamin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:pycon-uk-2016/why-do-kids-need-to-code-and-how-can-we-help.html</guid></item></channel></rss>