<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jakob Runge</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Discovering contemporaneous and lagged causal relations in autocorrelated nonlinear time series</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/discovering-contemporaneous-and-lagged-causal-relations-in-autocorrelated-nonlinear-time-series.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Discovering contemporaneous and lagged causal relations in autocorrelated nonlinear time series datasets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jakob Runge (German Aerospace Agency)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper introduces a novel conditional independence (CI) based method for linear and nonlinear, lagged and contemporaneous causal discovery from observational time series in the causally sufficient case. Existing CI-based methods such as the PC algorithm and also common methods from other frameworks suffer from low recall and partially inflated false positives for strong autocorrelation which is an ubiquitous challenge in time series. The novel method, PCMCI$^+$, extends PCMCI [Runge et al., 2019b] to include discovery of contemporaneous links. PCMCI$^+$ improves the reliability of CI tests by optimizing the choice of conditioning sets and even benefits from autocorrelation. The method is order-independent and consistent in the oracle case. A broad range of numerical experiments demonstrates that PCMCI$^+$ has higher adjacency detection power and especially more contemporaneous orientation recall compared to other methods while better controlling false positives. Optimized conditioning sets also lead to much shorter runtimes than the PC algorithm. PCMCI$^+$ can be of considerable use in many real world application scenarios where often time resolutions are too coarse to resolve time delays and strong autocorrelation is present.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jakob Runge</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/discovering-contemporaneous-and-lagged-causal-relations-in-autocorrelated-nonlinear-time-series.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item><item><title>Poster Spotlights 3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/poster-spotlights-3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Poster Spotlights 3 (session chair: Jakob Runge)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;79   |   BISCUIT: Causal Representation Learning from Binary Interactions   Phillip Lippe, Sara Magliacane, Sindy Löwe, Yuki M Asano, Taco Cohen, Efstratios Gavves
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/lippe23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/lippe23a.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;257   |   Composing Efficient, Robust Tests for Policy Selection   Dustin Morrill, Thomas Walsh, Daniel Hernandez, Peter R. Wurman, Peter Stone
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/morrill23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/morrill23a.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;294   |   Nyström $M$-Hilbert-Schmidt Independence Criterion   Florian Kalinke, Zoltán Szabó
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/kalinke23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/kalinke23a.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;354   |   JANA: Jointly Amortized Neural Approximation of Complex Bayesian Models   Stefan T. Radev, Marvin Schmitt, Valentin Pratz, Umberto Picchini, Ullrich Koethe, Paul Buerkner
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/radev23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/radev23a.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;476   |   Causal Inference With Outcome-Dependent Missingness And Self-Censoring   Jacob Morris Chen, Daniel Malinsky, Rohit Bhattacharya
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/chen23f.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/chen23f.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;516   |   CUE: An Uncertainty Interpretation Framework for Text Classifiers Built on Pre-Trained Language Models   Jiazheng Li, ZHAOYUE SUN, Bin Liang, Lin Gui, Yulan He
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/li23d.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/li23d.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;556   |   Fast and Scalable Score-Based Kernel Calibration Tests   Pierre Glaser, David Widmann, Fredrik Lindsten, Arthur Gretton
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/glaser23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/glaser23a.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;559   |   &amp;quot;Private Prediction Strikes Back!&amp;quot; Private Kernelized Nearest Neighbors with Individual R'{e}nyi Filter   Yuqing Zhu, Xuandong Zhao, Chuan Guo, Yu-Xiang Wang
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/zhu23b.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/zhu23b.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jakob Runge</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/poster-spotlights-3.html</guid><category>UAI 2023</category></item></channel></rss>