<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ian-rose.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>JupyterLab: The Evolution of the Jupyter Notebook</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2018/jupyterlab-the-evolution-of-the-jupyter-notebook.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Rose</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-22:pydata-la-2018/jupyterlab-the-evolution-of-the-jupyter-notebook.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We introduce JupyterLab, the next-generation UI developed by the Project
Jupyter team, and its emerging ecosystem of extensions. JupyterLab is
the next-generation Jupyter Notebook, providing a set of core building
blocks for interactive computing (e.g. notebook, terminal, file browser,
console) and well-designed interfaces for them that allow users to
combine them in novel ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>JupyterLab+Real Time Collaboration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2017/jupyterlabreal-time-collaboration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Granger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-06:pydata-seattle-2017/jupyterlabreal-time-collaboration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.pydata.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData is an educational program of NumFOCUS, a 501(c)3 non-profit organization in the United States. PyData provides a forum for the international community of users and developers of data analysis tools to share ideas and learn from each other. The global PyData network promotes discussion of best practices, new approaches, and emerging technologies for data management, processing, analytics, and visualization. PyData communities approach data science using many languages, including (but not limited to) Python, Julia, and R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData conferences aim to be accessible and community-driven, with novice to advanced level presentations. PyData tutorials and talks bring attendees the latest project features along with cutting-edge use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>