<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Programming Python as performance: live coding with FoxDot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/programming-python-as-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce the topic of live coding; the interactive
programming experience for generating audio and visuals but this talk
will mainly focus on audio. Live coders use programming languages to
describe rules for generating music but then re-write these rules while
the program is running. By continually writing and re-writing these
rules live coders creating a shifting musical experience that is always
in flux. All of this happens live in front of audience with the code
projected for all to see. I will go on to discuss the multiple tools
that are available for live coding and showcase the FoxDot environment,
which allows you to live code music using Python. I will talk about the
motivation for developing FoxDot and describe some of its key features
as well as how you can set it up yourself at home. The talk will be
concluded with a short demonstration that will be part explanation and
part performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Kirkbride</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/programming-python-as-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot.html</guid><category>FoxDot</category><category>PyCon SK</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Programming Music for Performance Live coding with FoxDot audiofix</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/programming-music-for-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot-audiofix.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apologies for the occasional mumbling in the audio over the presenter, a mic was left live next to the mixer for part of Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FoxDot is a Python library for interactive programming, specifically for live coding music. This talk will touch upon the history of live coding, the algorave movement (where people get together and dance to algorithms - yes, it's true), and how you can use Python to make your own music. The FoxDot editor gives users the ability to edit their Python code while it is being run, allowing them to enter a feedback loop where they can execute code, listen to the result, then change the code and re-execute it based on what they hear. Often dubbed &amp;quot;the composer programmer&amp;quot;, a live coder makes the act of composing music a performance practice in itself. Python's clean syntax and flexibility lends itself to this and FoxDot allows users to define musical algorithms quickly and easily. The talk will then culminate in a 10 minute improvised performance that will demonstrate the wide range of musical capabilities available in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Kirkbride</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-26:pycon-uk-2017/programming-music-for-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot-audiofix.html</guid></item><item><title>Programming Music for Performance: Live coding with FoxDot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2018/programming-music-for-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce the topic of live coding – the interactive programming experience for generating sound and visuals but this talk will mainly focus on the audio side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live coders use programming languages to describe rules for generating music but then re-write these rules while the program is running. By continually writing and re-writing these rules live coders creating a shifting musical experience that is always in flux. All of this happens live in front of an audience with the code projected for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will go on to discuss a few of the many tools that are available for live coding and showcase the FoxDot environment, which allows you to live code music using Python. I will talk about the motivation for developing FoxDot and describe some of its key features as well as how you can set it up yourself at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be concluded with a short demonstration that will be a partial explanation and partial performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Kirkbride</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-03:pycon-cz-2018/programming-music-for-performance-live-coding-with-foxdot.html</guid></item></channel></rss>