<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Paul Wolf</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_paul-wolf.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Clean Architecture with Django Rethinking basic assumptions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/clean-architecture-with-django-rethinking-basic-assumptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Wolf</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-03:/djangocon-europe-2021/clean-architecture-with-django-rethinking-basic-assumptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean Architectures and related architecture patterns like Hexagonal and Onion architecture are intended to provide more maintainable code and lower technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two parts of Django's architecture, the Django ORM and 3rd party Django REST Frameworks, make it difficult to get the benefits of a Clean Architecture. We look …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean Architectures and related architecture patterns like Hexagonal and Onion architecture are intended to provide more maintainable code and lower technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two parts of Django's architecture, the Django ORM and 3rd party Django REST Frameworks, make it difficult to get the benefits of a Clean Architecture. We look at ways we can achieve the benefits of Clean Architecture (CA) while using the Django framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the various Clean Architecture Patterns and what do they promise to do for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the ideal architecture pattern that Django supports?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem 1: most Object Relational Mappings including Django's do two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify the persistence model: normalisation of data, efficient storage, efficient lookup, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify the business entity domain: what business objects does the domain manage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that these are two different goals handled in one framework component, the ORM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem 2: REST frameworks have a heavy reliance on the ORM. This ties together the business domain to storage semantics making it hard to achieve some of the benefits of a Clean Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two solutions paths exist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django can serve a clean architecture-like paradigm, under specific circumstances. But there is some confusion about what CA looks like in practice that causes developers to go for solutions that are the opposite of CA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other solution is a more fundamental rethink of how to implement and use ORMs and REST frameworks (including remote request frameworks like GraphQL).&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon Europe 2021"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="DjangoConEU"></category><category term="djangoconeu2021"></category></entry></feed>