<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynote: Communities and education - exploring together</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/keynote-communities-and-education-exploring-together.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kushal and Anwesha Das&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kushal</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/keynote-communities-and-education-exploring-together.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion The Ethics and Politics of Programming</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/panel-discussion-the-ethics-and-politics-of-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a panel of four experts answering pre-submitted questions from the assembled audience under the guidance of a chairperson. Audience participation will be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fake news on social media, dragnet collection of personal data, being asked to write code for the benefit of your employers but that's not necessarily helpful for your users, using big data to analyse the behaviour of users, government control of the internet, violations of FLOSS licenced code. These subjects and more like them are ripe for discussion in this panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think &amp;quot;Question Time&amp;quot; on BBC1 at 10:30pm on a Thursday and you have a pretty good idea of what it will be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Willing&lt;/strong&gt; (CHAIR)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol Willing is a Python Software Foundation Fellow and former Director, a core developer for CPython and Project Jupyter, and a Research Software Engineer at Cal Poly San Luis Obispo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She's also Geek-In-Residence at Fab Lab San Diego and co-organizes PyLadies San Diego and San Diego Python. Combining a love of nature, the arts, and math with a BSE in Electrical Engineering from Duke and an MS in Management from MIT, she's enjoyed creating and teaching others for over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anwesha Das&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anwesha Das, is an Advocate practicing law for 7 years. She is an active user of FOSS technologies. She is the Organizer of PyLadies Pune. She maintains her blog at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anweshadas.in/"&gt;https://anweshadas.in/&lt;/a&gt;. One of her major goals is to help FOSS developers with the legal aspects of the software industry. She currently also blogs for the Python Software Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irina Bolychevsky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irina is passionate about products and using technology to make things better. She spent many years working on open data at Open Knowledge (as one of the directors and ckan product owner), at web startups, and recently as a data consultant for W3C, Open Data Institute and the UK and Dubai governments. She co-founded redecentralize.org — a project to promote and bring together people working on and interested in decentralised digital technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Miller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the only known biography of David Miller he is, &amp;quot;Human, frequently fascinated. Digital, Health with &amp;#64;ohcuk &amp;amp; friends.&amp;quot; He also happens to have a background in philosophy and an interest in ethical and political matters arising in the digital world. He's a founder of the NHS Hackday and runs Open Healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniele Procida&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniele works for Divio where he helps make Python/Django easier to deploy on the web. He is a member of the Django core team and the Django Software Foundation board, trying to contribute back to open source software and its communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carol Willing</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-28:pycon-uk-2017/panel-discussion-the-ethics-and-politics-of-programming.html</guid></item><item><title>Trends in licensesin Python ecosystem by Anwesha Das 38:47</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2016/trends-in-licensesin-python-ecosystem-by-anwesha-das-3847.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anwesha Das</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-23:pycon-india-2016/trends-in-licensesin-python-ecosystem-by-anwesha-das-3847.html</guid></item><item><title>The trends in choosing licenses in Python ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/the-trends-in-choosing-licenses-in-python-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The software licenses are the permissions over copyrighted software. The
permission and/ grant includes the grant to use, to redistribute, to
prepare derivative works etc. These software licenses also set forth the
limitations over these aforesaid rights. The software licenses basically
marks the boundary for the usage of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore from the above mentioned introduction it very clear that it is
very important for developers to choose the license for their code
wisely and correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyPI, the Python Package Index is a repository of software for the
Python programming language. There are currently 80000+ packages there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will go through the licenses of the top 2500 packages. We will
see the trend of choosing a license for these top Python projects. We
will discuss the licenses individually, compare them with each other.
the advantages and disadvantages of the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will further explain that why a license and/or licenses are being
favored by the developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anwesha Das</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pycon-us-2017/the-trends-in-choosing-licenses-in-python-ecosystem.html</guid></item></channel></rss>