<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Samantha Toet</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_samantha-toet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Exploring Eviction Trends in Virginia</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-virginia-2025/exploring-eviction-trends-in-virginia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michele Claibourn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-18:/pydata-virginia-2025/exploring-eviction-trends-in-virginia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where do landlords engage in more eviction actions? What characteristics of renters or landlords increase the practice of serial filing? There is widespread interest in using administrative data -- information collected by government and agencies in the implementation of public programs -- to evaluate systems and promote most just outcomes. Working …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where do landlords engage in more eviction actions? What characteristics of renters or landlords increase the practice of serial filing? There is widespread interest in using administrative data -- information collected by government and agencies in the implementation of public programs -- to evaluate systems and promote most just outcomes. Working with the Civil Court Data Initiative of Legal Services Corporation, we use data collected from civil court records in Virginia to analyze the behavior of landlords. Expanding on our Virginia Evictors Catalog, we use data on court evictions to build additional data tools to support the work of legal and housing advocates and model key eviction outcomes to contribute to our understanding of landlord behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Virginia 2025"></category></entry></feed>