<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Patrick Hoefler</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning Talk Day 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talk-day-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks of the second conference day at EuroSciPy 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talk-day-2.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Pandas + Dask DataFrame 2.0 - Comparison to Spark, DuckDB and Polars</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/pandas-dask-dataframe-20-comparison-to-spark-duckdb-and-polars.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dask is a library for distributed computing with Python that integrates
tightly with pandas and other libraries from the PyData stack. It offers
a DataFrame API that wraps pandas and thus offers an easy transition
into the big data space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, Dask was the easiest choice to use (it’s just pandas) but
struggled to achieve robust performance (there were many ways to
accidentally perform poorly). It was great for experts, but bad for
novices. Other tools (Spark, DuckDB, Polars) just did this better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, these pain points have been fixed with the following
features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new and vastly improved shuffle algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A logical query planning layer to improve performance and usability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reduced memory footprint through a more efficient data model due to
pandas 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will look into how these changes work together across pandas, Arrow,
and Dask to provide a better UX and a more robust and faster system
overall. Additionally, we will look into a comparison of Dask against
other tools in the big data space, including Spark, Polars and DuckDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use the TPC-H benchmarks to compare these tools. We will look
ahead into what the future will bring for pandas and Dask and how the
logical query planning layer can be extended to fit other frameworks
like Dask Array and XArray.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Hoefler</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/pandas-dask-dataframe-20-comparison-to-spark-duckdb-and-polars.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Processing Large Geospatial Datasets with Dask &amp; Xarray</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/processing-large-geospatial-datasets-with-dask-xarray.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geospatial datasets are growing in size, often exceeding 100TB and reaching into Petabyte scale. Many of these datasets are publicly available, providing a great resource for analysis, but working with them requires increasingly large computational resources and a diverse set of tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start by briefly introducing Dask and Xarray, which form the backbone of the geospatial stack in Python. Using the ERA5 dataset as a case study, we will demonstrate how Xarray can be used to explore large-scale climate data effectively from your local laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on this foundation, we will delve into recent advancements in Dask Array. Originally designed as a parallel NumPy API, Dask Array was used to handle much larger datasets over the last few years. We’ll explore the latest developments in Dask and Xarray that continue to expand the scalability and capabilities of these tools to catch up with the scale requirements of modern datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discussion will highlight improvements in ease of use, scalability, and performance. Additionally, we’ll present the first-ever set of geospatial benchmarks, collected earlier in 2024 from the community. These benchmarks provide a clear illustration of the scale at which Xarray and Dask are required to operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll offer a peak behind the scenes of an ongoing project aimed at building the first ever query optimizer for large scale array computations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Hoefler</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/processing-large-geospatial-datasets-with-dask-xarray.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item><item><title>Let's contribute to pandas (3 hours) PART.1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin are excited to bring you this open source workshop dedicated to contributing to pandas. This tutorial is 3 hours. We will have a break and continue with the same group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noa Tamir</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part1.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Let's contribute to pandas (3 hours) PART.2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin are excited to bring you this open source workshop dedicated to contributing to pandas. This tutorial is 3 hours. We will have a break and continue with the same group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noa Tamir</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/lets-contribute-to-pandas-3-hours-part2.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Pandas 2.0 and beyond</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/pandas-20-and-beyond.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has reached a 2.0 milestone in 2023. But what does that mean? And what is coming after 2.0? This talk will give an overview of what happened in the latest releases of pandas and highlight some topics and major new features the pandas project is working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joris Van den Bossche</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/pandas-20-and-beyond.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks DAY 1 | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-1-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Little</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-1-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item></channel></rss>