<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andreas-mueller.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Machine Learning with scikit learn Part One</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:scipy-2017/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tutorial materials found here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/"&gt;https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is the task of extracting knowledge from data, often with the goal of generalizing to new and unseen data. Applications of machine learning  now touch nearly every aspect of everyday life, from the face detection in our phones and the streams of social media we consume to picking restaurants,
partners, and movies. Machine learning has also become indispensable to many empirical sciences, from physics, astronomy and biology to social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scikit-learn has emerged as one of the most popular toolkits for machine learning, and is now widely used in industry and academia. The goal of this tutorial is to enable participants to use the wide variety of machine learning algorithms available in scikit-learn on their own data sets, for their own domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will comprise an introductory morning session and an advanced afternoon session. The morning part of the tutorial will cover basic concepts of machine learning, data representation, and preprocessing. We will explain different problem settings and concepts such as supervised learning,  unsupervised learning, dimensionality reduction, anomaly detection or clustering, and illustrate them with applications showing with algorithms can be used in each situation. We will cover the different families of methods (nearest-neighbors, kernel machines, tree-based techniques, linear models, neural network) with demos of SVMs, Random Forests, K-Means, PCA, t-SNE,
multi-layer perceptions and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon session, we will discuss setting hyper-parameters and how to prevent overfitting. We will go in-depth into the trade-off of model complexity and dataset size, as well as discussing complexity of learning algorithms and how to cope with very large datasets using online methods that support out-of-core computations. The session will conclude by stepping
through the process of building machine learning pipelines consisting of feature extraction, preprocessing and supervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning with scikit learn Part Two</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-two.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:scipy-2017/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-two.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tutorial materials found here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/"&gt;https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is the task of extracting knowledge from data, often with the
goal of generalizing to new and unseen data. Applications of machine learning now touch nearly every aspect of everyday life, from the face detection in our phones and the streams of social media we consume to picking restaurants, partners, and movies. Machine learning has also become indispensable to many empirical sciences, from physics, astronomy and biology to social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scikit-learn has emerged as one of the most popular toolkits for machine learning, and is now widely used in industry and academia. The goal of this tutorial is to enable participants to use the wide variety of machine learning algorithms available in scikit-learn on their own data sets, for their own domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will comprise an introductory morning session and an advanced afternoon session. The morning part of the tutorial will cover basic concepts of machine learning, data representation, and preprocessing. We will explain different problem settings and concepts such as supervised learning, unsupervised learning, dimensionality reduction, anomaly detection or clustering, and illustrate them with applications showing with algorithms can be used in each situation. We will cover the different families of methods (nearest-neighbors, kernel machines, tree-based techniques, linear models, neural network) with demos of SVMs, Random Forests, K-Means, PCA, t-SNE, multi-layer perceptrons and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon session, we will discuss setting hyper-parameters and how to prevent overfitting. We will go in-depth into the trade-off of model complexity and dataset size, as well as discussing complexity of learning algorithms and how to cope with very large datasets using online methods that support
out-of-core computations. The session will conclude by stepping
through the process of building machine learning pipelines consisting of feature extraction, preprocessing and supervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scikit-learn has emerged as one of the most popular open source machine learning toolkits, now widely used in academia and industry. scikit-learn provides easy-to-use interfaces to perform advances analysis and build powerful predictive models. The tutorial will cover basic concepts of machine learning, such as supervised and unsupervised learning, cross validation and model selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scikit-learn has emerged as one of the most popular open source machine learning toolkits, now widely used in academia and industry. scikit-learn provides easy-to-use interfaces to perform advances analysis and build powerful predictive models. The tutorial will cover basic concepts of machine learning, such as supervised and unsupervised learning, cross validation and model selection. We will see how to prepare data for machine learning, and go from applying a single algorithm to building a machine learning pipeline. We will also cover how to build machine learning models on text data, and how to handle very large datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along, there will be material online that you can download beforehand: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amueller/pydata-amsterdam-2016"&gt;https://github.com/amueller/pydata-amsterdam-2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually recommend to install the anaconda python distribution before coming: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://store.continuum.io/cshop/anaconda/"&gt;https://store.continuum.io/cshop/anaconda/&lt;/a&gt; and make sure that you are able to run the ipython notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="scikit-learn"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning with Scikit Learn - Part I</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-i.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning with Scikit Learn - Part II</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-ii.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>PyStruct Structured Prediction in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/pystruct-structured-prediction-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/pystruct-structured-prediction-in-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Automatic Machine Learning?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/automatic-machine-learning-scipy-2016-andreas-mueller.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/automatic-machine-learning-scipy-2016-andreas-mueller.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="SciPy 2016"></category></entry><entry><title>Commodity Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/commodity-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/commodity-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Large scale non-linear learning on a single CPU</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/large-scale-non-linear-learning-on-a-single-cpu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/large-scale-non-linear-learning-on-a-single-cpu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents several methods for learning non-linear models on a
single machine, where the dataset does not fit into ram. It will cover
the hashing trick, kernel approximations, neural networks, and extreme
learning machines (random neural networks). This will be a fairly
technical talk, showing off some of the lesser known out-of-core
capabilities of scikit-learn.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>