<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Winning an Election with Django and jQuery Mobile</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/winning-an-election-with-django-and-jquery-mobile.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winning an Election with Django and jQuery Mobile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 2:45 p.m.--3:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Palakovich Carr will discuss how he leveraged Django and jQuery
mobile to help run his wife's data driven political campaign. Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Palakovich Carr talks about building a mobile app to help his
wife's political campaign for a city council seat. See how he integrated
Django, AngularJS, and jQuery Mobile to build a canvasing (door
knocking) and phone banking mobile app. See what's gone right, what's
gone wrong, and a lot of code showing how it's done. Introduction (Very)
short demo of Voter Pad Brief overview of jQuery Mobile Using Django and
jQuery Mobile Using AngularJS and Django REST Framework Pitfalls in
jQuery Mobile Challenges integrating Django, AngularJS, and jQuery
Mobile together Pros and Cons of using Django and jQuery mobile vs.
native mobile apps Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Palakovich Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-01:djangocon-us-2013/winning-an-election-with-django-and-jquery-mobile.html</guid></item><item><title>[Poster] A Fast and Efficient Python Development Process for Small Teams</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/a-fast-and-efficient-python-development-process-f.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever had a feature take too long, not work, and make everybody crazy?
Our small team has learned some great tips to speed up development
without sacrificing quality and stability. Come see these hard learned
ideas, and how they can be applied to your team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Palakovich Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-17:pycon-us-2013/a-fast-and-efficient-python-development-process-f.html</guid><category>poster</category></item></channel></rss>