<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Akshay Gupta</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DataComPy - Dataframe Comparisons made Explicit (Sponsor: Capital One)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/datacompy-dataframe-comparisons-made-explicit-sponsor-capital-one.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DataComPy is a widely used validation tool with over 1.1 million monthly installations, written to quickly and comprehensively compare a pair of dataframes. Designed to help make differences between schemas and data clear and explicit, DataComPy generates a comprehensive report at the completion of all comparisons, providing useful metrics such as match percentages, maximal differences, and sample mismatches between comparable columns. In addition, it supports various forms of input data types for both native (Pandas, Polars, Spark, Snowpark) and indirect (Dask, Ray) comparisons. It also supports comparison of certain types of database tables, including Snowflake and DuckDB. Over the course of the presentation, we'll be delving further into how DataComPy works, what features it provides, and what types of practical use cases it is designed to help address.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Akshay Gupta</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-15:/pycon-us-2025/datacompy-dataframe-comparisons-made-explicit-sponsor-capital-one.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item><item><title>When is a compiled language like Rust beneficial for Data Scientists?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/when-is-a-compiled-language-like-rust-beneficial-for-data-scientists.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, there has been an increase in the number of libraries that leverage Rust and pyo3 to significantly increase performance. What's the catch? In this talk, we will discuss how the Data Science team at Capital One has been thinking about the power of Rust-backed Python and whether the benefits justify the complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Akshay Gupta</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/when-is-a-compiled-language-like-rust-beneficial-for-data-scientists.html</guid><category>SciPy 2024</category></item></channel></rss>