<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kevin-chrzanowski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Bokeh Maps: Making an interactive map for your next web application</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/bokeh-maps-making-an-interactive-map-for-your-next-web-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Chrzanowski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/bokeh-maps-making-an-interactive-map-for-your-next-web-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data scientists, analysts, and developers are proficient in creating
static maps but what about interactive ones? An interactive map of Los
Angeles neighborhoods will be made via Python’s Bokeh library to show
how quickly one can be built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maps are crucial for showing differences between regions. However, what
happens when users want to see regional changes over a range of time
periods for a variety of variables? One map may not be enough. Rather
than creating many maps for all your user’s needs, an interactive map
allows the viewer to choose the time period and variables of interest.
In order to get a better sense of the process of making an interactive
map, a map of Los Angeles neighborhoods will be built live using
Python’s Bokeh library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will cover how to add features and widgets such as a
hovertool, selection form, and mouse selection click to a map. We will
also go over the important modify_doc and update functions that are
crucial for an interactive map to be able to respond to input changes
from a viewer. We’ll deploy to a Google Cloud server, discuss when to
build an interactive map, and best practices for designing one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of certain data visual python libraries such as matplotlib or
seaborn, in addition to basic python functionality, will be assumed.
This is a presentation geared for intermediate python users.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>