<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dynamic programming for machine learning: Hidden Markov Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/dynamic-programming-for-machine-learning-hidden-markov-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dynamic programming turns up in many machine learning algorithms, maybe
because dynamic programming excels at solving problems involving
&amp;quot;non-local&amp;quot; information. I explore one technique used in machine
learning, Hidden Markov Models, and how dynamic programming is used when
applying this technique. Then, I'll show a few real-world examples where
Hidden Markov Models are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Hidden Markov Model deals with inferring the state of a system given
some unreliable or ambiguous observations from that system. One
important characteristic of this system is the state of the system
evolves over time, producing a sequence of observations along the way.
By incorporating some domain-specific knowledge, it’s possible to take
the observations and work backwards to a maximally plausible ground
truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk explores Hidden Markov Models in three steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, I define Hidden Markov Models and how they apply to machine
learning problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, I build up an understanding of the Viterbi algorithm, used to
infer the state of the system given a sequence of observations. This
involves some basic math, but the goal is to form an intuition for
the algorithm. Some sample Python code is presented to demonstrate
how simple the algorithm is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, I introduce several real-world applications of Hidden Markov
Models in machine learning. In this section, real-world
considerations like feature extraction and training are discussed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic math knowledge is expected, just the ability to express concepts
as equations and an understanding of Big-O notation. Basic Python
knowledge is also expected, as code samples will be presented. The goal
is build up intuition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://avikdas.com/2019/06/24/dynamic-programming-for-machine-%20learning-hidden-markov-models.html"&gt;The content of this talk is available as an article on my personal
blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Avik Das</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:pydata-la-2019/dynamic-programming-for-machine-learning-hidden-markov-models.html</guid></item></channel></rss>