<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2018/reinforcement-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melanie Warrick&lt;/strong&gt; , Google&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.ru/2018/en/program/content/Warrick/"&gt;**Reinforcement Learning**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinforcement learning is a popular subfield in machine learning because
of its success in beating humans at complex games like Go and Atari. The
field’s value is in utilizing an award system to develop models and find
more optimal ways to solve complex, real-world problems. This approach
allows software to adapt to its environment without full knowledge of
what the results should look like. This talk will cover reinforcement
learning fundamentals and examples to help you understand how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melanie Warrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-22:pycon-russia-2018/reinforcement-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Neural Nets for Newbies by Melanie Warrick (May 2015)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/neural-nets-for-newbies-by-melanie-warrick-may-2015.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Neural Nets for Newbies&amp;quot; is geared to provide clarity on what neural networks are, how to start using them and why they are valuable -- feature engineering. This talk is targeted to anyone who is passionate about understanding algorithms and code to define and leverage patterns in data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the Speaker: Melanie Warrick is a Deep Learning Engineer at Skymind.io.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was organized by the Bay Area Python Interest Group (&amp;quot;BayPiggies&amp;quot;) and held at LinkedIn on May 28, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melanie Warrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-18:bay-piggies/neural-nets-for-newbies-by-melanie-warrick-may-2015.html</guid></item><item><title>How to Get Started with Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/how-to-get-started-with-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provide an introduction to machine learning to clarify what it is, what
it's not and how it fits into this picture of all the hot topics around
data analytics and big data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melanie Warrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-12:pycon-us-2014/how-to-get-started-with-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Neural Nets for Newbies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/neural-nets-for-newbies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neural networks have regained popularity in the last decade, but they
get dismissed as being too complicated to understand and implement. This
talk breaks down the neural net structure as simply as possible, so you
have a framework on which to grow your knowledge in the space. I will
put neural nets in the context of real-world applications and share
Python packages and code where you can get started building your own.
Coming out this talk you won't know everything about neural nets, but
you will walk away with a solid foundation and some resources on where
to go next to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melanie Warrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-11:pycon-us-2015/neural-nets-for-newbies.html</guid></item></channel></rss>