<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_albert-nel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python in Blender</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/using-python-in-blender.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Albert Nel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/using-python-in-blender.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is such a beautiful language, and is used as a scripting language
in many open source graphical applications. By using the power of Python
within Blender, we can easily automate so many things, and make long
tedious tasks seem like child's play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is such a beautiful language, and is used as a scripting language
in many open source graphical applications. By using the power of Python
within Blender, we can easily automate so many things, and make long
tedious tasks seem like child's play. In this talk I wanted to share a
few real world examples where I used Python to do something that would
otherwise be impossible (Or just take too long!) At first, we will take
a quick look at the API, and how to get started. Here we will look at
where you can find what you are looking for, and how it all comes
together. This wont be too in-depth, but just enough to give you a
taste. We will play with the console a bit and see how to wield the
mighty sword that is Python. And then, we will look at some scripts.
These are a few of the scripts that I wrote while I was working on some
random things. This will cover some things such as: Adding new mesh
objects, updating object coordinates, changing special properties (such
as modifers), and setting keyframes all from the console. This talk is
for anyone interested in seeing just how to leverage the power of Python
in Blender. You need not have any experience with Blender since this
will be mostly focussed on the Python side of things, so I wont be
covering parts of Blender such as rendering, modeling etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry></feed>