<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Honza Javorek</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python Organizers' Panel: Exploring Community-Driven Python Conferences</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/python-organizers-panel-exploring-community-driven-python-conferences.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Forum Hall on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/python-organizers-panel-exploring-community-driven-python-conferences"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/python-organizers-panel-exploring-community-driven-python-conferences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panel Discussion with Alexander CS Hendorf, Alessia Marcolini, Jimena Bermúdez, Bára Drbohlavová, Honza Javorek, Tim (文昌) Hsu, David Vaz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Python conferences are primarily organized by the community? Go backstage and join us at the Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging and insightful discussion as we bring together a group of passionate Python conference organizers from the community. Discover the vibrant ecosystem behind Python conferences and gain valuable insights into their experiences, motivations, and learnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are an aspiring organizer, a Python enthusiast, or simply curious about the inner workings of community-driven events, this panel promises to provide a wealth of knowledge and inspiration. Don't miss the opportunity to hear firsthand from the dedicated individuals who make Python conferences an incredible experience for all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander CS Hendorf</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/python-organizers-panel-exploring-community-driven-python-conferences.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Because Web API Testing Should Be Easy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/because-web-api-testing-should-be-easy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web APIs are often called REST APIs, which recently became a part of the everyday life of many Python developers. Sure, it can be a blast to build an API with frameworks like Django or Flask, but writing tests for it can be a tedious drag: asserting every single HTTP code, set of headers, JSON responses, error states… you know the drill. Despite all that you do, you still need to assure your API clients won’t be exposed to any unexpected surprises. At Apiary, we've developed an Open Source testing framework called Dredd, which has baked in first-class Python support. It does all the heavy lifting and boring stuff for you while allowing you to alter the test cases with arbitrary Python code. Let Judge Dredd do your API justice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Honza Javorek</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-12:/pycon-sk-2017/because-web-api-testing-should-be-easy.html</guid><category>PyCon SK 2017</category></item></channel></rss>