<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Travis Hathaway</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_travis-hathaway.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Processing Open Street Map Data with Python and PostgreSQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/processing-open-street-map-data-with-python-and-postgresql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Travis Hathaway</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-11:/pycon-de-2022/processing-open-street-map-data-with-python-and-postgresql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Travis Hathaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Data Handling
The Open Street Map (OSM) project is a global, open-source database with over 50GB of data, and this number grows everyday with every user submission. With such a big data set out there, also comes a huge potential for analysis and use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Travis Hathaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Data Handling
The Open Street Map (OSM) project is a global, open-source database with over 50GB of data, and this number grows everyday with every user submission. With such a big data set out there, also comes a huge potential for analysis and use in scientific studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how to get started with your own analysis using PostgreSQL as the data store and Python as the data processing language. To help you see exactly how this works, I first introduce the OSM data types, explain how to import this data into PostgreSQL and then cover how you can organise a Python project for data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I end the talk by going over an example project, and there will also be plenty of links and resources for those wishing to learn even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/AKCLEP"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/AKCLEP&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2022"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConDE"></category><category term="pyconde2022"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="pydataberlin2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing Plugin Friendly Python Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/writing-plugin-friendly-python-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Travis Hathaway</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/writing-plugin-friendly-python-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, plugin systems are a ubiquitous way to extend and modify the behavior of applications and libraries. When software is written in a way that is plugin friendly, it encourages the use of modular organization where the contracts between the core software and the plugin have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, plugin systems are a ubiquitous way to extend and modify the behavior of applications and libraries. When software is written in a way that is plugin friendly, it encourages the use of modular organization where the contracts between the core software and the plugin have been well thought out. In this talk, we cover exactly how to define this contract and how you can start designing your software to be more plugin friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the talk we will be creating our own plugin friendly application using the pluggy library to show these design principles in action. At the end of the talk, I also cover a real-life case study of how the package manager conda is currently making its 10 year old code more plugin friendly to illustrate how to retrofit an existing project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category></entry></feed>