<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Elijah Caine</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_elijah-caine.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to Write an Email</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2015/how-to-write-an-email.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elijah Caine</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-31:/write-the-docs-europe-2015/how-to-write-an-email.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nobody loves email. Nobody really even likes email. In fact email can
totally suck and it is here to stay. Despite how we feel about it, we
have to deal with email almost every single day. Fortunately we can
improve email as a whole by learning how to write …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nobody loves email. Nobody really even likes email. In fact email can
totally suck and it is here to stay. Despite how we feel about it, we
have to deal with email almost every single day. Fortunately we can
improve email as a whole by learning how to write email that sucks just
a little bit less -- not that you write bad emails.. this talk is for
your... friend. Yeah, this talk is for your friends that really need to
setup up their email game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to email this talk will explore some fundamental
misunderstandings that people have with modes of online communication
and how to correct these misunderstandings. Like how to craft a good
Tweet, Facebook Post, and Instant Messaging interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not meant to be a tutorial but rather a conceptual guide for how
to think about on-line communication and how to correct some common
faults we share as members of the on-line community. The Internet isn't
going away anytime soon, and the amount we communicate over it is not
going to diminish anytime soon either. This talk attempts to teach one
how to make digital communication as painless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Europe 2015"></category></entry></feed>