<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_caroline-taylor.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Transfer those Skills! How to Identify, Communicate, and Sell your Transferable Skills when Switching Careers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/transfer-those-skills-how-to-identify-communicate-and-sell-your-transferable-skills-when-switching-careers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Caroline Taylor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-15:djangocon-us-2018/transfer-those-skills-how-to-identify-communicate-and-sell-your-transferable-skills-when-switching-careers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tech industry giants are acknowledging that diversity in employee
backgrounds is valuable for their organizations’ bottom lines. However,
it’s still tough for job seekers to land a tech job without prior
experience closely aligned with the job they’re applying for. This talk
will focus on helping people who are looking for their next tech role:
(1) understand themes of what hiring committees look for, (2) identify
transferable skills from nontraditional experience they already have,
(3) communicate the power of their unique set of past experiences, and
(4) learn tools to demonstrate these skills in their resume and job
interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees who are looking for their next role will leave with actionable
ideas for improving job application materials, conveying transferable
skills from non-technology-related jobs in interviews, and generally
rocking any job interview with basic tips that many people miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presenters, both of whom came to tech without a traditional CS
background, will give a short introduction of their experience and
expertise. They will discuss the aspects of their experience that they
expected to be valuable from the start, and those (sometimes
surprising!) skills whose value became apparent only after they got to
technical positions. Both presenters have participated in hiring panels,
one as a hiring manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will share tips and tricks based on industry best practices and
their experience reviewing resumes, cover letters, speaking with
references, and interviewing job candidates. They will highlight common
mistakes and things to consider when applying for, and then interviewing
for, attendees’ next tech job.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>