<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Adding Narrative to BI Dashboards with Natural Language Generation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/adding-narrative-to-bi-dashboards-with-natural-language-generation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are not always sufficient in understanding important
aspects of data. People have to interpret charts and build narratives
about it. Natural language generation technology can be used to greatly
improve the communicative power of the data. In this talk I will
introduce NLG and will present a case through the use of two open source
tools: Accelerate Text (NLG) and Metabase (BI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BI tools excel at visually organizing data in various dashboards. Yet
data visualizations are not always sufficient in understanding important
aspects of data. People have to interpret charts and build narratives
about data on their own. Furthermore, different groups of people often
need different narratives about the same data. For example, a story
about the same sales data is different for a CFO and for an Order
Fulfillment Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural language generation technology (NLG) can be used to greatly
improve the communicative power of a BI dashboards. With the use of NLG
we can produce different descriptions of the same data adopted to the
needs of each person reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration between BI and NLG will be demonstrated through the use
of two open source products: (a) TokenMill's open source NLG tool called
Accelerated Text (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tokenmill/acceleratedtext"&gt;https://github.com/tokenmill/acceleratedtext&lt;/a&gt;), to
illustrate how natural language can be generated using data; (b) and the
BI platform Metabase (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/metabase/metabase"&gt;https://github.com/metabase/metabase&lt;/a&gt;), to provide
analytical dashboards which will include both data visualizations and
automatically generated natural language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Žygimantas Medelis</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:pydata-warsaw-2019/adding-narrative-to-bi-dashboards-with-natural-language-generation.html</guid></item></channel></rss>