<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_juan-manuel-santos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>(GNU/Linux) Instalado para durar</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2018/gnulinux-instalado-para-durar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eduardo Casarero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-ar-2018/gnulinux-instalado-para-durar.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Esta charla propone un check list básico para la instalción de gnu/linux en servidores con el objetivo de alojar servicios con largos ciclos de vida (años) y minimizar el sobre-costo administrativo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El dinamismo de la industria a veces genera situaciones de instalación de servidores que no son las optimas para durar años en producción. Durante esta charla revisaremos un check list básico de tareas y configuraciones que nos ayudarán a que ese servidor instalado pueda transcurrir su largo ciclo de vida con la menor sobrecarga administrativa posible. (selección de OS, selección de paquetes, hardening, configuraciones de hardware, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>You need more security in your application packaging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/you-need-more-security-in-your-application-packaging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Manuel Santos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-11:europython-2017/you-need-more-security-in-your-application-packaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are as many different ways to package an application as there
are programming or scripting languages. No one tool or library is in
itself better than another; however when security comes into the
picture, there is definitely a pattern between ease of installation
and how secure the delivered application is. As more work is put into
packaging the application, more measures can be taken in order to
ensure its integrity and prevent security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The roles involved in the lifecycle of an application, from the
start of the development process until it reaches the end user and it
is actually used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The inherent problems in this subject, regarding installation and
security, as well as how they are related.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The different ways of packaging an application in order to deliver
it to an end user, focused on a Python perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the talk, attendees will have a better grasp on which is the
best way for them to package and deliver their application according
to their environment and target audience. They will also learn about
the upgrade path to switch from one delivery method to another,
should they need or want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this talk, it is desired that attendees have some general systems
knowledge. Even though the talk will be focused on Python
applications, some knowledge of information security is desired.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Salting things up in the sysadmin's world</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/salting-things-up-in-the-sysadmins-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Manuel Santos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:europython-2015/salting-things-up-in-the-sysadmins-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Juan Manuel Santos - Salting things up in the sysadmin's world
[EuroPython 2015]
[21 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SaltStack is a thriving configuration management system written in
Python that leverages YAML and Jinja2 which, by now, probably needs no
introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover a brief summary of why we need configuration
management tools, followed by a full dive into SaltStack, its
features, pros and cons, how to use it and how to extend it. By the
end of this talk you will have gone from knowing little or nothing
about SaltStack, to being able to deploy your own setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be targeted to either seasoned Python developers who
are taking their first steps in the system administration world, or
established system administrators who secretly love Python and prefer
to stay away of configuration management systems based on other
languages.
Its advisable that attendees have some familiarity with Python as well
as with system administration concepts. Also, this presentation will
be focused on GNU/Linux systems, so it is expected that attendees are
comfortable with some of its concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Salting things up in the DevOps' World: things just got real</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/salting-things-up-in-the-devops-world-things-just-got-real.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Manuel Santos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-31:europython-2016/salting-things-up-in-the-devops-world-things-just-got-real.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Juan Manuel Santos - Salting things up in the DevOps' World: things just got real
[EuroPython 2016]
[19 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/salting-things-up-in-the-devops-world-things-just-got-real"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/salting-things-up-in-the-devops-world-things-just-got-real&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SaltStack is a thriving configuration management system written in
Python that leverages YAML and Jinja2 which, by now, probably needs no
introduction. This talk will explore Salt beyond the minimum required
setup, targeting developers/sysadmins already using Salt, and those
considering making the switch from other systems but wishing to dive
deeper first. Attendees should be familiar with configuration
management systems and practices, and comfortable using and reading
YAML and Jinja syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much more to Salt than the basics. This talk will go beyond
the minimum required setup and will take a look at Salt under the
hood, which will appeal not only to system administrators, but will
also be more interesting to developers and to the DevOps community in
general as the talk progresses. Topics include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction and basics review (master/minions, matching, grains, pillar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt Mine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syndic node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State modules vs. runner modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Reactor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Event System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt Beacons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees should be familiar with configuration management systems and
practices, and also feel comfortable using and reading YAML and Jinja
syntax. This talk is targeted to developers or sysadmins already using
Salt, and to those who are considering switching to it from other
systems but wish to dive deeper before making that decision. After the
talk, attendees will have a better grasp of the more advanced
possibilities that Salt brings, and be ready to apply them to their
use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>