<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Nathan Van Gheem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unify Your Service Architecture With OpenAPI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2020/unify-your-service-architecture-with-openapi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Unify Your Service Architecture With OpenAPI&amp;quot; by: Nathan van Gheem
This talk will go through understanding what OpenAPI and JSON Schema is, how it can help your organization write better endpoints, why it is superior to alternatives like grpc and how to utilize it in your python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also describe approaches to integrating OpenAPI and JSON schema into your python projects with simple patterns utilizing dependency injection, automatic definition testing with pytest and output validation. Also, it will demonstrate how using libraries like pydantic will also give you automatic mypy support along with JSON Schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll utilize patterns that can be translated to any Python framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2020 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2020.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan van Gheem</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-06-18:/python-web-conf-2020/unify-your-service-architecture-with-openapi.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2020</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2020</category></item><item><title>Taming the Monolith and Transitioning to Service Architecture</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/taming-the-monolith-and-transitioning-to-service-architecture.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you built (or inherited) a successful monolith! Well, successful in that you have many customers; however, now problems are everywhere. How do you scale this thing? How do you build teams as your company grows? Come to this talk to learn strategies on navigating the difficulties of scaling a Monolith. Learn about transition strategies and service architecture design patterns to help you scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Van Gheem</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/taming-the-monolith-and-transitioning-to-service-architecture.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>