<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Daren Eiri</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daren-eiri.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Why You Should Add Logging To Your Code (and make it more helpful)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/why-you-should-add-logging-to-your-code-and-make-it-more-helpful.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daren Eiri</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/why-you-should-add-logging-to-your-code-and-make-it-more-helpful.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how the log4r package can help you better understand the errors your code may produce, and how to also get promptly alerted for severe errors by leveraging cloud monitoring solutions like Azure Monitor or AWS CloudWatch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an error happens in your API, Shiny App, or quarto document …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how the log4r package can help you better understand the errors your code may produce, and how to also get promptly alerted for severe errors by leveraging cloud monitoring solutions like Azure Monitor or AWS CloudWatch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an error happens in your API, Shiny App, or quarto document, it is not always clear what line of code you need to look at, and the error messages aren’t always helpful. By walking through a simple API example, I show how you can use logging packages like log4r to provide error messages that make sense to you. I also show how you can use cloud-based data collection platforms like Azure Monitor or AWS CloudWatch to set up alerts, so you can get notified by email or text message for those severe errors that you need to be immediately aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gain more visibility into the health of your code by incorporating logging and pushing your logs to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dareneiri.github.io/positconf2023/"&gt;https://dareneiri.github.io/positconf2023/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>