<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Snakes on a Cloud: "Data science, meet DevOps"</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/snakes-on-a-cloud-data-science-meet-devops.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover how IBM Cloudant engineers use data to inform development and
operations every day! Sources such as Splunk and Graphite are pivotal
for meeting our service needs. I will demonstrate a data processing
engine based on Pandas and NumPy that can help tame these sources.
Then discover how you can use Jupyter notebooks with IBM's Bluemix
platform to do more with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snakes on a Cloud: &amp;quot;Data science, meet DevOps&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running an always-on database service such as IBM Cloudant is a
complex task. Accomplishing this requires a mix of development and
operations informed by data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various data sources such as application logs, system metrics, and
project management systems are used every day by Cloudant engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I'll describe how DevOps works at Cloudant, and how data is used
to meet our service needs. Break through the buzzwords and see the
reality of a running service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll demonstrate a data processing engine called Forecast, which
combines various sources at Cloudant for analysis. Forecast allows
engineers to go beyond manual inspection by using Pandas and NumPy to
analyze information. We'll see how we can realize new insights from
our service metrics with tooling and automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we'll examine data using Jupyter Notebooks as provided by IBM
Bluemix's data science platform. I'll walk us through visualization of
Forecast's output and we'll learn how Bluemix can make data science
simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kyle Snavely</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/snakes-on-a-cloud-data-science-meet-devops.html</guid></item></channel></rss>