<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jeethu-rao.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Faster Python startup</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/faster-python-startup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeethu Rao</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/faster-python-startup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cPython’s startup speed generally quite fast compared to other
similar dynamic language interpreters. Despite this, the interpreter’s
startup time increases linearly with the number and size of imported
python modules. Although interpreter startup speed isn’t a significant
concern in long running servers, it does matter for the command line and
other frequently launched applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the oldest tricks in the book, when it comes to performance
optimizations is to perform frequent and expensive operations fewer
times and reuse results from previous invocations. We noticed that the
overhead of reading and un-marshalling .pyc files at startup can be
eliminated if we could directly embed code objects and their associated
object graph from .pyc files into the data segment of the cPython
binary. This technique is quite similar to the approach taken by image
based languages like Smalltalk in the past. Implementing this for
cPython is made simpler because marshaled code objects in .pyc files
contain a subset of the types of objects that marshal format supports.
With this approach, loading a module included in the python binary is as
cheap as dereferencing a pointer, albeit at the cost of increased binary
size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss the approach taken to implement the
aforementioned idea for Python 3.6 and the challenges faced in
implementing it. It will also talk about benchmark results from the
improvements and possible future directions for this work. Although this
talk delves into cPython internals, no prior experience with cPython
internals is required to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>