<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Grishma Jena</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Data Science beasts (failures) and where to find them</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2023/Data_Science_beasts_failures_and_where_to_find_them.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the field of Data Science encourages trial and error, but we can do a better job of destigmatizing failure and learn from our collective experiences. Join me as I take us on an adventure to find the beasts i.e. the different ways Data Science projects can fail. I will be talking about 4 major reasons for failure (data, infrastructure, implementation, and culture), their different aspects, and supplementing it with my experiences and case studies. I will also share how to control these beasts and recommend actions to be taken to ensure a successful end-to-end Data Science project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Grishma Jena</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-08:/pybay-2023/Data_Science_beasts_failures_and_where_to_find_them.html</guid><category>PyBay 2023</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Data Science with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/introduction-to-data-science-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wish to perform Data Science but don’t know how to? Have a dataset that
you really want to analyze but not sure how to start? This hands-on
session teaches how to explore datasets, use Machine Learning algorithms
and derive insights from models using popular Python tools like Jupyter,
pandas, sklearn and numpy. Aimed at budding data scientists with prior
programming experience in any language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Grishma Jena</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-02:/pycon-us-2019/introduction-to-data-science-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>tutorial</category></item></channel></rss>