<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Karishma Srikanth</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_karishma-srikanth.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Adding a Touch of glitr: Developing a Package of Themes on Top of ggplot</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/adding-a-touch-of-glitr-developing-a-package-of-themes-on-top-of-ggplot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Chafetz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/adding-a-touch-of-glitr-developing-a-package-of-themes-on-top-of-ggplot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you create brand cohesion across your large team when it comes to data viz? Inspired by the BBC's bbplot, our team at the US Agency for International Development (USAID) developed a package on top of ggplot2 to create a common look and feel for our team's products …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you create brand cohesion across your large team when it comes to data viz? Inspired by the BBC's bbplot, our team at the US Agency for International Development (USAID) developed a package on top of ggplot2 to create a common look and feel for our team's products. This effort improved not just the cohesiveness of our work, but also trustworthiness. By creating this package, we reduced the reliance on using defaults and the time spent on each project customizing numerous graphic elements. More importantly, this package provided an easier on-ramp for new teammates to adopt R. We share our journey within a federal agency developing a style guide and aim to guide and inspire other organizations who could benefit from developing their own branding package and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/achafetz/adding-a-touch-of-glitr"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/achafetz/adding-a-touch-of-glitr&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://usaid-oha-si.github.io/glitr/"&gt;https://usaid-oha-si.github.io/glitr/&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://issuu.com/achafetz/docs/oha_styleguide"&gt;https://issuu.com/achafetz/docs/oha_styleguide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Building scalable data pipelines through R and global health information systems' API</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/building-scalable-data-pipelines-through-r-and-global-health-information-systems-api.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Karishma Srikanth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/building-scalable-data-pipelines-through-r-and-global-health-information-systems-api.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Efficient and scalable analytics workflows are critical for an adaptive and data-driven organization. How can we scale systems to support an office charged with implementing USAID's $6 billion HIV/AIDS program? Our team leveraged R and global health APIs to build more efficient workflows through automation by developing custom …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Efficient and scalable analytics workflows are critical for an adaptive and data-driven organization. How can we scale systems to support an office charged with implementing USAID's $6 billion HIV/AIDS program? Our team leveraged R and global health APIs to build more efficient workflows through automation by developing custom R packages to access health program data. Our investment in creating an automated data infrastructure with flexible, open-source tools like R enabled us to build reproducible workflows for analysts in over 50 partner countries. We would like to share our experience in a federal agency integrating APIs with R to develop scalable data pipelines, as inspiration for organizations facing similar resource &amp;amp; data challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>