<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_torsten-scholak.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Intro to Bayesian Machine Learning with PyMC3 and Edward</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/intro-to-bayesian-machine-learning-with-pymc3-and-edward.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Torsten Scholak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-18:pycon-us-2017/intro-to-bayesian-machine-learning-with-pymc3-and-edward.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been uprising of probabilistic programming and Bayesian
statistics. These techniques are tremendously useful, because they help
us to understand, to explain, and to predict data through building a
model that accounts for the data and is capable of synthesizing it. This
is called the generative approach to statistical pattern recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating the parameters of Bayesian models has always been hard,
impossibly hard actually in many cases for anyone but experts. However,
recent advances in probabilistic programming have endowed us with tools
to estimate models with a lot of parameters and for a lot of data. In
this tutorial, we will discuss two of these tools, PyMC3 and Edward.
These are black box tools, swiss army knifes for Bayesian modeling that
do not require knowledge in calculus or numerical integration. This puts
the power of Bayesian statistics into the hands of everyone, not only
experts of the field. And, it's great that these are implemented in
Python with its rich, beginner-friendly ecosystem. It means we can
immediately start playing with it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have planned three awesome parts, spread over three awesome hours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First hour: Introduction to Bayesian machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second hour: Baby steps in PyMC3 and Edward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third hour: Solve a real-world problem with PyMC3 or Edward (model,
fit, criticize).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>