<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to train an image classifier using PyTorch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-train-an-image-classifier-using-pytorch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neural networks are everywhere nowadays. But while it seems everyone is
using them, training your first neural network can be quite a hurdle to
overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will take you by the hand, and following an example image
classifier I trained, I will take you through the steps of making an
image classifier in PyTorch. I will show you code snippets and explain
the more intricate parts. Also, I will tell you about my experience, and
about what mistakes to prevent. After this all you need to start
training your first classifier is a data set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I will provide a link to the full codebase at the end. The
talk will focus on the practical aspect of training a neural network,
and will only touch the theoretical side very briefly. Some basic prior
knowledge of neural networks is beneficial, but not required, to follow
this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rogier van der Geer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/how-to-train-an-image-classifier-using-pytorch.html</guid><category>Deep Learning</category><category>Fun and Humor</category><category>Image Processing</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>Risk Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2017/risk-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training a genetic algorithm to play the game of Risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popular board game of Risk has many fans around the world. Using a Python-based simulation of the game, we use a genetic algorithm to train a risk-playing algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk we’ll explain what genetic algorithms are and we’ll explain an entertaining use-case: how to win at popular board games. During the talk we’ll demo how object oriented patterns help with the design and implementation of these algorithms. We’ll also demonstrate a library that allows users to push their own risk bots into a game and battle it out on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rogier van der Geer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pydata-amsterdam-2017/risk-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>How to conquer the world</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/how-to-conquer-the-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rogier van der Geer - How to conquer the world
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/a-genetic-algorithm-to-play-the-game-of-risk"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/a-genetic-algorithm-to-play-the-game-of-risk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popular board game of Risk has many fans around the world.
Using a Python-based simulation of the game, we use a genetic
algorithm to train a risk-playing algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk we'll explain what genetic algorithms are and we'll
explain an entertaining use-case: how to win at popular board games.
During the talk we'll  demo how object oriented patterns help with the
design and implementation of these algorithms. We'll also demonstrate
a library that allows users to push their own risk bots into a game
and battle it out on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rogier van der Geer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/how-to-conquer-the-world.html</guid></item></channel></rss>