<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Raspberry Pi Weather Station</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/raspberry-pi-weather-station.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Robinson - Raspberry Pi Weather Station
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
[Education Summit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi weather station project introduces young people to
using python programming to  solve real and technical problems. The
weather station consists of a range of sensors including:
Anemometer
Rain gauge
Wind Vane
Temperature Probe
Barometer
Air Quality Sensor
Hygrometer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1000 kits are being given away to schools to take part in the project
by following our schemes of work which will involve.
Programming basic interrupt based sensors
Advanced Sensors using ADC chips
Create a pygame based UI
Logging data to MySQL and Oracle Apex
Presenting data to a web app
Deploying the weather station
Integrating Apex database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love feedback on the project from Python Developers and
support in updating some libraries from python 2 to 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Robinson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-06:europython-2015/raspberry-pi-weather-station.html</guid></item><item><title>Pycon - A teacher's perspective</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/pycon-a-teachers-perspective.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Robinson - Pycon - A teacher's perspective
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
[Education Summit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perspective of the impact of the PyconUK education track from the
point of view of teachers and educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having attended the education track at Pycon UK 2014 as a teacher, my
talk will share both my experiences and those of other teachers
attending. The  education track bought educators and developers
together in a way that allowed the teachers to get support and advice
whilst developers   get to support teachers in developing exciting &amp;amp;
real applications for teaching computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will focus on two aspects of the education track. The
workshops delivered for teachers by python developers and how this
helps build teachers confidence.  But also the breakout sessions where
educators and developers with common interests can work together to
develop something. This might be a program / library or a teaching
resource, some developers gave a hands on and bespoke training session
to a group of teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are to get more young people programming or at least having  a
positive experience of programming then we need to minimize obstacles
to that experience. By having educators and developers working
together we can identify those obstacles and eliminate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goo.gl/nt05hC"&gt;https://goo.gl/nt05hC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Robinson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-05:europython-2015/pycon-a-teachers-perspective.html</guid></item></channel></rss>