<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Eli Holderness</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_eli-holderness.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Pointers? In my Python? It's more likely than you think</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pointers? In my Python? It's more likely than you think
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Eli Holderness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered about the difference between is and ==, or why you might need to use deepcopy? Maybe you’ve been stumped by an interview question about object lifetimes, or overriding …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pointers? In my Python? It's more likely than you think
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Eli Holderness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered about the difference between is and ==, or why you might need to use deepcopy? Maybe you’ve been stumped by an interview question about object lifetimes, or overriding the __eq__ method. Or, perhaps, you just really want to see some tuples behaving badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me for a tour of some of CPython’s dark memory magic and unintuitive behaviours, where we’ll find out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What pointers are and where you’ll see them in your code;
What the id of a Python object is, and why it matters;
How CPython can tell when you’re done using an object, and what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a wonderful thing that takes all the complication of memory management away from us. We don’t have to worry about pre-allocating memory for our objects, or remember to free it once we’re done. So, given that we’re not doing it manually, how do these things happen? Do we have to care? Well, sometimes. Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll discuss what a pointer is, where they crop in in Python, and what you need to know in order to avoid getting tripped up by them. We’ll also cover the id of an object, why it's implemented the way it is, and why 'equal' is different from 'identical'. Finally, we’ll talk about garbage collection, what reference counting is, and how CPython knows when it’s time to get rid of unused objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you just want to understand what’s going on under the hood without having to dive into the implementation, or you’re on the hunt for some new diabolical things to do with code (self-referential lists are only the beginning!), come along to this talk and learn about the pointers in your Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at anyone with an interest in how Python handles objects in memory, or who’s ever been confused by side-effects popping up in their code. Absolutely no knowledge of C is required, and Python beginners are extremely welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>A Brief History of Data Storage</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/a-brief-history-of-data-storage.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/a-brief-history-of-data-storage.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/a-brief-history-of-data-storage"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/a-brief-history-of-data-storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For millennia, humans have known things. Pretty quickly, we started writing them down; our brains aren't very good at storing all the things we know reliably, and we needed something more durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long time ago …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/a-brief-history-of-data-storage"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/a-brief-history-of-data-storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For millennia, humans have known things. Pretty quickly, we started writing them down; our brains aren't very good at storing all the things we know reliably, and we needed something more durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, this meant clay tablets with cuneiform on them, and things have only got more complicated from there. Nowadays, we try to store data so that computers can understand it too, and that's given us a bewildering array of options - portable hard drives, magnetic tape storage and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll take a look at the history of data storage, and discuss why some methods have worked better than others. We'll talk about why writing things down for humans is different than doing it for computers, and why it's difficult to do both at the same time (this is what code is). Finally, we'll look at today's state-of-the-art for keeping data safe, and discuss what the future might hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk has no prerequisites, although a fondness for weird facts will help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Pointers? In My Python? It's More Likely Than You Think</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2021/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-18:/pycon-india-2021/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyCon India 2021 Online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India is the largest gathering of Pythonistas in India for the Python programming language.
The 13th edition of PyCon India took place online from 17th Sept to 20th Sept 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk Detail: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think~bo2V3/"&gt;https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyCon India 2021 Online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India is the largest gathering of Pythonistas in India for the Python programming language.
The 13th edition of PyCon India took place online from 17th Sept to 20th Sept 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk Detail: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think~bo2V3/"&gt;https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think~bo2V3/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to subscribe to the PyCon India channel: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;
Follow PyCon India on Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconindia"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconindia&lt;/a&gt;
Follow PyCon India on Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/PyConIndia/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/PyConIndia/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon India 2021"></category><category term="PyConIndia"></category><category term="PyConIndia2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Pointers? In my Python? It's more likely than you think</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2022/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-18:/pycon-uk-2022/pointers-in-my-python-its-more-likely-than-you-think.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn about Python's memory handling, including:
- what pointers are, and why it matters
- what object IDs are, and what they mean
- how CPython can tell when you're done with an object, and what happens next&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No C knowledge required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a wonderful thing that takes all the complication …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn about Python's memory handling, including:
- what pointers are, and why it matters
- what object IDs are, and what they mean
- how CPython can tell when you're done with an object, and what happens next&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No C knowledge required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a wonderful thing that takes all the complication of memory management away from us. We don’t have to worry about pre-allocating memory for our objects, or remember to free it once we’re done. So, given that we’re not doing it manually, how do these things happen? Do we have to care? Well, sometimes. Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll discuss what a pointer is, where they crop up in Python, and what you need to know in order to avoid getting tripped up by them. We’ll also cover the &lt;cite&gt;id&lt;/cite&gt; of an object, how it varies between different implementations like IronPython and PyPy, and why &lt;cite&gt;is&lt;/cite&gt; is different from &lt;cite&gt;==&lt;/cite&gt;. Finally, we’ll talk about garbage collection, what reference counting is, and how CPython knows when it’s time to get rid of unused objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you just want to understand what’s going on under the hood without having to dive into the implementation, or you’re on the hunt for some new diabolical things to do with code (self-referential lists are only the beginning!), come along to this talk and learn about the pointers in your Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at anyone with an interest in how Python handles objects in memory, or who’s ever been confused by side-effects popping up in their code. Absolutely no knowledge of C is required, and Python beginners are extremely welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon UK 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>ADHDidn't: 7 Things That Wrecked My Productivity During WFH, and How I Dealt</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2021/adhdidnt-7-things-that-wrecked-my-productivity-during-wfh-and-how-i-dealt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-03-22:/python-web-conf-2021/adhdidnt-7-things-that-wrecked-my-productivity-during-wfh-and-how-i-dealt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;ADHDidn't: 7 Things That Wrecked My Productivity During WFH, and How I Dealt With Them&amp;quot; by: Eli Holderness
I’m just going to say it: I’m Bad at working from home. That’s a problem, because I’ve been doing it for the last year, it looks like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;ADHDidn't: 7 Things That Wrecked My Productivity During WFH, and How I Dealt With Them&amp;quot; by: Eli Holderness
I’m just going to say it: I’m Bad at working from home. That’s a problem, because I’ve been doing it for the last year, it looks like we might have more than a little while to go yet before office life resumes, and my ADHD isn’t exactly going anywhere in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even aside from the myriad ways that remote working can expose issues in a company’s management or communications infrastructure, there are a whole host of problems that can arise on a personal level. In this talk, I discuss some of the ones I’ve grappled with over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can’t stay focused? End up endlessly doomscrolling, or procrastinating for hours before really starting to work for the day? Trouble sleeping, or zoning out during the day with nobody around to keep you on track? If that sounds familiar, stop by and maybe get some ideas of things you can do about it - or at least feel less alone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2021 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2021.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2021"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2021"></category></entry><entry><title>You Shall Not Password: Modern Authentication for Web Apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/you-shall-not-password-modern-authentication-for-web-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eli Holderness</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/you-shall-not-password-modern-authentication-for-web-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the good old days, your users would log into a web app with a username and password. But now people expect an alphabet soup of SSO, 2FA, OAuth, OIDC, SAML, FIDO2, OTP… What do they all mean - and why do they matter? Why is central authentication useful? What …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the good old days, your users would log into a web app with a username and password. But now people expect an alphabet soup of SSO, 2FA, OAuth, OIDC, SAML, FIDO2, OTP… What do they all mean - and why do they matter? Why is central authentication useful? What does two-factor authentication really protect us from, and what’s still wide open? Learn how to keep your users safe as we discuss the good, the bad and the ugly of modern authentication mechanisms for the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll cover what authentication is, common ways of doing it, and common pitfalls. We’ll also cover what makes a web authentication system good, and whether that’s distinct from whether it’s secure (spoiler alert: it is!). Attendees will come away with a sense of what the authentication landscape looks like for modern web apps and why, and a few weird industry factoids to share at dinner parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at anyone passingly familiar with web development, with an interest in security, or who simply wants to know what’s really going on when you ‘sign in with Google.’
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>