<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ryan Cheley</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Contributing to Django or how I learned to stop worrying and just try to fix an ORM Bug</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/contributing-to-django-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-just-try-to-fix-an-orm-bug.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll start with my experience at DjangoCon US 2022 and the work I did while at the sprints on an ORM related bug. Then we'll walk through the process I went through as I realized that the bug I thought could be closed was actually still a bug and needed to be fixed. I'll talk about the process I used to work on the bug and the great support I got from the community (both in person at Django Con US and online afterward).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk you'll realize that while the Django ORM can seem big and scary, and you may be hesitant to try and tackle a bug or other issue related to it, at the end of the day, it's &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key take aways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using public notes as a way to track your learning and progress on (any) issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting comfortable with the idea of becoming the world's foremost expert on an issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting stuck is OK because the Django community is amazing and supportive and wants to see you succeed in fixing this bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Cheley</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/djangocon-us-2023/contributing-to-django-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-just-try-to-fix-an-orm-bug.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Error Culture</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/error-culture.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my talk titled &amp;quot;Error Culture,&amp;quot; I take a deep dive into the widespread but often overlooked issue of how organizations manage error alerts in technology and programming domains. The core of my discussion revolves around the concept of 'error culture'—the organizational tendency to ignore or minimize the significance of error notifications due to their frequency and the false perception of irrelevance. This paradox arises from our dependency on technology and the need to be alerted to failures, which results in a deluge of alerts, many of which are false positives or not actionable, leading to a dangerous desensitization to potentially critical warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through my analysis, I address the serious consequences of error culture, such as the risk it poses by allowing significant alerts to slip through the cracks and the challenges it creates in integrating new team members who lack critical, undocumented knowledge. I pinpoint several root causes behind this phenomenon, including alert fatigue, misunderstandings about the alerts' purpose, and a culture that inadvertently celebrates crisis resolution over preventive measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience has led me to identify certain symptoms that indicate the presence of an error culture, such as an over reliance on email rules to filter alerts and a widespread uncertainty about why certain alerts are received in the first place. To move forward, I propose a refined strategy for managing alerts to ensure they are meaningful, actionable, and directed at the appropriate recipients. This approach involves clarifying the significance of each alert, tailoring them to the correct audience, and providing actionable resolution steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will leave you with a call to action, urging a shift towards a more mindful and efficient approach to error management. By reevaluating our interaction with technology alerts, I believe we can transform them from noise into valuable signals that enhance organizational efficiency, resilience, and growth. Join me as I outline practical steps for combating error culture and fostering a proactive error management environment within our organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Cheley</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-23:/djangocon-us-2024/error-culture.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Error Culture</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/error-culture.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &amp;quot;Error Culture,&amp;quot; I delve into the overlooked issue of disregarding error alerts in tech environments, a practice that stems from alert overload and leads to critical oversights. I dissect the roots, including alert fatigue and a culture that undervalues preventative measures, and highlight symptoms like excessive reliance on email filtering. My talk proposes actionable solutions to ensure alerts are meaningful and directed at the right people, advocating for a shift towards a culture where alerts enhance organizational efficiency and resilience. Join me as I offer insights into transforming error management from a neglected aspect into a cornerstone of proactive organizational strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Cheley</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-08:/pycascades-2025/error-culture.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2025</category></item></channel></rss>