<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The story of stackless Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/the-story-of-stackless-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] C Tismet A Rigo - 4 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk gives a good overview of the status of Stackless Python: Its
history from the beginning, its current status and its future
development to be expected. A discussion and comparison with similar
approaches like Greenlet, Eventlet and how they relate is also included.
Stackless Python 1.0 was started in 1998 as an implementation of true
continuations, with all implied complications. In 2002, Stackless 2.0
was born, a complete rewrite. Continuations were abandoned in favor of
the much easier to comprehend tasklets - one-shot continuations that
could resume their current state just once, like Coroutines. In 2004,
Stackless 3.0 was created, which merged the 2.0 features with a new
concept: so-called “Soft-Switching”, which made the Pickling of Program
State” possible. As a consequence, a few recent application make solely
use of Program State Pickling, which changes the purpose of Stackless
Python quite a bit. One example of this is the “Nagare Web Framework”
which will be shown in examples. In the light of the popularity of a
Stackless spin-off, called “Greenlet”, the concept of a new Stackless
branch will be depicted: Stackless, written as a pure extension module
on top of Greenlets, which includes State Pickling - a feature that
seemed to be impossible to implement without changing CPython. But the
impossible and ways to get around it was always a major topic in this
project, which is going to augment what Stackless on PyPy already can
do. Christian Tismer, creator of Stackless Python Perhaps with Armin
Rigo as a guest, talking about Stackless status in PyPy. Otherwise, I
will insert this myself. cheers – Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Armin Rigo</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-05:europython-2012/the-story-of-stackless-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>