<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kate Wilcox</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kate-wilcox.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Aw Snap! The Docs, They Are A-Changin’ (with apologies to Bob Dylan)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-prague-2017/aw-snap-the-docs-they-are-a-changin-with-apologies-to-bob-dylan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kate Wilcox</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-11:/write-the-docs-prague-2017/aw-snap-the-docs-they-are-a-changin-with-apologies-to-bob-dylan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation explores the evolution of language in technical
documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reign of the long-form narrative in tech docs is long gone. Nobody
wants to read a 600 page user manual cover to cover before using an
application or API. Users crave bite-size chunks of information, and
they want …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation explores the evolution of language in technical
documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reign of the long-form narrative in tech docs is long gone. Nobody
wants to read a 600 page user manual cover to cover before using an
application or API. Users crave bite-size chunks of information, and
they want them exactly at the point of need. They want just enough
information to complete their task and not one conjunction more. In
other words, users want high-calorie nutrient-dense documentation, and
they want it fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To satisfy users, we documentarians embrace minimalism and topic-based
architectures such as DITA. We organize content by type: task, concept,
reference, etc. We use active voice. We keep sentences short. And
consciously or not, we’ve begun to challenge time-honored tech writing
traditions, such as prohibitions on future tense, contractions, idioms,
and colloquialisms – at least in American English documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, it’s no longer enough for docs to be technically accurate.
They must also use contemporary themes familiar to users and, whenever
possible, humor. Exhibit one is this Google Chrome error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Aw Snap! Something went wrong while displaying this webpage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the folks at ReadMe.io used this line to describe a Delete button in
their interface (from the 2007 film, Juno):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is one doodle that can’t be undid, homeskillet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without question, the language we use in technical documentation is
changing. Contractions, idioms, and colloquialisms, which were once
banned as potentially confusing to translators, are now commonplace, and
we use them to make our docs sound friendlier. Jargon abounds, the word
“please” is no longer taboo, and exclamation points are not only
allowed, they’re encouraged! They show enthusiasm for the subject!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we’ll mine the docosphere for current trends,
innovations, and answers to these questions: • How has the language in
tech docs evolved over the past decade, and where is it headed? • What
are the minimum daily requirements for language in this brave new world:
Correct grammar, complete sentences, parallel construction, proper word
choice, clarity, brevity? • What is the role of humor in tech docs? • Is
it OK for tech docs to use colloquialisms, idioms, contractions, and
even emojis? • What are the implications of this evolution on
localization?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Prague 2017"></category></entry></feed>