<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Ministry of Silly Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/the-ministry-of-silly-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyGotham 2019's Lightning Talks&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aditya Sirish</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/the-ministry-of-silly-talks.html</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting and observing Airfare trends using Python and Neural Networks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2018/forecasting-and-observing-airfare-trends-using-python-and-neural-networks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have always been taught that the earlier you book a flight, the
cheaper it is. What if I said it isn't? You see it's not a straight line
and it has a minimum at some point (someday before the flight). We are
going to see how historical Airfare data can help us derive the best day
to book a flight so that you 'actually' get the cheapest fares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk would talk about the entire process, from getting the data, to
training a basic Neural network on the data. With advancements in deep
learning in these few years, it is very easy to train a simple
statistical model to predict the prices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anuj Menta</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-fr-2018/forecasting-and-observing-airfare-trends-using-python-and-neural-networks.html</guid></item><item><title>Visualising the world of competitive programming with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2018/visualising-the-world-of-competitive-programming-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Competitive programming has grown exponentially in the last decade.
Millions of students, teachers, professionals solve problems including
complex optimisations every minute. With the influx of programming
languages, developers have a wide range of tools to choose from and use
them to solve competitive challenges. Some of the popular platforms
include Codeforces, Codechef, Hackerrank, Hackerearth, Topcoder etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we are going to use the dataset of codes scraped from
Codeforces from a variety of challenges. These include programs written
by top rated coders across the world to the newbies. The platform allows
you to code in 26 different languages which obviously include popular
programming languages like C, C++, Java, Javascript, PHP, Python etc.
There are a very wide range of challenges in competitive programming
like Sorting, Binary Search, Trees, Graphs, Dynamic Programming to name
a few. The talk will cover the visualization of the dataset among broad
classifications of how each programming language performs in these
classifications. How efficient are programming languages across
classifications in terms of time and memory and several others? The talk
would also specifically cover the ease of using Python to solve
different classes of challenges in competitive programming and the usage
of Python over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major takeaways :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABC of web scraping and best practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizing web scraping to scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No-SQL databases for storing unstructured data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does Python as a language fare in competitive programming in
terms of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;efficiency and popularity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I pursue competitive programming using Python ONLY?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An analysis of popular programming languages used for solving
challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anuj Menta</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-fr-2018/visualising-the-world-of-competitive-programming-with-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>