<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Overcoming life’s hurdles</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/overcoming-lifes-hurdles.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Believing in your dreams is one of the most important steps you'll take
in goal setting. While many of us can come up with things we want to
accomplish, it is the emotional connection we make with the dream by
believing in its possibility that lead us to action and accomplishments.
For Olympian Sarah Wells, this belief was mandatory to fuel her Olympic
dream after a devastating stress fracture in her leg threatened her
chance of making the team. Sarah's story is one of guts, courage and
perseverance. Audiences will leave inspired to dream big, overcome
obstacles and of course believe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sarah-wells-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sarah Wells Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Wells is a Canadian Olympian specializing in the 400m hurdles.
Recruited by her high school teacher, Sarah fell in love with the sport
of track and 15 years old and field and joined the Toronto Track club in
2005. With only 8 months of training under her belt, Sarah qualified for
her first national team and travelled to Morocco Marrakesh to represent
Canada. Since then Sarah has been a 4-time National Champion and a
7-time National Team member. In 2012, after winning the Canadian
National Championships for the 3rd time in her career, Sarah represented
Canada in the London Olympics and finished as an Olympic Semi Finalist.
Following the Olympics, Sarah continued progressing and came home a
double-medallist from the 2015 Pan-American games held in her home city
of Toronto. Sarah has overcome many obstacles in her career and has set
her sights on becoming a 2-time Olympian at the 2020 Olympics in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sarah Wells</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/overcoming-lifes-hurdles.html</guid></item></channel></rss>