<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Decoupling Django with Django REST (and a sprinkle of React)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/decoupling-django-with-django-rest-and-a-sprinkle-of-react.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="abstract"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of JavaScript as the lingua-franca of the web and the
steady growth of libraries like React, today’s web developers can build
rich and well structured frontend experiences. Pair that with Django and
Django REST framework and you get the perfect combination. But it’s not
all bells and whistles. What challenges are we going to face when
decoupling Django with Django REST? What are the best practices? How to
structure such a project? In this talk I’ll guide Django developers
(both beginners and intermediate) from 0 to structuring a decoupled
Django project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="description"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to give Django developers an overview of a
Django REST project, paired with React, as well as the tradeoffs of the
decoupled approach. By the end of the talk the developer should be able
to configure a new Django REST project and use a frontend library for
interacting with the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-and-when-to-decouple-django"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;1. Why and when to decouple Django&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways for decoupling a Django application and each one
depends on the use case. In this section we’ll outline what decoupling
is, why decoupling is a great approach and why sometimes it is not the
right thing to do. We’ll see what the challenges of such approach are
and how to deal with authentication in a decoupled context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-rest-fundamentals"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;2. Django REST fundamentals&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django REST framework is a Django application for exposing API endpoints
from a Django project. It this section we’ll see the building blocks of
a Django API app: the model, the serializer and the view. Models should
not be a surprise for the audience, they come from Django. Serializers
instead are provided by Django REST. We’ll also see how a Django REST
view looks like and how to leverage both function based views and
generic views within the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="setting-up-the-frontend"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;3. Setting up the frontend&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key for a truly decoupled experience is a frontend for consuming and
interacting with the API. In this section we’ll see how to structure a
Django REST project alongside with React. We will explore two
approaches: fully decoupled frontend and mixed frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-note-on-testing-and-closing-words"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;4. A note on testing and closing words&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of a decoupled Django site we move from the typical
Django tests to testing the API’s response instead. We will see how a
simple API test looks like. And for the JavaScript frontend we’ll take a
look at the current available tooling for functional testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1735"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1735&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valentino Gagliardi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/decoupling-django-with-django-rest-and-a-sprinkle-of-react.html</guid><category>javascript</category><category>django-rest-framework</category><category>REST</category><category>django</category></item></channel></rss>