<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_damon-mcdougall.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to Choose a Good Colour Map</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/how-to-choose-a-good-colour-map.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damon McDougall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/how-to-choose-a-good-colour-map.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representing data through colours is a very common approach to conveying
important information to an audience. We suggest some best practices
scientists should consider when deciding how they should present their
results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representing data through colours is a very common approach to conveying
important information to an audience. This is done throughout all fields
in the scientific community and stakes a claim in the commercial and
marketing realm as well. Colour maps and contour maps are the preferred
way for scientists to visualise three-dimensional data in two
dimensions. Research has shown that the choice of colourmap is crucial
since the human brain interpolates hue poorly. We suggest some best
practices scientists should consider when deciding how they should
present their results. Specifically, we look at some examples of
colourmaps that can easily be misinterpreted, making reference to an
in-depth supportive study, and suggest alternative approaches to improve
them. We conclude by listing some open source tools that aid making good
colourmap choices. Kristen Thyng's talk on perception of colourmaps in
matplotlib is an excellent follow-on from this.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="vis"></category></entry><entry><title>RM204 BOF MatPlotLib Discussion</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/rm204-bof-matplotlib-discussion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damon McDougall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/rm204-bof-matplotlib-discussion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will have an open discussion about current matplotlib enhancement
proposals and take calls for new ones. Anyone interested in matplotlib's
future development efforts is more than welcome to attend. There will be
no presentation. Current MEPs exist here:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/wiki#matplotlib-enhancement-proposals-meps"&gt;https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/wiki#matplotlib-enhancement-proposals-meps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="matplotlib"></category></entry></feed>