<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kristen-m-thyng.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Perceptions of Matplotlib Colormaps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/perceptions-of-matplotlib-colormaps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kristen M. Thyng</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/perceptions-of-matplotlib-colormaps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On several issues related to the perception of colormaps...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The choice of colormap in a scientific figure significantly affects the
way the presented information is perceived by the viewer. This follows
on Damon McDougall's talk on how to choose a colormap for an application
by delving deeper into several important issues and how well many of the
available Matplotlib colormaps stand up against the concerns. For
example, it is known that the human brain is better able to interpret
changes in magnitude of the luminance and saturation of colors in
colormaps instead of the hue. Also, some research has shown that
logarithmic changes in brightness are perceived as linear changes. Next,
being able to print a color plot in black and white from a published
paper is sometimes mandatory and often desirable, and is related to the
grey scale in a colormap. Finally, it is important to account for
various types of color blindness when choosing a divergent colormap for
the plot to be as accessible as possible. All of these concerns have
implications for the design of colormaps, and will be examined in the
context of the properties of the available Matplotlib colormaps in order
to make a best choice for a given application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract and slides available &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dmcdougall/scipy14-colormaps"&gt;on
Github.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="vis"></category></entry></feed>