<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alex-hill.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Many-to-many, minus the middleman</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/many-to-many-minus-the-middleman.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Hill</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/many-to-many-minus-the-middleman.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about an alternative Django ManyToManyField implementation
that uses (abuses?) PostgreSQL's full-text search engine instead of an
intermediary table to store its relationships. As well as showing off
some handy things you can do with this field, we'll talk along the way
about full-text search in Postgres, inverted indexes, and how Django's
ManyToManyField is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, ManyToManyField uses an intermediary table to record
its relationships –&amp;nbsp;a classic relational database technique you most
likely mastered in Databases 101. But to believe some present-day
commentators, classic relational databases with their fixed schemas and
their ACID habit belong back in the 70s where they came from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Postgres, the hip, switched-on parent who works as a public
defender and gets on uncomfortably well with your friends. Postgres
builds on a wealth of relational history while embracing modern
non-relational ideas in a thoughtful, sane way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll press full-text search, one of Postgres' repertoire
of many useful features, into a service it performs remarkably well
despite being designed for quite a different purpose. Code and
benchmarks provided!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>