<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kirk-kaiser.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Recreating "The Clock" with Machine Learning and Web Scraping</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/recreating-the-clock-with-machine-learning-and-web-scraping.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kirk Kaiser</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/recreating-the-clock-with-machine-learning-and-web-scraping.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Clock&amp;quot; is a 2010 art installation by Christian Marclay. It is an
experimental film that features over 12,000 individual shots of clocks from
movies and television, edited in such a way that the film itself functions
as a clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll use modern machine learning models and video web
scraping to recreate the concept behind &amp;quot;The Clock&amp;quot;. We'll use Kubernetes to
orchestrate building a modern video scraper, capable of getting around the
walls of YouTube and Instagram to grab user content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll then use existing machine learning models to infer when clocks occur
in videos, to create our own montage with the found internet video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, we'll learn how to build and monitor machine learning
services meant to scale from our local computers to hundreds of machines.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Birding with Python and Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/birding-with-python-and-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kirk Kaiser</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/birding-with-python-and-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, the power of computer vision has exploded. In this talk, we'll apply a deep learning model to a bird feeder. We'll use that model to detect, identify, and record birds that come to a smart bird feeder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, we'll learn about different platforms to deploy deep learning cameras on, from the lowly Raspberry PI all the way up to the powerful NVIDIA Jetson embedded computer with a built in GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine learning"></category></entry></feed>