<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nicholas-malaya.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>MASA: A Tool for the Verification of Scientific Software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/masa-a-tool-for-the-verification-of-scientific-s.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicholas Malaya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/masa-a-tool-for-the-verification-of-scientific-s.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numerical simulations have a broad range of application, from aircraft
design to drug discovery. However, any prediction from a computer must
be tested to ensure its reliability. Verification ensures the outputs of
a computation accurately reflect the underlying model. This talks covers
MASA, a tool for the verification of software used in a large class of
problems in applied mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numerical simulations have an incredibly broad range of applicability,
from computer aided aircraft design to drug discovery. However, any
prediction arising from a computer model must be rigorously tested to
ensure its reliability. Verification is a process that ensures that the
outputs of a computation accurately reflect the solution of the
mathematical models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will first provide an introduction to the method of
manufactured solutions (MMS), which is a powerful approach for
verification of model problems in which a solution cannot be determined
analytically. However, verifying computational science software using
manufactured&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;solutions requires the generation of the solutions with associated
forcing terms and their reliable implementation in software. There are
several issues that arise in generating solutions, including ensuring
that they are meaningful, and the algebraic complexity of the forcing
terms. After briefly discussing these issues, the talk will introduce
MASA, the Manufactured Analytical Solution Abstraction library. MASA is
an open-source library written in C++ (with python interfaces) which is
designed for the veri?cation of software used for solving a large class
of problems stemming from numerical methods in applied mathematics
including nonlinear equations, systems of algebraic equations, and
ordinary and partial differential equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example formulations in MASA include the Heat Equation, Laplace's
Equation, and the Navier-Stokes Equations, but in principle MASA
supports instantiating any model that can be written down
mathematically. This talk will end with details on two methods to import
manufactured solutions into the library, either by generate the source
terms, or using the automatic differentiation capabilities provided in
MASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library is available at:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/manufactured-solutions/MASA"&gt;https://github.com/manufactured-solutions/MASA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>