<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_guillem-duran-ballester.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hackeando el Reinforcement Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2018/hackeando-el-reinforcement-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillem Duran Ballester</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-es-2018/hackeando-el-reinforcement-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pesar de los recientes avances en el campo del aprendizaje por refuerzo (Reinforcement Learning), generar fácilmente datasets de ejemplos de buena calidad sigue siendo un auténtico infierno. Por suerte, si nos permitimos hacer un poco de trampas y utilizar algoritmos de planificación, es posible conseguirlo. En hackeando el Reinforcement Learning, presentaremos una &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/FragileTheory/FractalAI"&gt;nueva familia de algoritmos de planificación&lt;/a&gt; capaces de obtener puntuaciones sobrehumanas utilizando muy pocos recursos de computación.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de esta charla es ofrecer una explicación intuitiva de cómo funciona esta nueva familia de algoritmos mediante animaciones visuales y demostraciones en vivo. Esta charla estará dividida en cuatro apartados que se corresponden con los pasos a seguir para hackear cualquier sistema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recopilación de información&lt;/strong&gt;: En esta es una breve introducción a los conceptos necesarios para poder seguir la charla y entender el probema que queremos resolver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Escaneo y detección de vulnerabilidades&lt;/strong&gt;: Aquí explicaremos con animaciones visuales y sin entrar en detalles matemáticos en qué consisten los nuevos algoritmos presentados y cómo se integran con el aprendizaje por refuerzo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explotación del sistema&lt;/strong&gt;: Python ofrece una gran cantidad de librerias y herramientas para trabajar con problemas de aprendizaje por refuerzo. En esta sección realizaremos una prueba de concepto en la que mostraremos como generar partidas de Ms.Pacman de calidad sobrehumana en tan solo unos minutos. Además, se mostraran ejemplos de como integrar los algoritmos presentados con las liberías ya existentes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mantener el acceso y gestionar huellas&lt;/strong&gt;: Por último, se explicará que tipo de problemas pueden ser resueltos eficientemente, qué resultados hemos obtenido en diferentes pruebas, y dónde encontrar recursos adicionales para aprender más sobre el tema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esta charla es una adaptación de &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Guillemdb/hacking-rl"&gt;Hacking reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt;, presentada en EuroPython2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Happiness inside a job: a social network analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-barcelona-2017/happiness-inside-a-job-a-social-network-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-20T12:45:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-20T12:45:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Guillem Duran Ballester</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pydata-barcelona-2017/happiness-inside-a-job-a-social-network-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will show how to analyze social network data from a mobile phone application to predict employee turnover and employee happiness. We will look into the process of extracting new features from a dataset using social network analysis techniques. We will also show how these features can be visualized and used to boost machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will show how to analyze social network data to predict employee turnover and employee happiness. This talk is a summary of different notebooks about social network analysis that will be available on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Guillem-db/PyData-Bcn-2017"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. Please note that all the methodology and details we are using, are explained in depth in the notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From tables to graphs: How to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pandas.pydata.org/"&gt;pandas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://networkx.github.io/"&gt;networkx&lt;/a&gt; to merge several DataFrames into a graph, and different criteria for creating a graph representation of a database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph features: How to extract new features using social network analysis techniques such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scikit-learn.org/stable/modules/generated/sklearn.decomposition.NMF.html"&gt;Non-Negative Matrix Factorization&lt;/a&gt; and graph &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://networkx.github.io/documentation/development/reference/algorithms.centrality.html"&gt;centrality metrics&lt;/a&gt;. We will explain what these features represent, and how they relate to other types of features that can be extracted directly from the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving ML models: How to use graph features to boost machine learning models. We will talk about different feature selection techniques that can be used to filter out the most significant set of graph-based features using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scikit-learn.org/"&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization: How to visualize social interactions using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/"&gt;bokeh&lt;/a&gt;, and how visualization techniques can be used to check data integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also review common mistakes that can happen during the modeling process and, how to prevent invalid data from getting leaked into your machine learning models. To conclude we compare the merits of using a Python framework versus R Language in terms of development time and computational performance. Data set provided by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://myhappyforce.com"&gt;https://myhappyforce.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Inside Airbnb: Visualizing data that includes geographic locations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/inside-airbnb-visualizing-data-that-includes-geographic-locations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillem Duran Ballester</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:europython-2017/inside-airbnb-visualizing-data-that-includes-geographic-locations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about creating visualizations for data that includes
geographical locations. We will be using data from InsideAirbnb.com
to represent the current status of Airbnb listings in Mallorca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will show practical examples of different visualizations of geographical data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will start with how to use bokeh to overlay data on google
maps. We will use examples to show how the GMapPlot interface works.
We will briefly explain how to use it,  and what are its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we will talk about plotting shapefiles with holoviews.
Shapefiles are files that describe the shape of maps. We will explain
how to deal with shapefiles. For instance, we will describe how we
use shapefiles to group geographical data by regions. We will also
briefly explain how holoviews works and how it can be used to display
geographical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, we will talk about using datashader and geoviews to
visualize big data. First, we will briefly introduce datashader, bin
based plotting and the datashader Pipeline. After that, we will show
how to create plots with geoviews: how is the Interface, a few use
cases and some examples. Finally, we will move to plotting big data
on interactive maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we will finish with dynamic maps for visualizing time
series: we will explain how do we do it and show some examples of how
to build an interactive dashboard for visualizing geographical data
that varies over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>