<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Alex Monahan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alex-monahan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python and SQL: Better Together, Powered by DuckDB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/python-and-sql-better-together-powered-by-duckdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Monahan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/python-and-sql-better-together-powered-by-duckdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data management systems and data scientists have a troubled
relationship: Common systems such as Postgres or Spark are hard to set
up and maintain, hard to transfer data into and out of, and hard to
integrate into Python workflows. In response, data scientists have
developed their own data wrangling …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data management systems and data scientists have a troubled
relationship: Common systems such as Postgres or Spark are hard to set
up and maintain, hard to transfer data into and out of, and hard to
integrate into Python workflows. In response, data scientists have
developed their own data wrangling tools including Pandas and Polars.
These tools are more natural to use, but are limited in the amount of
data they can process and the amount of automatic optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuckDB is a novel database management system purpose-built to combine
cutting edge data processing and dataframe-like ease of use. DuckDB
integrates deeply with the Python data analytics and engineering
ecosystems - its Python client has over 1.5 million downloads each
month. DuckDB can read and write popular Python dataframe libraries:
Pandas, Polars, and Apache Arrow. DuckDB can even query Pandas
dataframes faster than Pandas itself. Beyond dataframes, reading and
writing is supported for Postgres, MySQL, and SQLite databases, and
across many file formats (even on cloud object storage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the friendliest SQL dialect in the world, DuckDB provides
options for using Pythonic dataframe syntax directly on top of the
database engine. DuckDB includes a relational API, an experimental
PySpark-compatible API, and is the default engine for the Ibis portable
dataframe library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuckDB supports complex queries, is MIT licensed, and has no external
dependencies - it is a single pip install away! It is fast, easy to
install and use, and handles larger than RAM datasets. Since DuckDB runs
in the same process as the Python interpreter, no socket communication
has to occur, making data transfer virtually instantaneous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our talk, we will describe DuckDB, compare it with Python dataframe
libraries, and show how to combine DuckDB and dataframes for fast and
easy data processing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>In Process Analytical Data Management with DuckDB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Monahan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DuckDB is a novel analytical data management system. DuckDB supports complex queries, has no external dependencies, and is deeply integrated into the Python ecosystem. Because DuckDB runs in the same process, no serialization or socket communication has to occur, making data transfer virtually instantaneous. For example, DuckDB can directly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DuckDB is a novel analytical data management system. DuckDB supports complex queries, has no external dependencies, and is deeply integrated into the Python ecosystem. Because DuckDB runs in the same process, no serialization or socket communication has to occur, making data transfer virtually instantaneous. For example, DuckDB can directly query Pandas data frames faster than Pandas itself. In our talk, we will describe the user values of DuckDB, and how it can be used to improve their day-to-day lives through automatic parallelization, efficient operators and out-of-core operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>How to bootstrap a Data Warehouse with DuckDB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/how-to-bootstrap-a-data-warehouse-with-duckdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guen Prawiroatmodjo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/how-to-bootstrap-a-data-warehouse-with-duckdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Data Warehouse (DW) is a powerful tool to manage your scientific data, training data, logs, or any other type of relational data. Most Data Warehouses are cloud-based and built to scale to petabyte workflows, but might not be optimal for smaller workloads that need a fast iteration cycle …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Data Warehouse (DW) is a powerful tool to manage your scientific data, training data, logs, or any other type of relational data. Most Data Warehouses are cloud-based and built to scale to petabyte workflows, but might not be optimal for smaller workloads that need a fast iteration cycle. Likewise, a collection of CSV files and python scripts can become painful to share and maintain. This is where DuckDB comes in! DuckDB is a fast, in-process database that you can run on your laptop, supports a rich SQL dialect, and you can push to the cloud with just a single line of code. In this talk, we’ll show you how to bootstrap a Data Warehouse on your laptop using open source, including ETL (extract-transform-load) data pipelines, dashboard visualization, and sharing via the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>