<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jonathan-helmus.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The Sheer Joy of Packaging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/the-sheer-joy-of-packaging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Sarahan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-10:scipy-2018/the-sheer-joy-of-packaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building packages in Python used to be hard, especially the ones
including compiled extensions. Fortunately, it is getting easier thanks
to efforts in the scientific Python community. However, there are still
a lot of challenges and complexities facing the package builder.There
are at least two major packaging systems (pip/wheel and conda), and lots
of different ways to do work with these systems. This tutorial will
cover packaging from start to finish for both PyPI and conda, including
setup.py, flit, wheels, twine, conda-build, scikit-build, anaconda
cloud, and conda-forge. Particular attention will be paid to critical
details, such as binary compatibility and platform
differences.Presenter(s): Speaker: Michael Sarahan, Anaconda, Inc.
Speaker: Matthew McCormick, Kitware, Inc. Speaker: Jean-Christophe
Fillion-Robin, Kitware, Inc. Speaker: Filipe Fernandes, SECOORA Speaker:
Chris Barker, NOAA Speaker: Matt Craig, Minnesota State University
Moorhead Speaker: Jonathan Helmus, Anaconda, Inc. Speaker: Ray Donnelly,
Anaconda, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Berryconda Scientific Python on the Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/berryconda-scientific-python-on-the-raspberry-pi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Helmus</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:scipy-2017/berryconda-scientific-python-on-the-raspberry-pi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi is a series of low cost single-board computers widely used for teaching computer science and popular with the robotics community. Although Python has been a target programming language on the Pi, the selection of scientific Python packages available in the default Raspbian operating system is often limited. Many of the popular newer libraries are missing, and only older versions of many of the core packages are available. Users wanting a wider and more up-to-date selection of packages are left to compile the software themselves or to use an alternative operating system.     The berryconda project aims to address these limitations. Berryconda is a conda based Python distribution for the Raspberry Pi. With it, you can install and manage a scientific python stack on your Raspberry Pi using conda, an open-source package and environment management system.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Exploring Open Access Weather Radar with the Python ARM Toolkit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/exploring-open-access-weather-radar-with-the-python-arm-toolkit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Helmus</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:scipy-2015/exploring-open-access-weather-radar-with-the-python-arm-toolkit.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Building and Distributing Python Software with Conda</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2016/building-and-distributing-python-software-with-conda.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Helmus</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-07:depy-2016/building-and-distributing-python-software-with-conda.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conda is a cross platform, package management system widely used in the scientific and data science Python communities. Conda can be used to package and distribute software written in any language but has first class support for Python packages. This talk will briefly cover how to use conda to install and manage data science packages as well as how conda can be used to create isolated computing environments. The main focus of the talk will be an in-depth look at how to easily and reproducibly create conda packages for your own Python software, and options for how to share these packages with others. Finally, combining a collection of conda packages into custom cross-platform installable conda-based Python distributions will be explored.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Speeding Up Python Data Analysis Using Cython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/speeding-up-python-data-analysis-using-cython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Helmus</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/speeding-up-python-data-analysis-using-cython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an ideal language for developing software for the analysis of
scientific data. Although packages such as NumPy, SciPy, and pandas can
offer execution speeds similar to those possible using statically typed,
compiled languages, oftentimes Python code is too slow for the task at
hand. Cython is a static compiler for Python which, with the addition of
a few type declarations, allows Python code to execute at significantly
faster speeds. This talk will detail how to use Cython to optimize the
run time of Python code for analysis of scientific data with examples
taken from the development of algorithms in the Python ARM Radar Toolkit
(Py-ART), an open source library for working with weather radar data in
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>