<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michal-zylinski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>From process to production</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-group/from-process-to-production.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michał Żyliński</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-03:pydata-warsaw-group/from-process-to-production.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#11 PyData Warsaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over last few years Microsoft has undergone significant transformation into a truly data-driven enterprise. It required a lot of effort and tools that were built mostly with an internal audience in mind. Now it is time to share our experiences with the wider community. Let's start with very unsexy, yet necessary task - making your models run happily as part of larger IT infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Rise of Cortana: how artificial intelligence has changed global company?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2015/rise-of-cortana-how-artificial-intelligence-has-changed-global-company.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michał Żyliński</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-16:pycon-pl-2015/rise-of-cortana-how-artificial-intelligence-has-changed-global-company.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michał Żyliński &amp;quot;Rise of Cortana: how artificial intelligence has changed global company?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet of Things, big data, machine learning are certainly drawing a lot of attention nowadays. This session is supposed to be practical, hands-on, human-friendly introduction to advanced analytics topics that surround us. It will be about turning data into something cool and hopefully useful. It will be about doing something fast, but not dirty. And yes, it’ll try to explain how Python and open source is helping Microsoft transition towards future.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python i Microsoft – razem czy osobno?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2013/python-i-microsoft-razem-czy-osobno.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michał Żyliński</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-18:pycon-pl-2013/python-i-microsoft-razem-czy-osobno.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Python i Microsoft -- razem czy osobno?
Prelegent/Speaker: Michał Żyliński&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wspólna historia Pythona i Microsoft przypomina górski maraton -- jest długa i kręta. Na przestrzeni ostatnich lat nasz dialog ze środowiskami open-source ewoluował z pozycji zamkniętej twierdzy do coraz bardziej aktywnego angażowania się i wspierania rozwijanych społecznościowo projektów i technologii. Podczas tej sesji postaram się podsumować aktualny stan oferty Microsoft dla wszystkich entuzjastów języka Python, omawiając zarówno rzeczy typowe (np. ofertę narzędziową), jak i bardziej egzotyczne i znane zapewne tylko nielicznym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>