<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Automated Discovery of Cancer Types from Genes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/automated-discovery-of-cancer-types-from-genes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cancer treatment often focuses on organ of origin, but different types
can occur in one organ. Gene expression provides valuable clues of the
cancer type, but studying data manually is difficult. Instead, we use
variational autoencoding, a deep learning method, to derive
36-dimensional feature space from 5000-dimensional gene space and show
its efficacy in classification and a TSNE visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many other diseases are relatively predictable and treatable,
cancer is very diverse and unpredictable, making diagnosis, treatment,
and control extremely difficult. Traditional methods try to treat cancer
based on the organ of origin in the body, such as breast or brain
cancer, but this type of classification is often inadequate. If we are
able to identify cancers based on their gene expressions, there is hope
to find better medicines and treatment methods. However, gene expression
data is so vast that humans cannot detect such patterns. In this
project, the approach is to apply unsupervised deep learning to
automatically identify cancer subtypes. In addition, we seek to organize
patients based on their gene expression similarities, in order to make
the recognition of similar patients easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traditional clustering algorithms use nearest neighbor methods and
linear mappings, we use a recently developed technique called
Variational Autoencoding (VAE) that can automatically find clinically
meaningful patterns and therefore find clusters that have medicinal
significance. Python-based deep learning framework, Keras, offers an
elegant way of defining such a VAE model, training, and applying it. In
this work, the data of 11,000 patients across 32 different cancer types
was retrieved from The Cancer Genome Atlas. A VAE was used to compress
5000 dimensions into 100 clinically meaningful dimensions. Then, the
data was reduced to two dimensions for visualization using tSNE
(t-distributed stochastic neighbor embedding). Finally, an interactive
Javascript scatter plot was created. We noticed that the VAE
representation correctly clustered existing types, identified new
subtypes, and pointed to similarities across cancer types. This
interactive plot of patient data also allows the study of nearest
patients, and when a classification task was created to validate the
accuracy of the representation, it achieved 98% accuracy. The hope is
that this tool will allow doctors to quickly identify specific subtypes
of cancer found using gene expression and allow for further study into
treatments provided to other patients who had similar gene expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shruthi Ravichandran</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/automated-discovery-of-cancer-types-from-genes.html</guid></item></channel></rss>