<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Johannan Hjersman</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_johannan-hjersman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Unlocking Creative Potential Through Teaching</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2024/unlocking-creative-potential-through-teaching.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johannan Hjersman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-21:/pybay-2024/unlocking-creative-potential-through-teaching.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teaching is not merely reserved for academia - it happens everyday in tech. It takes on many forms from instructing an entire team to a new process or an informal knowledge transfer between two engineers. Many shy away from the opportunity, but can find that often the mentor can learn …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teaching is not merely reserved for academia - it happens everyday in tech. It takes on many forms from instructing an entire team to a new process or an informal knowledge transfer between two engineers. Many shy away from the opportunity, but can find that often the mentor can learn as much as the mentee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me as we explore the importance of teaching in tech, where we will start with Bloom's Taxonomy as the driver for learning. From there, I'll provide examples and case-studies from my own experiences in tech and how I learn from those specific use-cases to generalize for future applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Mentor Today, Lead Tomorrow. Why Interns Are Your Next Best Investment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2025/mentor-today-lead-tomorrow-why-interns-are-your-next-best-investment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johannan Hjersman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-10-18:/pybay-2025/mentor-today-lead-tomorrow-why-interns-are-your-next-best-investment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late May, the Federal Reserve Bank of New York announced CS majors ranked 7th in unemployment at 6.1%. With the scarcity of openings for interns and new grads relative to previous years, internships are now more important than ever. Join me in highlighting the value of interns …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late May, the Federal Reserve Bank of New York announced CS majors ranked 7th in unemployment at 6.1%. With the scarcity of openings for interns and new grads relative to previous years, internships are now more important than ever. Join me in highlighting the value of interns to the company, mentor, mentee, and industry as a whole with an example using Python with Pandas and Matplotlib. The talk will also show the benefits of interns both immediate and after the internship experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2025"></category></entry></feed>