<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sebastiaan Zeeff</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Introducing Asynchronous SQLAlchemy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/introducing-asynchronous-sqlalchemy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing Asynchronous SQLAlchemy
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Sebastiaan Zeeff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the increasing popularity of asynchronous frameworks, such as FastAPI, communicating asychronously with databases has become a hot topic in Python development. While there were already a lot of database drivers with asynchronous support available, support for asynchio in Object-Relation Mapping (ORM) frameworks was a lot rarer. That is, until the release of version 1.4 of SQLAlchemy back in March of 2021, which added support for Asynchronous I/O to one of the most popular ORM frameworks for Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Sebastiaan Zeeff will give an overview of the newly added support for asyncio in SQLAlchemy. He will go over how easy it is to set up and use the new AsyncEngine, show you how to avoid getting bitten by some of the pitfalls, and explain how you can use the synchronous functions and methods of SQLAlchemy under asyncio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this talk is an introduction to SQLAlchemy's asyncio support, it is aimed at those who already have some experience with ORM and asyncio. Extensive knowledge of SQLAlchemy is not required, although having a bit of experience with the framework won't hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/introducing-asynchronous-sqlalchemy.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item><item><title>Demystifying Python’s Internals</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/demystifying-pythons-internals.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Demystifying Python’s Internals: Diving into CPython by implementing a pipe operator - presented by Sebastiaan Zeeff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diving into the CPython source code can feel daunting. Whether you want to start contributing or just want to get a better understanding of Python by exploring its source code, it’s often difficult to know where to start or what you’re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will show you around the CPython source code by implementing a new operator, a pipe operator. While doing so, I will discuss core parts of the internals, such as Python’s grammar, its syntax trees, and the underlying logic that will perform the operation. By the end, you will have a good idea of the moving parts involved in core language features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also take you through the steps necessary to make it all work. I’ll show you how I obtained a copy of the source code, regenerated the parser and token files, and how I compiled my modified version of CPython. I will also write and run tests to help me implement my changes. This should give you a mental framework that helps you while diving into more comprehensive resources, like the excellent Python Developer’s Guide (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://devguide.python.org/"&gt;https://devguide.python.org/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is aimed at everyone who wants to explore CPython’s internals. You don’t have to be an expert in Python, although some affinity with Python helps with understanding the internals. I will also use C to implement some of the operator logic, but knowledge of C is by no means required. In short, if you’re interested in diving into the CPython source code, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/demystifying-pythons-internals.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Don’t Panic! A Developer’s Guide to Security</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/dont-panic-a-developers-guide-to-security.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-20]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/dont-panic-a-developers-guide-to-security"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/dont-panic-a-developers-guide-to-security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, you play a crucial role in the security of your projects. At the same time, it can be difficult to know if what you’re doing is enough. Luckily, you don’t have to be a security expert to contribute to the security of your projects. Instead, you can use industry standards as a guide for your approach to security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce you to a framework that is especially accessible to developers, the [OWASP DevSecOps Maturity Model](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://owasp.org/www-project-devsecops-maturity-model/"&gt;https://owasp.org/www-project-devsecops-maturity-model/&lt;/a&gt;), and help you get started with a systematic approach to improving the security of your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/dont-panic-a-developers-guide-to-security.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Demystifying Python’s Internals: Diving Into CPython｜Sebastiaan Zeeff｜PyCon APAC 2022</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2022/demystifying-pythons-internals-diving-into-cpythonsebastiaan-zeeffpycon-apac-2022.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon APAC 2022｜一般演講 Talks｜國泰金控 Cathay Financial Holdings / 美光科技 Micron 冠名贊助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✏️ 共筆 Note：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/SyOpLpmkj"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/SyOpLpmkj&lt;/a&gt;
🖐🏻 Slido：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://app.sli.do/event/4u3ARAHdFep9SSeVgb6Smr"&gt;https://app.sli.do/event/4u3ARAHdFep9SSeVgb6Smr&lt;/a&gt;
💬 語言 Language：英文 English
🎯 層級 Level：中階 Intermediate
🔎 分類 Category：Python 核心 Python Core&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 摘要 Abstract 💡
Diving into the Python source code can feel daunting. In my talk, I will take you through Python's internals by showing you how to implement a new operator, a pipe operator. This will take you on a journey through all the steps Python takes to execute your code, from parsing your code to evaluating bytecode. By the end, you will have a mental framework that allows you to dive into more comprehensive resources with more confidence. You don't have to be an expert in Python to follow along, although some affinity with Python will help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 講者介紹 About Speaker - Sebastiaan Zeeff 🚀
Sebastiaan is a Software Engineer for the Ordina Pythoneers and a Fellow of the Python Software Foundation. He has a passion for teaching Python and writing clean code. Sebastiaan is also active in the Python community, as an owner of Python Discord, open-source contributor, and Python educator. As a public speaker, he makes frequent appearances at Python conferences, including various regional PyCons, EuroPython, FOSDEM, and Pyjamas Conf. Sebastiaan lives in The Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#python #pycontw #pyconapac2022 #python #cpython #pipeoperator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycontw.blogspot.com"&gt;https://pycontw.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-03:/pycon-apac-2022/demystifying-pythons-internals-diving-into-cpythonsebastiaan-zeeffpycon-apac-2022.html</guid><category>PyCon APAC 2022</category></item><item><title>The Magic of Self: How Python inserts self into methods</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2023/the-magic-of-self-how-python-inserts-self-into-methods.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how &lt;cite&gt;self&lt;/cite&gt; works? Whenever you call a method, &lt;cite&gt;self&lt;/cite&gt; seems to magically appear as an argument. But behind this dark magic lies a well-defined protocol, the descriptor protocol, that you can implement yourself. Join me and learn how Python inserts &lt;cite&gt;self&lt;/cite&gt; into methods!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phrase that I hear a lot is that “Python is easy to learn but hard to master”. In a way that’s true: Python’s many abstractions allow you to focus on the business logic of your code instead of the lower-level implementation details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, most of Python’s abstractions aren’t &lt;em&gt;magical&lt;/em&gt;: Its versatile data model allows you to hook into almost every aspect of the language to implement objects that behave just as Python’s built-in objects do. This enables you to create new types of objects that have high-level interfaces of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I want to entice you to explore the wonderful landscape of Python’s data model by diving into an especially magical feature: The automatic insertion of &lt;cite&gt;self&lt;/cite&gt; into methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first came across &lt;cite&gt;self&lt;/cite&gt; in a method signature, chances are that you learned that inserting the instance into methods is just something Python does for you; that you shouldn’t worry too much about it. I will go one step further and show you that there’s a well-defined protocol behind this magic, the descriptor protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end, not only should you be able to implement descriptors of your own, but you should also be able to recognize that some well-known features of Python, such as properties and classmethods, are implemented using the same descriptor protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-24:/pycon-uk-2023/the-magic-of-self-how-python-inserts-self-into-methods.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2023</category></item><item><title>The magic of "self": How Python inserts "self" into methods.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/the-magic-of-self-how-python-inserts-self-into-methods.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A phrase that I hear a lot is &amp;quot;Python is easy to learn, but hard to master&amp;quot;. In a way that's true: Python is easy to learn because its high level of abstraction allows you to focus on the business logic of what you're trying to do instead of the lower-level implementation details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Python's abstraction isn't magical: Its versatile data model allows you to hook into almost every part of the language to implement objects that behave just as Python's built-in objects do, enabling you to create similarly high-leveled interfaces for your own objects. That's where &amp;quot;hard to master&amp;quot; comes in: There is so much to learn that you're never done learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I want to entice you to look beyond Python's high-level interface into the wonderful landscape of its data model. I'll do that by explaining one of Python's most &amp;quot;magical&amp;quot; features: The automatic insertion of self into methods. Often, to beginners, the insertion of the instance as the first argument to methods is explained as something that Python just does for you: &amp;quot;Don't worry about it, it just happens!&amp;quot;. More intermediate Python programmers typically get so used to self that they hardly notice it anymore in their function signatures, let alone wonder about what's powering it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain this bit of Python magic, I’ll give you an informal introduction to something called descriptors. To be sure, this talk isn’t going to be an in-depth discussion of the finer details of the descriptor protocol. Rather, it’s aimed at advanced beginners and intermediate Python developers who are eager to get an idea of what lies beneath the surface of Python. With this talk, I hope to pique your curiosity about the more advanced features of the Python programming language and hopefully give you a glimpse of all the things that are possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sebastiaanzeeff.nl/pycon"&gt;https://sebastiaanzeeff.nl/pycon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/the-magic-of-self-how-python-inserts-self-into-methods.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>Demystifying Python’s Internals: Diving into CPython by implementing a pipe operator</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/demystifying-pythons-internals-diving-into-cpython-by-implementing-a-pipe-operator.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diving into the CPython source code can feel daunting. Whether you want to start contributing or just want to get a better understanding of Python by exploring its source code, it’s often difficult to know where to start or what you’re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will show you around the CPython source code by implementing a new operator, a pipe operator. While doing so, I will discuss core parts of the internals, such as Python’s grammar, its syntax trees, and the underlying logic that will perform the operation. By the end, you will have a good idea of the moving parts involved in core language features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also take you through the steps necessary to make it all work. I’ll show you how I obtained a copy of the source code, regenerated the parser and token files, and how I compiled my modified version of CPython. I will also write and run tests to help me implement my changes. This should give you a mental framework that helps you while diving into more comprehensive resources, like the excellent Python Developer’s Guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is aimed at everyone who wants to explore CPython’s internals. You don’t have to be an expert in Python, although some affinity with Python helps with understanding the internals. I will also use C to implement some of the operator logic, but knowledge of C is by no means required. In short, if you’re interested in diving into the CPython source code, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan Zeeff</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/demystifying-pythons-internals-diving-into-cpython-by-implementing-a-pipe-operator.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>talk</category></item></channel></rss>