<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Maren Westermann</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building diverse open source communities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/building-diverse-open-source-communities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today state of the art scientific research as well as industrial software development strongly depend on open source libraries. The demographic of the contributors to these libraries is predominantly white and male. In order to increase participation of groups who have been historically underrepresented in this domain PyLadies Berlin, a volunteer run community group focussed on helping marginalised people to professionally establish themselves in tech, has been running hands on monthly open source hack nights for more than a year. After some initial challenges the initiative yielded encouraging results. This talk summarises the learnings and teaches how they can be applied in the wider open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maren Westermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/building-diverse-open-source-communities.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>How to increase diversity in open source communities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/how-to-increase-diversity-in-open-source-communities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today state of the art technology and scientific research strongly depend on open source libraries. The demographic of the contributors to these libraries is predominantly white and male. This situation creates problems not only for individual contributors outside of this demographic but also for open source projects such as loss of career opportunities and less robust technologies. In recent years there have been a number of various recommendations and initiatives to increase the participation in open source projects of groups who are underrepresented in this domain. While these efforts are valuable and much needed, contributor diversity remains a challenge in open source communities. This talk highlights the underlying problems and explores how we can overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maren Westermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/how-to-increase-diversity-in-open-source-communities.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category></item></channel></rss>