<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Rita Kesrouani</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Giving Python to non-developers: A real-life story</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2022/giving-python-to-non-developers-a-real-life-story.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how JPMorgan gave access to Python to hundreds of non-developers: what infrastructure was required, what training was given and how to shift the culture.  Lessons learnt from the human side of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When JPMorgan decided to give Python development tools to hundreds of non-developers, it was a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the huge amounts of financial data available and the tools becoming easier to use, it made sense to allow the business to extract relevant information directly themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly the infrastructure had to be there: a Python development &amp;amp; runtime environment, access to data and to JPMorgan analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But having the infrastructure ready was only the beginning.  We needed training.  It needed to be relevant, rewarding, and even fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about the culture?  How do we get non-developers to take their first plunge into Python, and then get into good development habits, without becoming full-time developers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story of our on-going journey.  We learnt some important lessons along the way.  We’ll share them so that you too can give Python to non-developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philippe Masson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-17:/pycon-uk-2022/giving-python-to-non-developers-a-real-life-story.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2022</category></item></channel></rss>