<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kismat Singh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kismat-singh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Enabling AI Everywhere with PyTorch and Intel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/enabling-ai-everywhere-with-pytorch-and-intel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kismat Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/enabling-ai-everywhere-with-pytorch-and-intel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlocking the availability of and access to generative AI technologies has great societal value. In this keynote, Kismat Singh will present how open software built on industry-standard frameworks such as PyTorch, and ubiquitous hardware from Intel that forms a large part of the current installed base across edge, PC …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlocking the availability of and access to generative AI technologies has great societal value. In this keynote, Kismat Singh will present how open software built on industry-standard frameworks such as PyTorch, and ubiquitous hardware from Intel that forms a large part of the current installed base across edge, PC and cloud are keys to democratizing AI and allowing new solutions to be implemented across industries ranging from healthcare, telecommunication, industrial and more. Kismat will share his thoughts on how software acceleration, flexibility and security are important factors in deploying AI applications in production and what he sees as challenges with those projects. He will also discuss Open Platform for Enterprise AI (OPEA), a new Linux Foundation AI and Data project that gives developers access to open source, standardized, modular, and heterogenous retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines that they can use for their enterprise-grade Generative AI deployments. Lastly, he will share some exciting Intel contributed features recently upstreamed into PyTorch. He will end the keynote by stating what he believes to be the future of AI and the part each of us will play in it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>