<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to Learn Django the Wrong Way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/how-to-learn-django-the-wrong-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to Learn Django the Wrong Way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday 12:15 p.m.--1 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Novice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you remember your very first Django project and some embarrassing
mistakes you made? Come hear about some 'aha' moments of a novice
Djangonaut! I'll share valuable lessons I learned by doing things the
wrong way. If you are a Django novice, you'll learn some pitfalls to
avoid. If you are a seasoned Djangonaut, you can find out challenges
that a new Djangonaut, your new hire or mentee may face! Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you remember your very first Django project and some mistakes you
made? Or are you a Django novice embarking on your first application or
struggling with one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come hear about my experiences as an entry developer &amp;#64;InVitae. In this
talk, I'll give a quick overview of my first Django project and give
snapshots to explain how it changed over time. There will be code
snippets to show some horrible code I initially wrote, consequences of
those code, and improvements that were made later. In the process,
you'll find out how I learned Django (more accurately, still learning)
by doing things the wrong way and how one can learn about good software
engineering practices through bad practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some potential topics include: Where does this function belong-- in
models or views or another file? Facing the consequences of bad schema
in an agile programming environment Auto-reloading troubles to removing
the cache layer Migrating from function-based views to class-based views
A posteriori testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is two-fold: to give a fresh perspective on how
building a Django application may be like for the complete newbie (those
new to programming and to Django), and to help prevent other beginners
from making the same mistakes I made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Moon Limb</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-03:djangocon-us-2013/how-to-learn-django-the-wrong-way.html</guid></item></channel></rss>