<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Thibaud Colas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Accessibility wins for Django projects - Thibaud Colas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2020/accessibility-wins-for-django-projects-thibaud-colas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon Europe 2020 (Virtual)
September 19, 2020 - 13h15 (GMT+1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Accessibility wins for Django projects” by Thibaud Colas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is a big topic, which can be hard to approach. We'll look at how the team behind Wagtail set to work on making their CMS more accessible, focusing on Django-specific improvements that are relevant to all projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thibaud Colas</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-19:/djangocon-europe-2020/accessibility-wins-for-django-projects-thibaud-colas.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2020</category></item><item><title>Kontrasto: improving accessibility with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/kontrasto-improving-accessibility-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces [Kontrasto](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kontrasto.netlify.app/"&gt;https://kontrasto.netlify.app/&lt;/a&gt;), a library for Django and Wagtail that automatically improves the contrast of text over images. We’ll look into how it works, how accessibility guidelines define color contrast, and more generally where Django developers’ expertise can be used to improve accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kontrasto is a dual client-side and server-side library, with both approaches bringing some benefits and drawbacks. If time allows, we’ll compare both approaches and think of the implications for performance and energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thibaud Colas</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-22:/djangocon-us-2021/kontrasto-improving-accessibility-with-python.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>Django’s accessibility track record</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/djangos-accessibility-track-record.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are great accessibility guidelines out there. Great tools to evaluate individual websites too. Between the big picture and individual projects, we can look at what Django specifically does – and what changes at the level of the framework could improve large swaths of the Django web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start by looking at the HTTP Archive’s dataset of 8M websites, 30’000 of which are built with Django. We can identify which issues are common compared to other frameworks, and review specific issues in more depth to understand where they might appear in Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can then look into the implementation details to understand exactly how users of assistive technology would benefit or be harmed by Django’s design choices. And accordingly highlight the correct approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A practical example of this where we can go very deep is Django’s implementation of HTML forms. Django’s default markup previously left a lot to be desired, and it being “the default” led to a lot of websites shipping with accessibility issues. This has been improved from release to release, addressing basic issues and introducing more advanced patterns like ARIA attributes for errors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thibaud Colas</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-18:/djangocon-us-2023/djangos-accessibility-track-record.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Faster, leaner, greener: 10x lower website carbon emissions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/faster-leaner-greener-10x-lower-website-carbon-emissions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ll first look at a quantitative assessment of thousands of Django websites on the web, to get a good picture of the Django ecosystem’s overall emissions, and understand which specific aspects of a project contribute to overall power and resource usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll then dive deeper on a single Django website’s energy use, studying djangoproject.com specifically, as a good example of a high-traffic website with a big footprint. We’ll use different performance testing, power measurement, and generic static analysis tools to understand how the site could be improved. We will review common issues, straightforward improvements, and more “pie in the sky” changes that are attainable with effort:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy consumption of front-end technology (React, HTMX, vanilla JS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How design affects emissions (light vs. dark mode, image assets, fonts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application server: serverless Django options to reduce emissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database: how SQLite and other &amp;quot;serverless&amp;quot; database options can reduce emissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overlap with common Django performance considerations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thibaud Colas</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-24:/djangocon-us-2024/faster-leaner-greener-10x-lower-website-carbon-emissions.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>