<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jon Nordby</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Audio Classification with Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/audio-classification-with-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Sound is a rich source of information about the world around us.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Modern deep learning approaches can give human-like performance on a
range of sound classifiction tasks.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This makes it possible to build systems that use sound to for example:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;understand speech, to analyze music, to assist in medical diagnostics,
detect quality problems in manufacturing, and to study the behavior of
animals.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk will show you how to build practical machine learning models
that can classify sound.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We will convert sound into spectrograms, a visual representation of
sound over time,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;and apply machine learning models similar to what is used to for image
classification.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The focus will be on Convolutional Neural Networks, which have been
shown to work very well for this task.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The Keras and Tensorflow deep learning frameworks will be used. Some
tricks for getting usable results with small amounts of data will be
covered, including transfer learning, audio embeddings and data
augmentation.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;A basic understanding of machine learning is recommended.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Familiarity with digital sound is a bonus.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jon Nordby</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/audio-classification-with-machine-learning.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Deep Learning</category><category>Machine-Learning</category></item><item><title>Sound Event Detection with Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/sound-event-detection-with-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sound Event Detection with Machine Learning
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Jon Nordby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound Events (or Audio Events or Acoustic Events) are individual distinct sounds. This could be the pop of roasting popcorn kernels, the cough of a patient, a car that is passing by on a road, or the sound of an alarm in an office building. Sound Event Detection (SED) is the task of detecting such sounds, returning precise times that each kind (class) of sound occurs. It finds uses in music analysis, manufacturing, medicine and noise monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will show how to realize a basic Sound Event Detection system in Python, using fermentation tracking of beer brewing as a fun and practical example. The talk will cover all major parts of such a system, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting and exploring a custom dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the supervised learning task from the dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracting spectrogram features from audio waveforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Recurrent Neural Network (RNN)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running the trained model on an real-time audio stream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processing model output probabilties into discrete events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the performance of the resulting SED system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example code in Python covering these aspects will be provided.
Libraries used with be Keras, TensorFlow and scikit-learn for machine learning, and pysoundfile, sounddevice and librosa for audio processing, with some numpy and pandas for general data manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jon Nordby</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/sound-event-detection-with-machine-learning.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item></channel></rss>