<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michelle-brenner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Ahead in the Clouds: How to get started with serverless on Google, Amazon &amp; Microsoft</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/ahead-in-the-clouds-how-to-get-started-with-serverless-on-google-amazon-microsoft.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michelle Brenner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/ahead-in-the-clouds-how-to-get-started-with-serverless-on-google-amazon-microsoft.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serverless apps are everywhere these days, but how do you get started?
How do you decide which provider to go with? I have created the same
Python app with 3 services, AWS, Google Cloud &amp;amp; Microsoft Azure. I will
go over the highlights and lowlights, and how to judge what’s right for
your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serverless apps are everywhere these days, but how do you get started?
How do you decide which provider to go with? I have created the same
Python based app with 3 services, AWS, Google Cloud &amp;amp; Microsoft Azure. I
will go over the highlights and lowlights, and how to judge what’s right
for your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal for creating this app was to answer these questions. What
services are available for which languages, but especially Python? How
fast can I get to coding? How do I programmatically define the
infrastructure? How do I test everything? How is their CI/CD pipeline?
How do I secure the app? How can I monitor what is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my research I ran into a common problem. There are guides on how
to use the UI to create samples. There is technical documentation that
will give you the name of the flag you are looking for. There is rarely
a user story to help you go from nothing to a running application. My
user story is that I wanted an endpoint that allows you to add data to
persistent storage, get, edit and delete that data. Seems
straightforward, but there is a steep learning curve that had me tearing
my hair out. This talk is not just to give you a better understanding of
serverless offerings, but to keep you from getting discouraged at the
inevitable blockers. At the end of this talk you’ll walk out with the
confidence to create your first serverless microservice and smash any
walls you hit along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Data to Get Your Next Raise</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2018/using-data-to-get-your-next-raise.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michelle Brenner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-23:pydata-la-2018/using-data-to-get-your-next-raise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people dread the annual review process. It is difficult to remember
everything you have done and summarize it in a concise, clear way. As
engineers, there is the additional factor of translating technical
achievements into a format business folks can understand. I propose a
solution for tracking and reporting achievements in a way that’s simple
and easy for stakeholders to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>