<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Emily Riederer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>dbtplyr: Bringing Column-Name Contracts from R to dbt</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/dbtplyr-bringing-column-name-contracts-from-r-to-dbt.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;starts_with(language): Translating select helpers to dbt. Translating syntax between languages transports concepts across communities. We see a case study of adapting a column-naming workflow from dplyr to dbt's data engineering toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dplyr's select helpers exemplify how the tidyverse uses opinionated design to push users into the pit of success. The ability to efficiently operate on names incentivizes good naming patterns and creates efficiency in data wrangling and validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in a polyglot world, users may find they must leave the pit when comparable syntactic sugar is not accessible in other languages like Python and SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will explain how dplyr's select helpers inspired my approach to 'column name contracts,' how good naming systems can help supercharge data management with packages like {dplyr} and {pointblank}, and my experience building the {dbtplyr} to port this functionality to dbt for building complex SQL-based data pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/emilyriederer/dbtplyr"&gt;https://github.com/emilyriederer/dbtplyr&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://emilyriederer.com"&gt;https://emilyriederer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Emily Riederer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/dbtplyr-bringing-column-name-contracts-from-r-to-dbt.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Python Rgonomics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/python-rgonomics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science languages are increasingly interoperable with advances like Arrow, Quarto, and Posit Connect. But data scientists are not. Learning the basic syntax of a new language is easy, but relearning the ergonomics that help us be hyperproductive is hard. In this talk, I will explore the influential ergonomics of R's tidyverse. Next, I will recommend a curated stack that mirrors these ergonomics while also being genuinely truly Pythonic. In particular, we will explore packages (polars, seaborn objects, greattables), frameworks (Shiny, Quarto), dev tools (pyenv, ruff, and pdm), and IDEs (VS Code extensions). The audience should leave feeling inspired to try Python while benefiting from their current knowledge and expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Emily Riederer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/python-rgonomics.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>