<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mike Van Winkle</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mike-van-winkle.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>From Hobby to Planet Scale: 5 Different Ways to Deploy Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2025/from-hobby-to-planet-scale-5-different-ways-to-deploy-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Van Winkle</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-27:/north-bay-python-2025/from-hobby-to-planet-scale-5-different-ways-to-deploy-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Van Winkle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/ZSMCNT"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/ZSMCNT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're finally done building your super awesome world-changing python project and now you want to get it out there. Where do you start? DIY? Premium Services? In this talk I will cover 5 different ways to deploy Python and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Van Winkle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/ZSMCNT"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/ZSMCNT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're finally done building your super awesome world-changing python project and now you want to get it out there. Where do you start? DIY? Premium Services? In this talk I will cover 5 different ways to deploy Python and when you should use them. Whether you have a small hobby site that you want to deploy on the cheap, or have a big project you expect to scale, we will discuss all the things you need to consider when deploying Python. I will present a matrix of decision vectors (complexity, reliability, scale, cost, fun) and how each approach stacks up and examples and references of each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approaches included in this talk will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-managed (self-hosted) VPS using native ubuntu –  This approach is best suited for hobby sized or small to medium projects where the primary deciding factor is either cost or learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-managed VPS hosting with Docker – This approach is also suitable for small projects but having to install and manage docker containers introduces additional complexity, though that complexity may be useful once you need to scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serverless using AWS Lambda – This approach can be cost effective for small to medium projects, but the complexity may not be worth it for hobby sized projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serverless using Kubernetes – This is a very complex approach but is likely the best way to affordably scale to planet scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Premium services like Vercel or Render –  This approach is great for some projects but not for all. I will cover the when and when not to consider using premium services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Apr 27 13:10:00 2025 at Reis River Ranch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="North Bay Python 2025"></category></entry></feed>