<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_liana-bakradze.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Learning Python like a Pro</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/learning-python-like-a-pro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liana Bakradze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/learning-python-like-a-pro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many awesome tools to learn and teach Python to beginners. You can teach it with games, interactive tutorials and microcontrollers. However, if one is to stay in the world of programming, sooner or later one needs to start using more professional tools such as IDEs, debuggers, profilers, version control systems and databases. Needless to say, the transition from IDLE to PyCharm can be very frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating your own course is a time-consuming process, but after the course has been created you also need to check students' solutions which consumes even more time. Wouldn't it be great to automate checking process and to concentrate on the creative part of content creation and explaining concepts to students?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an attempt to solve these problems &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/10081-edutools"&gt;EduTools plugin&lt;/a&gt; was created.
It’s a free open-source plugin that can be installed on PyCharm/IntelliJ
IDEA IDEs to create and take programming courses right inside the IDE.
This way a novice programmer dives into professional environment
straight away and an educator gets a tool to automate solution checking.
Not only the plugin allows to create courses, but it also comes with
integration with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://stepik.org"&gt;Stepik MOOC platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'd like to demonstrate how one can create a course with automated checks using EduTools plugin, share it with students and connect to Stepik platform to gather solutions and statistics. I'll show how to create a simple course containing theory, code task with feedback prompts and test with choice problems. I'll also show how to use our existing free courses in class with the ability to view your students' solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Learn Python The Fun Way</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/learn-python-the-fun-way.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liana Bakradze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-28:europython-2016/learn-python-the-fun-way.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liana Bakradze - Learn Python The Fun Way
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/learn-python-the-fun-way"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/learn-python-the-fun-way&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming is one of the most important 21st-century skills and tons
of different online and offline resources can help you to master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, playing games is really effective way for us to
learn and it's also the most fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is it possible to learn real programming language like Python by
playing a game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll show you some projects that allow you to achieve
that. I also want to inspire you to help such projects and to suggest
ideas how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming is one of the most important 21st-century skills. It
doesn't only provide promising career opportunities but teaches how to
reason logically, systematically and creatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code readability, rich standard library, straightforward syntax and
other features make Python a great language for teaching beginners how
to program. Python community is very supportive and friendly to
newcomers and does awesome work to make Python available to everyone.
Tons of different online and offline resources can help you to master
Python programming. Problem solving is the classical way of learning
how to code. But it can be boring for some people, especially for
kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, playing games is really effective way for us to
learn and it's also the most fun. You can find different games
designed to teach basics of programming, but most of them use special
visual environments and don't teach real text based languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is it possible to learn programming language like Python by playing a game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll show you a few projects for different age and levels
that allow you to achieve that. I'll pay attention on methods that are
used to teach programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to inspire you to help such projects and to suggest ideas
how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="education"></category><category term="gamification"></category></entry></feed>