<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_cenk-bircanoglu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Image Generation with Tensorflow (GANs)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/image-generation-with-tensorflow-gans.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cenk Bircanoğlu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/image-generation-with-tensorflow-gans.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an opensource language that has a wide community, and nowadays
the biggest companies also create frameworks, libraries with Python and
open- sourced them. Tensorflow is the most used library in Deep Learning
by researchers and there are many examples of various fields like
Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Signal Processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, Generative Adversarial Networks a.k.a. GAN collect nearly all
interests on it by the Computer Vision experts. There are diverse
applications like image colorization, image generation from random
numbers, computer game character creation, face frontalization, face
alignment, 2D to 3D image transfer, style transfer and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we are going to talk about GANs and the implementation
details on Tensorflow which is backed by Google and has the power of
either work on CPU and GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation of GANs can be divided into 2 parts. One is called
generator and other is called discriminator. In this talk, the
differences between the discriminator and generator also are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, some various architecture of GANs like PGGAN, DCGAN, STARGAN,
architectures showed in Tensorflow code, which of these are not already
implemented in Tensorflow by the date now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session will be finished with showing some examples of outputs in
face generation, room generation, and also live demo of the style
transfer implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="image-processing"></category><category term="computer-science"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category><category term="ComputerVision"></category></entry></feed>