<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jimmy Jia</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jimmy-jia.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Using Flask-RESTy to build flexible REST APIs, fast!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/flaskcon-2020/using-flask-resty-to-build-flexible-rest-apis-fast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jimmy Jia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-04:/flaskcon-2020/using-flask-resty-to-build-flexible-rest-apis-fast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents Flask-RESTy, a modular library for building REST APIs using Flask along with SQLAlchemy and marshmallow. Flask-RESTy provides a flexible API with multiple levels of abstraction, ranging from high-level helpers that allow building CRUD APIs in just a few lines of code, to lower-level helpers that allow …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents Flask-RESTy, a modular library for building REST APIs using Flask along with SQLAlchemy and marshmallow. Flask-RESTy provides a flexible API with multiple levels of abstraction, ranging from high-level helpers that allow building CRUD APIs in just a few lines of code, to lower-level helpers that allow implementing highly customized business logic while preserving consistent authorization and validation logic. Through the use of these different elements of the library built on top of each other, developers can both implement complex endpoints in a consistent way and quickly spin up more conventional endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="FlaskCon 2020"></category><category term="Flask-resty"></category><category term="Flask"></category><category term="FlaskCon"></category></entry></feed>