<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Zero Code to Python Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2018/from-zero-code-to-python-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teaching computational thinking in the classroom is a challenge as there's a wide range of skills, including the teacher's.
The Gigglebot is a microbit rover that covers the steps from no coding to Python coding through a variety of approaches so that no one in the classroom gets left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation page -- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2018.pycon.ca/talks/talk-PC-54340"&gt;https://2018.pycon.ca/talks/talk-PC-54340&lt;/a&gt;
Author website --  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eleanorstrib.com/"&gt;http://eleanorstrib.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Parrot</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ca-2018/from-zero-code-to-python-code.html</guid></item><item><title>Multiprocessing: how to run Blockly generated code in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2017/multiprocessing-how-to-run-blockly-generated-code-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockly is a front-end GUI developed by Google that allows developers to create a drag-and-drop language for their product. However Blockly only generates a string and does not run code directly. I will take a look at the various potential approaches to execute code that is in a string:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exec - quick for short commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subprocess - can be interrupted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiprocessing - can pass data back and forth by using queues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is mainly about launching processes, dealing with zombies, interrupting processes based on user input and passing data back and forth between processes. Brief mentions of Flask are to be expected. Examples will be based on my experience in developing Bloxter a graphical drag-and-drop language for the GoPiGo3 to be used at home or in classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Parrot</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-19:pycon-ca-2017/multiprocessing-how-to-run-blockly-generated-code-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Multiprocessing: how to run Blockly generated code in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/montreal-python/multiprocessing-how-to-run-blockly-generated-code-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockly is a front-end GUI developed by Google that allows developers to create a drag-and-drop language for their product. However Blockly only generates a string and does not run code directly. I will take a look at the various potential approaches to execute code that is in a string: exec - quick for short commands subprocess - can be interrupted * multiprocessing - can pass data back and forth by using queues The talk is mainly about launching processes, dealing with zombies, interrupting processes based on user input and passing data back and forth between processes. Brief mentions of Flask are to be expected. Examples will be based on my experience in developing Bloxter a graphical drag-and-drop language for the GoPiGo3 to be used at home or in classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Montréal-Python 67: Ultramodern Vintage - PyCon Canada Special
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://montrealpython.org/2017/10/mp67/"&gt;https://montrealpython.org/2017/10/mp67/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Parrot</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-30:montreal-python/multiprocessing-how-to-run-blockly-generated-code-in-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>