<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lisa Carpenter</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Streamlit for Python - How to create beautiful interactive GUIs and web apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/streamlit-for-python-how-to-create-beautiful-interactive-guis-and-web-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this 3.5 hour tutorial, attendees will learn how to use the streamlit
library in Python to create interactive graphical user interfaces (GUIs)
for their data science projects. Through a series of hands-on exercises,
attendees will gain practical experience using streamlit to build and
customize their own interactive GUIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will begin by introducing attendees to the basics of
streamlit, including how to install and set up the library, as well as
the key concepts and components of streamlit applications. Attendees
will then learn how to use streamlit to create simple, yet effective,
GUIs for their data science projects, including how to display and
interact with data, add text and images, and create custom layouts and
widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the tutorial progresses, attendees will have the opportunity to work
on more advanced topics, such as using streamlit to create custom
interactive plots and charts, and integrating streamlit with other
popular libraries such as Pandas and Altair. By the end of the tutorial,
attendees will have a solid understanding of how to use streamlit to
create effective and engaging interactive GUIs for their own data
science projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will be led by an experienced data scientist with a strong
background in Python and streamlit, and will include plenty of hands-on
exercises to help attendees apply what they learn in a practical
setting. Attendees will also have access to detailed tutorial materials
and code samples, as well as support from the instructor and other
attendees throughout the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lisa Carpenter</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-19:/pycon-us-2023/streamlit-for-python-how-to-create-beautiful-interactive-guis-and-web-apps.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>