<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_thomas-mayer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Germany's next topic model</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/germanys-next-topic-model.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Mayer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/germanys-next-topic-model.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identifying topic models for user generated content like hotel reviews
turns out to be difficult with the standard approach of LDA (Latent
Dirichlet Allocation; Blei et al., 2003). Hotel review texts usually
don't differ as much in the topics that are covered as is typical with
other genres such as Wikipedia or newsgroup articles where there is
commonly only a very small set of topics present in each document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, we developed our own approach to topic modeling that is
especially tailored to non-edited texts like hotel reviews. The approach
can be divided into three major steps. First, using the concept of
second-order cooccurrences we define a contextual similarity score that
enables us to identify words that are similar with respect to certain
topics. This score allows us to build up a topic network where nodes are
words and edges the contextual similarity between the words. With the
help of algorithms from graph theory, like the Infomap algorithm
(Rosvall and Bergstrom, 2008), we are able to detect clusters of highly
connected words that can be identified as topics in our review texts. In
a further step, we use these clusters and the respective words to get a
topic similarity score for each word in the network. In other words, we
transform a hard clustering of words into topics into a probability
score of how likely a certain word belongs to a given topic/cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is structured as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References: David M. Blei, Andrew Y. Ng, Michael I. Jordan: Latent
dirichlet allocation. In: Journal of Machine Learning Research, Jg. 3
(2003), S. 993–1022, ISSN 1532-4435 M. Rosvall and C. T. Bergstrom, Maps
of information flow reveal community structure in complex networks, PNAS
105, 1118 (2008) &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0706851105"&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0706851105&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.0609"&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.0609&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Networks"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Visualisation"></category></entry></feed>