<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Deborah Diller Harris</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Feature Engineering: An Apprentice’s Guide to the “Dark Art” of Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/feature-engineering-an-apprentices-guide-to-the-dark-art-of-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is feature engineering considered the &amp;quot;dark art&amp;quot; of machine
learning? Transforming raw data into a form that your machine learning
algorithm can utilize seems mysterious and downright frightening! Bring
your wizard hat and join me as this machine learning apprentice shares
her personal book of feature engineering incantations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is feature engineering and why do we need it? When is it applied?
Is it an art or a science? Find out the answers to these questions and
more as we explore different methods of feature engineering with
practical examples provided. There are three main methods of feature
engineering: adjusting raw features, combining raw features and
decomposing raw features into usable subsets. We will use datasets to
illustrate binning, encoding, binaries, summing, differencing, feature
scaling, extraction, and the manipulation of date/time features.
Finally, we will explore the performance of a machine learning model
before and after feature engineering is applied. As a postscript,
current automated feature engineering tools for Python will be
introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deborah Diller Harris</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-27:/pyohio-2019/feature-engineering-an-apprentices-guide-to-the-dark-art-of-machine-learning.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2019</category></item><item><title>Combating PTSD with Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2021/combating-ptsd-with-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States is facing an urgent crisis in the treatment of its
military veterans. Post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) is a serious
health issue assailing our veteran population. There are currently
300,000+ disability claims and appeals pending in the Board of Veteran
Affairs’ (BVA) of the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs. PTSD claims
makeup at least 22% of that total. Presently, the timeline from claim to
appeal exceeds 4 years. This logjam in the VA claims and appeals can be
mitigated by automating this process using machine learning techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All PTSD claims are legal arguments. As such, all legal arguments must
have structured reasoning. Using this legal structure, documents can be
processed by Python NLP machine learning models. These models can be
used to streamline the process of adjudicating the claims and appeals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bit.ly/DeepLearningPTSD"&gt;https://bit.ly/DeepLearningPTSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Paper: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/deborahanneharris/legal-documents/"&gt;https://github.com/deborahanneharris/legal-documents/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deborah Diller Harris</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-31:/pyohio-2021/combating-ptsd-with-machine-learning.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2021</category></item></channel></rss>