<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jeffrey Mew</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Supercharge your Data Science workflow with Notebooks, VS Code, and Azure</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/supercharge-your-data-science-workflow-with-notebooks-vs-code-and-azure.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks and interactive programming have become one of the most popular tools for developing Python due to its flexibility and ease of use. Visual Studio Code now offers a first class Notebooks experience along with many great features for Data Scientists and Python developers alike. Come see how you can explore, experiment and productionize machine learning models using the flexibility of Notebooks combined with the power and productivity of VS Code. Along the way we’ll also be connecting to several Azure services from within VS Code, including Azure Virtual Machines for running the training job, Azure Storage for storing the dataset and model, Azure Functions for deploying our model and endpoint, and Azure Web Service for running a web application for making predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeffrey Mew</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/supercharge-your-data-science-workflow-with-notebooks-vs-code-and-azure.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Jupyter</category></item><item><title>Python &amp; Visual Studio Code - Revolutionizing the way you do data science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/python-visual-studio-code-revolutionizing-the-way-you-do-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Python &amp;amp; Visual Studio Code - Revolutionizing the way you do data science - presented by Jeffrey Mew&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey A on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio Code along with GitHub, Codespaces, and Azure Machine Learning have been investing substantially into tools and platforms to make the lives of Python data scientists easier, and we want to share why VS Code is now the #1 tool for Python Data Scientists according to the 2021 Python Software Foundation Developer Survey, and how you can leverage VS Code to take your data science productivity to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk through several common Python data science scenarios, showcasing all the productive tooling VS Code has to offer along the way. As a sneak peek, we will be demoing a best in class Jupyter Notebooks experience with VS Code Notebooks, a revolutionary new data cleaning / preparation experience with Data Wrangler in VS Code, collaboration features with GitHub and Codespaces, Azure Machine Learning for deployment, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeffrey Mew</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/python-visual-studio-code-revolutionizing-the-way-you-do-data-science.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Build an AI-powered Pet Detector in Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/build-an-ai-powered-pet-detector-in-visual-studio-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered what breed that dog or cat is? Let’s build a pet detector
service to recognize them in pictures!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered what breed that dog or cat is? Let’s build a pet detector
service to recognize them in pictures! In this talk, we will walk
through the training, optimizing, and deploying of a deep learning model
by using VS Code and the Azure Machine Learning service. We will use
transfer learning to recognize dog and cat breeds. Next, we’ll optimize
the model using Azure Machine Learning service to improve the model
accuracy. Putting on our developer hat, we'll then refactor the
notebooks into Python modules using VS Code. Finally, we will deploy the
model as a web service in Azure, all from the comforts of VS Code. Come
to see how Azure and VS Code makes AI and machine learning development
and deployment easy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeffrey Mew</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:/pydata-la-2019/build-an-ai-powered-pet-detector-in-visual-studio-code.html</guid><category>PyData LA 2019</category></item></channel></rss>