<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Phillip Cloud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_phillip-cloud.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Ibis: A fast, flexible, and portable tool for data analytics</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ibis-a-fast-flexible-and-portable-tool-for-data-analytics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ibis-a-fast-flexible-and-portable-tool-for-data-analytics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ibis provides a common dataframe-like interface to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without ever having to learn SQL. No more pains rewriting pandas code to something …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ibis provides a common dataframe-like interface to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without ever having to learn SQL. No more pains rewriting pandas code to something else when you run into performance issues; write your code once using Ibis and run it on any supported backend. In this tutorial users will get experience writing queries using Ibis on a number of local and remote database engines.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Ibis: Because SQL is everywhere but you don't want to use it</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-but-you-dont-want-to-use-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-but-you-dont-want-to-use-it.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, come and learn about Ibis! It offers a dataframe-like interface to construct concise and composable queries and then executes them against a wide variety of backends (Postgres, DuckDB, Spark, Snowflake, BigQuery, you name it.).&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>CI madness with Ibis: testing 20 query engines on every commit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/ci-madness-with-ibis-testing-20-query-engines-on-every-commit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/ci-madness-with-ibis-testing-20-query-engines-on-every-commit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidy Finance merges financial economics research with the principles of transparency and reproducibility, offering a novel open-source toolkit in R and Python. Our multi-language approach simplifies empirical studies in finance and teaches reproducible research with clean, understandable code. In my talk, I'll showcase how Tidy Finance improves finance research …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidy Finance merges financial economics research with the principles of transparency and reproducibility, offering a novel open-source toolkit in R and Python. Our multi-language approach simplifies empirical studies in finance and teaches reproducible research with clean, understandable code. In my talk, I'll showcase how Tidy Finance improves finance research and education, aiding finance professionals in applying its principles for better teaching and research. Attendees from diverse backgrounds will learn about fostering open-source initiatives in their fields. Join us to support a transparent, reproducible research environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Porque SQL está en todas partes.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/porque-sql-esta-en-todas-partes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/porque-sql-esta-en-todas-partes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nos encanta usar Python en nuestro trabajo, pero lamentablemente la base
de datos de tu empresa donde ejecutas tus ETL (extracción,
transformación y carga) te lo previene. Muy probablemente tu base de
datos hable SQL, ¿Por qué? Porque SQL está en todos lados, ha estado
presente durante un largo …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nos encanta usar Python en nuestro trabajo, pero lamentablemente la base
de datos de tu empresa donde ejecutas tus ETL (extracción,
transformación y carga) te lo previene. Muy probablemente tu base de
datos hable SQL, ¿Por qué? Porque SQL está en todos lados, ha estado
presente durante un largo tiempo, está estandarizado y es conciso.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Pero realmente está estandarizado? ¿Y siempre es conciso? ¡No! ¿Aún
necesitamos usarlo? ¡Probablemente sí! ¿Qué puede hacer una persona que
trabaja con datos? ¿SQL con string-templating (plantilla de cadena de
caracteres)? print(f&amp;quot;Ese camino conduce a {locura}}&amp;quot;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mejor, ¡ven y aprende sobre Ibis!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ibis es una biblioteca completamente en Python que ofrece una una
interfaz similar a aquellas con estructuras de datos tabulares (data
frames), que te permite construir queries concisas y componibles que se
pueden ejecutar en una amplia variedad de backends (SQLite, DuckDB,
Postgres, Spark, Clickhouse, Snowflake, BigQuery, ¡y más!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Alguna vez has tenido que traducir un prototipo de Pandas a PySpark
para ejecutarlo en &amp;quot;datos reales&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿O descargar un enorme archivo parquet porque los datos en la fuente son
el resultado de 500 líneas de SQL denso y tienes miedo de tocarlo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Quieres probar esta cosa llamada &amp;quot;DuckDB&amp;quot; pero no quieres aprender SQL?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Tienes una relación de amor/odio con SQL porque te permite hacer tu
trabajo, pero piensas que debe haber una mejor manera?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Te has quedado atascado manteniendo un creciente y amorfo conjunto de
SQL con plantillas que solo se suponía que se usaría para esa
demostración?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bueno, si eres un ingeniero de datos, científico de datos, entusiasta de
los datos o cualquier cosa relacionada con los datos, ¡ven y únete a
nosotros para descubrir lo que Ibis puede hacer por ti!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Ibis: blazing fast analytics with DuckDB, Polars, Snowflake, and more, from the comfort of your Python repl.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/introduction-to-ibis-blazing-fast-analytics-with-duckdb-polars-snowflake-and-more-from-the-comfort-of-your-python-repl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-15:/pycon-us-2024/introduction-to-ibis-blazing-fast-analytics-with-duckdb-polars-snowflake-and-more-from-the-comfort-of-your-python-repl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tabular data is ubiquitous, and pandas has been the de facto tool in
Python for analyzing it. However, as data size scales, analysis using
pandas may become untenable. Luckily, modern analytical databases (like
DuckDB) are able to analyze this same tabular data, but perform
orders-of-magnitude faster than pandas, all …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tabular data is ubiquitous, and pandas has been the de facto tool in
Python for analyzing it. However, as data size scales, analysis using
pandas may become untenable. Luckily, modern analytical databases (like
DuckDB) are able to analyze this same tabular data, but perform
orders-of-magnitude faster than pandas, all while using less memory.
Many of these systems only provide a SQL interface though; something far
different from pandas’ dataframe interface, requiring a rewrite of your
analysis code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Ibis comes in. Ibis provides a common dataframe interface
to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake,
Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same
consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without
ever having to learn SQL (but you can use SQL if you want to!). No more
pains rewriting pandas code to something else when you run into
performance issues; write your code once using Ibis and run it on any
supported backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we’ll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basic operations of Ibis (&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;select&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;filter&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;group_by&lt;/tt&gt;,
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;order_by&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;join&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;aggregate&lt;/tt&gt;), and how these operations
may be composed to form more complicated queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Ibis may be used on a number of different local and remote
backend engines to execute the same queries on different systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tradeoffs of different database engines, and recommendations for
how to choose the best tool for the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Ibis integrates into the larger Python data ecosystem, including
tools like Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, PyArrow, pandas, Altair, and
VegaFusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hands-on tutorial, with numerous examples to get your hands
dirty. Participants should ideally have some experience using Python and
pandas, but no SQL experience is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Phillip Cloud - Blaze in the Real World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dallas-2015/phillip-cloud-blaze-in-the-real-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-24:/pydata-dallas-2015/phillip-cloud-blaze-in-the-real-world.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyData Dallas 2015"></category></entry><entry><title>Phillip Cloud - Driving Blaze in the Real World of Data Land Mines</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2014/phillip-cloud-driving-blaze-in-the-real-world-of-data-land-mines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-11-22:/pydata-new-york-city-2014/phillip-cloud-driving-blaze-in-the-real-world-of-data-land-mines.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyData New York City 2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Run Numba functions in SQLite: WTF?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2018/run-numba-functions-in-sqlite-wtf.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-17:/pydata-new-york-city-2018/run-numba-functions-in-sqlite-wtf.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyData New York City 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>Blaze and Odo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/blaze-and-odo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-25:/pydata-seattle-2015/blaze-and-odo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blaze and Odo are designed to help domain experts answer questions more quickly. They work together by providing a symbolic computation layer (blaze) alongside a graph of data converters (odo) that enables users to move seamlessly between formats in the most performant way. We discuss both libraries in the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blaze and Odo are designed to help domain experts answer questions more quickly. They work together by providing a symbolic computation layer (blaze) alongside a graph of data converters (odo) that enables users to move seamlessly between formats in the most performant way. We discuss both libraries in the context of PyData and emerging data analytics technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaze separates expressions from computation. Odo moves complex data resources from point A to point B. Together Blaze and Odo smooth over many of the complexities of computing with large data warehouse technologies like Redshift, Impala and HDFS. Because we designed Blaze and Odo with PyData in mind they also integrate well with pandas, numpy, and a host of other foundational libraries. We show examples of both Blaze and Odo in action and discuss the design behind each library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://slides.com/phillipcloud/odo-5"&gt;http://slides.com/phillipcloud/odo-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Seattle 2015"></category></entry><entry><title>Blaze + Odo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/blaze-odo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Phillip Cloud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-09:/scipy-2015/blaze-odo.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="SciPy 2015"></category></entry><entry><title>SciPy Tools Plenary Day 3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Nunez-Iglesias</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy is organized by NumFOCUS, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that promotes open source scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>