<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Samira Soleimani</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Multi-objective Optimization for COVID Vaccine Management</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2021/multi-objective-optimization-for-covid-vaccine-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In the past several months, we have seen that effectively distributing
COVID-19 vaccinations is an incredibly important and daunting task.
Due to a wide and asymmetric imbalance between supply and demand,
finding the right balance, timing, and utilization of vaccinations has
proven difficult for everyone involved. Organizations need to
correctly predict demand at different times at specific locations to
minimize spoilage and optimize utilization rate while accounting for
limited supply.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this talk, Samira Soleimani, Data Scientist at CGI, will
demonstrate how machine learning algorithm and multi-objective
optimization can be used to help tackle this challenge. First, Samira
will explain the difference between single-objective and
multi-objective optimizations. Second, she will introduce and compare
line and curve-fitting approaches to define objective functions for
distribution optimization. Then, she will explain and implement
multi-objective particle swarm optimization (PSO) in the python
package “PyGMO” to find the optimal point for vaccine distribution in
a neighborhood.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samira Soleimani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-31:/pyohio-2021/multi-objective-optimization-for-covid-vaccine-management.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2021</category></item></channel></rss>