<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_liam-andrew.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Saved you a click (or three): Supercharging the Django admin with actions and views</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2017/saved-you-a-click-or-three-supercharging-the-django-admin-with-actions-and-views.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liam Andrew</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-14:djangocon-us-2017/saved-you-a-click-or-three-supercharging-the-django-admin-with-actions-and-views.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US 2017 - Saved you a click (or three): Supercharging the Django admin with actions and views by Liam Andrew&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to “save you a click”: while this is a pejorative phrase in The Texas Tribune’s newsroom, we love saving our reporters and editors clicks in the Django admin when they’re filing a breaking story. We’ve combined several helpful Django features, libraries, patterns and customizations – ranging from the obvious to the advanced – to supercharge our admin, allowing for live previews, shortcuts, and dynamic updates. Taken together, these tools suggest a framework for developing new admin features quickly and maintainably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk would be especially valuable to Django developers who know the basics of customizing the admin, but aren’t sure where to take it next, or want to add some bells and whistles. It also opens up to larger questions about customizing the admin that would benefit more advanced Django developers. I would definitely allow time for questions and discussion to hear from others who might have tricks up their sleeves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/saved-you-a-click-or-three-supercharging-the-django-admin-with-actions-and-views/"&gt;https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/saved-you-a-click-or-three-supercharging-the-django-admin-with-actions-and-views/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>