<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Cheuk Ting Ho</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Let's build a BeeWare app that uses Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/lets-build-a-beeware-app-that-uses-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will go through the basics of building a Beeware app. However, instead of starting from scratch, we will assume that we have a Django app that is already built - we will use the first step tutorial on Django documentation. Then, we will start building the BeeWare UI and link it up with the already working Django app. After building our example, we will also discover other alternatives that BeeWare can work with Django so in the future, if you are building another BeeWare app, you can decide which method you want to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction of BeeWare (10 mins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the Django App is running (5mins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building the BeeWare UI (10 mins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine with Django (10 mins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion and alternatives (10 mins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/djangocon-us-2023/lets-build-a-beeware-app-that-uses-django.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Fuzzy Matching - Smart Way of Finding Similar Names Using Fuzzywuzzy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/fuzzy-matching-smart-way-of-finding-similar-names-using-fuzzywuzzy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matching strings should be one of the first natural language processing
problem that human encounter since we start use computer to handle data.
Unlike numerical value which has an exact logic to compare them, it is
very hard to say how alike two strings are for a computer. One may
compare them character by character and have an idea of how many
characters in the pair of stings are the same. Unfortunately in most
application we need computer to perceive strings like we do and
therefore we have to use fuzzy matching. Fuzzy matching on names is
never straight forward though, the definition of how “difference” of two
names are really depends case by case. For example with restaurant
names, matching of words like “cafe” “bar” and “restaurant” are consider
less valuable then matching of some other less common words. Also, do we
consider company names that matches partly (like “Happy Unicorn company”
and Happy Unicorn co.”) are the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of the talk Levenshtein Distance, a measure of the
similarity between two strings, will be explained. Different functions
in Fuzzywuzzy like “partial &lt;em&gt;ratio” and “token&lt;/em&gt; sort_ratio” will also
be explored and compared for difference. It is very important to
understand our tool and choose the right one for our task. Then in the
second half, we will start tackling the example problem: matching
company names, we will show that besides using Fuzzywuzzy, we have to
also handle problem like finding and avoid matching of common words and
speeding up the matching process by grouping the names. By combining all
tricks and techniques that we demonstrate, we will also evaluate how
efficient this method is and the advantage of using this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people in all level of Python experience who would like
to learn a trick or two and would like to be able to solve similar
problems in the future. Theory of how the library works will be
explained and It is easy to be pick up even for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:/europython-2018/fuzzy-matching-smart-way-of-finding-similar-names-using-fuzzywuzzy.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2018</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks 07/28</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/lightning-talks-0728.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talk 1
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/lightning-talks-0728.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>I have to Confess, I still Love Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/i-have-to-confess-i-still-love-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - I have to Confess, I still Love Pandas - presented by Cheuk Ting Ho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Cheuk will reapproach Pandas as someone who is a fluent user of the library. Cheuk will review why Pandas is useful to work with data and what advantage it has over the alternatives methods. As Pandas has many functionalities, Cheuk will dissect the discussion on the potential usage of Pandas in day-to-day data science workflow: data inspection, data cleaning, feature engineering etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussing the advantage of using Pandas, Cheuk will discuss the flip side. What makes Pandas a difficult tool to use at first. Here Cheuk will share how she used it efficiently with new users and some fundamental concepts about Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for Pandas users (new and old) or potential users. Those who are familiar with Pandas may get a refreshing idea from a new angle about the tool. And for the new users, it will be a good startup guide to make the journey of using it a bit easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/i-have-to-confess-i-still-love-pandas.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks Wednesday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/lightning-talks-wednesday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Forum Hall on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/lightning-talks-wednesday"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/lightning-talks-wednesday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Wednesday's lightning talks, hosted by Laís Carvalho ⬇️
00:00 &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Wednesday's Lightning Talks&lt;/em&gt;
01:11 &lt;em&gt;Pyvo Meetup &amp;#64; EuroPython&lt;/em&gt; — Mia Bajić
03:24 &lt;em&gt;AI Game Tournament&lt;/em&gt; — Neil Vaytet
06:48 &lt;em&gt;How Government Policy Can Affect Open Source&lt;/em&gt; — Cheuk Ting Ho
11:10 &lt;em&gt;AWS Lambda ❤️ Python 3.11&lt;/em&gt; — Jonas Weissensel
14:22 &lt;em&gt;Brings Llamas Closer&lt;/em&gt; — Vaibhav (VB) Srivastav
20:10 &lt;em&gt;Adding Arrow Function to Python Grammar&lt;/em&gt; — Oguz Albayrak
25:35 &lt;em&gt;A Curious Bug that Happened with List Comprehensions&lt;/em&gt; — Jouni Seppänen
30:49 &lt;em&gt;Spy&lt;/em&gt; — Antonio Cuni
36:27 &lt;em&gt;Learning Python Through Blocks&lt;/em&gt; — Joshua Lowe
42:49 &lt;em&gt;25 Years of Open Source Software&lt;/em&gt; — Radomir Dopieralski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing up is on a first-come-first-served basis. The queue is reset every day in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presenter may talk about / present (almost) everything with certain boundaries. And each presentation is not longer than five minutes and full of fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mia Bajić</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/lightning-talks-wednesday.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Polars vs Pandas - what's the difference?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/polars-vs-pandas-whats-the-difference.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/polars-vs-pandas-whats-the-difference"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/polars-vs-pandas-whats-the-difference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you heard about Polars? What are the differences? Is Polars replacing Pandas? In this talk, we are going to demystify these questions about Polars. Compares the differences between Polars and Pandas, and explains the pros and cons of both of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/polars-vs-pandas-whats-the-difference.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Q&amp;A panel for data science newbies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/qa-panel-for-data-science-newbies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2B on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/qa-panel-for-data-science-newbies"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/qa-panel-for-data-science-newbies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you just getting started in the world of data science and feeling overwhelmed by the abundance of information on various packages, models, and techniques? Perhaps you're finding it challenging to decide which visualization package to use or which tools to begin with. Maybe you're puzzled by the distinctions between pip and Conda, or you're feeling bombarded by all the news about AI and large language models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worry no more! Join us for this Q&amp;amp;A session, where a panel of data science experts will be there to address all of your pressing questions. This session is designed to create a relaxed and welcoming environment for complete beginners in the field, offering guidance on topics that might be causing confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/qa-panel-for-data-science-newbies.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Counting down for CRA - updates and expectations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/counting-down-for-cra-updates-and-expectations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Counting down for CRA - updates and expectations by Cheuk Ting Ho, Deb Nicholson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/counting-down-for-cra-updates-and-expectations"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/counting-down-for-cra-updates-and-expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EU Commission is likely to vote on the Cyber Resilience Act (CRA) later this year. The CRA is an ambitious step towards protecting consumers from software security issues by creating a new list of responsibilities for software developers and providers. The Act also creates a new category of actor known as an “Open Source Steward” which we think makes important allowances for public open source repositories like CPython and Python Package Index (PyPI.) Once the dust settles, everyone who makes software will need to consider the CRA’s mandates in their security roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will look at the timeline for the new legislation, any critical discussions happening around implementation and most importantly, the new responsibilities outlined by the CRA. We’ll also discuss what the PSF is doing for CPython and for PyPI and what each of us in the Python ecosystem might want to do to get ready for a new era of increased certainty – and liability – around security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Target audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers and maintainers whose project or product may be affected by the CRA. European legislation won’t just affect the European market, it will affect the software industry and the open source community globally as it is very hard to segregate one project or product from the EU market. So, this is for everyone in the Python community who shares their code with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Goal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To educate the general public about CRA - how it can affect us and how to get ready for it. We also want to provide more information for the Python community about what has been done by the PSF regarding the CRA to reassure them that the Python community is aware and getting prepared for the CRA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/counting-down-for-cra-updates-and-expectations.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>Generating Data Frames for your test - using Pandas strategies in Hypothesis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/generating-data-frames-for-your-test-using-pandas-strategies-in-hypothesis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you test your data pipeline? Do you use Hypothesis? In this workshop, we will use Hypothesis - a property-based testing framework to generate Pandas DataFrame for your tests, without involving any real data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/generating-data-frames-for-your-test-using-pandas-strategies-in-hypothesis.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talk Day 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talk-day-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks of the second conference day at EuroSciPy 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/lightning-talk-day-2.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Day 1 Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/day-1-lightning-talks.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Bakker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/day-1-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Driving down the Memray lane Profiling your data science work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When handling a large amount of data, memory profiling the data science workflow becomes more important. It gives you insight into which process consumes lots of memory. In this talk, we will introduce Mamray, a Python memory profiling tool and its new Jupyter plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Untangle Python Spaghettis - Deep Dive Into Environments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/untangle-python-spaghettis-deep-dive-into-environments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After learning doing in Python, we started multiple Python or Data Science projects. Dependency management becomes a skill that we need to avoid requirement conflicts amount projects. In this talk, we will learn how dependencies management tools work and how to choose the right one to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-19:/pycascades-2023/untangle-python-spaghettis-deep-dive-into-environments.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2023</category></item><item><title>Trojan Source Code - Can We Trust Open-Source Anymore?｜Cheuk Ting Ho｜PyCon APAC 2022</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2022/trojan-source-code-can-we-trust-open-source-anymorecheuk-ting-hopycon-apac-2022.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon APAC 2022｜一般演講 Talks｜國泰金控 Cathay Financial Holdings / 美光科技 Micron 冠名贊助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✏️ 共筆 Note：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/jeexX3rHS3-5sHLa8MRmfA"&gt;https://hackmd.io/jeexX3rHS3-5sHLa8MRmfA&lt;/a&gt;
🖐🏻 Slido：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://app.sli.do/event/1KMf9S167YGfLtQPu3hxLv"&gt;https://app.sli.do/event/1KMf9S167YGfLtQPu3hxLv&lt;/a&gt;
💬 語言 Language：英文 English
🎯 層級 Level：入門 Novice
🔎 分類 Category：資訊安全 Security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 摘要 Abstract 💡
Recently, a paper is published to demonstrate how a visibly valid contribution can contain malicious code by exporting the Unicode control characters. Some of these has been tested on Python and it works. Shall the Python and open-source communities be concerned?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 About Speaker - Cheuk Ting Ho 🚀
Before working in Developer Relations, Cheuk has been a Data Scientist in various companies which demands high numerical and programmatical skills, especially in Python. To follow her passion for the tech community, now Cheuk is the Developer Advocate for Anaconda. Besides her work, Cheuk enjoys speaking at various conferences. Cheuk also organises events for developers. Cheuk has organised conferences including EuroPython (of which she is a board member), PyData Global and Pyjamas Conf. Believing in Tech Diversity and Inclusion, Cheuk constantly organizes workshops and mentored sprints for minority groups. In 2021, Cheuk has become a Python Software Foundation fellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#python #pycontw #pyconapac2022 #datasecurity #opensource #trojansource&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycontw.blogspot.com"&gt;https://pycontw.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-03:/pycon-apac-2022/trojan-source-code-can-we-trust-open-source-anymorecheuk-ting-hopycon-apac-2022.html</guid><category>PyCon APAC 2022</category></item><item><title>Under and Dunder - Python secret functions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/under-and-dunder-python-secret-functions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheuk Ting Ho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/VLPJZL"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/VLPJZL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start, we will be using &lt;cite&gt;dir&lt;/cite&gt; to look into the secret functions Python objects have. Eg:
&lt;cite&gt;__getitem__&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;__iter__&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;__next__&lt;/cite&gt; Then, we will investigate where is the dunder function goes? Why is it not accessible. And at the end, we will see how dunder functions can change the identity of the Python objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for attendees who have just begin their Python journey. By explaining the dunder functions and the nature of Python objects, attendees will have a better understanding of why Python is fundamentally different from other programming languages. Hopefully, this knowledge will help them out when they continue their Python journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Sep  5 13:35:00 2020 at Obvious&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/under-and-dunder-python-secret-functions.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2020</category><category>CheukTingHo</category><category>PyCon</category><category>PyConAU</category><category>PyConline</category><category>Python</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2020</category></item><item><title>Case Study in Travel Business - Understanding agent connections using NetworkX</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-understanding-agent-connections-using-networkx.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network analysis is getting more and more attention in Business
Intelligence, people hope to get information out of the structure of an
organization or a communication network. In this talk, we use the hotel
room search requests from travel agents, including online public
website, B2C, B2B and B2B2C, to build a relational network among them.
By using this network as an example, we demonstrate how insights can be
extract by studying network properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of the talk, we will explain how the network is built
using NetworkX, an open-source python library that is designed for the
creation, manipulation, and study of the structure, dynamics, and
functions of complex networks. When 2 agents are making the same search
at the same time , a link ( or an “edge” in network analysts terms) is
made pointing form the initial searcher to the subsequent searcher.
Using a list of these searches, a directed graph is built. We will also
demonstrate how to pick the biggest connected component out form the
graph. In the second half, with the graphs created, we show how
different functions of NetworkX can be used to study the graphs. By
compare the graph properties of our graph to the other popular network
graphs, we can get the insight of how the network was created. Also by
studying the graphs, we can understand the behavior of the agents and
can even figure out which agents are acting as main hubs in the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people who are interested in network analysis and would
like to see how it can be used in a business case. Audiences with any
level of python experience can learn some basic concept of network
analysis work and how it can be applied to provide business insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:/pycon-de-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-understanding-agent-connections-using-networkx.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2018</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Networks</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest And You Can Have Pythin In Your Language</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/hacktoberfest-and-you-can-have-pythin-in-your-language.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:/pycon-de-2018/hacktoberfest-and-you-can-have-pythin-in-your-language.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2018</category><category>lightning talk</category></item><item><title>Running An Open Source Project Like A Start Up</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2019/running-an-open-source-project-like-a-start-up.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Cheuk Ting Ho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago, I started an open source project - PicknMIx. It feels like running a start up if you are serious about it. Want to know my story? Want to check if you can do it as well? I will tell you. (Stickers not guaranteed though)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/9ARCJA"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/9ARCJA&lt;/a&gt;
Follow us on Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-09:/pycon-de-2019/running-an-open-source-project-like-a-start-up.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2019</category></item><item><title>Plénière n°3 / Keynote #3: The Role of 21st Century Technology in Protests</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/pleniere-ndeg3-keynote-3-the-role-of-21st-century-technology-in-protests.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since June 2019, Hong Kong shocked the world with massive protests. As protesters are mainly young, educated and technology-aware people, they are trying to use the new technology to outwit the government which also use AI and technology to control its people. Who got the upper hand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever think about using Tinder to look for a ‘date’ in the protest? Or using Uber to call for a free ride to drive you to safety?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the talk, we will cover the background of the protest, why it happened and how it is started. We will briefly talk about the politic environment of Hong Kong and what causes the protest 1: the fear of losing a “high degree of autonomy”
In the second part, which is the main part of the talk, we will cover how technology/ apps like Telegram, Tinder, Pokemon Go, Twitch, AirDrop, Bridgefy, Uber, etc were used in by the protesters and what
role they play in the protest. People use Telegram’s encryption to communicate without worrying leaking of identity; they use Tinder to spread the news about where and when to protest; They use Pokemon Go
to gather people 4; AirDrop to spread the message to the Chinese tourists; Bridgefy to communicate where internet is not available at crowded areas 3; Uber to let the protested know where there are
volunteer drivers to take you to safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third part, we will have a look at what technology the Chinese government may use to tighten its grip over Hong Kong. One of the front lines of the protest in the online activism 5, the Chinese
government has it’s own ‘50 cent army’ which is also known as ‘China bots’ who were paid to leave pro-CCP comments on social media. Which eventually cause Twitter and Facebook to shout down lots of accounts. Also, there are attacks cyberattacks, suspected to be related to the protest, towards Telegram and an online forum LiHKG which the protesters used to communicate. It is also suspected that the
government installed ‘smart’ lamppost which use facial detection to monitor the citizen of Hong Kong after protested found parts made by a Shanghai company which also made the surveillance cameras in mainland China 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for audients who are interested to know how our lives are changed by technology and how they could influence our society. By the end of the talk, audients will be more aware of what consequence new technology may bring us and be more thoughtful about the ethics behind the implementation of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:/pycon-fr-2019/pleniere-ndeg3-keynote-3-the-role-of-21st-century-technology-in-protests.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2019</category></item><item><title>Driving down the Memray lane - Profiling your data science work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will be exploring what memory profiling is, and how it can help with data science work. We will start the talk with a basic explanation of how Python arrange memories for various objects. This lays the foundation explanation of why we need a special tool to memory profile Python programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we will be going through a data science use case where we memory profiles some part of the process with the Memray Jupyter plug-in. This would be a use case that a data science practitioner or learner would be familiar with and they can see how memory profiling could be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will then explain how to interpret the frame diagram in Memray, a commonly used diagram in memory profiling to understand how much memory a process and its sub-process uses. This is something that for a new user, it could be hard to understand and not know what to look into. From this example, audiences can see what they can learn about from the frame diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#### Goal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for data scientists, learners or anyone who is interested in memory profiling their Python program. Although the talk will be using a data science use case as an example, the explanation and the tool can be expanded to be used in any Python program. However, for data science practitioners and learners who have been using Python to process data, this may be a step forward for them to improve their data workflow and prevent memory leaks from their programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-18:/pycon-fr-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2023</category></item><item><title>Trying no GIL on scientific programming</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2023/trying-no-gil-on-scientific-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will have a look at what is no-gil Python and how it may improve the performance of some scientific calculations. First of all, we will touch upon the background knowledge of the Python GIL, what is it and why it is needed. On the contrary, why it is stopping multi-threaded CPU processes to take advantage of multi-core machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we will have a look at no-gil Python, a fork of CPython 3.9 by Same Gross. How it provides an alternative to using Python with no GIL and demonstrates it could be the future of the newer versions of Python. With that, we will try out this version of Python in some popular yet calculation-heavy algorithms in scientific programming and data sciences e.g. PCA, clustering, categorization and data manipulation with Scikit-learn and Pandas. We will compare the performance of this no-gil version with the original standard CPython distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for Pythonistas who have intermediate knowledge of Python and are interested in using Python for scientific programming or data science. It may shine some light on having a more efficient way of using Python in their tasks and interest in trying the no-gil version of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-18:/pycon-fr-2023/trying-no-gil-on-scientific-programming.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2023</category></item><item><title>Under and Dunder - Python secret functions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2020/under-and-dunder-python-secret-functions.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-02:/pycon-india-2020/under-and-dunder-python-secret-functions.html</guid><category>PyCon India 2020</category></item><item><title>Launch Jupyter to the Cloud with Docker and Terraform</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-with-docker-and-terraform.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launch Jupyter to the Cloud: an example of using Docker and Terraform&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will use a task: hiring a GPU on Google Cloud Platform to train neural network, as an example to show how an application can be deployed on a cloud platform with Docker and Terraform. The goal is to have Jupyter Notebook running in an environment with Tensorflow (GPU version) and other libraries installed on a Google Compute Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people with no experience in application deployment on cloud service but would benefit form computational reproducibility and cloud service, potentially data scientists/ analysts or tech practitioners who didn't have a software developing background. We will use an example that is simple but useful in data science to demonstrate basic usage of Docker and Terraform which would be beneficial to beginners who would like to simplify their work flow with those tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-05:/pycon-israel-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-with-docker-and-terraform.html</guid><category>PyCon Israel 2018</category><category>jupyter</category><category>docker</category><category>terraform</category></item><item><title>Batteries Included: Things you can do with standard libraries</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2021/batteries-included-things-you-can-do-with-standard-libraries.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any Python user knows the power of Python is having many packages in PyPI that you can simply pip install. Imagine pip is not allowed at work due to security issues. Don't worry! You can still do many things with the standard libraries included. Let me show you those that you should know and use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-08-27:/pycon-latam-2021/batteries-included-things-you-can-do-with-standard-libraries.html</guid><category>PyCon Latam 2021</category></item><item><title>Knowledge graph data modelling with TerminusDB – Cheuk Ting Ho (PyCon Taiwan 2021)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2021/knowledge-graph-data-modelling-with-terminusdb-cheuk-ting-ho-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 10:00-11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing data in a tabular format is not always ideal. Taking advantage of strong data in knowledge graphs can make handling complex data structure possible and data visualization easier. In this workshop, you will get all the basics to start modelling data in the terms of triples and building schemas of a knowledge graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short Format of your Workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview-5 min, Lecture - 30 mins, Breaks- 10 minutes, Hands-on training - 40 mins, Closing - 5 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course Benefits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will have learnt a new skill set that may assist you in your project in data science or research. You will have a new tool that you can better model your data and collaborate with others. Also, you gain all the prerequisites to use WOQL - a query language for knowledge graph and the TerminusDB Python client to manage, manipulate and visualize data in your knowledge graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is required from attendees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A computer with stable internet connection; TerminusDB Desktop App or Docker image (a.k.a TerminusDB Bootstrap) which you can download from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://terminusdb.com/hub/download"&gt;https://terminusdb.com/hub/download&lt;/a&gt; (FREE); Python client for TerminusDB (require Python equal or larger than 3.6); An opened mind and ready to learn something new&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://terminusdb.com/blog/"&gt;https://terminusdb.com/blog/&lt;/a&gt;
HackMD: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FBkR6iXczF"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FBkR6iXczF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Cheuk Ting Ho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheuk has been a Data Scientist in various companies which demands high numerical and programmatical skills, especially in Python. To follow her passion for the tech community, now Cheuk is the Developer Relations Lead at TerminusDB - an open-source graph database. Cheuk maintains its Python client and engages with its user community daily. Besides her work, Cheuk enjoys talking about Python in personal streaming platform and MidMeetPy podcast. Cheuk has also been a guest speaker at Universities and various conferences. On top of speaking at conferences, Cheuk also participates as organizers. Conferences that Cheuk has organized include EuroPython(which she is a board member of), PyData Global and Pyjamas Conf. Believing in gender equality, Cheuk constantly organizes workshops and mentored sprints to support Tech Diversity and Inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-03:/pycon-taiwan-2021/knowledge-graph-data-modelling-with-terminusdb-cheuk-ting-ho-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</guid><category>PyCon Taiwan 2021</category></item><item><title>Turning Pandas DataFrames to Semantic Knowledge Graph – Cheuk Ting Ho (PyCon Taiwan 2021)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2021/turning-pandas-dataframes-to-semantic-knowledge-graph-cheuk-ting-ho-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, 14:05-14:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember how many times you look up “how to do this in pandas”? Though it is the most popular data handling library in Python, it is quite complicated due to the rigidness of storing data in tabular formats. This is most obvious when the data stored is imported from a JSON file and end up having multiple layers of objects. At this point, you wished for a data structure that let you store data with objects and subclasses, just like in object-orientated programs. The answer? Semantic knowledge graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Cheuk will first introduce what is semantic knowledge graphs. It’s building block: triples, and how all data can be described will them - with objects and properties. Cheuk will assume no prior knowledge and will explain via examples and visualization with the TerminusDB model builder - a graphical interface that allows you to build schemas for semantic knowledge graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next part, Cheuk will show how to construct a schema based on a pandas DataFrame. With the Python client of TemrinusDB, schema can be built programmatically follow by importing the data in the DataFrame. In this part, basic Python knowledge is assumed. In this part, Cheuk will show the internals of pandas, dissecting it and reconstruct a knowledge graph schema. Cheuk will also show the code that transforms the data and insert them in the prepared graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Cheuk will visualize the graph in a customized interactive graph visualization in Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.
HackMD: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FHJZaKgtzt"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FHJZaKgtzt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Cheuk Ting Ho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheuk has been a Data Scientist in various companies which demands high numerical and programmatical skills, especially in Python. To follow her passion for the tech community, now Cheuk is the Developer Relations Lead at TerminusDB - an open-source graph database. Cheuk maintains its Python client and engages with its user community daily. Besides her work, Cheuk enjoys talking about Python in personal streaming platform and MidMeetPy podcast. Cheuk has also been a guest speaker at Universities and various conferences. On top of speaking at conferences, Cheuk also participates as organizers. Conferences that Cheuk has organized include EuroPython(which she is a board member of), PyData Global and Pyjamas Conf. Believing in gender equality, Cheuk constantly organizes workshops and mentored sprints to support Tech Diversity and Inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-02:/pycon-taiwan-2021/turning-pandas-dataframes-to-semantic-knowledge-graph-cheuk-ting-ho-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</guid><category>PyCon Taiwan 2021</category></item><item><title>Time Series Analysis with Seasonal Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Case Study in Travel Business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For time series analysis, everyone’s talking about ARIMA or
Holt-Winters. But there’s other models which could also break down a
seasonal series into trend, seasonality and noise. We will use an open
source Python library called Seasonal to analyse B2B worldwide travel
data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-18:/pycon-uk-2018/time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2018</category></item><item><title>Do we have a diversity problem in Python community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/do-we-have-a-diversity-problem-in-python-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python community cares about diversity. So do we still have a problem in, especially gender, diversity? We will look at some data and see if there’s a true problem, discuss what the problem may be and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-15:/pycon-uk-2019/do-we-have-a-diversity-problem-in-python-community.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2019</category></item><item><title>I hate writing tests, that's why I use Hypothesis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2022/i-hate-writing-tests-thats-why-i-use-hypothesis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok, I lied, I still write tests. But instead of the example-based tests that we normally write, have you heard of property-based testing? By using Hypothesis, instead of thinking about what data I should test it for, it will generate test data, including boundary cases, for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore what is property-based testing and why it can do a lot of heavy lifting in writing tests for us. As a contributor, I will introduce Hypothesis, a Python library that can help perform property-based tests with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of the talk, we will understand the power of property-based tests, what is it, how is it different from what we “normally do” - testing by example, and why is it useful in testing our code. This will be followed by demonstrations using Hypothesis. With a few examples, we will have a glimpse of how to create strategies - recipes for describing the test data you want to generate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we will also explore the Ghostwriters in Hypothesis which will actually write the test for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for Pythonistas who are new to property-based testing and found thinking of what parameters to use for testing a difficult task. This talk may provide them with a new approach to writing tests, which will be more efficient for some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-16:/pycon-uk-2022/i-hate-writing-tests-thats-why-i-use-hypothesis.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2022</category></item><item><title>Knowledge graph data modelling with TerminusDB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/knowledge-graph-data-modelling-with-terminusdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;FOR WHOM IS YOUR WORKSHOP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data scientists, engineers and researchers who have no prior experience in knowledge graph data modelling. In this workshop, we will start from the fundamentals - learning how to think in terms of triples to describe relations of different data objects. If your work involves data analysis, data management, data collaboration or anything data-related, this is a workshop for you to have a brand new insight into how data should be represented and stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHORT FORMAT OF YOUR WORKSHOP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview-10 min, Lecture - 60 mins, Breaks- 20 minutes, Hands-on training - 80 mins, Closing - 10 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT ATTENDEES WILL LEARN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, you will be able to think like a knowledge graph expert and construct a proper schema to store your data in a knowledge graph format. You will acquire the skills that you need to build knowledge graphs in TerminusDB - an open-source graph database that enables revisional control and collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COURSE BENEFITS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will have learnt a new skill set that may assist you in your project in data science or research. You will have a new tool that you can better model your data and collaborate with others. Also, you gain all the prerequisites to use WOQL - a query language for knowledge graphs and the TerminusDB Python client to manage, manipulate and visualize data in your knowledge graph.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/knowledge-graph-data-modelling-with-terminusdb.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Day 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are a ~ 5 minutes long, on any topic of interest to other Python people. It doesn't have to be about something that you wrote, it can be something that you learned, or a technique you think other people will be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:50 - Sameer Wagh - Data Science without Data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2:25 - Cheuk Ting Ho - Cultural Shock - My 1st&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:25 - Łukasz Langa - COVARIANCE/CONTRAVARIENCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11:45 - Seth M Larson - Truststore: OS trust stores in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15:50 - Pablo Galindo - Memray: hardcore memory profiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:17 - Graham Waters -The grief cycle, data security breaches, how we could code the future of America and the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24:17 - Mason Egger - What is Synthetic Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29:55 - Sophia Yang - Holoviz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;34:00 - Shiray Lamba - Robyn; The fastest rust based python webframework server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;39:00 - Chris May - Three steps to elegant code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;43:50 - Chris Ariza - Getting to 100% coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;49:15 - Indra - Jupyter ML model to production ML as a service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sameer Wagh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-1.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Trying No GIL on Scientific Programming</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/trying-no-gil-on-scientific-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, Sam Gross, the author of nogil fork on Python 3.9,
demonstrates the GIL can be removed. For scientific programs which use
heavy CPU-bound processes, it could be a huge performance improvement.
In this talk, we will see if this is true and compare the nogil version
to the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will have a look at what is no-gil Python and how it
may improve the performance of some scientific calculations. First of
all, we will touch upon the background knowledge of the Python GIL, what
is it and why it is needed. On the contrary, why it is stopping
multi-threaded CPU processes to take advantage of multi-core machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we will have a look at no-gil Python, a folk of CPython 3.9
by Same Gross. How it provides an alternative to using Python with no
GIL and demonstrates it could be the future of the newer versions of
Python. With that, we will try out this version of Python in some
popular yet calculation-heavy algorithms in scientific programming and
data sciences e.g. PCA, clustering, categorization and data manipulation
with Scikit-learn and Pandas. We will compare the performance of this
no-gil version with the original standard CPython distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for Pythonistas who have intermediate knowledge of Python
and are interested in using Python for scientific programming or data
science. It may shine some light on having a more efficient way of using
Python in their tasks and interest in trying the no-gil version of
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/trying-no-gil-on-scientific-programming.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Power up your work with compiling and profiling</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/power-up-your-work-with-compiling-and-profiling.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you been troubled by Python code that took too long to run? Do you
want to know why and how to improve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this workshop, we will introduce Numba - a JIT compiler that is
designed to speed up numerical calculations. Most people found all of it
is like a mystery - It sounds like magic, but how does it work? Under
what conditions does it work? And because of it, new users found it hard
to start using it and it requires a steep learning curve to get the hang
of it. This workshop will provide all the knowledge that you need to
make Numba works for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop is for Data scientists or developers who have math-heavy
code that would like to speed up with the benefit of Numpy and Numba.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/power-up-your-work-with-compiling-and-profiling.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Making Python safer than ever</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/making-python-safer-than-ever.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is one of the programming languages that has a huge open-source
supply chain. There are over 400,000 Python packages on Python Package
Index (PyPI) and many more on other registries like conda-forge, mostly
for scientific libraries. Making sure this and the wider Python
ecosystem are secure is a huge job and requires consistent
contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to OpenSSF’s Alpha-Omega project and AWS, we now have a PSF
Security Developer-in-Residence and PyPI Safety &amp;amp; Security Engineer
whose responsibility includes a security audit of the PyPI codebase and
infrastructure, improving security practices, and establishing metrics
on security posture to show the impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will go over the work that has been done by the PSF
security team and what the best practices for Python library maintainers
and users are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="goal"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Goal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to draw awareness of security, especially in
Python's ecosystem. It highlights how PSF is helping the community, on
the other hand, it also provides advice for a user or community member
on what can be done to make sure they are using Python safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="target-audiences"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Target audiences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ths talk is for anyone in the Python community. If you are using Python,
or your company is using Python. This talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/making-python-safer-than-ever.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Acknowledging Women’s Contributions in the Python Community Through Podcast</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/acknowledging-womens-contributions-in-the-python-community-through-podcast.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python community has been making efforts in improving the diversity
and representation among its members. There are examples of success
stories such as PyCon US Charlas, PyLadies, Djangonaut, and Django
Girls. Yet in the Python podcast community, women are still
underrepresented, making up only 17% of invited guests among the popular
podcast series. Being a guest in a podcast is a privilege, and an
opportunity to influence the Python community. There are many women and
underrepresented group members who have made impactful contributions to
the Python community globally, and they deserve the recognition and to
be heard by the rest of us. Disheartened by the lack of representation
by women on Python podcasts, and inspired by others who have shown us
how diversity in the community can be improved through intentionality,
we decided to start a podcast with a goal to highlight their voices so
that they could receive the recognition they deserve. In this talk,earn
about them, and about our podcast series. We’ll also share how you can
further help out cause in improving representation and diversity in the
Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="goal"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Goal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To raise awareness of the underrepresentation of certain groups,
especially women. To acknowledge the progress made by the Python
community and what can be done further to continue the improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="target-audience"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who cares about the diversity and inclusion progression in the
Python community. Community leaders who want to be allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/acknowledging-womens-contributions-in-the-python-community-through-podcast.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>PyO3 101 - Writing Python modules in Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/pyo3-101-writing-python-modules-in-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Rust has been getting more and more popular over other
similar programming languages like C and C++ due to its robust compiler
checking and ownership rules to make sure memory is safe. Hence there
are more and more Python libraries that have been written in Rust
natively with a Python API interface. One of the tools that have been
driving this movement is PyO3, a toolset that proves Rust bindings for
Python and tools for creating native Python extension modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interactive workshop, we will cover the very basics of using
PyO3. There will be hands-on exercises to go from how to set up the
project environment to writing a &amp;quot;toy&amp;quot; Python library written in Rust
using PyO3. We will cover a lot of expectations of the API provided by
PyO3 to create Python functions, modules, handling errors and converting
types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="goal"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Goal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give developers who are not familiar with PyO3 an introduction to
PyO3 so they can consider building their Python libraries with Rust to
make use of Rust's memory-safe property and parallelism ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="target-audiences"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Target audiences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any developers who are interested in developing Python libraries using
Rust. It will be an advantage if the attendees are comfortable writing
in Rust. However, attendees are not required to be familiar with Rust as
all the Rust codes will be provided. Basic knowledge of Python will be
assumed from the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-15:/pycon-us-2024/pyo3-101-writing-python-modules-in-rust.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Friday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/lightning-talks-friday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collection of lightning talks made by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2:05 - Rodrigo Girão Serrão - Meta lightning talk
7:15 - Laís Carvalho - Join Humble Data!
10:05 - Cheuk Ting Ho - Too many swags!! Let's review the swags so we know who's giving us good stuff
14:40 - Quang Vu - Enhancing My Archery Practice with Computer Vision
18:55 - Meagen Voss - Maaah! How I Killed My Site with a Goat Gif
24:25 - Will Lachance - How much energy will my solar panels produce?
29:10 - Amanda Lundberg - Captioner is Human
33:55 - Thomas Weiss - Predicting Fire Weather Using Historical RAWS Data
38:25 - Tom Rutherford - The power and danger of os.fork
42:45 - Cody Maloney - Remember to .close() file-like objects
47:25 - Anthony Shaw - CSnakes: Python in .NET
52:55 - Trey Hunner - Systems, gates, and rage&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rodrigo Girão Serrão</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/lightning-talks-friday.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item><item><title>Case Study in Travel Business - Time Series Analysis with Seasonal Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For time series analysis, everyone's talking about ARIMA or Holt-Winters. But there's other models which could also break down a seasonal series into trend, seasonality and noise. We will use an open source Python library called Seasonal to analyse B2B worldwide travel data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:/pydata-amsterdam-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</guid><category>PyData Amsterdam 2018</category></item><item><title>Launch Jupyter to the Cloud: an example of using Docker and Terraform</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-an-example-of-using-docker-and-terraform.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of reasons using a cloud service is favorable, but how to
make sure consistency between development and deployment? With Docker,
we can &amp;quot;ship&amp;quot; the project to different platforms in the same
environment. Going one step further we can also create the cloud
infrastructure as code with Terraform. As an example, we will deploy a
Jupyter notebook on Google Cloud Platform using both tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-07:/pydata-berlin-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-an-example-of-using-docker-and-terraform.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2018</category></item><item><title>Driving down the Memray lane - Profiling your data science work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When handling a large amount of data, memory profiling the data science workflow becomes more important. It gives you insight into which process consumes lots of memory. In this talk, we will introduce Mamray, a Python memory profiling tool and its new Jupyter plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/driving-down-the-memray-lane-profiling-your-data-science-work.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item><item><title>3 things about Chatbot (you don't have to learn it the hard way)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/3-things-about-chatbot-you-dont-have-to-learn-it-the-hard-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am telling you 3 things about Chatbot (so you don't have to learn it the hard way)
Cheuk Ting Ho
Audience level:
Intermediate
Description
Chatbot is cool! Now we can talk to our gadgets as if it’s a real human, right? It also makes you wonder when you chat with the “customer service” online, is that a real person or a robot on the other side? My boss wanted me to build a chatbot, and here’s 3 things that I discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/pydata-london-2019/3-things-about-chatbot-you-dont-have-to-learn-it-the-hard-way.html</guid><category>PyData London 2019</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning with Keras</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/deep-learning-with-keras.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computers are getting closer to speak like humans. But can we even make them speak in particular ways, like as Trump or Shakespeare? In this hands on talk we will see how this is possible with the latest deep learning techniques combined with word embeddings and other advanced NLP technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright belongs to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-09:/pylondinium-2018/deep-learning-with-keras.html</guid><category>PyLondinium 2018</category></item><item><title>If Errol Street Could Talk</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2019/if-errol-street-could-talk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversity statement quoted as follows: &amp;quot;The Python Software Foundation and the global Python community welcome and encourage participation by everyone. Our community is based on mutual respect, tolerance, and encouragement, and we are working to help each other live up to these principles. We want our community to be more diverse: whoever you are, and whatever your background, we welcome you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversity, big deal! As an active members and event organisers (and also on the minority side of the gender) in the Python community, we have alway been concern by the question of: Do we truly have a problem in diversity? Especially, gender diversity. We would like to find out the truth, by data science, and see if we can find a clue why and how we can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will show the research others did regarding the representation of women in the R and Python communities [1]. Then, we will show the research that we did based on our experience and statistic. Including static analysis of the speakers diversity (regarding gender) at major PyCon and PyData conferences. Finally, as we all care about diversity and want improvements, we would like to find out the reason and what we can do about it. We would propose what we, the minorities and allies, could do against this seemingly unbalance situation and make the community better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for all that who cares about diversity in our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://reshamas.github.io/why-women-are-flourishing-in-r-community-but-lagging-in-python/"&gt;https://reshamas.github.io/why-women-are-flourishing-in-r-community-but-lagging-in-python/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-06-16:/pylondinium-2019/if-errol-street-could-talk.html</guid><category>PyLondinium 2019</category></item><item><title>I Have to Confess, I Still Love Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2022/i-have-to-confess-i-still-love-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is the first Python library that I learned to use. It is used by
data scientists to manage, transform and inspect data. As more and more
open-source tools appear, it seems the spotlight has shifted and I would
love to shine some light on this tool that all should know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-30:/pyohio-2022/i-have-to-confess-i-still-love-pandas.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2022</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks DAY 2 | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto Pastor Muela</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item></channel></rss>