<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tilde Thurium</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>To rewrite or not to rewrite: an OSS community journey in the LLMiverse</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2024/to-rewrite-or-not-to-rewrite-an-oss-community-journey-in-the-llmiverse.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I love breaking changes!” said no developer, ever. Backwards incompatibility can be disruptive to a community, but sometimes it’s a necessary evil in the long run to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haystack is a free open source Python LLM framework. It was launched in 2020, before LLMs were cool. In 2023 we decided to undergo a major re-architecture, culminating in the release of Haystack 2.0. It wasn't an easy decision. By involving the open source community in our design process early on, we are confident we built a more usable, flexible foundation for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you'll learn how we designed abstractions with the right level of flexibility / composability in the rapidly changing LLM landscape. We'll not only show you the new features Haystack 2.0 provides, but we will also give you a peek into our future roadmap. You'll walk away with a better understanding of how modern LLM frameworks can help you solve problems at scale with LLM technologies, as well as an enriched understanding of how to think for the long-term when building for an open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tilde Thurium</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-30:/north-bay-python-2024/to-rewrite-or-not-to-rewrite-an-oss-community-journey-in-the-llmiverse.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2024</category></item><item><title>Prompt engineering &amp; social justice: what we know so far</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2025/prompt-engineering-social-justice-what-we-know-so-far.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tilde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/ZEFTCV"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/ZEFTCV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large language models are only as good as the data we feed into them. Unfortunately, we haven't quite dismantled racism, sexism, and all the other -isms just yet. Generative AI isn't going away, so let's apply a harm reduction lens. Given the imperfect tools that we have, how can we write LLM prompts that are less likely to reflect our own biases? In this session, we'll will review 5 current research papers straddling the intersection of prompt engineering and social science. We'll also walk through an interactive live demo in Python, showing how to apply this research to real world problems. You'll leave with some ideas about how you, as users and builders of generative AI applications, can iterate towards a more equitable world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Apr 27 16:20:00 2025 at Reis River Ranch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tilde Thurium</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-27:/north-bay-python-2025/prompt-engineering-social-justice-what-we-know-so-far.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2025</category></item></channel></rss>