<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_marianne-hoogeveen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The physics of deep learning using tensor networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-physics-of-deep-learning-using-tensor-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marianne Hoogeveen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/the-physics-of-deep-learning-using-tensor-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tensor networks have been used in Physics to find efficient expressions of many-body quantum systems, describing systems from materials to holographic spacetime. As it happens, one can also use tensor networks in machine learning. Exploring the equivalence between these two affords us intuition on inductive bias, which is the set of assumptions that determine our choice of machine learning model.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Cat's Alive! Add Some Weirdness To Your Code With Quantum Computing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/the-cats-alive-add-some-weirdness-to-your-code-with-quantum-computing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jorn Mossel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-05:pygotham-2019/the-cats-alive-add-some-weirdness-to-your-code-with-quantum-computing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear 10x programmer. Aren’t you bored of writing code that always works, and
gives you the exact result you want? Don't lose hope, try a quantum
computer! Regardless of how good your code is (and we’re talking about a
brand new programming language), you will never get it fully under control,
and that's the beauty. Let us show you how mount this untamable quantum
beast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the basics of a quantum computer (which unfortunately doesn't
consist of a bunch of Schrodinger's cats doing computations, either alive or
dead), we will explain why people think there might be problems where this
new evolution of computation will reign supreme in the future, and how we
can use it to find good approximate solutions to complex problems in the
meantime. We will talk about the new wave of development in quantum hardware
and software, but the cherry on the cake will be running a computation on
actual quantum hardware - live.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What physics can teach us about learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/what-physics-can-teach-us-about-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marianne Hoogeveen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/what-physics-can-teach-us-about-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do convolutional networks work well for images? What happens in a neural
network when it 'learns’? What is machine learning, actually? These are the
type of questions that we should all be wondering about if we use machine
learning, and especially deep neural networks, on a daily basis. The field
of deep learning is developing rapidly with new architectures being invented
to try to solve ever more challenging problems, and this zoo of neural
networks needs a taxonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to bring order to the chaos is by using a physicist's intuition.
Bridges are being built, formalizing the link between well-developed fields
in physics and neural networks, which allow us to understand extracting
information relevant on the macroscopic scale as both a machine learning
problem and a problem that has been known in the physics community for a
long time, namely describing physical systems at different length scales.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Plant Factory: Sensor, Data, Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2019/plant-factory-sensor-data-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marianne Hoogeveen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-10:pydata-amsterdam-2019/plant-factory-sensor-data-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="pydata"></category></entry></feed>