<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Justin Braaten</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_justin-braaten.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Bridging the gap between Earth Engine and the Scientific Python Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/bridging-the-gap-between-earth-engine-and-the-scientific-python-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Qiusheng Wu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/bridging-the-gap-between-earth-engine-and-the-scientific-python-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine's new data extraction interfaces seamlessly transfer geospatial data into familiar Python formats provided by NumPy, Pandas, GeoPandas, and Xarray. This integration empowers you to harness Earth Engine's vast data catalog and compute power directly within your preferred Python workflows. For example, the Xee library leverages Xarray's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine's new data extraction interfaces seamlessly transfer geospatial data into familiar Python formats provided by NumPy, Pandas, GeoPandas, and Xarray. This integration empowers you to harness Earth Engine's vast data catalog and compute power directly within your preferred Python workflows. For example, the Xee library leverages Xarray's lazy evaluation and Dask to streamline the extraction and analysis of Earth Engine data, offering a more Pythonic alternative to traditional image exports. Earth Engine's new data extraction interfaces unlock fresh geospatial analysis potential by leveraging the unique strengths of both the scientific Python ecosystem and Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>