<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jyotika Singh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jyotika-singh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Demystifying Natural Language Processing across Several Industry Verticals</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/demystifying-natural-language-processing-across-several-industry-verticals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-23:/djangocon-us-2021/demystifying-natural-language-processing-across-several-industry-verticals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability of a machine to understand human language. NLP is a popular field of data science and is widely used across different industry verticals to solve for various challenges. This talk will highlight NLP, what it is and will follow into how over …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability of a machine to understand human language. NLP is a popular field of data science and is widely used across different industry verticals to solve for various challenges. This talk will highlight NLP, what it is and will follow into how over 5 industries use NLP to solve for their use cases. The industries include e-commerce, finance, real estate, social media, and more.
This talk will then progress into some practical implementations of the common industrial solutions that are widely used across the globe today. These applications include sentiment analysis, automated customer service solutions like chatbots, and more. Furthermore, using open-source libraries to build these NLP utilizations will be discussed and presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Audio Processing and ML using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/audio-processing-and-ml-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-17:/pybay-2019/audio-processing-and-ml-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Challenges with Audio Classification problems focussing on cleaning and building features from audio which can then be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Challenges with Audio Classification problems focussing on cleaning and building features from audio which can then be used to build a classification model, features that work well with audio and speech data and the open source libraries useful for the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Audio data, unlike other data, needs a bit of a different approach while trying to extract information and building classification models. I will talk about cleaning audio signal approaches, how to form features from an audio and what features help extract the unseen information that can help with classification models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1evkUgkxPTNFBUE7obMnACa__5tUp01sX/view?usp=sharing"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1evkUgkxPTNFBUE7obMnACa__5tUp01sX/view?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
I am a Data Scientist living in San Diego and a UCLA Master's graduate. I'm passionate about solving problems using the power of Data and Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Classifying Audio into Types using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/classifying-audio-into-types-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/classifying-audio-into-types-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Jyotika Singh) What is audio data? How to build features and classification models on audio? How to solve audio classification problems in python? This talk will answer all those questions and highlight the challenges in classifying using audio, the features that work well with audio and speech data and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Jyotika Singh) What is audio data? How to build features and classification models on audio? How to solve audio classification problems in python? This talk will answer all those questions and highlight the challenges in classifying using audio, the features that work well with audio and speech data and extracting them, the open-source tools in Python that can be leveraged and some usage examples and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/TCJLKP/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/TCJLKP/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 11:00:00 2021 at Science, Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="JyotikaSingh"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Features from Audio for Machine Learning – Jyotika Singh (PyCon Taiwan 2021)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2021/building-features-from-audio-for-machine-learning-jyotika-singh-pycon-taiwan-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-03:/pycon-taiwan-2021/building-features-from-audio-for-machine-learning-jyotika-singh-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 10:00-10:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio signals are a different type of data than the more commonly seen types, such as text, numbers and images. Thus, numerical feature extraction for audio data is different and follows processes that try to replicate how human ears perceive sound. Audio and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 10:00-10:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio signals are a different type of data than the more commonly seen types, such as text, numbers and images. Thus, numerical feature extraction for audio data is different and follows processes that try to replicate how human ears perceive sound. Audio and speech processing has a massive amount of research and methods available in MATLAB. Given the popularity of Python in the field of Machine Learning, feature extraction and audio classification model building in Python will be discussed. This talk will cover details about Audio signals, feature types, feature extraction using Python, open-source tools, followed by practical examples of training Machine Learning models using Audio data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike types of data that are more commonly dealt with in the industry these days, such as numerical data, text or image data, audio signals need a different approach while trying to extract information and building machine learning models. This talk will highlight the challenges with Audio Classification problems starting with what an audio signal is and what its numerical representation means, how it is widely different from other data types, what feature extraction from audio looks like, how to go about it, what it means and the open-source tools in Python that can be leveraged for the same. Digital signal processing, that includes audio processing, is a whole separate field to study and leveraging portions of learning from that in order to build successful models on audio data is an interesting and challenging problem. In addition, Matlab is a popular language of choice with great tools for audio signal processing. Python being a popular language of choice for Machine Learning presents another set of challenges to build successful audio and speech classification solutions in Python alone. Focus will then upon how to build classification models from the features representing the unseen information from audio and speech signals and doing it all leveraging different open-source tools available to Python users. This will be followed by a few examples of different audio classification and prediction problem statements, such as audio type classification, music genre classification and spoke location name classification, and a solution for attempting to solve them using Python using the different features formation techniques and tools discussed earlier in the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.
HackMD: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FHy9u4GqfF"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FHy9u4GqfF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jyotika Singh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jyotika Singh is the VP of Data Science at ICX Media where mentors and manages her team as they work on NLP, feature engineering, supervised &amp;amp; unsupervised machine learning, research, analytics, programming in Python and distributed computing with Spark. She earned her Master’s in Science from the UCLA where she researched signal &amp;amp; speech processing, developed novel approaches to remove noise from speech and worked on a variety of machine learning on image, text, social media, consumer &amp;amp; entertainment data. She enjoys working on problem solving techniques on text, audio &amp;amp; image, and has opened multiple open-source projects to share her work with the Python &amp;amp; Data Science community. She is passionate about women in STEM and continues mentorship efforts to support the topic. She volunteers as a mentor at Data Science Nigeria and Women Impact Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>pyAudioProcessing: Building audio classification models in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2021/pyaudioprocessing-building-audio-classification-models-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-02:/pygotham-2021/pyaudioprocessing-building-audio-classification-models-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike types of data that are more commonly dealt with in the industry these
days, such as numerical data, text or image data, audio signals need a
different approach while trying to extract information and building machine
learning models. This talk will highlight the challenges with Audio
Classification problems …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike types of data that are more commonly dealt with in the industry these
days, such as numerical data, text or image data, audio signals need a
different approach while trying to extract information and building machine
learning models. This talk will highlight the challenges with Audio
Classification problems starting with what an audio signal is and what its
numerical representation means, how it is widely different from other data
types, what feature extraction from audio looks like, how to go about it,
what it means and the open-source tools in Python that can be leveraged for
the same. Digital signal processing, that includes audio processing, is a
whole separate field to study and leveraging portions of learning from that
in order to build successful models on audio data is an interesting and
challenging problem. In addition, Matlab is a popular language of choice
with great tools for audio signal processing. Python being a popular
language of choice for Machine Learning presents another set of challenges
to build successful audio and speech classification solutions in Python
alone. Focus will then upon how to build classification models from the
features representing the unseen information from audio and speech signals
and doing it all leveraging different open-source tools available to Python
users. This will be followed by a few examples of different audio
classification and prediction problem statements, such as audio type
classification, music genre classification and spoke location name
classification, and a solution for attempting to solve them using Python
using the different features formation techniques and tools discussed
earlier in the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyGotham 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Classifying Spoken Location Names</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2021/classifying-spoken-location-names.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-31:/pyohio-2021/classifying-spoken-location-names.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will highlight a problem such as classification of speech data
where the expected spoken utterance is a location name, and how one can
have a machine learn differences between utterances. Speech feature
extraction and building a successful classification model will be
discussed using open-source tools in Python …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will highlight a problem such as classification of speech data
where the expected spoken utterance is a location name, and how one can
have a machine learn differences between utterances. Speech feature
extraction and building a successful classification model will be
discussed using open-source tools in Python, along with practical
examples to demonstrate usage using pyAudioProcessing.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jsingh811/pyAudioProcessing"&gt;https://github.com/jsingh811/pyAudioProcessing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Applications of Natural Language Processing Across Several Industry Verticals</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/applications-of-natural-language-processing-across-several-industry-verticals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jyotika Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/applications-of-natural-language-processing-across-several-industry-verticals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability of a machine to understand human language. NLP is a popular field of data science and is widely used across different industry verticals to solve for various challenges. This talk will highlight NLP, what it is and will follow into how 5 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the ability of a machine to understand human language. NLP is a popular field of data science and is widely used across different industry verticals to solve for various challenges. This talk will highlight NLP, what it is and will follow into how 5+ industries use NLP to solve for their use cases. The industries include retail, finance, real estate, entertainment, marketing and more. This talk will then progress into some practical implementations of the common industrial solutions that are widely used across the globe today. These applications include building or chatbots, automated customer service solutions and recommendation engines. Furthermore, using open-source libraries to build these NLP utilizations will be discussed and presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>