<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ching Lam Choi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ching-lam-choi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Corona-Net</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/corona-net.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ching Lam Choi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/corona-net.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fighting COVID-19 with Machine Learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identified in December 2019, the novel Coronavirus has infected 2.7 million worldwide, and claimed the lives of 0.2 million. Amidst this deadly pandemic, I started my open source project, Corona-Net, in the hopes of contributing to the global fight against the Coronavirus …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fighting COVID-19 with Machine Learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identified in December 2019, the novel Coronavirus has infected 2.7 million worldwide, and claimed the lives of 0.2 million. Amidst this deadly pandemic, I started my open source project, Corona-Net, in the hopes of contributing to the global fight against the Coronavirus. Corona-Net is a 3-part project dedicated to the classification, binary segmentation and multi-class segmentation of COVID-19. I first leverage the EfficientNet model for COVID-19 diagnosis, then utilise and refine the U-Net architecture for both binary and 3-class (ground-glass, consolidation, pleural effusion) segmentation of COVID-19 symptoms, through inference on the COVID-19 CT segmentation (chest axial CT) dataset. Through Corona-Net, I aim to develop a reliable, visual-semantically balanced method for automatic COVID-19 diagnosis, as well as extend an invitation to all to collaborate and stand together against this pandemic. My PyTorch code is publicly available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/chinglamchoi/Corona-Net"&gt;https://github.com/chinglamchoi/Corona-Net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Computer Vision"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Deep Learning"></category><category term="Image Processing"></category><category term="Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)"></category></entry></feed>