<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Choi Ching Lam</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_choi-ching-lam.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Corona-Net: Fighting COVID-19 with Machine Learning – PyCon Taiwan 2020</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2020/corona-net-fighting-covid-19-with-machine-learning-pycon-taiwan-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Choi Ching Lam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-06:/pycon-taiwan-2020/corona-net-fighting-covid-19-with-machine-learning-pycon-taiwan-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R3 11:55–12:10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce my open source Python project, Corona-Net, COVID-19 chest CT segmentation  with PyTorch. I leverage the EfficientNet model for image-level COVID-19 diagnosis, as well as the UNet -- a Fully Convolutional encoder-decoder network -- for binary and multi-class medical …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R3 11:55–12:10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce my open source Python project, Corona-Net, COVID-19 chest CT segmentation  with PyTorch. I leverage the EfficientNet model for image-level COVID-19 diagnosis, as well as the UNet -- a Fully Convolutional encoder-decoder network -- for binary and multi-class medical segmentation. Through UNet, I successfully detect and localise COVID-19 symptoms, including ground-glass, consolidation and pleural effusion, from axial chest CT slices, using open source datasets and annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Choi Ching Lam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choi Ching Lam is a high school programmer from Hong Kong, keenly interested in Computer Vision and Scientific Computing. She is an open source enthusiast with a deep appreciation for Python and Julia. Presently an intern at NVIDIA's AI Tech Center, Ching Lam aspires to become a Machine Learning researcher.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2020"></category></entry></feed>