<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_franklin-sarkett.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building a Data Driven Organization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/building-a-data-driven-organization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Franklin Sarkett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/building-a-data-driven-organization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buckminster Fuller said, “If you want to teach people a new way of
thinking, don’t bother trying to teach them. Instead, give them a tool,
the use of which will lead to new ways of thinking.” This profound
insight shaped the way I build my organization. We will look at some
tools that enable us to think like a data-driven organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckminster Fuller said, “If you want to teach people a new way of
thinking, don’t bother trying to teach them. Instead, give them a tool,
the use of which will lead to new ways of thinking.” This profound
insight shaped the way I build my organization. We will look at some of
the tools that enable us to think like a data-driven organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams are built out of three things: * People * Processes * Resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a 3 step process we can deploy. We start by focusing on
resources, then processes, and lastly people. With each step we climb
the ladder of value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With resources, we have tools. By choosing specific tools, we can being
to shape our thinking. We can create mental pathways that intentionally
take us in a particular direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we establish the tools, we focus on our processes. These are our
workflows and in many ways, our philosophies. How we think things should
proceed. This could be kanban and how we move work from left to right
through the pipeline, and it can be kaizen and belief in small,
continuous improvement. Processes can be considered tools as much as
resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we have resources and processes, we can free up bandwidth with our
people. People are most creative and dynamic at this stage once friction
is removed and adding business value can go from one-off fixes to
becoming part of the organization itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools that facilitate a data-driven culture: * Mental models * Kanban
and Kaizen * Opinionated, structured data science like Kedro * OKRs *
KPIs&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>