<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dataflow Notebooks Encoding and Using Cell Dependencies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/dataflow-notebooks-encoding-and-using-cell-dependencies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dataflow notebooks extend the Jupyter Notebook environment and IPython kernel to allow users to construct clear dependencies between cells, making it possible to construct a graph that details all defined dependencies between cells. In this environment, unique, persistent cell identifiers make references between cells more robust than existing solutions. Using the dependency graph, we can dynamically update upstream dependencies for a cell or select downstream cells that depend on the current one. This helps users better organize their work, allows for non-linear orderings of cells, and enables greater reproducibility and more opportunities for reuse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Koop</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:scipy-2017/dataflow-notebooks-encoding-and-using-cell-dependencies.html</guid></item><item><title>VisTrails: A Python-Based Scientific Workflow and Provenance System (#172)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/vistrails-a-python-based-scientific-workflow-and.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;VisTrails: A Python-Based Scientific Workflow and Provenance System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by David Koop (University of Utah and VisTrails, Inc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will give an overview of VisTrails
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vistrails.org/"&gt;http://www.vistrails.org&lt;/a&gt;), a
python-based open- source scientific workflow that transparently
captures provenance (i.e., lineage) of both data products and the
processes used to derive these products. We will show how VisTrails can
be used to streamline data exploration and visualization. Using real
examples, we will demonstrate key features of the system, including the
ability to visually create information processing pipelines that combine
multiple tools and Iibraries such as VTK, pylab, and matplotlib. We will
also show how VisTrails leverages provenance information not only to
support result reproducibility, but also to simplify the creation and
refinement of pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Koop</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/vistrails-a-python-based-scientific-workflow-and.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>scientific</category><category>vistrails</category></item></channel></rss>