<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Han Seong-min</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Data Engineering in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/data-engineering-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today's data is changing trends to meet the needs of AI and data-driven business. Various keywords such as LakeHouse, ELT, DataOps, and Feature Store are becoming known to many engineers through corporate white papers and open sources. These trends are leading to changes in the movement of the Python ecosystem. In this session today, we will look at the changes in data trends in 2022 and what movements there are for data engineering and data science in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Han Seong-min</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/data-engineering-in-python.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2022</category><category>Open Source / Community</category></item><item><title>Global Interpreter Lock GIL Detailed Exploration</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/global-interpreter-lock-gil-detailed-exploration.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we will look at the core structure of the Python Global Interpreter Lock (GIL), the basic concepts of the GIL and the innate background of Python related to RefCount and ThreadSafe, and a session that takes an in-depth look at the future and trends of the GIL, including Pycon Language Summit 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Han Seong-min</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/global-interpreter-lock-gil-detailed-exploration.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2022</category><category>Python Core &amp; Fundamental</category></item><item><title>Deep dive into Python through CPython code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/deep-dive-into-python-through-cpython-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When working with Python, we often encounter low-level implementations such as CPU/IO Bound, Selector, Global Interpreter Lock, and AsyncIO. And sometimes, we do not understand the functions of the structure exactly and often develop while memorizing the code pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we have to apply the low-level implementation, we cannot implement it because we have deviated from the memorized pattern, and in this way, we fall into the continuation of abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation session, we have prepared a diagram of the low-level implementations we encounter in Python using CPython code and computer science theories, so that you can take the first step toward understanding the principles that were difficult to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han Seong-min
An engineer who is interested in MLOps and focuses on productization of AI. He is also a member of the GDG community and is trying to create opportunities to foster the developer ecosystem in Korea and exchange information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is currently focusing on configuring the MLOps pipeline for the global market, and he works with engineers from various countries while traveling between offices in Korea and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Han Seong-min</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/deep-dive-into-python-through-cpython-code.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>