<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_matteo-cafasso.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hunting Malware with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/hunting-malware-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matteo Cafasso</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/hunting-malware-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Matteo Cafasso - Hunting Malware with Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worms, Trojans, BotNets and Ransomware. These bad guys are quite known nowadays but how do they look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am gonna show one of the approaches IT Security experts employ to study these threats using open source Python technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation would be a live demo in which I'll execute some malware in a secure environment and show how it behaves and how to detect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will show a Sandboxing technology developed within F-Secure named Sandboxed Execution Environment (SEE). SEE is a Python framework which allows to quickly build behavioural scanning engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEE will be used altogether with other open source technologies to show some recent malware to the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I am a software engineer working in F-Secure Labs. F-Secure Corporation is an IT security company based in Helsinki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among my duties, malware handling and analysis automation is one of the most interesting to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I develop and maintain the main behavioural scanning engines within F-Secure back-end and SEE is one of their core technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>