<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jeffrey-yau.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Time Series Forecasting using Statistical and Machine Learning Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2017/time-series-forecasting-using-statistical-and-machine-learning-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeffrey Yau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-27:pydata-new-york-city-2017/time-series-forecasting-using-statistical-and-machine-learning-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time series data is ubiquitous, and time series modeling techniques are data scientists’ essential tools. This presentation compares Vector Autoregressive (VAR) model, which is one of the most important class of multivariate time series statistical models, and neural network-based techniques, which has received a lot of attention in the data science community in the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Applied Time Series Econometrics in Python and R</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/applied-time-series-econometrics-in-python-and-r.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeffrey Yau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/applied-time-series-econometrics-in-python-and-r.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series data is ubitious, and time series statistical models should be included in any data scientists’ toolkit. This tutorial covers the mathematical formulation, statistical foundation, and practical considerations of one of the most important classes of time series models: the AutoRegression Integrated Moving Average with Explanatory Variables model and its seasonal counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series data is ubitious, both within and out of the field of data science: weekly initial unemployment claim, tick level stock prices, weekly company sales, daily number of steps taken recorded by a wearable, just to name a few. Some of the most important and commonly used data science techniques to analyze time series data are those in developed in the field of statistics. For this reason, time series statistical models should be included in any data scientists’ toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 120-minute tutorial covers the mathematical formulation, statistical foundation, and practical considerations of one of the most important classes of time series models, AutoRegression Integrated Moving Average with Explanatory Variables (ARIMAX) models, and its Seasonal counterpart (SARIMAX).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry></feed>