<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Waldemar Hummer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_waldemar-hummer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>LocalStack: Turbocharging dev loops and team collaboration for cloud applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/localstack-turbocharging-dev-loops-and-team-collaboration-for-cloud-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Waldemar Hummer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/localstack-turbocharging-dev-loops-and-team-collaboration-for-cloud-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - LocalStack: Turbocharging dev loops and team collaboration for cloud applications - presented by Waldemar Hummer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the staggering dominance of public cloud providers, dev teams across the globe are increasingly focusing time and energy on optimizing their cloud development and deployment flows. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - LocalStack: Turbocharging dev loops and team collaboration for cloud applications - presented by Waldemar Hummer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the staggering dominance of public cloud providers, dev teams across the globe are increasingly focusing time and energy on optimizing their cloud development and deployment flows. The traditional deploy-and-test cycles against public clouds can become slow and tedious, where developers are often facing several minutes of idle times between deployments that need to be frequently triggered during testing &amp;amp; debugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we provide a hands-on introduction to LocalStack (39k+ Github stars), a fully functional local AWS cloud stack. With LocalStack, applications can be developed entirely on your local machine, reducing dev&amp;amp;test cycles from minutes to seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session covers interactive live coding to showcase common scenarios and use cases, different settings for local debugging of Lambdas and containerized apps (e.g., ECS/EKS), as well as some advanced new features that can radically improve productivity and team collaboration patterns.
We will also glance over the large ecosystem of tools that LocalStack natively integrates with - from IaC frameworks like Terraform or Pulumi, to application frameworks like Serverless or Architect, to a whole suite of tools provided by AWS itself (CDK, SAM, Copilot, Chalice, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll wrap up the session with a deep dive into some of the Python internals of LocalStack, which reveals some interesting architectural patterns and hidden gems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>