<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - An Seong-jin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_an-seong-jin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Easily produce and share content using Jupyter Books</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/easily-produce-and-share-content-using-jupyter-books.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>An Seong-jin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/easily-produce-and-share-content-using-jupyter-books.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When conducting data analysis and research using ython, .ipynb files are mainly used. When sharing the content publicly, GitHub is mainly used. Since GitHub is a developer-friendly code management platform, it is not an efficient platform for non-developer decision makers, stakeholders, and others to consume the content. In this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When conducting data analysis and research using ython, .ipynb files are mainly used. When sharing the content publicly, GitHub is mainly used. Since GitHub is a developer-friendly code management platform, it is not an efficient platform for non-developer decision makers, stakeholders, and others to consume the content. In this session, we will look at how to use Jupyter Book to convert .ipynb files into publication-level results and share them online so that anyone can easily access them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sungjin Ahn
I am interested in technologies related to cloud, machine learning, and data science. I am also interested in resolving information gap issues caused by language factors. I am working as a Technical Trainer at Microsoft and am giving lectures to make it easy to understand Data &amp;amp; AI services in Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry></feed>