<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GIS Panel Discussion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/gis-panel-discussion-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authors: Panel participants: Sergio Ray (Arizona State U), Shaun
Walbridge (ESRI), Andrew Wilson (TWDB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: GIS - Geospatial Data Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Wilson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-01:scipy-2013/gis-panel-discussion-0.html</guid><category>geospatial data analysis</category><category>gis</category></item><item><title>Deploying Python Tools to GIS Users</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/deploying-python-tools-to-gis-users.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The geospatial community has coalesced around Python, both in the
commercial and open source spaces. In this talk, I'll show how Python
tools can be shared with users of ArcGIS, a commercial GIS system which
uses Python as its primary development environment. By constructing
small Python wrappers, code can be shared in graphical tools which
enable non-programmers to use what you've built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geospatial data is frequently manipulated directly using Python tools,
commonly built on top of powerful libraries such as GDAL, GEOS and
NetCDF. Delivering model results to end users in many instances requires
providing tools in familiar graphical environments, such as desktop GIS
systems, which can permit users without programming knowledge to
integrate models and results into their existing scientific workflows.
This talk discusses how to construct simple wrappers around existing
Python programs to enable their use by ArcGIS, a commonly used
commercial GIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two separate approaches will be illustrated: creating Python toolboxes,
or collections of tools embeddable in workflows, and creating customized
Python graphical add-ins, which can control the graphical environment
provided within ArcGIS. Building contextual help, interactive widgets,
and leveraging &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;numpy&lt;/tt&gt; for direct data integration will be discussed.
While ArcGIS exposes much of its functionality via the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ArcPy&lt;/tt&gt;
package, this talk instead focuses on integrating code from other
environments, and doesn't presume existing ArcGIS expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shaun Walbridge</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/deploying-python-tools-to-gis-users.html</guid><category>gis</category></item></channel></rss>