<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jonathan-whitmore.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Exploratory data analysis in python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/exploratory-data-analysis-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chloe Mawer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-17:pycon-us-2017/exploratory-data-analysis-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the recent advancements in machine learning algorithms and
statistical techniques, and the increasing ease of implementing them in
Python, it is tempting to ignore the power and necessity of exploratory
data analysis (EDA), the crucial step before diving into machine
learning or statistical modeling. Simply applying machine learning
algorithms without a proper orientation of the dataset can lead to
wasted time and spurious conclusions. EDA allows practitioners to gain
intuition for the pattern of the data, identify anomalies, narrow down a
set of alternative modeling approaches, devise strategies to handle
missing data, and ensure correct interpretation of the results. Further,
EDA can rapidly generate insights and answer many questions without
requiring complex modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a fantastic language not only for machine learning, but also
EDA. In this tutorial, we will walk through two hands-on examples of how
to perform EDA using Python and discuss various EDA techniques for
cross-section data, time-series data, and panel data. One example will
demonstrate how to use EDA to answer questions, test business
assumptions, and generate hypotheses for further analysis. The other
example will focus on performing EDA to prepare for modeling. Between
these two examples, we will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data profiling and quality assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic describing of the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualizing the data including interactive visualizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying patterns in the data (including patterns of correlated
missing data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing with many attributes (columns)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing with large datasets using sampling techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Informing the engineering of features for future modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying challenges of using the data (e.g. skewness, outliers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing an intuition for interpreting the results of future
modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intended audience for this tutorial are aspiring and practicing data
scientists and analysts, or anyone who wants to be able to get insights
out of data. Students must have at least an intermediate-level knowledge
of Python and some familiarity with analyzing data would be beneficial.
Installation of Jupyter Notebook will be required (and potentially, we
will also demonstrate analysis in JupyterLab, if its development in the
next few months allows). Instructions will be sent on what packages to
install beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Mental Models to Use and Avoid as a Data Scientist</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/mental-models-to-use-and-avoid-as-a-data-scientist.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Whitmore</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/mental-models-to-use-and-avoid-as-a-data-scientist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Jupyter Notebooks and Python code, we will present several data-driven examples of some simple, powerful, yet relatively uncommon, ways of thinking as a good Data Scientist. We will also warn about a few dangerous ways of thinking to avoid. Our Jupyter Notebooks and slides will be made freely available after the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>