<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Brett Lykins</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brett-lykins.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Nornir Solve Big Problems Fast</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2020/nornir-solve-big-problems-fast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brett Lykins</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-25:/pytexas-2020/nornir-solve-big-problems-fast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nornir is an extremely powerful Python automation framework. It is Python from top to bottom; made to be used by Python, for Python, and in Python. If you’re sick of learning a new pseudo-language or writing logic into YAML files, just to automate a simple task, Nornir is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nornir is an extremely powerful Python automation framework. It is Python from top to bottom; made to be used by Python, for Python, and in Python. If you’re sick of learning a new pseudo-language or writing logic into YAML files, just to automate a simple task, Nornir is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Brett Lykins
Brett Lykins is a Managing Consultant at Network to Code. He has been in the networking field since 2007, most recently spending 6 years at Rackspace Technology prior to joining Network to Code. Brett has a passion for helping businesses achieve success through innovative technologies, network automation, and process improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Nornir: Solve Big Problems Fast</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2020/nornir-solve-big-problems-fast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brett Lykins</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-06-18:/python-web-conf-2020/nornir-solve-big-problems-fast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Nornir: Solve Big Problems Fast&amp;quot; by: Brett Lykins
Managing over 60,000 network devices can be a mind-boggling and difficult task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years at Rackspace, we have tried many tools and frameworks to help us wrangle this problem, with varying degrees of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, we’ve begun making …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Nornir: Solve Big Problems Fast&amp;quot; by: Brett Lykins
Managing over 60,000 network devices can be a mind-boggling and difficult task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years at Rackspace, we have tried many tools and frameworks to help us wrangle this problem, with varying degrees of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, we’ve begun making use of Nornir to rapidly solve some of our complex and pressing issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nornir, as a native Python automation framework, allows us to leverage our existing Python based infrastructure, applications, and libraries and generate meaningful and powerful APIs and services for our end users and administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By utilizing Nornir’s built in Inventory, Task, and Result handling framework, we can quickly solve a problem and have an application from prototype to production in under a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows our network developers to focus on solving the problem at hand, not on reinventing the wheel for every new API or application that is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2020 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2020.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2020"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2020"></category></entry></feed>