<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ruth Ikegah</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ruth-ikegah.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Keynote: Women of Open Source Community Africa; Emerging a Star</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/keynote-women-of-open-source-community-africa-emerging-a-star.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ruth Ikegah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-18:/djangocon-us-2022/keynote-women-of-open-source-community-africa-emerging-a-star.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not just a zero-hero story but also about consistency and strategic effort. I began my journey into Open Source through the Women of Open Source Community Africa (WOSCA) initiative in Africa. WOSCA is an initiative of She Code Africa and Open Source Community Africa to promote a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not just a zero-hero story but also about consistency and strategic effort. I began my journey into Open Source through the Women of Open Source Community Africa (WOSCA) initiative in Africa. WOSCA is an initiative of She Code Africa and Open Source Community Africa to promote a more gender diverse, inclusive, and innovative culture within the African open source ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking on challenges from WOSCA brought me into contact with the open-source community, influencing my career to date. Despite the difficulties I faced in finding an OSS project, using Git, and navigating through project codebases, in less than a year, I launched myself from being a code newbie to being an advocate for beginners, the first African Female GitHub Star, and a Maintainer in the CHAOSS community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share how my strategy, lessons, and paths worked for me and how we can be more proactive about diversifying open source contributions in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2022"></category></entry></feed>