<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Harald Lieder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>High Volume PDF Text Extraction using Python Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/high-volume-pdf-text-extraction-using-python-open-source-tools.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-20]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/high-volume-pdf-text-extraction-using-python-open-source-tools"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/high-volume-pdf-text-extraction-using-python-open-source-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All major companies have huge amounts of (mostly PDF) documents that contain important - even critically important - information, that does no longer exist anywhere else in their data stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports, once generated for shareholders and legal or financial authorities, may still be useful for developing longterm forecasts or triggering company management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By definition, documents are intended for human perception, and as such contain unstructured data from an information technology perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, tools to extract PDF text content (mostly, but not only text) from millions of pages have become important vehicles to recreate structured information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation talks about extraction &amp;quot;need for speed&amp;quot; in this Big Data scenario, the need for integration with OCR capabilities and presents an open-source toolset which combines both, top-of-the-class performance and maximum extraction detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Harald Lieder</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/high-volume-pdf-text-extraction-using-python-open-source-tools.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item></channel></rss>