<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mario Munoz</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why I Didn't Start With Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/why-i-didnt-start-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I started learning Python, it was exciting&amp;amp;mdash;uncharted territory ahead. With powerful tools at my fingertips and plenty of ideas, they needed to find a place to land. A web framework, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bombarded my search engine with variations of &amp;quot;which Python framework should I use.&amp;quot; This led me to several &amp;quot;batteries included&amp;quot; vs &amp;quot;microframework&amp;quot; comparisons, with varying degrees of usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will highlight some reasons I ultimately decided to build my blog, [Python By Night](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pythonbynight.com"&gt;https://www.pythonbynight.com&lt;/a&gt;), on the backbone of FastAPI, and where I am today on my Python journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-17:/djangocon-us-2022/why-i-didnt-start-with-django.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>Back to the Future of Hypermedia in Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/back-to-the-future-of-hypermedia-in-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hypermedia is your friend&amp;quot;, they said. &amp;quot;You don't need JavaScript&amp;quot;, they said. &amp;quot;You'll be _fine_...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that hypermedia has been making a quiet resurgence in the web development landscape. One of the most popular toolkits in the Python space is htmx, offering a simple, declarative approach to AJAX and Server Sent Events directly from your HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this trend is taking shape in the Python ecosystem as a whole, Django goes even further, providing a maturing set of patterns, tooling, and projects that take full advantage of these new (old?) paradigms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some of the ways that Django is leading the charge in making hypertext cool again? What are some examples of projects already utilizing these tools? Is this a viable approach to _serious_ web design? And what are some of the ways that we could improve the adoption of hypermedia within Django, and Python as a whole?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-18:/djangocon-us-2023/back-to-the-future-of-hypermedia-in-django.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote - How To Be A Developer and Other Lies We Tell Ourselves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/keynote-how-to-be-a-developer-and-other-lies-we-tell-ourselves.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the children's book &amp;quot;Am I Even A Bee?&amp;quot; by Felicity Muth, Osmia begins feeling uneasy when she notices that she doesn't look like other bees at all. She even notices that some flies, moths, or beetles look more like bees than she does. Her perspective changes when she bumps into another unlikely bee named Xyla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our journey as developers sometimes follows a similar pattern. We may question what it means to be a developer in the first place and we're not quite sure how we fit in. On the other end, when we grow to be more experienced, we may inadvertently (or sometimes consciously) make it more difficult for others to _belong_.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the role of community in an individual's sense of identity, and what are some of the ways that we try to come to terms with our place within the developer landscape? Let's find out... together!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-24:/djangocon-us-2024/keynote-how-to-be-a-developer-and-other-lies-we-tell-ourselves.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Back to the Future of Hypermedia in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2023/back-to-the-future-of-hypermedia-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hypermedia is your friend,&amp;quot; they said. &amp;quot;You don't need JavaScript anymore,&amp;quot; they said. &amp;quot;You'll be _fine_...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that hypermedia has been making a quiet resurgence in the web development landscape. One of the most popular toolkits in the Python space is htmx, offering a simple, declarative approach to AJAX, CSS Transitions, and Server Sent Events directly from your HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, tools like TailwindCSS are making it easier to design your application simply by adding preconfigured CSS classes to your HTML elements. There's no need to meddle around with a CSS file or fear that completely changing your design will increase bloat or introduce clashing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now build a beautiful and responsive application with nothing more than Python and HTML!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's take a look at some of the tools that exist to enable the PyHAT (Python htmx ASGI Tailwind) stack and discuss where we can go from here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-30:/north-bay-python-2023/back-to-the-future-of-hypermedia-in-python.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2023</category></item><item><title>Bridges, or Benefits of Connecting Our Communities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2024/bridges-or-benefits-of-connecting-our-communities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bridge can both literally and metaphorically connect people of different communities together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why distinct communities exist within the software space, some good, some bad, some _natural_. For example, &amp;quot;baby duck syndrome&amp;quot;denotes a situation where a computer user &amp;quot;imprints&amp;quot; on the first system they learn. This can lead to identifying within the context of that community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the Python space, we can see small and large communities converging around a certain package or framework. These communities can be vibrant, supportive, and generally wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suggest ways in which we can &amp;quot;build bridges&amp;quot; from these communities in order to learn from each other, promote diversity, and break down barriers. This will not only benefit those of us within these communities, but also newcomers looking to find their footing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-29:/north-bay-python-2024/bridges-or-benefits-of-connecting-our-communities.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2024</category></item><item><title>Goodbye, "Hello, World." Hello, Functional FastAPI Web App!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/goodbye-hello-world-hello-functional-fastapi-web-app.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building a web application with Python is super easy. With just a few lines of code, you can get a simple, working app running directly on your computer's browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome! But then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial focuses on that awkward transition from beginner to intermediate—when you want a project to be less of a sketchpad and more of an actual, useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will learn tactics on how to find and use resources when devising a plan for your web application, as well as hands-on learning for tackling common (and necessary) aspects of building your app, such as configuration, app structure, and database modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the training, you will be following along as we build the foundation of a fully-functional web application, and will leave with the ability to further refine it for real-world scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/goodbye-hello-world-hello-functional-fastapi-web-app.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Day 2 PM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-2-pm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are a ~ 5 minutes long, on any topic of interest to other Python people. It doesn't have to be about something that you wrote, it can be something that you learned, or a technique you think other people will be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:35 - Christian Maureia Fredes - Python en Espanol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05:35 - Mario Munoz - My First Pycon: Reflections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:20 - Georgi Ker - Open source is a walk in the park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14:30 - Bence Nagy - Lint your code, repo, playlist, and fashion sense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19:49 - Mark Shannon - Help us speed up Python with benchmarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23:35 - Larry Hastings - Correlate your data with Correlate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;27:39 - Rich Taggart - The importance of effective concise communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35:38 - William Woodruff - Securing your PyPI account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40:18 - Alexa Lindberg - Generating recipes w/ GPT-2 &amp;amp; Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:53 - Srinivas Bontula - Managing transitive dependencies for Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50:25 - Adrian - When to rewrite in rust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Maureia Fredes</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-2-pm.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>so much depends upon... your python app's dependencies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/so-much-depends-upon-your-python-apps-dependencies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you keep track of your project's building blocks? Is it enough
just pinning your dependencies in a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/tt&gt; file? Or is
there any reason to learn one (or any) in a myriad of dependency
management tools?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It depends.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Untangling the complexity of this topic &lt;em&gt;might not&lt;/em&gt; be worth it for
certain small projects. But there are a lot of reasons why learning
about (and using) a dependency management tool will help you in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out why embracing proper dependency management can help your
project's predictability, sustainability, security, and yes, even
simplicity. Learn how you can use a tool like &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pdm&lt;/tt&gt; to help accomplish
these goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/so-much-depends-upon-your-python-apps-dependencies.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Web Development With A Python-backed Frontend: Featuring HTMX and Tailwind</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/web-development-with-a-python-backed-frontend-featuring-htmx-and-tailwind.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to bring hypermedia into your web design workflow, ditching the
complexity of JSON-over-HTTP for a more RESTful approach?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create and design your web application with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://htmx.org"&gt;htmx&lt;/a&gt;
and spark joy in your design process. Splash in a little &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tailwindcss.com"&gt;Tailwind
CSS&lt;/a&gt;, too. (&lt;em&gt;Ssshh. You're a Full-Stack
Developer now.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-19:/pycon-us-2023/web-development-with-a-python-backed-frontend-featuring-htmx-and-tailwind.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Add RSS to My Website with Python? Yes!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2022/add-rss-to-my-website-with-python-yes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should I add RSS to my website?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it really hard to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I do it all with Python?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's find out how!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-30:/pyohio-2022/add-rss-to-my-website-with-python-yes.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2022</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talk: Adding RSS... YES!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-adding-rss-yes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Munoz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/lightning-talk-adding-rss-yes.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>