<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Rory Tanner</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rory-tanner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Information micro-architecture: grammar, syntax, and cognitive rhetoric</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2016/information-micro-architecture-grammar-syntax-and-cognitive-rhetoric.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rory Tanner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:/write-the-docs-europe-2016/information-micro-architecture-grammar-syntax-and-cognitive-rhetoric.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most discussions of information architecture (IA) treat it as a
high-level discipline: it’s that thing we do site-wide, obsessing
happily about taxonomies, hierarchies, and metadata, so that our content
is more maintainable, navigable, and searchable. But what do your
readers do when they actually find the information that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most discussions of information architecture (IA) treat it as a
high-level discipline: it’s that thing we do site-wide, obsessing
happily about taxonomies, hierarchies, and metadata, so that our content
is more maintainable, navigable, and searchable. But what do your
readers do when they actually find the information that they’re looking
for? They read it. They read the words. Where’ s your information
architecture now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’ll identify a few different ways that we can apply IA
principles productively also at the micro levels of paragraph, sentence,
and phrase. We’ll focus on a series of syntactic structures that prove
their special architectural significance, based on the results of
ongoing content testing at docs.shopify.com and on recent work in the
field of psycholinguistics. These key examples show how far we can
improve sentence processing speed, and thereby reader engagement, when
we use grammar deliberately as information micro-architecture. The
composition and revision strategies that this approach suggests are
especially useful for anyone who’s writing, editing, or optimizing
content for use at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Europe 2016"></category></entry></feed>