<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_yotam-perkal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Dataframe Validation In Python - A Practical Introduction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2018/dataframe-validation-in-python-a-practical-introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yotam Perkal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-04:pycon-israel-2018/dataframe-validation-in-python-a-practical-introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Machine Learning models rely on data in order to make their predictions, data quality evaluation is a crucial aspect of any ML pipeline. We as Engineers/Data-Scientists, should validate our data in the same manner in which we validate our code. Data errors can lead to: Bad and costly decisions, Inaccurate predictions due to invalid data and Time waste. There is an abundance of different libraries that perform various kinds of data integrity checks. I will specifically focus on Dataframe validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will present the problem and give a practical overview (accompanied by Jupyter Notebook code examples) of three libraries that aim to address it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voluptuous - Which uses Schema definitions in order to validate data [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alecthomas/voluptuous"&gt;https://github.com/alecthomas/voluptuous&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engarde - A lightweight way to explicitly state your assumptions about the data and check that they're actually true [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/TomAugspurger/engarde"&gt;https://github.com/TomAugspurger/engarde&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TDDA - Test Driven Data Analysis [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tdda/tdda"&gt;https://github.com/tdda/tdda&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you will understand the Importance of data validation and get a sense of how to integrate data validation principles as part of the ML pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>