<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mine Cetinkaya-Rundel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reproducible Manuscripts with Quarto</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/reproducible-manuscripts-with-quarto.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we present a new capability in Quarto that provides a straightforward and user-friendly approach to creating truly reproducible manuscripts that are publication-ready for submission to popular journals. This new feature, Quarto manuscripts, includes the ability to produce a bundled output containing a standardized journal format, source documents, source computations, referenced resources, and execution information into a single bundle that is ingested into journal review and production processes. We'll demo how Quarto manuscripts work and how you can incorporate them into your current manuscript development process as well as touch on pain points in your current workflow that Quarto manuscripts help alleviate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/reproducible-manuscripts-with-quarto.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Reproducible, dynamic, and elegant books with Quarto</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/reproducible-dynamic-and-elegant-books-with-quarto.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building on my experience writing books with Quarto for various audiences (R learners, statistics learners, and Quarto learners), for various venues (self-published and publisher-published), in various formats (HTML books hosted online and PDF books printed), I will share best practices and tips and tricks for authoring reproducible, dynamic, and elegant books with Quarto. I will also highlight a few features from the recent releases of Quarto that pertain to books (e.g., flexible and custom cross-references, embedding computations from notebooks, and inline code in multiple languages) as well as share examples of how to make your web-hosted books more interactive with tools like webR and shinylive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mine Cetinkaya-Rundel</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/reproducible-dynamic-and-elegant-books-with-quarto.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>