<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tobias-brandt.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Friday Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2015/friday-lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Jorgensen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-02:pycon-za-2015/friday-lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtu.be/MNyOPWT8ncw?t=0h0m0s"&gt;(0:00:00)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Using Odo to
load data&lt;/strong&gt; by Tobias Brandt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtu.be/MNyOPWT8ncw?t=0h5m23s"&gt;(0:05:23)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sh&lt;/strong&gt; by
Adrianna Pińska&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtu.be/MNyOPWT8ncw?t=0h8m44s"&gt;(0:08:44)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Pygame Zero&lt;/strong&gt;
by Neil Muller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtu.be/MNyOPWT8ncw?t=0h11m57s"&gt;(0:11:57)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;How not to
hate Javascript&lt;/strong&gt; by Adam Jorgensen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtu.be/MNyOPWT8ncw?t=0h16m28s"&gt;(0:16:28)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Testing code
examples from your slides&lt;/strong&gt; by Jeremy Thurgood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category><category term="Room 215"></category></entry><entry><title>The Split-Apply-Combine Pattern for Data Science in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2015/the-split-apply-combine-pattern-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tobias Brandt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-01:pycon-za-2015/the-split-apply-combine-pattern-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many data science problems involve the application of a
split-apply-combine pattern, where you break up a big dataset into
independent pieces, operate on each piece in isolation and then put all
the pieces back together. This crops up in all stages of a data
analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During data preparation, when performing group-wise ranking,
standardisation, or normalisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During modelling, when fitting separate models to each group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During communication, when creating summaries or visualisations for
display or analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has many tools that make it easy to utilise this strategy when
solving data science problems. These range from list and dictionary
comprehensions in the language, the &lt;em&gt;map&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;reduce&lt;/em&gt; functions and
&lt;em&gt;itertools&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;functools&lt;/em&gt; modules in the standard library to dedicated
packages like &lt;em&gt;Pandas&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PyToolz&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Blaze&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dask&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit recognition of the applicability of the pattern allows one to
reuse standard components for the bookkeeping code that handles the
splitting and combining of the independent pieces. This allows one to
concentrate on the data analysis code that is unique to the problem at
hand. Since implicit in the pattern is the independence of the pieces,
its applicability immediately implies a strategy for parallelisation
which allows one to easily scale one's solution from single core to
out-of-core computation on multiple machines, often with only very few
changes to the code required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the pattern and how to recognise it by
presenting some common code blocks. We will then look at some of the
tools available, in particular &lt;em&gt;Pandas&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PyToolz&lt;/em&gt;, demonstrate their
use, and discuss their strengths and weaknesses. Finally we'll show how
to take a simple analysis and parallelise it to process a dataset that
is too large to fit in memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Room 211"></category></entry><entry><title>Deep Learning in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/deep-learning-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tobias Brandt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-07:pycon-za-2016/deep-learning-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will give an introduction to Neural Networks and Deep Learning
in Python. We will cover some of the history of Neural Networks and
obstacles that were encountered in the 1990s. This will then lead onto
the developments in 2006 and 2012 that lead to the resurgence of
interest in Neural Networks and the rebranding of the field as Deep
Learning. These developments will be illustrated by means of an extended
example of building a classifier of hand written digits on the MNIST
dataset. We will start with a simple Multi-Layer Perceptron and then
build this up into a Stacked Denoising Autoencoder. All code will be
developed using the Keras framework and TensorFlow and can be run on a
simple laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="keras"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry><entry><title>You suck at shell scripting: building awesome command line tools in Python for fun and profit!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/you-suck-at-shell-scripting-building-awesome-command-line-tools-in-python-for-fun-and-profit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tobias Brandt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-05:pycon-za-2017/you-suck-at-shell-scripting-building-awesome-command-line-tools-in-python-for-fun-and-profit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You do! You're aweful! You are as bad at shell scripting as Helen
Zille is at Twitter. However clever that 140 character bash one liner
seemed at the time, you know that you regretted it once it became an
integral part of your production build pipeline. This talk will show
you how to write maintainable Command Line Interfaces with click and
pathlib that won't leave you trying to rewrite your git commit
history after the next production system outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a simple illustration I'll demonstrate command line application to
download and analyse digital asset data (aka cryptocurrencies).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>