<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ingrid Towey</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to edit other people's content without pissing them off - Ingrid Towey</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2019/how-to-edit-other-peoples-content-without-pissing-them-off-ingrid-towey.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ingrid Towey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-20:/write-the-docs-portland-2019/how-to-edit-other-peoples-content-without-pissing-them-off-ingrid-towey.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Portland 2019</category></item><item><title>The Wisdom of Crowds: Crowdsourcing Minimalism in an Open Organization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/the-wisdom-of-crowds-crowdsourcing-minimalism-in-an-open-organization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Wisdom of Crowds:Crowdsourcing Minimalism in an Open Organization by
Ingrid Towey, Brice Fallon-Freeman, and Aneta Petrová&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does choosing flavors of LaCroix sparkling water for the Red Hat
breakroom have to do with improving technical documentation? At Red Hat,
everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, when we wanted to make a culture shift in our approach to
documentation, we couldn't legislate the change from the top down.
Managers and experts just don't have that kind of authority at Red Hat.
Changing the way we write has had to be a grassroots, bottom-up effort.
Just like we all get to vote on which flavors of sparkling water and
other beverages are stocked in our fridge, writers, editors, content
strategists, and managers ALL have a say in our latest writing trends.
At Red Hat, we have an open culture where people expect to have a voice
in decisions and aren't afraid to speak their minds. This open culture
affects every aspect of our working lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Did We Want to Change? We wanted to introduce our teams to
minimalist writing. But first we had to convince people that minimalism
isn't just about shorter sentences and less fluffy documentation.
Minimalist writing means that you focus like a laser on just what your
customers need at the moment. It's harder than it sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Did We Do It?First, we formed an international team that could
influence writers across all our geographical regions (geos). Brice
Fallon-Freeman (from Australia), Aneta Petrová (from the Czech
Republic), and I (from the US) became this team and brainstormed ways to
introduce these concepts to our departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aneta and Brice came up with the idea of crowdsourcing minimalist
writing critiques, and all three of us tried the concept in our
different geos. We got volunteers to join our groups, and then we got
more volunteers who were willing to have their content critiqued. This
“crowd” of writers and editors then worked together to give meaningful
feedback to the people who had been brave enough to volunteer their
content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this model is that it gives experienced writers a way to
teach more junior writers without the process being apparent. No one has
to admit to being ignorant. Inexperienced writers get to learn about
minimalism by watching other people apply it to real content and not in
some kind of fake training situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss our strategies and methods in more detail and
show examples of content before and after crowdsourced minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ingrid Towey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/the-wisdom-of-crowds-crowdsourcing-minimalism-in-an-open-organization.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Portland 2017</category></item></channel></rss>