<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aater-suleman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>3 hours to Docker fundamentals: Jumpstart your Docker knowledge</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/3-hours-to-docker-fundamentals-jumpstart-your-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aater Suleman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pytexas-2014/3-hours-to-docker-fundamentals-jumpstart-your-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker, the new trending containerization technique, is gaining interest
from organizations of all sizes with its lightweight, portable, “build
once, configure once and run anywhere” functionalities. Docker skills
are expected to be in high-demand because of its ability to streamline
workflow and reduce the need for hardware investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial focuses on providing an in-depth understanding of Docker
and how to containerize Python web applications. Docker provides a
mechanism for low overhead virtualization and can be a key aspect of a
DevOps architecture. Docker allows isolated environments to be created
in a single machine without imposing a performance overhead. This leads
to new possibilities for optimizing the developer flows and creating
multi-tenant applications, saving time coding and improving quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will highlight a list of best practices, pitfalls, and dos
and dont’s from real-world case studies. We’ll walk through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic concepts and Docker terminology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must Know Docker Features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker in the real world using examples of projects implemented at
Flux7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>