<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Emil Hvitfeldt</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_emil-hvitfeldt.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Styling and Templating Quarto Documents</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/styling-and-templating-quarto-documents.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emil Hvitfeldt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/styling-and-templating-quarto-documents.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quarto is a powerful engine to generate documents, slides, books, websites, and more. The default aesthetics looks good, but there are times when you want and need to change how they look. This is that talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you want your slides to stand out from the crowd, or you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quarto is a powerful engine to generate documents, slides, books, websites, and more. The default aesthetics looks good, but there are times when you want and need to change how they look. This is that talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you want your slides to stand out from the crowd, or you need your documents to fit within your corporate style guide, being able to style Quarto documents is a valuable skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have persevered and created the perfect document, you don't want the effort to go to waste. This is where templating comes in. Quarto makes it super easy to turn a styled document into a template to be used over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Tidypredict with recipes, turn workflow to SQL, spark, duckdb and beyond</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/tidypredict-with-recipes-turn-workflow-to-sql-spark-duckdb-and-beyond.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emil Hvitfeldt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/tidypredict-with-recipes-turn-workflow-to-sql-spark-duckdb-and-beyond.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidypredict is one of my favorite packages. Being able to turn a fitted model object into an equation is very powerful! However, in tidymodels, we use recipes more and more to do preprocessing. So far, tidypredict didn’t have support for recipes, which severely limited its uses. This talk …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidypredict is one of my favorite packages. Being able to turn a fitted model object into an equation is very powerful! However, in tidymodels, we use recipes more and more to do preprocessing. So far, tidypredict didn’t have support for recipes, which severely limited its uses. This talk is about how I fixed that issue. After spending a couple of years thinking about this problem, I finally found a way! Being able to turn a tidymodels workflow into a series of equations for prediction is super powerful. For some uses, being able to turn a model to predict inside SQL, spark or duckdb allows us to handle some problems with more ease.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>