<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Angel Rivera</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_angel-rivera.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>You want to Kubernetes? You MUST know Docker!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2020/you-want-to-kubernetes-you-must-know-docker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Angel Rivera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-06-18:/python-web-conf-2020/you-want-to-kubernetes-you-must-know-docker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You want to Kubernetes? You MUST know Docker!&amp;quot; by: Angel Rivera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving velocity is the new normal in software development and release practices. DevOps teams are becoming more efficient and optimizing their ability to produce quality software consistently and faster. This velocity can be directly attributed to the adoption …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You want to Kubernetes? You MUST know Docker!&amp;quot; by: Angel Rivera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving velocity is the new normal in software development and release practices. DevOps teams are becoming more efficient and optimizing their ability to produce quality software consistently and faster. This velocity can be directly attributed to the adoption of DevOps and CI/CD practices and the implementation of DevOps tooling is at the core of these gains. Container orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are incredibly powerful and companies of all shapes and sizes wanting to embrace this powerful technology find it very difficult to find a starting point. Often enough this can be attributed to the lack of foundational skill sets required to succeed in their Kubernetes journey. This includes the lack of knowledge and experience with the Docker runtime and containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a deep understanding of the Docker runtime and containers is a paramount in successfully adopting and operating Kubernetes. In this talk Angel will discuss the skill sets that individuals and teams must develop prior to endeavoring in their Kubernetes initiatives. Attendees will learn about the various skill sets needed to proficiently get started with Kubernetes. Angel will also discuss the critical aspects of the Docker runtime and containers along with demonstrating how to perform critical actions within the Docker runtime. Attendees will walk away with a solid grasp of the Docker runtime and containers that will better prepare them for their DevOps and Kubernetes initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2020 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2020.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2020"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2020"></category></entry><entry><title>CI/CD Agility and Controlling Pipeline Sprawl</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2021/cicd-agility-and-controlling-pipeline-sprawl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Angel Rivera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-03-22:/python-web-conf-2021/cicd-agility-and-controlling-pipeline-sprawl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;CI/CD Agility and Controlling Pipeline Sprawl&amp;quot; by: Angel Rivera
The adoption of CI/CD has automated the process of how DevOps teams build, test, and deliver software at rapid speeds and with high confidence. Although CI/CD platforms offer many benefits, in the attempt to make sophisticated pipelines …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;CI/CD Agility and Controlling Pipeline Sprawl&amp;quot; by: Angel Rivera
The adoption of CI/CD has automated the process of how DevOps teams build, test, and deliver software at rapid speeds and with high confidence. Although CI/CD platforms offer many benefits, in the attempt to make sophisticated pipelines, many teams run into the issue of “Pipeline Sprawl”. Pipeline sprawl makes it difficult for DevOps teams to identify and reuse common execution patterns which diminishes their ability to efficiently ship new code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Angel will discuss the common pain points associated with existing CI/CD platforms. The talk will pull in examples from his recent experience and conversations with DevOps teams from across the open source community, startups, and large enterprises. Attendees will learn technical strategies to develop optimized pipeline configurations and diminish potentially costly vendor-lock in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2021 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2021.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2021"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2021"></category></entry></feed>