<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python from Space</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2017/python-from-space.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is designed to give you all the tools you will need to go home and start using satellite imagery to make an impact on the world. The talk will cover finding, processing, evaluating and visualizing open satellite data using open source tools written in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth imaging satellites, just like our computers, are shrinking and becoming more ubiquitous than ever before. It is now possible to obtain open satellite data on a daily if not weekly basis and for this data to be put to work; helping us better understand our planet and quickly respond to disaster situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will work through a jupyter notebook that covers the satellite data ecosystem and the python tools that can be used to sift through and analyze that data. Topics include python tools for using Open Street Maps data, the Geospatial Data Abstraction Library (GDAL), and OpenCV and NumPy for image processing. This talk is intended for novice and intermediate python developers who are interested in using data science and satellite imagery for social good and fundamental scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katherine Scott is the image analytics team lead at Planet Labs. Katherine holds a masters degree in computer science from Columbia University and dual engineering degrees from the University of Michigan. Prior to working at Planet Katherine was a co-founder at Tempo Automation and Sight Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-12:pybay-2017/python-from-space.html</guid></item><item><title>Python from Space: Analyzing Open Satellite Imagery Using the Python Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/python-from-space-analyzing-open-satellite-imagery-using-the-python-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earth imaging satellites, just like our computers, are shrinking and
becoming more ubiquitous than ever before. It is now possible to obtain
open satellite data on a daily if not weekly basis and for this data to
be put to work; helping us better understand our planet and quickly
respond to disaster situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will work through a jupyter notebook that covers the
satellite data ecosystem and the python tools that can be used to sift
through and analyze that data. Topics include python tools for using
Open Street Maps data, the Geospatial Data Abstraction Library (GDAL),
and OpenCV and NumPy for image processing. This talk is intended for
novice and intermediate python developers who are interested in using
data science and satellite imagery for social good and fundamental
scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-19:pycon-us-2017/python-from-space-analyzing-open-satellite-imagery-using-the-python-ecosystem.html</guid></item><item><title>Caffe + Jupyter + Pandas It’s not rocket science, well sorta</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/caffe-jupyter-pandas-its-not-rocket-science-well-sorta.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will walk the users through the entire process of building a convolutional neural network for image classification. The process starts with a flask application to label your data, followed by characterizing, training, and evaluating the CNN using Pandas, Jupyter Notebooks, and Bokeh plots. Finally we show how the CNN can be deployed and used in real-world applications.
​
Abstract
Convolutional Neural Networks: they’re new, they’re big, they’re complex, they’re poorly documented and accordingly they are a little scary. At Planet we will image the entire earth every day, and to deliver that data to customers we need to analyze images without it ever being seen by human eyes. In this talk we’ll cover how to build, train, and characterize a neural net for image classification all from the comfort and safety of a Jupyter notebook. This talk will serve as a template for building and using your very own CNN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio
Katherine Scott is a senior software engineer at Planet working on image classification. Prior to planet Ms. Scott was the co-founder and CTO of Tempo Automation and a co-founder at Sight Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-20:pybay-2016/caffe-jupyter-pandas-its-not-rocket-science-well-sorta.html</guid></item><item><title>SimpleCV - Computer Vision using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/simplecv-computer-vision-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is a brief summary of Computer Vision tutorial we proposed for
PyCon. In this talk we will discuss what computer vision is, why it's
useful, what tools exist in the Python ecosystem, and how to apply it to
your project. The talk will focus on the SimpleCV library but also touch
upon NumPy. SciPy and iPython notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-15:pycon-us-2013/simplecv-computer-vision-using-python.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>A Gentle Introduction to Computer Vision</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/a-gentle-introduction-to-computer-vision.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you want to create a script to warp your photos, scrape your photo
archive for images of cats, or create a dart turret that follows your
face? This tutorial will show you how to do this and a whole lot more
with computer vision. The tutorial will be suitable for all levels of
developers and is a great way for python novice’s to explore the world
of computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-14:pycon-us-2013/a-gentle-introduction-to-computer-vision.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Hello Physical World: A Crash Course on the Internet of Things</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/hello-physical-world-a-crash-course-on-the-inter.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Live and direct from the PyCon stage learn how to connect your things to
the internet! In this talk we'll connect physical things and people to
the internet. In this talk we will live code a tiny web server that
interacts with the physical world via sensors, actuators, video, and
audio. We will explore tools in the Python ecosystem that make this
possible and show how they work together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-12:pycon-us-2014/hello-physical-world-a-crash-course-on-the-inter.html</guid></item><item><title>Robots Robots Ra Ra Ra!!!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/robots-robots-ra-ra-ra.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lots of people want to learn more about robotics but are unsure where to
start. Turns out there is a python robotics framework, and it runs some
of the most sophisticated robots in the world! It is also open source,
well-documented, and has a great community. In this talk we will look at
Robot Operating System ROS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katherine Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-11:pycon-us-2015/robots-robots-ra-ra-ra.html</guid></item></channel></rss>