<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Automate, contribute, repeat.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/automate-contribute-repeat.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Theo Crevon - Automate, contribute, repeat.
[EuroPython 2016]
[19 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/automate-contribute-repeat"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/automate-contribute-repeat&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Ableton we love music and we love open-source. Ansible is an
amazing tool which allows us to free more time for music by automating
boring and repetitive tasks, and to contribute back to the open-source
community with ease. Here's an opportunity to share our love for it,
our experience with it, and our contributions to it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers are never as convenient as when they work for us. If you
agree with this motto, then Ansible, a deployment and automation tool
written in Python, might come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Ableton, Ansible is involved in every aspect of deployment and
automation. From local machine setup, to vm creation and deployment in
our self-hosted datacenter, to our services in the immensity of the
cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is dead simple to use, can deal with any number of hosts in
parallel and has robust compatibility with Unix as well as Windows
systems, you will probably never have to write a shell script again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is written in Python and exposes a clean, extensible and
easy to adapt design and architecture; contributing features to the
project and fixing the bugs you might encounter during the journey is
extremely easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Ableton we love music and we love open-source. Ansible is an
amazing tool which allows us to free more time for music by automating
boring and repetitive tasks, and to contribute back to the open-source
community with ease. Here's an opportunity to share our love for it,
our experience with it, and our contributions to it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automate, contribute, repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Theo Crevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-31:europython-2016/automate-contribute-repeat.html</guid></item></channel></rss>