<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jorge-torres.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Machine Learning Democratization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/machine-learning-democratization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jorge Torres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/machine-learning-democratization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can't expect Machine Learning experts to be both domain experts
across various fields and also true experts in ML, it is crucial to
rethink how we build tools so that we can provide Machine Learning
capabilities to experts in various disciplines that are not necessarily
savvy in machine learning, but are experts in their own domains, so that
they can too become participants of the data science community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is divided into three sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one, dives into the importance of democratizing Machine
Learning, its objective is to demonstrate why now this is a crucial
issue to be solved and to show the risks and problems that present
themselves when Machine Learning Engineers take in the responsibility of
building predictive technologies in domains that are not necessarily
where they are the most experts on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of this talk focuses on some solutions and approaches to
challenges of democratizing Machine Learning, as well as the journey and
results we have seen at MindsDB while at this endeavor as well as what
would be new ways that the ML community can think of the next generation
of tools being built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and most extensive section of this talk, focuses on the new
issues that are born once machine Learning capabilities are on the hands
of not ML experts, more importantly, the implications of delegating the
Machine Learning machinery to a system, and what is important in order
to trust those systems. Which leads to the importance in further
developing our understanding of explainability, interpretability, and
robustness of ML.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>