<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Project Jupyter with Jessica Forde, Yuvi Panda and Chris Holdgraf: GCPPodcast 122</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/google-cloud-platform/project-jupyter-with-jessica-forde-yuvi-panda-and-chris-holdgraf-gcppodcast-122.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Original post: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gcppodcast.com/post/episode-122-project-jupyter-with-jessica-forde-yuvi-panda-and-chris-holdgraf/"&gt;https://www.gcppodcast.com/post/episode-122-project-jupyter-with-jessica-forde-yuvi-panda-and-chris-holdgraf/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Forde, Yuvi Panda and Chris Holdgraf join Melanie and Mark to discuss Project Jupyter from it’s interactive notebook origin story to the various open source modular projects it’s grown into supporting data research and applications. We dive specifically into JupyterHub using Kubernetes to enable a multi-user server. We also talk about Binder, an interactive development environment that makes work easily reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Forde</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-11:google-cloud-platform/project-jupyter-with-jessica-forde-yuvi-panda-and-chris-holdgraf-gcppodcast-122.html</guid></item><item><title>Binder 2.0: The Next Generation of Reproducible Scientific Environments with repo2docker and BinderHub</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/binder-20-the-next-generation-of-reproducible-scientific-environments-with-repo2docker-and-binderhub.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mybinder.org/"&gt;Binder&lt;/a&gt; allows researchers to quickly create
and share computational environments needed to interact with research
code and data. In this talk, we discuss the technical decisions and
changes made in Binder 2.0. Many changes focus on deployment —
modern-day cloud management tools (Kubernetes and Helm) and JupyterHub
make the service more reliable, scalable, and easier to deploy. We focus
on improvements for researchers using Binder to share their work.
Supporting new workflows, languages, and REST APIs in Binder 2.0
required developing two new components: repo2docker and BinderHub. We
will describe how these components work and how researchers can best use
them. We will conclude with a vision for the future of
Binder.Presenter(s): Speaker: M Pacer, University of California,
Berkeley Speaker: Chris Holdgraf, University of California, Berkeley
Speaker: Min Ragan-Kelley, IPython/Jupyter&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">M Pacer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-12:scipy-2018/binder-20-the-next-generation-of-reproducible-scientific-environments-with-repo2docker-and-binderhub.html</guid></item></channel></rss>