<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kang Ji-hoon</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kang-ji-hoon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Migrating from Python2 to Python3 after 15 years</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/migrating-from-python2-to-python3-after-15-years.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kang Ji-hoon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/migrating-from-python2-to-python3-after-15-years.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NAVER Search SRE team introduces the process of migrating Python2 used in the search service monitoring system to Python3.
The project, which has been in operation for a long time, was written with more than 40,000 lines of Python2 code for 15 years and was highly complex …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NAVER Search SRE team introduces the process of migrating Python2 used in the search service monitoring system to Python3.
The project, which has been in operation for a long time, was written with more than 40,000 lines of Python2 code for 15 years and was highly complex.
We will cover the difficulties encountered while continuously using Python2, the reasons for not switching to Python3 sooner, and the differences between Python2 and Python3 versions.
We will talk about how to build CPython directly before using Python3 and the process through which the conversion was done.
We will share the process through which the service was judged and verified for abnormalities after the conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kang Ji-hoon
Currently developing a search service monitoring system at NAVER Search SRE. At Pycon Korea 2020, I presented a session titled “Sharing Experience in Developing Sentence Similarity Algorithm in Script Prompter Service” and will be participating in Pycon Korea 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry></feed>