<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kim Tae-hong</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kim-tae-hong.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Let's try real-time data processing with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/lets-try-real-time-data-processing-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Tae-hong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-02:/pycon-korea-2022/lets-try-real-time-data-processing-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, there have been many introductions on the development of real-time data processing and analysis systems. In particular, data pipelines using Apache Kafka are being developed. I would like to share my experience developing an Apache Kafka consumer using Python through the system development process …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, there have been many introductions on the development of real-time data processing and analysis systems. In particular, data pipelines using Apache Kafka are being developed. I would like to share my experience developing an Apache Kafka consumer using Python through the system development process called real-time threat analysis. Through this presentation, I hope to be helpful to those who want to develop a service that collects real-time data to Apache Kafka and quickly develops a consumer using Python to process data. The main contents of this presentation are as follows. - Concepts required for data pipeline development - Introduction to Python Kafka client library - Experience in developing real-time data processing pipelines For questions and inquiries, please contact &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:rlaxoghd91&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;rlaxoghd91&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. Also, the code used in the presentation can be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/kimtaehong/pycon2022"&gt;https://github.com/kimtaehong/pycon2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Python Library"></category></entry></feed>