<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jeon Da-min</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>This is really non-existent, I started making the Korean package below because it didn't exist.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/this-is-really-non-existent-i-started-making-the-korean-package-below-because-it-didnt-exist.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is considered the second best language for everything with its rich packages and concise syntax.
Among many fields, task automation is perhaps the area where Python, with its concise syntax and high productivity, can excel the most.
Based on a huge community, among the hundreds of thousands of packages, there are many packages that can automate various office programs, so it is very easy to write Python scripts for task automation across multiple programs.
However, since I could not find an automation package for the Hangul program, which is mainly used in public institutions, I used to automate it using alternative methods.
I wanted to be able to create scripts in a Pythonic way, so I waited for someone to create a package, but I couldn't stand the inconvenience and ended up creating the Hangul package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeon Da-min
I majored in physics in college and have been working at KOICA, an international development cooperation organization, since 2015 to contribute to making a better world. I started learning Python around 2017 to work more efficiently. I am interested in data science and task automation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeon Da-min</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/this-is-really-non-existent-i-started-making-the-korean-package-below-because-it-didnt-exist.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>