<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Build a Private Developer’s Cloud Using TripleO</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2016/build-a-private-developers-cloud-using-tripleo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TripleO is an OpenStack Deployment &amp;amp; Management tool built using python. The Cloud, Big Data, Internet of Things – so many technologies are the new hotness right now and TripleO quickstart is one of many ways to dive into one of the largest open source umbrella project, OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">K Rain Leander</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-10:pycon-se-2016/build-a-private-developers-cloud-using-tripleo.html</guid><category>TripleO</category><category>OpenStack</category></item><item><title>Leveraging Procedural Knowledge</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/leveraging-procedural-knowledge-by-k-rain-leander.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leveraging Procedural Knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the road to senior developer, one has to learn multiple languages.
This often seems like a series of massive obstacles wherein each new
language resembles a new beginning. However, developers may often
underestimate the extent to which procedural knowledge from one language
transfers to a new language. In this talk, I will demonstrate that the
process from Red Hat Technical Account Manager to Django Girls workshop
participant to OpenShift developer was a series of procedural knowledge
transfers, wherein the obstacles to learning reduces with each new
technology that is learned. I will provide specific examples, from using
editors to troubleshooting issues, and conclude with practical
recommendations on which language to start with and how to create a
coherent plan for transitioning from one language to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HIXQ/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HIXQ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">K Rain Leander</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-24:djangocon-us-2015/leveraging-procedural-knowledge-by-k-rain-leander.html</guid></item></channel></rss>