<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Riley Murray</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_riley-murray.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Convex Optimization using CVXPY</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/convex-optimization-using-cvxpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steven Diamond</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/convex-optimization-using-cvxpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a convex optimization problem, the goal is to find a numerical assignment to a variable that minimizes an objective function, while also satisfying some constraints. The variable might represent parameters in a machine learning model, trades in a financial portfolio, actuations for controllers of a physical system, or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a convex optimization problem, the goal is to find a numerical assignment to a variable that minimizes an objective function, while also satisfying some constraints. The variable might represent parameters in a machine learning model, trades in a financial portfolio, actuations for controllers of a physical system, or tunable parameters for the design of a physical device. In industry, convex optimization problems are solved to land rockets, allocate financial portfolios, fit machine learning models, and control self-driving cars, among other applications. By abstracting away numerical solvers, CVXPY makes it easy to specify and solve convex optimization problems. CVXPY is best understood as a rewriting system for convex optimization problems, with a user-facing front-end and a solver-facing back-end:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front-end: CVXPY provides users with a large library of atomic functions, like exp, log, and norm. These atoms can be composed according to a simple rule that guarantees convexity of the composition, forming the grammar of CVXPY. Formulating problems using this rule is known as Disciplined Convex Programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back-end: When the &lt;cite&gt;solve&lt;/cite&gt; method on a problem is called, CVXPY transparently rewrites it into a terse numerical format expected by a solver; it will then call the solver, and return a solution to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will cover the basics of convex optimization with CVXPY, with an emphasis on real-world applications. Attendees will come away with:
* A thorough understanding of what a convex optimization problem is.
* The ability to model real-world problems as convex optimization problems, using CVXPY.
* The ability to use CVXPY Parameters to solve many related convex optimization problems in a short amount of time.
* An exposure to advanced features included in CVXPY, including quasiconvex programming, log-log convex programming, and differentiating through parametric convex optimization problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target audience:
* Computationally-minded scientists and engineers from any field who are interested in learning about a powerful tool for solving mathematically modeled problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:
* Basic understanding of linear algebra and probability.
* We do _not_ assume any familiarity with convex optimization or mathematical programming.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cvxgrp/cvx_short_course"&gt;https://github.com/cvxgrp/cvx_short_course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>