<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_bryan-van-de-ven.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Developing Dashboard Applications Using Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2018/developing-dashboard-applications-using-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-22:pydata-la-2018/developing-dashboard-applications-using-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover learn best practices for creating interactive,
streaming dashboard applications using Bokeh, based on the learnings
from developing the Dask Distributed diagnostic UI. During this talk,
we’ll develop a new Bokeh dashboard application to identify faces using
OpenCV.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting started with Bokeh / Let's build an interactive data visualization for the web..in Python!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-19:pydata-london-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bokeh data visualization library allows you to build interactive
visualizations for the web in python. This training gives a quick
introduction to Bokeh's unique features. We'll do exercixes building
up a variety of visualizations and finish discussing topics and
questions from participants related to their own datasets &amp;amp; needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/"&gt;Bokeh data visualization library&lt;/a&gt;
allows you to build interactive visualizations for the web in python. It
has a range of capabilities from quick &amp;quot;one-line&amp;quot; charts to streaming
datasets to integrating with your existing plot libraries such as
matplotlib or ggplot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This training gives a quick hands-on introduction to Bokeh's core
features. We'll do exercises building up a variety of visualizations and
finish up discussing topics and questions from participants related to
their own datasets &amp;amp; needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the planned outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes) Bokeh feature walk-through. The relationship between
bokeh, bokehjs and bokeh-server. The various API levels of bokeh
(models, plotting, charts). And, examples of a variety of
visualizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): Exercises - 1 - The charts &amp;amp; plotting interface. Get
quickly plotting in an ipython notebook. Different types of data
accepted, and how to customize a plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(10 minutes): Tips for navigating the Bokeh docs and examples as
you're getting up to speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): Exercises - 2 - (a) The models interface. Build a
custom plot from the ground up using the Models API. (b) Quick, yet
custom, using the charts interface and models together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(10 minutes): Sharing your plots. Overview of the different ways to
share your plots with your colleagues and the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): Exercises - 3 - Add custom interactivity - Customize
your hover and selections. Implement linked selection, brushing, and
panning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): open space for questions and interactively solving
Bokeh problems on your real-life problems &amp;amp; data as time permits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Bokeh - Interactive Visualization for Large Datasets</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualization-for-large-datasets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van De Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-02-21:pydata-london-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualization-for-large-datasets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a Python interactive visualization library for large datasets
that natively uses the latest web technologies. Its goal is to provide
elegant, concise construction of novel graphics in the style of
Protovis/D3, while delivering high-performance interactivity over large
data to thin clients. This tutorial will walk users through the steps to
create different kinds of interactive plots using Bokeh. We will cover
using Bokeh for static HTML output, the IPython notebook, and plot
hosting and embedding using the Bokeh server.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Bokeh and Friends</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2017/bokeh-and-friends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-06:pydata-seattle-2017/bokeh-and-friends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Bokeh rapidly approaches a 1.0 release, the project focus is shifting towards making Bokeh a solid, stable, minimal (but extensible) platform for interactive web-based visualization. This talk will briefly discuss some of the history of the project leading up to the present, including lessons learned about OSS development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Bokeh rapidly approaches a 1.0 release, the project focus is shifting towards making Bokeh a solid, stable, minimal (but extensible) platform for interactive web-based visualization. This is great news for users, but also means that developers of higher-level or domain-specific tools can build upon it with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will briefly discuss some of the history of the project leading up to the present, including lessons learned about OSS development. After this quick status update, I will discuss and demonstrate two tools that are already building on and integrating with Bokeh:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datashader is a sophisticated Python rendering pipeline that can be used together with Bokeh to effectively visualize large (billion+ point) data sets quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holoviews is a very high level data language for slicing and dicing datasets that can automatically build interactive visualizations using Bokeh, based on the structure of your data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive Data Visualization with HoloViews &amp; Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/interactive-data-visualization-with-holoviews-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jean-Luc Stevens</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-04:scipy-2017/interactive-data-visualization-with-holoviews-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are audio issues with this video that cannot be fixed. We recommend listening to the tutorial without headphones to minimize the buzzing sound.
Tutorial information may be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/"&gt;https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualization represents a major bottleneck in scientific research, engineering, data science, and data analytics. The tools in the Python scientific ecosystem make it very simple to do many of the tasks required, but building visualizations to help understand complex patterns and relationships in your data still typically involves a large amount of custom coding for every new type of plot. Writing long and detailed scripts for plotting slows down the process of exploration and reporting, while the difficulty involved means that many important observations and discoveries are missed due to inadequate visualizations. The complexity of the resulting plotting code makes it difficult to rapidly build sophisticated, interactive visualizations that can quickly reveal the underlying structure of the data, and once such complex plotting scripts have been created they can be a major impediment to future understanding, reproduction, and modification of the research process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will learn how to approach the problem of interactive visualization declaratively. Using the HoloViews library, you can annotate your data and store it in general-purpose containers that will be instantly visualizable. The declarative objects in HoloViews wrap your data to make it incredibly easy to visualize how different sets of data relate to each other, using subfigures, animations, interactive widgets and custom interactions. This flexibility has made HoloViews the chosen future replacement for the high-level Bokeh Charts API and works particularly well with IPython/Jupyter notebooks, where you can immediately see the output from selecting, combining, slicing, or sampling these objects. Each of these operations generates a different type of visualization, that can be flexibly extended even to complex dashboards deployed using the Bokeh server or Jupyter dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core design principle of HoloViews is to make it simple to create complex plot layouts and interactivity by applying compositional operations to a small number of elements and containers. Since HoloViews separates the declaration of the data from the precise visual details of the plotting code, the same HoloViews objects can be rendered using matplotlib for publication-quality plots, or bokeh for interactive use. Overall, this means the user can focus on &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; to plot before worrying about &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; exactly it should be displayed, providing a huge boost in productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="HoloViews"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Beautiful Interactive Visualizations in the Browser with Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/beautiful-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-24:pydata-seattle-2015/beautiful-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive Data Visualization Applications for the Browser w/ Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/interactive-data-visualization-applications-for-the-browser-w-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-20:pybay-2016/interactive-data-visualization-applications-for-the-browser-w-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest&lt;/a&gt;) provides a compelling open-source platform for creating interactive data visualization applications in the browser. This talk will demonstrate Bokeh's newest capabilities: the second generation Bokeh server, APIs for streaming data, new hooks for user-extensibility (e.g. to easily leverage JavaScript 3D plot libraries), new features for GIS, and more.
​
Abstract
With support from the DARPA XDATA Initiative, commercial engagements, and contributions from over 150 community members, the Bokeh visualization library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source project with heavy interest and following on GitHub (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bokeh/bokeh"&gt;https://github.com/bokeh/bokeh&lt;/a&gt;). The principal goals of Bokeh are to provide capability to developers and domain experts: easily create and share interactive, versatile, and powerful visualizations that extract insight from data sets that may be remote, large, or streaming. Bokeh provides a platform for anyone to create interactive data and visualization applications in the browser for themselves, their colleagues, or for a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give a quick overview of recent developments, and demonstrate some of the newest capabilities of Bokeh including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bokeh applications and the second generation Bokeh server (that is more performant, better documented, and much simpler to use and deploy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APIs for streaming data (both in the notebook and Bokeh applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to extend Bokeh with your own custom functionality (for example to create 3D plots or network graphs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent GIS features such as support for GeoJSON and tiled map data sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Datashader library that can be used together with Bokeh to visualize billions of data points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the talk will discuss near-term plans for the project, it's governance, and community development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/bryan-van-de-ven-interactive-data-visualization-applications-for-the-browser-with-bokeh"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/bryan-van-de-ven-interactive-data-visualization-applications-for-the-browser-with-bokeh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Data Applications with Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/data-applications-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van De Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/data-applications-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Applications with Bokeh&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive Data Visualization in the Browser with Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/interactive-data-visualization-in-the-browser-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/interactive-data-visualization-in-the-browser-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Bryan Van de Ven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With support from the DARPA XDATA Initiative, commercial engagements, and contributions from over 150 community members, the Bokeh visualization library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source project with heavy interest and following on GitHub (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bokeh/bokeh"&gt;https://github.com/bokeh/bokeh&lt;/a&gt;). The principal goals of Bokeh are to provide capability to developers and domain experts: easily create and share interactive, versatile, and powerful visualizations that extract insight from data sets that may be remote, large, or streaming. Bokeh provides a compelling open-source visualization platform for scientists who want to create interactive data applications in the browser for themselves, their colleagues, or for a wider audience, recently evidenced by the first instances of interactive Bokeh visualizations appearing in published journal articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give a quick overview of recent developments, and demonstrate some of the newest capabilities of Bokeh including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bokeh applications and the second generation Bokeh server (that is more performant, better documented, and much simpler to use and deploy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APIs for streaming data (both in the notebook and Bokeh applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to extend Bokeh with your own custom functionality (for example to create 3D plots or network graphs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent GIS features such as support for GeoJSON and tiled map data sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the session will conclude with a brief demonstration using the new Datashader library can be used together with Bokeh to visualize billions of data points.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 19/05/2016</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-19052016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-23:scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-19052016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryan Van de Ven - OSS &amp;#64; Continuum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wesley Ramos - Teoria de Resposta ao Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raul Lopez Briega - Github Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nahuel Defossé - Pilas Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Ochoa - VisPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filpe Fernandes - Catalog Driven Workflow: SECOORA Model Skill Assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nahuel Defossé: Divy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Story Time with Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/story-time-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/story-time-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Bokeh for Data Storytelling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2015/bokeh-for-data-storytelling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-05:euroscipy-2015/bokeh-for-data-storytelling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bokeh visualization library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source project. This talk will describe Bokeh and show how it can enable domain experts to easily create novel and powerful visualizations that extract insight from remote, possibly large data sets, to be published to the web for others to explore and interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Tutorial | Basic Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2015/tutorial-basic-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-05:euroscipy-2015/tutorial-basic-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to use Bokeh to create interactive visualizations and data applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Bokeh for Data Applications and Visualization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2016/bryan-van-de-ven-bokeh-for-data-applications-and-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-12:pydata-london-2016/bryan-van-de-ven-bokeh-for-data-applications-and-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData London 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is an Interactive visualization library that targets modern web browsers for presentation. It provides elegant, concise construction of basic exploratory and advanced custom graphics, but can also be used to develop sophisticated dashboards and data applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0:00
- 0:05 Introduction and Setup
0:05
- 0:20 Review and Practice with Bokeh Basics
0:20
- 0:40 Widgets, Interactions and Streaming in the Notebook
0:40
- 1:05 Handling Larger Data Sets with Bokeh and Datashader
1:05
- 1:30 Building Bokeh Applications&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote - Learning == Creating (We're All in it Together)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2015/keynote-bryan-van-de-ven-learning-creating-were-all-in-it-together.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-11-09:python-brasil-2015/keynote-bryan-van-de-ven-learning-creating-were-all-in-it-together.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote da Conferência Python Brasil 11 [2015] - São José dos Campos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A conferência Python Brasil aconteceu dos dias 09 e 10 de Novembro de 2015, no Novotel, em São José dos Campos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keynote do Bryan Van de Ven, sobre Learning == Creating (We're All in it Together)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mais informações:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pythonbrasil.github.io/pythonb"&gt;http://pythonbrasil.github.io/pythonb&lt;/a&gt;...
Twitter: &amp;#64;pythonbrasil
Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.facebook.com/pythonbrasil"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/pythonbrasil&lt;/a&gt;
Manual do Big Kahuna: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://manual-do-big-kahuna.readthed"&gt;https://manual-do-big-kahuna.readthed&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Bokeh: Interactive Visualizations in the Browser</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a Python visualization library for large datasets that natively
uses the latest web technologies. Its goal is to provide concise
construction of novel graphics, while delivering high-performance
interactivity over large data to thin clients. This talk will cover the
motivation and architecture behind Bokeh, demonstrate interesting uses
and capability, and discuss future plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With support from the DARPA XDATA Initiative, and contributions from
community members, the Bokeh visualization library
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source
project with heavy interest and following on GitHub
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ContinuumIO/bokeh"&gt;https://github.com/ContinuumIO/bokeh&lt;/a&gt;). The principal goals of Bokeh are
to provide capability to developers and domain experts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily create novel and powerful visualizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that extract insight from remote, possibly large data sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published to the web for others to explore and interact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe how the architecture of Bokeh enables these
goals, and demonstrate how it can be leveraged by anyone using python
for analysis to visualize and present their work. We will talk about
current development and future plans, including a brief discussion of
Joseph Cottam's exciting academic work on abstract rendering for large
data sets that is going into Bokeh
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/JosephCottam/AbstractRendering"&gt;https://github.com/JosephCottam/AbstractRendering&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="vis"></category></entry></feed>