<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ralph-heinkel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The value of mindfulness and how it has arrived at Google</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/the-value-of-mindfulness-and-how-it-has-arrived-at-google.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ralph Heinkel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/the-value-of-mindfulness-and-how-it-has-arrived-at-google.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ralph Heinkel - The value of mindfulness and how it has arrived at Google
[EuroPython 2016]
[22 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/the-value-of-mindfulness-and-how-it-has-arrived-at-google"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/the-value-of-mindfulness-and-how-it-has-arrived-at-google&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness has proven to be a foundational skill that started as a
pure buddhist practice. Nowadays mindfulness serves as the core
technique of several western programs ranging from  curing stress-
induced medical problems to curricula for teaching successful business
leadership, such as the Search Inside Yourself program developed at
Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this seminar is to provide a practical experience of
mindfulness with a short introduction to how it can be applied by
digital workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness has proven to be a foundational skill that started as a
pure buddhist practice. Nowadays mindfulness serves as the core
technique of several western programs ranging from  curing stress-
induced medical problems to curricula for teaching successful business
leadership, such as the Search Inside Yourself  (SIY) program
developed at Google in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind is the root of all things. Neuroscience shows that attention is a
fundamental function of the mind. Being able to direct attention to
the present moment - and keep it there while performing daily tasks -
is a great tool to navigate through life and its  challenges with more
engagement, more happiness, and more resilience. Focusing attention in
a relaxed way enables us to disconnect from the overall noise found in
a high-speed environment and get things done without feeling too
overwhelmed by them. But being effective is not only about checking
off more tasks - it is about how we are in resonance with our
environment, how we interact with others, and how we face the
increasing complexity in our professional life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this seminar is to provide a practical experience of
mindfulness with a short introduction to how it can be applied in a
technology driven world as experience by digital workers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Combining the powerful worlds of Python and R</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/combining-the-powerful-worlds-of-python-and-r.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ralph Heinkel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-25:europython-2014/combining-the-powerful-worlds-of-python-and-r.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although maybe not very well known in the Python community there exists
a powerful statistical open-source ecosystem called R. Mostly used in
scientific contexts it provides lots of functionality for doing
statistical analysis, generation of various kinds of plots and graphs,
and much, much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The triplet &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.r-project.org"&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rforge.net/Rserve/"&gt;Rserve&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pyRserve/"&gt;pyRserve&lt;/a&gt; allows the
building up of a network bridge from Python to R: Now R-functions can be
called from Python as if they were implemented in Python, and even
complete R scripts can be executed through this connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pyRserve is a small open source project originally developed to fulfill
the needs of a German biotech company to do statistical analysis in a
large Python-based Lab Information Management System (LIMS). In contrast
to other R-related libraries like RPy where Python and R run on the same
host, pyRserve allows the distribution of complex operations and
calculations over multiple R servers across the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this talk is to show how easily Python can be connected to R,
and to present a number of selected (simple) code examples which
demonstrate the power of this setup.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>pyRserve</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2011/pyrserve.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ralph Heinkel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-05:pycon-de-2011/pyrserve.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pyRserve ist ein Python Client, der es erlaubt, über TCP/IP eine
Verbindung zu dem Statistik Paket R auf einem Server aufzubauen und
Remote Procedure Calls abzusetzen. Dadurch können aus Python heraus
komplexe statistische Berechnungen durchgeführt werden. In diesem
Vortrag wird pyRserve vorgestellt und anhand von Beispielen gezeigt, wie
man den vollen Umfang von R aus Python heraus nutzen kann.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>