<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_robert-lehmann.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Teaching Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/teaching-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lehmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/teaching-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Python in bringing people closer to programming has been popular
for a while. But what are the most effective ways to do so? The
OpenTechSchool reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has been used in educational programmes ever since. With a
bandwidth that large, navigating the landscape of Python tutorials is
hard indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will look at successful Python teaching material. From the
numerous iterations our material has gone through, we draw conclusions
on what's crucial in teaching Python. It will introduce how the
OpenTechSchool is teaching Python and what measures it found most
effective in spreading programming in general and Python in particular.
Among these are rapid feedback, supervised learning, localization, and
knowing your target audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is a member of the OpenTechSchool, a free community
initiative which offers Python workshop on a number of topics. Some of
the workshops have been running for more than two years now. He has
written the first versions of &amp;quot;Python for beginners,&amp;quot; a workshop which
has been used in many cities to teach Python to programming novices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>OpenTechSchool Potpourri</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/opentechschool-potpourri.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lehmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-15:pycon-de-2013/opentechschool-potpourri.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die OpenTechSchool ist eine Community-Initiative die freie
Programmierworkshops für sämtliche Zielgruppen anbietet. Mit mehreren
freien Materialien für Programmieranfänger und -fortgeschrittene bringen
wir unseren Teilnehmern Grundlagen oder spezielle Themenkomplexe bei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag blickt zurück auf ein Jahr voller Workshops in mehreren
Städten, mit einem Fokus auf Python. Mit verschiedenen Konzepten wie
Workshops, Learners Meetups und Hackdays haben wir das verschiedenste
Publikum — von Konferenzteilnehmern zu Kindern — bedient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortragende speist seine Erfahrungen aus der Erarbeitung mehrerer
Python-Curriculi, dem Coaching auf verschiedenen Events in Berlin sowie
der Organisation der Lokalgruppe in Zürich.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="opentechschool"></category></entry></feed>