<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Chiin-Rui Tan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Accessible Python education for schoolgirls using Avocados, Zombies, and Korean!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/accessible-python-education-for-schoolgirls-using-avocados-zombies-and-korean.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine this school scenario: an entire year group of students aged 11-12, the majority completely new to coding, undergoing 6 hours of compulsory lessons on Python for Scientific Computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine these outcomes:
•       Students wanting to continue coding from the lessons outside of class in their own time
•       Students asking to replicate the lesson computing environment at home
•       Students disappointed for the lessons to come to an end and asking for more
•       Students struggling in Science discovering intrinsic ability in computing, bringing new enjoyment and confidence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lastly, imagine that all the students are girls!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will share this actual case study of a pioneering Python education initiative implemented at a secondary school for girls in London, UK for a cohort of 120 students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will gain actionable insights of the factors that enabled these children to develop basic but working proficiency of a mainstream scientific data stack using typical school IT resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this talk aims to increase awareness of Scientific Computing &amp;amp; Data Science as potentially effective and empowering Python education for young people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chiin-Rui Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/accessible-python-education-for-schoolgirls-using-avocados-zombies-and-korean.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Case Study</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Education</category><category>Learning</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>How Scientific Computing is advancing the world of Football</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/how-scientific-computing-is-advancing-the-world-of-football.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How Scientific Computing is advancing the world of Football
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Chiin-Rui Tan, Sara Nunnington&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ultra-competitive sporting world, the value of data and computing has been on the rise. When the difference between winning and losing, success and failure hinges on the smallest of margins, being able to calculate and implement optimal, timely decisions is literally game-changing, and potentially life-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Football, or Soccer to others, as the most popular sport in the world, perfectly illustrates the importance of computational data-empowered decisions, both on and off the pitch. This talk, accessible to beginner Pythonistas with intermediate football knowledge, provides the audience with an overview of popular applications of Python Scientific Computing &amp;amp;amp; Data Science within the ecosystem of typically well-funded clubs, but emphasising the opportunities available to democratise such enabling tech more inclusively, and benefiting a more diverse base. Example takeaways are real-world use-cases involving spatio-temporal tracking &amp;amp;amp; event data, Computer Vision/video AI, tactical analysis, and player insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk ultimately supports the audience discovering this fast-growing domain and the role Python has and continues to play in advancing it globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chiin-Rui Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/how-scientific-computing-is-advancing-the-world-of-football.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks Thursday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/lightning-talks-thursday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Forum Hall on 2023-07-20]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/lightning-talks-thursday"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/lightning-talks-thursday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Thursday's lightning talks, hosted by Omotola Omotayo ⬇️
00:00 &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Thursday's Lightning Talks&lt;/em&gt;
00:28 &lt;em&gt;Being Nice&lt;/em&gt; — Daniele Procida
07:41 &lt;em&gt;I am Biased&lt;/em&gt; —  Filipa Andrade
11:46 &lt;em&gt;What APL Taught Me about Python&lt;/em&gt; — Rodrigo Girão Serrão
16:54 &lt;em&gt;All You Need to Know About Federated Learning in 2 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; — Sarah Diot-Girard
21:43 &lt;em&gt;A Different (Travel) Program&lt;/em&gt; — Riccardo Polli
23:40 &lt;em&gt;fstring.help Or: How I Bought Yet Another Domain&lt;/em&gt; — Florian Bruhin
28:57 &lt;em&gt;Community Conference / Events Announcements &amp;amp; Celebration!&lt;/em&gt;
35:49 &lt;em&gt;Pick a Side: Planet or Profit?&lt;/em&gt; — Chiin-Rui Tan
41:18 &lt;em&gt;Isolated Python Functions&lt;/em&gt; — Meder Kamalov
45:12 &lt;em&gt;Gambatte Terminal&lt;/em&gt; — Vincent Michel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing up is on a first-come-first-served basis. The queue is reset every day in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presenter may talk about / present (almost) everything with certain boundaries. And each presentation is not longer than five minutes and full of fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniele Procida</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/lightning-talks-thursday.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item></channel></rss>