<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_john-berryman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-28T15:15:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Search Logs + Machine Learning = Auto-Tagged Inventory</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/search-logs-machine-learning-auto-tagged-inventory.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-28T15:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T15:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>John Berryman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/search-logs-machine-learning-auto-tagged-inventory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventbrite is exploring a new machine learning approach that allows us
to harvest data from customer search logs and automatically tag events
based upon their content. The results have allowed us to provide users
with a better inventory browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For e-commerce applications, matching users with the items they want is
the name of the game. If they can't find what they want then how can
they buy anything?! Typically this functionality is provided through
search and browse experience. Search allows users to type in text and
match against the text of the items in the inventory. Browse allows
users to select filters and slice- and-dice the inventory down to the
subset they are interested in. But with the shift toward mobile devices,
no one wants to type anymore - thus browse is becoming dominant in the
e-commerce experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there's a problem! What if your inventory is not categorized?
Perhaps your inventory is user generated or generated by external
providers who don't tag and categorize the inventory. No categories and
no tags means no browse experience and missed sales. You could hire an
army of taxonomists and curators to tag items - but training and
curation will be expensive. You can demand that your providers tag their
items and adhere to your taxonomy - but providers will buck this new
requirement unless they see obvious and immediate benefit. Worse,
providers might use tags to game the system - artificially placing
themselves in the wrong category to drive more sales. Worst of all,
creating the right taxonomy is hard. You have to structure a taxonomy to
realistically represent how your customers think about the inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventbrite is investigating a tantalizing alternative: using a
combination of customer interactions and machine learning to
automatically tag and categorize our inventory. As customers interact
with our platform - as they search for events and click on and purchase
events that interest them - we implicitly gather information about how
our users think about our inventory. Search text effectively acts like a
tag and a click on an event card is a vote for that clicked event is
representative of that tag. We are able to use this stream of
information as training data for a machine learning classification
model; and as we receive new inventory, we can automatically tag it with
the text that customers will likely use when searching for it. This
makes it possible to better understand our inventory, our supply and
demand, and most importantly this allows us to build the browse
experience that customers demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will explain in depth the problem space and Eventbrite's
approach in solving the problem. I will describe how we gathered
training data from our search and click logs, and how we built and
refined the model. I will present the output of the model and discuss
both the positive results of our work as well as the work left to be
done. Those attending this talk will leave with some new ideas to take
back to their own business.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Elasticsearch in an Hour</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2017/elasticsearch-in-an-hour.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>John Berryman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-30:pyohio-2017/elasticsearch-in-an-hour.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The use of search is ubiquitous. As a developer you need search in your technology tool belt. This talk introduces Elasticsearch, a front-running, open source search technology. We'll create an application, execute a search, and dive into internals so that you'll know where search is most useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>