<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - San Gultekin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_san-gultekin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Risk Bounds for Low Cost Bipartite Ranking</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/risk-bounds-for-low-cost-bipartite-ranking.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>San Gultekin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/risk-bounds-for-low-cost-bipartite-ranking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Risk Bounds for Low Cost Bipartite Ranking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Gultekin (Columbia University)*; John Paisley (Columbia University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bipartite ranking is an important supervised learning problem; however, unlike regression or classification, it has a quadratic dependence on the number of samples. To circumvent the prohibitive sample cost, many recent work focus on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Risk Bounds for Low Cost Bipartite Ranking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Gultekin (Columbia University)*; John Paisley (Columbia University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bipartite ranking is an important supervised learning problem; however, unlike regression or classification, it has a quadratic dependence on the number of samples. To circumvent the prohibitive sample cost, many recent work focus on stochastic gradient-based methods. In this paper we consider an alternative approach, which leverages the structure of the widely-adopted pairwise squared loss, to obtain a stochastic and low cost algorithm that does not require stochastic gradients or learning rates. Using a novel uniform risk bound---based on matrix and vector concentration inequalities---we show that the sample size required for competitive performance against the all-pairs batch algorithm does not have a quadratic dependence. Generalization bounds for both the batch and low cost stochastic algorithms are presented. Experimental results show significant speed gain against the batch algorithm, as well as competitive performance against state-of-the-art bipartite ranking algorithms on real datasets.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>