<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tuan Anh Le</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tuan-anh-le.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Learning to learn generative programs with Memoised Wake-Sleep</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/learning-to-learn-generative-programs-with-memoised-wake-sleep.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luke Hewitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/learning-to-learn-generative-programs-with-memoised-wake-sleep.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Learning to learn generative programs with Memoised Wake-Sleep&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Hewitt ( Massachusetts Institute of Technology)*; Tuan Anh Le (MIT); Joshua Tenenbaum (MIT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We study a class of neuro-symbolic generative models in which neural networks are used both for inference and as priors over symbolic, data-generating programs. As generative models, these …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Learning to learn generative programs with Memoised Wake-Sleep&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Hewitt ( Massachusetts Institute of Technology)*; Tuan Anh Le (MIT); Joshua Tenenbaum (MIT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We study a class of neuro-symbolic generative models in which neural networks are used both for inference and as priors over symbolic, data-generating programs. As generative models, these programs capture compositional structures in a naturally explainable form. To tackle the challenge of performing program induction as an ‘inner-loop’ to learning, we propose the Memoised Wake-Sleep (MWS) algorithm, which extends Wake Sleep by explicitly storing and reusing the best programs discovered by the inference network throughout training. We use MWS to learn accurate, explainable models in three challenging domains: stroke-based character modelling, cellular automata, and few-shot learning in a novel dataset of real-world string concepts.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>