<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - PJ Hagerty</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pj-hagerty.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Urban Legends: What You Code Makes You Who You Are</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2016/urban-legends-what-you-code-makes-you-who-you-are.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>PJ Hagerty</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-10:/pycon-se-2016/urban-legends-what-you-code-makes-you-who-you-are.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tools are just a means to an end. So why do developers think the language they use defines the problems they solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will take a look at misconceptions across the board, some experiences, both positive and negative, people have had crossing barriers to new languages, and show …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tools are just a means to an end. So why do developers think the language they use defines the problems they solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will take a look at misconceptions across the board, some experiences, both positive and negative, people have had crossing barriers to new languages, and show some of the benefits thinking of one's self as a coder and not a &amp;quot;Ruby coder&amp;quot; or a &amp;quot;Python dev&amp;quot; can have on being a better problem solver.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon SE 2016"></category></entry><entry><title>Coding and the Mozart Effect</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2022/coding-and-the-mozart-effect.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>PJ Hagerty</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-21:/pytexas-2022/coding-and-the-mozart-effect.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most developers code to music...some are even musicians themselves. Is it possible to streamline workflow by adjusting how we listen to music and what music we listen to? Studies have shown that exposure to certain kinds of music can help to develop cognitive strength and improve performance of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most developers code to music...some are even musicians themselves. Is it possible to streamline workflow by adjusting how we listen to music and what music we listen to? Studies have shown that exposure to certain kinds of music can help to develop cognitive strength and improve performance of tasks. This talk will explore those studies and show what sort of things can be done to improve the listeners environment and help people to create better code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: PJ Hagerty
PJ is the founder of DevRelate.io and a board member of Open Sourcing Mental Illness (OSMIhelp.org). He is an organizer of DevOps Days Buffalo, CodeDaze, and ElixirDaze. PJ is a developer, writer, speaker, musician, and Community Advocate. He is known to travel the world speaking about programming and the way people think and interact. He is also known for wearing hats.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2022"></category></entry></feed>