<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_richard-spiers.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Monkeying around with Twisted</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/monkeying-around-with-twisted.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Spiers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/monkeying-around-with-twisted.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twisted is an open source framework for writing network based services.
It utilises an asynchronous, event driven model which allows the rapid
development of custom network protocols. While Twisted makes
implementing network services much easier, it comes with its own set of
challenges. One of these challenges involves tracking the context of
multiple requests. In a traditional web server the thread ID could be
used to track a particular request and modify log entries appropriately.
However, this does not work in Twisted as it utilises a single thread
(generally speaking). We have chosen to tackle this issue, amongst
others, by monkey patching some of the Twisted subsystems. Through this
talk we will introduce Twisted as a viable option for programming
network based services. No previous Twisted knowledge is required, and
the concepts introduced will be explained through real world examples of
restful controllers implemented in Twisted. This primer will be followed
by a discussion on our solution to the context tracking problem as well
as some of the other areas in which we have found monkey patching to be
beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry></feed>