<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Diego Torres Quintanilla</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_diego-torres-quintanilla.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How JupyterLab 4 is strategic to Two Sigma and you</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/how-jupyterlab-4-is-strategic-to-two-sigma-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Diego Torres Quintanilla</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/how-jupyterlab-4-is-strategic-to-two-sigma-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two Sigma's financial scientists spend many of their most productive hours testing their hypotheses about the market in JupyterLab. Like with any research environment, responsiveness and easy collaboration are key to keep our users focused on their hypotheses, not the tools they use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two Sigma's financial scientists spend many of their most productive hours testing their hypotheses about the market in JupyterLab. Like with any research environment, responsiveness and easy collaboration are key to keep our users focused on their hypotheses, not the tools they use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss Two Sigma's partnership with QuantStack's team to deliver direct-to-upstream contributions to improve JupyterLab's performance and furtheir its Real-Time Collaboration (RTC) initiative, all to be soon seen in JupyterLab 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond just a teaser of new features to get excited for, this talk is a testimonial of a fruitful and successful relationship between two private entities, Two Sigma and QuantStack, which not only furthers each partner's own internal goals but also improves quality of life of all Jupyter users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key takeaways
Get excited for JupyterLab 4, which will bring large performance improvements throughout the whole application.
JupyterLab 4 will pave the way for a Real-Time Colalboration mode in JupyterLab, similar to Google Docs. Come join the effort!
For small and medium-size organizations, an external partnership with a team like QuantStack can help them exponentiate their impact in the open-source community.
Making sure your organization runs on the latest version of Jupyter is key to shipping your contributions directly to your users.
JupyterLab's extensibility is a great way to deliver value to an organization's internal users. But it can also undermine your organization's ability to stay current with open-source.
Call to action
Two Sigma, QuantStack, and many other members of the Jupyter community are actively contributing to Jupyter's general performance and making Real-Time Collaboration a reality. Use the lessons you learn in this talk to get your organization involved, or get involved yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience
This talk is aimed at 1. Jupyter users looking to hear about new and exciting features and 2. users of Jupyter at private entities who are interested in ways to get their organization involved in open-source development. You do not need any specific knowledge of how Jupyter works to get value from this talk. If you're interested in contributing to Jupyter, the talk will also give you an idea of features that are being actively developed by the project's contributors and hopefully get you excited about contributing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Cleaning, optimizing and windowing pandas with numba</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/cleaning-optimizing-and-windowing-pandas-with-numba.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Diego Torres Quintanilla</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:/pydata-new-york-city-2019/cleaning-optimizing-and-windowing-pandas-with-numba.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has accrued a sizable debt in flexibility and maintainability to deliver excellent performance. This talk will show how Pandas maintainers and Two Sigma are using Numba to pay off some of this debt in one of the gnarliest parts of the code: window operations. If merged to mainstream …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has accrued a sizable debt in flexibility and maintainability to deliver excellent performance. This talk will show how Pandas maintainers and Two Sigma are using Numba to pay off some of this debt in one of the gnarliest parts of the code: window operations. If merged to mainstream Pandas, this work will deduplicate code, make it easier to debug and make window operations extensible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData New York City 2019"></category></entry></feed>