<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_javier-alvarez.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>High performance machine learning with dislib</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/high-performance-machine-learning-with-dislib.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Javier Álvarez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/high-performance-machine-learning-with-dislib.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCOMPSs is a distributed programming model and runtime for Python.
PyCOMPSs' main goal is to make distributed computing accessible to
non-expert developers by providing a simple programming model, and a
runtime that automates many aspects of the parallel execution. In
addition to this, PyCOMPSs is infrastructure agnostic, and can run on
top of a wide range of platforms, from HPC clusters to clouds, and from
GPUs to FPGAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present dislib, a distributed machine learning library
built on top of PyCOMPSs. Inspired by scikit-learn, dislib programming
interface is based on the concept of &lt;em&gt;estimators&lt;/em&gt;. This provides a clean
and easy-to-use API that highly increases the productivity of building
large-scale machine learning pipelines. Thanks to PyCOMPSs, dislib can
run in multiple distributed platforms without changes in the source
code, and can handle up to billions of input samples using thousands of
CPU cores. This makes dislib a perfect tool for scientists (and other
users) that are not machine learning experts, but that still want to
extract useful knowledge from extremely large data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present dislib, a distributed machine learning library
built on top of PyCOMPSs programming model. One of the main focuses of
dislib is solving large-scale scientific problems on high performance
computing clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>