<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Bruno Gonçalves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Natural Language Processing from Scratch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2017/natural-language-processing-from-scratch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We introduce the fundamental technique of natural language processing using Python and OpenNasa datasets. In particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bag of words models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stop words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tf/idf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic topic modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;word clouds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A GitHub repository will be made available with all the code and slides used during the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bruno Gonçalves</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-07:/pygotham-2017/natural-language-processing-from-scratch.html</guid><category>PyGotham 2017</category></item><item><title>Graphs for Data Science with NetworkX</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2021/graphs-for-data-science-with-networkx.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphs are simple concepts: a set of individual Nodes (components) connected
by Edges (relationships). In this very simplicity lies their power. They can
describe the structure of our friendships, connections between airports, the
spread of diseases from person to person, the relation of one concept to
another, how species interact in an ecosystem or how computers communicate
to form the World Wide Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networks are the fundamental language of our increasingly complex world and
the key to successfully understand it. By exploring in detail the way graphs
can be used to explore, describe, analyze and understand empirical datasets
we will put you at the forefront of this growing field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lecture we will use Python's NetworkX to build our understanding of
network representations and algorithms by exploring real world network
datasets such as the airline transportation network, the bitcoin transaction
network, the road network of open street map, etc. Through this practical
approach attendees will better understand the fundamental ideas and concepts
that lie at the base of  our increasingly complex world and take the first
steps towards being at the forefront of this growing field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bruno Gonçalves</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-01:/pygotham-2021/graphs-for-data-science-with-networkx.html</guid><category>PyGotham 2021</category></item></channel></rss>