<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Chioma Onyekpere</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_chioma-onyekpere.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Monitoring carbon emissions: making the impact of your python code visible</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/monitoring-carbon-emissions-making-the-impact-of-your-python-code-visible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica Greene</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/monitoring-carbon-emissions-making-the-impact-of-your-python-code-visible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If the Internet was a country, it would be the 4th largest polluter”
[1] The power to make impactful change through technology has never been
greater. Doing so starts with understanding the problem space. Our
workshop will guide you through the process of quantifying the emissions
of your Python …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If the Internet was a country, it would be the 4th largest polluter”
[1] The power to make impactful change through technology has never been
greater. Doing so starts with understanding the problem space. Our
workshop will guide you through the process of quantifying the emissions
of your Python code and integrating this awareness into your monitoring
strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the basics of observability, an essential part of
operating a deployed service, you’ll learn why it’s important to monitor
your Python code, what makes a good metric, and the common pitfalls to
avoid. We’ll then dive into the practical aspects of exposing and
creating custom metrics, scraping and storing them in Prometheus, a time
series database, and then visualising them in dashboards using Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will also include an overview of climate-conscious tech,
discussing the tech industry’s contribution to the climate crisis and
introducing the principles of green coding. We’ll explore techniques and
libraries for extracting metrics for carbon awareness, because &amp;quot;If you
can't measure it, you can't improve it.&amp;quot; (Peter Drucker) and guide
attendees through a practical session on instrumenting your Python code
for carbon emissions and visualizing this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By attending this workshop, you’ll gain valuable insights and hands-on
experience in making your code more carbon-conscious. You’ll learn about
carbon-aware workloads, strategies for making your services more energy,
and carbon efficient, the importance of cloud provider regions and
transparency, and how to advocate for change. These skills and knowledge
can be integrated into your day-to-day work, making a real difference in
our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us in this journey towards a more sustainable future in tech and a
better planet for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*source: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sustainablewebmanifesto.com/#citation"&gt;https://www.sustainablewebmanifesto.com/#citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>