<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andrew-stretton.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-27T10:30:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Frictionless Data, Frictionless Development edit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/frictionless-data-frictionless-development-edit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T10:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T10:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Stretton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/frictionless-data-frictionless-development-edit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A common problem in Data Engineering is how to create a platform capable both of importing and exporting tabular data in numerous formats and of maintaining a change history of the data while users update and query it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools like Trifacta &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cloud.google.com/dataprep/"&gt;Google Cloud Dataprep&lt;/a&gt; provide a turnkey solution to part of the pipeline but the open source &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://frictionlessdata.io/tools/"&gt;Frictionless Data tools&lt;/a&gt; from OKFN can provide a simpler subset of these features tailored to your requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pandas.pydata.org/"&gt;Pandas&lt;/a&gt; is built around the Dataframe, the Frictionless Data approach uses &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://frictionlessdata.io/data-packages/"&gt;data packages&lt;/a&gt; consisting of a JSON table schema and a data URI. These schemata can be easily generated for any dataset and work well for a number of applications such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating new data with tools like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://goodtables.okfnlabs.org/"&gt;Goodtables&lt;/a&gt; or tableschema-py&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a data update interface with tools such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/handsontable/handsontable"&gt;Handsontable JS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating declarative data processing pipelines that a front end can easily interact with via &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/frictionlessdata/datapackage-pipelines"&gt;datapackages pipelines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kubernetes.io/"&gt;kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing data into various databases and repository tools such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ckan/ckan/tree/master/ckanext/datastore"&gt;CKAN datastore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extending the schema to allow export to linked data formats such as IIIF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover these use cases and compare with the approaches taken by other open-source data science / BI tools such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/blaze/datashape"&gt;Datashape&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/blaze/odo"&gt;ODO&lt;/a&gt; from Continuum and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/apache/incubator-superset"&gt;Superset&lt;/a&gt; from AirBnB. I will aim to demonstrate that that lightweight web standards like datapackages speed up the development process.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Twisted up in a Distributed Tornado - a beginners guide to async frameworks in python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2017/twisted-up-in-a-distributed-tornado-a-beginners-guide-to-async-frameworks-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Stretton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-05:pydata-london-2017/twisted-up-in-a-distributed-tornado-a-beginners-guide-to-async-frameworks-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twisted up in a Distributed Tornado - a beginners guide to async frameworks in python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filmed at PyData 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
By coming to this tutorial you will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What event-driven Python Frameworks are and why they are useful
How to overcome any fears you may have about event-driven Python programming
Enough examples to be able to consider projects like Dask/Distributed and Tornado for your next project
Abstract
At some point in a career in data science, software development or data engineering you will be looking to develop a piece of code that runs alongside another piece of code. For example, you might want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use all of your processors when running a script
Consume social media data as it is created
Create a super simple task scheduler without an ugly while True loop
Understand how Jupyter notebooks work
Write to a database and move on to the next task without waiting for confirmation
Call a function and throw an exception if it takes too long
There are numerous ways of achieving such concurrency. If creating a project to run on one or a few machines which needs good exception handling then I find tools like Twisted, Tornado and Dask/Distributed ideal for the above tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a python developer I have always tended to work with Celery and felt intimidated by the different flow control when using async tools like Twisted and Tornado. In this tutorial I will walk through the examples above and talk about how I went from Async novice to Dask/Distributed contributor in 6 months. The tutorial will concentrate mainly on practical use cases. Along the way we will encounter some bumps in the road which will hopefully aid attendees' understanding of the basic dos and don'ts around these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By coming to this tutorial you will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What event-driven Python Frameworks are and why they are useful
How to overcome any fears you may have about event-driven Python programming
Enough examples to be able to consider projects like Dask/Distributed and Tornado for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>