<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Natalie O'Shea</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building a Flexible, Scaleable Self-Serve Reporting System with Shiny</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/building-a-flexible-scaleable-self-serve-reporting-system-with-shiny.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working in the high-touch world of consulting, our team needed to develop a reporting system that was flexible enough to be tailored to the specific needs of any given partner while still reducing the highly manual nature of populating client-ready slide decks with various metrics and data visualizations. Utilizing the extensive resources developed by the R user community, I was able to create a flexible, scalable reporting system that allows users to populate templated Google slide decks with metrics and professional-grade visualizations using data pulled directly from our database at the time of query. This streamlined approach enables our consultants to spend less time copy-pasting data from one channel to another and instead focus on what they do best: surfacing business-relevant insights and recommendations for our partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By sharing my approach to customizable self-serve reporting in Shiny, I hope attendees will walk away with new ideas about how to combine parameterized reporting and dashboard development to get the best of both worlds. Additionally, I hope to end by sharing how this project was pivotal in making the business case for procuring Posit products for my broader organization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalie O'Shea</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/building-a-flexible-scaleable-self-serve-reporting-system-with-shiny.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item></channel></rss>