<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lucas Durand</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>🐍 Building an Interactive 🕸️ Network Graph 🕸️ to Understand Communities 👩🏽‍💻</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/building-an-interactive-network-graph-to-understand-communities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="abstract"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are hard to understand, developers doubly so! In this tutorial,
we will explore &lt;strong&gt;how communities form&lt;/strong&gt; in organizations to develop a
better solution than &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;The Org Chart&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;. We will walk through using a few
key Python libraries in the space, develop a toolkit for Clustering
Attributed Graphs (more on that later) and build out an extensible
interactive dashboard application that promises to take your legacy HR
reporting structure to the &lt;strong&gt;next level&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="description"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will develop some fundamental knowledge on Graph
Theory and capabilities in using key Python libraries to construct and
analyze network graphs, including &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;xarray&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;networkx&lt;/tt&gt;, and
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;dash-cytoscape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;. We will also dig into exploratory data analysis of
people data, and use &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;faker&lt;/tt&gt; to generate realistic &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; data that
matches our statistical understanding, without breaching data privacy.
The goal of this talk is to build the tools you need to launch your own
interactive dashboard in Python that can help explore communities of
people based on shared characteristics (e.g. programming languages,
projects worked on, apps used, management structure). The data we will
dig into focuses on building a better understanding of &lt;strong&gt;developers +
users&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they form communities, but this could just as easily
be extended to any social network. The work we do here can be easily
extended to your communities and use cases -- let's build something
together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="getting-started"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the tutorial, head over to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://lucasdurand.xyz/network-graph-tutorial/"&gt;https://lucasdurand.xyz/network-graph-tutorial/&lt;/a&gt; for more information on
setting up your environment. If you have your own &lt;em&gt;people data&lt;/em&gt;, bring
that along too and we can give it a try, but if not then we will make
some synthetic data as a stand-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lucas Durand</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-15:/pycon-us-2024/building-an-interactive-network-graph-to-understand-communities.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>