<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sarah-diot-girard.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>What about tests in Machine Learning projects?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/what-about-tests-in-machine-learning-projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Diot-Girard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-04:euroscipy-2019/what-about-tests-in-machine-learning-projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once your machine learning POC seems promising and your development
environment is set up, the next step is to refactor your code and write
TESTS. We know that a lot of people think tests are too complicated and
boring to write and they are not very useful. Some manual checks can
address the need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;It is not totally false. Tests can be really boring and time consuming
to write when you don't have the right tools, the right APIs, the
right environments or the right code structure.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;But it is always a bad idea to ignore tests or to perform them
manually. If you want to be involved in your project life cycle, if
you want to bring it from POC to production you need to care about
tests. After some years tackling production bugs, you can't feel safe
delivering without tests as you can't start driving until your seat
belt is fastened.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more than one way to test. Tests can be split on several levels
(unit, component, functional, performances, etc...) to be able to
quickly identify the faulty code/data/parameter. Tests must also be
automated in a Continuous Integration and run at least on each
experiment before merging it in the baseline pipeline as it is done in
software engineering (the CI is triggered on each feature branch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about how to easily write tests and testable code, how to
avoid most common traps and what are the benefits of tests on
unrealistic data in your Machine Learning project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Tests on real data are also really important but they are not the main
purpose of this talk.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides are here:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sdg.jlbl.net/slides/tests_for_datascientist/presentation.html"&gt;sdg.jlbl.net/slides/tests_for_datascientist/presentation.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good practices tell you must write tests! But testing Machine Learning
projects can be really complicated. Test writing seems often
inefficient. Which kind of test should be written? How to write them?
What are the benefits?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Privacy-preserving Machine Learning for text processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2019/privacy-preserving-machine-learning-for-text-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Diot-Girard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-09:pydata-berlin-2019/privacy-preserving-machine-learning-for-text-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sarah Diot-Girard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyData
Privacy is something we all care about, but when it is time to put our principles into application, it is not so trivial, especially when working with text. This talk aims at presenting a few options to handle privacy when dealing with text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/MF9DAV"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/MF9DAV&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to easily set up and version control your Machine Learning Pipelines</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2019/how-to-easily-set-up-and-version-control-your-machine-learning-pipelines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Diot-Girard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-10:pydata-amsterdam-2019/how-to-easily-set-up-and-version-control-your-machine-learning-pipelines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full Title: How to easily set up and version your Machine Learning pipelines, using DVC and MLV-tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephanie Bracaloni, Sarah Diot-Girard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard about Machine Learning versioning solutions? Have you ever tried one of them? And what about automation? Come with us and learn how to easily build versionable pipelines! This tutorial explains through small exercises how to setup a project using DVC and MLV-tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Usages avancés de NumPy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2018/usages-avances-de-numpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Diot-Girard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-fr-2018/usages-avances-de-numpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python a la réputation d'être lent. C'est pourtant un langage largement
utilisé dans des contextes de calculs numériques intensifs. La clé de ce
paradoxe ? NumPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumPy, ou Numerical Python, permet un stockage efficace des matrices
numériques de dimension arbitraire. Cette présentation a pour objectif
de donner quelques trucs et astuces qui vous permettront un usage
optimal des NumPy arrays. Nous aborderons notamment la vectorisation, le
broadcasting, les ufuncs et les strides.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Trust me, I'm a Data Scientist - ethics for builders of data-based applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/trust-me-im-a-data-scientist-ethics-for-builders-of-data-based-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Diot-Girard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/trust-me-im-a-data-scientist-ethics-for-builders-of-data-based-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Science is gonna save the world, right? Or is it? Machine Learning
epic fails are being largely commented. It’s easy to convince ourselves
that they are due to the inconsiderate misuse of Data Science. But is it
really so? Is it possible that innocuous choices lead an honnest team to
a disaster?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the course of this talk, we will build together an (imaginary)
application: a disruptive AI-based smart virtual assistant, pledging to
help high-schoolers with their university choice. We will see how
unintended biaises may creep in at every step, even with the best of
intentions. We will explore different topics, such as algorithmic
fairness, model interpretability and the handling of minority classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this practical example, this talk will present a review of major
ethical pitfalls identified in the Machine Learning community along with
suggestions on how to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is intended for beginner to intermediate Data Scientists, and
people working with Data Scientists, even without specific technical
knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides :
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sdgjlbl.github.io/Presentations/Data%20Science%20and%20Ethics/presentation.html#/"&gt;https://sdgjlbl.github.io/Presentations/Data%20Science%20and%20Ethics/presentation.html#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>