<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mahe Iram Khan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Publishing your Python project, the conda way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/publishing-your-python-project-the-conda-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conda is an open source, language agnostic package and environment
management system for Linux, macOS, and Windows. The conda ecosystem,
including the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conda-forge.org/"&gt;conda-forge&lt;/a&gt; package
repository, is widely used to install, run and update packages and their
dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial you will learn how to create a full-fledged and easy to
install Python software package using conda. We will start by
introducing software packaging and packaging concepts (package
dependencies, open source licensing, ...), and an introduction to the
conda ecosystem and how conda implements software packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our time will be spent doing a hands-on walk through of how to
prepare a Python software package for conda, and then how to submit that
package to the conda-forge, a widely used community driven package
repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop is a hands-on workshop, where participants use their own
laptops to prepare a full-fledged Python software package that is
submission-ready for the conda-forge package repository. &lt;strong&gt;Participants
need to bring a WiFi enabled laptop with a web browser, a command line
interface, a text editor program, and git and/or a GitHub client already
installed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Workshop participants will gain a basic understanding of software
packaging, and how to prepare and publish their packages in the conda
ecosystem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Clements</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/publishing-your-python-project-the-conda-way.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>