<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Aleksander Molak</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aleksander-molak.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Practical graph neural networks in Python with TensorFlow and Spektral</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/practical-graph-neural-networks-in-python-with-tensorflow-and-spektral.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aleksander Molak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-13:/pycon-de-2022/practical-graph-neural-networks-in-python-with-tensorflow-and-spektral.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Aleksander Molak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Deep Learning
Graph neural networks (GNNs) have become one of the hottest research topics in recent years. Their popularity is reinforced by hugely successful industry applications in social networks, biology, chemistry, neuroscience and many other areas. One of the main challenges faced by data …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Aleksander Molak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Deep Learning
Graph neural networks (GNNs) have become one of the hottest research topics in recent years. Their popularity is reinforced by hugely successful industry applications in social networks, biology, chemistry, neuroscience and many other areas. One of the main challenges faced by data scientists and researchers who want to apply graph networks in their work is that they require different data structures and a slightly different training approach than traditional deep learning models. During the workshop we’ll demonstrate how to implement graph neural networks, how to prepare your data and – finally – how to train a GNN model for node-level and graph-level tasks using Spektral and TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/ZMFZUB"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/ZMFZUB&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2022"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConDE"></category><category term="pyconde2022"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="pydataberlin2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The Battle of Giants - Causality vs NLP - From Theory to Practice</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/the-battle-of-giants-causality-vs-nlp-from-theory-to-practice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aleksander Molak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/the-battle-of-giants-causality-vs-nlp-from-theory-to-practice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 3.2 new papers published on Arxiv every day in 2022, causal inference has exploded in popularity, attracting large amount of talent and interest from top researchers and institutions including industry giants like Amazon or Microsoft. Text data, with its high complexity, posits an exciting …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 3.2 new papers published on Arxiv every day in 2022, causal inference has exploded in popularity, attracting large amount of talent and interest from top researchers and institutions including industry giants like Amazon or Microsoft. Text data, with its high complexity, posits an exciting challenge for causal inference community. In the workshop, we'll review the latest advances in the field of Causal NLP and implement a causal Transformer model to demonstrate how to translate these developments into a practical solution that can bring real business value. All in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category></entry></feed>