<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sebastián Ramírez</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynote: Modern Python through FastAPI and friends</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2021/keynote-modern-python-through-fastapi-and-friends.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote: Modern Python through FastAPI and friends - Sebastián Ramírez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India is the largest gathering of Pythonistas in India for the Python programming language.
The 13th edition of PyCon India took place online from 17th Sept to 20th Sept 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to subscribe to the PyCon India channel: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;
Follow PyCon India on Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconindia"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconindia&lt;/a&gt;
Follow PyCon India on Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/PyConIndia/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/PyConIndia/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastián Ramírez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-18:/pycon-india-2021/keynote-modern-python-through-fastapi-and-friends.html</guid><category>PyCon India 2021</category><category>PyConIndia</category><category>PyConIndia2021</category></item><item><title>Introducción a FastAPI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/introduccion-a-fastapi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(English version below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aprende a hacer una API lista para producción en muy poco tiempo usando
FastAPI... explicado con memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Con documentación y validación de datos automáticas, basada en
estándares, alto desempeño y otras ventajas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Además, puedes escribir todo el código con autocompletado y chequeos de
errores de tipos, incluso para tus propios datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En esta charla verás de qué se trata FastAPI, qué beneficios te da y por
qué sería útil para ti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;También verás cómo declarar datos para recibir en cada request (cada
mensaje HTTP), usando tipos de Python estándar. Incluyendo parámetros en
el path, en queries, y en cuerpos (body) de mensajes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;También verás cómo declarar cuerpos de mensajes complejos con datos muy
anidados. Y así, aún con código muy simple, tener documentación para
todo tu API, serialización (conversión de datos) y validación, todo
siguiendo estándares, y todo automáticamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to create an API ready for production in very little time
using FastAPI... explained with memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your API will have automatic validation, documentation based on
standards, high performance, and several other features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this, having editor support including autocompletion everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you will learn what FastAPI can do, and how it could
benefit you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will see how to declare the data you want to receive in each request
using standard Python type annotations. Including path parameters, query
parameters, body payloads with JSON, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also see how to use simple, standard, Python type annotations
to declare complex JSON body payloads with deeply nested structures, and
get automatic data validation, serialization, and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastián Ramírez</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/introduccion-a-fastapi.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>