<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Auto scaling on the Cloud the right way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2014/auto-scaling-on-the-cloud-the-right-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Horizontal scaling on the Cloud is the way to adapt resources to load of systems. The Cloud allows users to scale virtually indefinitely, or enough for their needs.
This way the number of servers follows trend of requests, and TCO (Total Cost of Owneship) of IT infrastructure can be minimised. Nonetheless companies can avoid dealing with capacity planning and pre-provisioning issues.
This talk will show how to use Python and Rackspace/OpenStack API and SDK to implement an event-based scaling solution (software released under the open-source Apache License).
The outline of this talk will be:
- Auto scale (Why, What, When, How);
- Leveraging Cloud Monitoring to trigger Auto Scale policies;
- Configuration management system (Ansible and playbooks) to deploy applications;
- &amp;quot;Go Live!&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Update&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Rollback&amp;quot; patterns.
Outcome: Knowledge of scaling techniques, Cloud patterns and issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simone Soldateschi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-06-02:pycon-russia-2014/auto-scaling-on-the-cloud-the-right-way.html</guid></item><item><title>Orchestration and CI/CD with Ansible and OpenStack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/orchestration-and-cicd-with-ansible-and-openstac.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project will demonstrate how to leverage CI/CD pipelines, to deploy
and rollback applications in the Openstack Cloud. Best-practices allow
to automate tasks and achieve high-degree of repeatability and
robustness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins will be used to implement continuous integration and continuous
delivery jobs and pipelines. Packer will create images of disposable
systems, being containers and Cloud servers. Ansible will be used to
both create images with Packer, and eventually orchestrate provisioning
of systems in staging and production environments in a blue-green
fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep knowledge of deployment and workflow allows to continuously refine
the process, adapt it to custom requirements, and make it smoother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following technologies will be presented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker on CoreOS cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenkins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Openstack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vagrant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simone Soldateschi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:pycon-au-2015/orchestration-and-cicd-with-ansible-and-openstac.html</guid></item></channel></rss>