<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Here Come The Robots - Django and Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2019/here-come-the-robots-django-and-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A practical, hands-on guide to using machine learning in your Django projects, including a live demo of four applications.
Machine Learning is probably the most important development in our industry (and possibly our civilisation!). Previously restricted to math geniuses with access to supercomputers and massive data centres, machine learning tools are increasingly available as web services which are easily consumed from more traditional web applications. Python has become the lingua franca of machine learning, so Django developers are well placed to take advantage of the next wave of application development.
In this talk I’ll outline the various machine learning platforms and provide a set of practical examples that demonstrate how Django developers can start taking advantage of artificial intelligence in their own applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Dyson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-21:djangocon-europe-2019/here-come-the-robots-django-and-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Here Come The Robots - Python and Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-philippines-2019/here-come-the-robots-python-and-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning is probably the most important development in our industry (and possibly our civilisation!). Previously restricted to math geniuses with access to supercomputers and massive data centres, machine learning tools are increasingly available as web services which are easily consumed from more traditional web applications. Python has become the lingua franca of machine learning, so Python developers are well placed to take advantage of the next wave of application development. This talk outlines the various machine learning platforms and provides a set of practical examples that demonstrate how Python developers can start taking advantage of artificial intelligence in their own applications.  The intended audience is pretty wide: web developers, students, data scientists should all come away with a set of ideas and tools for implementing machine learning without needing a degree in artificial intelligence!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Dyson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-23:pycon-philippines-2019/here-come-the-robots-python-and-machine-learning.html</guid><category>machine learning</category></item><item><title>Here Come The Robots - Django and Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/here-come-the-robots-django-and-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning is probably the most important development in our
industry (and possibly our civilisation!). Previously restricted to math
geniuses with access to supercomputers and massive data centres, machine
learning tools are increasingly available as web services which are
easily consumed from more traditional web applications. Python has
become the lingua franca of machine learning, so Django developers are
well placed to take advantage of the next wave of application
development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’ll outline the various machine learning platforms and
provide a set of practical examples that demonstrate how Django
developers can start taking advantage of artificial intelligence in
their own applications. These will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image recognition - using Microsoft Azure Vision to automatically
caption and label the images your users upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entity analysis - using the Google Cloud Natural Language API to tag
news articles with people, locations and events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictions - using Amazon Machine Learning to build a ‘you may also
like’ feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sentiment analysis - using IBM Watson to understand the tone of
comments submitted to your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Dyson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/here-come-the-robots-django-and-machine-learning.html</guid></item><item><title>Serverlessness - augmenting your Django apps with Functions-as-a-Service</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/serverlessness-augmenting-your-django-apps-with-functions-as-a-service.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So-called 'serverless' platforms promise to free developers from having to worry about operating systems, hard disks, backups and scaling. Amazon, Google and Microsoft each have their own take on the serverless model, and recent third party abstractions make it much simpler to get started with Functions-as-a-Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom will take you through the pros and cons of the serverless model, and use a set of practical case studies to demonstrate ways that Django developers can take advantage of this emerging shift in the way that we host our applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Dyson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/serverlessness-augmenting-your-django-apps-with-functions-as-a-service.html</guid></item><item><title>CMS Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/iacopo-spalletti-tom-dyson-daniele-procida-cms-at.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-31:djangocon-europe-2015/iacopo-spalletti-tom-dyson-daniele-procida-cms-at.html</guid></item><item><title>Wagtail - Yet Another Django CMS</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/wagtail-yet-another-django-cms-by-tom-dyson.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wagtail - Yet Another Django CMS by Tom Dyson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wagtail was launched in February 2014, shortly after its first
implementation for the Royal College of Art. It has been
enthusiastically received by Django developers around the world, and now
powers sites for small businesses, UN agencies, and global brands in
tech, political and entertainment sectors. Tom will explain why his
agency decided to build a new CMS, share some lessons learned in running
a growing open source project, and outline Wagtail's roadmap to version
2 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HH7a/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HH7a/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Dyson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-21:djangocon-us-2015/wagtail-yet-another-django-cms-by-tom-dyson.html</guid></item></channel></rss>