<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Controlling a confounding effect in predictive analysis.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/controlling-a-confounding-effect-in-predictive-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, when predicting the salary to offer given the descriptions
of professional experience, the risk is to capture indirectly a gender
bias present in the distribution of salaries. Another example is found
in biomedical applications, where for an automated radiology diagnostic
system to be useful, it should use more than socio-demographic
information to build its prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I will talk about confounds in predictive models. I will review
classic deconfounding techniques developed in a well-established
statistical literature, and how they can be adapted to predictive
modeling settings. Departing from deconfounding, I will introduce a
non-parametric approach –that we named “confound-isolating
cross-validation”– adapting cross-validation experiments to measure the
performance of a model independently of the confounding effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples are mentioned in this work are related to the common issues
in neuroimage analysis, although the approach is not limited to
neuroscience and can be useful in another domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confounding effects are often present in observational data: the effect
or association studied is observed jointly with other effects that are
not desired.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Darya Chyzhyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-04:euroscipy-2019/controlling-a-confounding-effect-in-predictive-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>Explore the brain with Nilearn</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/explore-the-brain-with-nilearn.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past recent years, the Python programming language became popular
and widely used in many science areas, that you can notes from huge
amount of high quality &lt;strong&gt;scientific&lt;/strong&gt; libraries available in GitHub.
Python has already won the confidence in neuro-imaging community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis of different &lt;strong&gt;neuroimaging&lt;/strong&gt; modalities consists of
identifying such a complex pipeline that include supporting specific
&lt;strong&gt;MRI&lt;/strong&gt; data acquisition, image processing, statistics and predictive
modeling, and visualization of the results. &lt;strong&gt;Nilearn&lt;/strong&gt; is a Python
package designed to face these challenges. It provides state-of-the-art
&lt;strong&gt;machine-learning&lt;/strong&gt; methods for analysis task fMRI, resting-state, or
anathomical data. In my talk, I would like to present general purpose of
Nilearn, focusing on &lt;strong&gt;functional connectivity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;connectome&lt;/strong&gt;
analysis in resting-state fMRI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Darya Chyzhyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/explore-the-brain-with-nilearn.html</guid><category>computer-science</category><category>cognitive-science</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item></channel></rss>