<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ben-lopatin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>This Old Pony: Working With Legacy Django Apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/this-old-pony-working-with-legacy-django-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Lopatin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-20:djangocon-us-2016/this-old-pony-working-with-legacy-django-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legacy software is software that already exists. It may be a project you've inherited after joining a team, a new client's application, or something you wrote last year, or last month. Most software developers seem to prefer &amp;quot;greenfield&amp;quot; development, where you get to start from a clean slate. The reality is that there's a lot of &amp;quot;brownfield&amp;quot; development out there, that it rarely makes sense to throw away working software, and we can control the experience quite a bit to make our lives, and the software, better. If you haven't worked with legacy software chances are pretty good you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll first walk through what &amp;quot;legacy&amp;quot; means, and what this looks like specifically for Django developers and Django projects. We'll also cover some of the scenarios in which you may find yourself working with legacy codebases. This includes the types of issues you'll be presented with, both generally and specific to Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we mean by legacy code?
What does a legacy Django project look like?
What kinds of issues will you need to deal with?
How to approach the codebase
Tools for working with your new legacy codebase
Introducing or fixing tests
Common issues to look for and how to solve them
Legacy deployment processes and other scary nightmares
More features! Balancing business needs and &amp;quot;perfect&amp;quot; code
Deciding when to upgrade Django and other dependency versions, and how to do this&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding the Needle: Search and Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/finding-the-needle-search-and-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Lopatin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-01:djangocon-us-2013/finding-the-needle-search-and-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding the Needle: Search and Django&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 4 p.m.--4:45 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most websites share at least two things in common: content and users who
want to find content. This talk will cover the basics of site search
using search engines (the kind you run, not Google), setting up a Django
project with Haystack, highlight some of the gotchas you might
encounter, and touch on some more advanced functionality. Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to find content on a site is important to users, and there
are some great tools that make a sometimes tricky problem a lot simpler.
This talk will address the search problem, introduce a few of the tools
at your disposal, and provide a way to get started using Django
Haystack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals is for developers new to search to understand what's different
about using a search engine as an additional service, to be aware of
some of the &amp;quot;gotchas&amp;quot;, and to know not just what's possible but how to
get started. Advanced topics in brief One slice at a time: Faceting
Finding Carmen Diego: Geospatial search This, this, this: Relevance
boosting Puppies, dogs, and canines: Synonym searching&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>