<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mali-akmanalp.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Library UX: Using abstraction towards friendlier APIs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/library-ux-using-abstraction-towards-friendlier-apis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mali Akmanalp</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pycon-us-2017/library-ux-using-abstraction-towards-friendlier-apis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Complicated libraries can be a pain in the butt to use. It's not
surprising that there are a lot of &amp;quot;X for humans&amp;quot; libraries out there,
some of which are mostly wrappers around more frustrating interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a theoretical talk. I'll touch upon theory to give you
context, but will then talk about what that means for you in practice so
that you can write better libraries. I'll talk about why library UX
matters, about abstraction as a general concept, about out what happens
when you over/under abstract, and about some useful tips to help build
friendly APIs. Meanwhile, I'll show some positive examples from
libraries we know and love (flask, SQLAlchemy, Requests, etc). Once you
recognize these effects in play, you'll be able to apply them to your
own code and make life better for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Other people's messy data (and how not to hate it!)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/other-peoples-messy-data-and-how-not-to-hate-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mali Akmanalp</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-12:pycon-us-2015/other-peoples-messy-data-and-how-not-to-hate-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever viscerally hated a dataset? Do you want to just get data
cleaning out of the way? Are you always left wondering how it consumes
most of your time? Whether you work in the sciences, work with
government data or scrape websites, data cleaning is a necessary evil.
We'll share our woes and check out state of the art in day to day data
cleaning tools and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>