<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jennifer-klay.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Project based introduction to scientific computing for physics majors</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/project-based-introduction-to-scientific-computin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Klay</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/project-based-introduction-to-scientific-computin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will present an overview of a project-based introductory
course in scientific computing using python for physics majors at Cal
Poly San Luis Obispo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computational tools and skills are as critical to the training of
physics majors as calculus and math, yet they receive much less emphasis
in the undergraduate curriculum. One-off courses that introduce
programming and basic numerical problem-solving techniques with
commercial software packages for topics that appear in the traditional
physics curriculum are insufficient to prepare students for the
computing demands of modern technical careers. Yet tight budgets and
rigid degree requirements constrain the ability to expand computational
course offerings for physics majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present an overview of a recently revamped course at Cal
Poly San Luis Obispo that uses Python and associated scientific
computing libraries to introduce the fundamentals of open-source tools,
version control systems, programming, numerical problem solving and
algorithmic thinking to undergraduate physics majors. The spirit of the
course is similar to the bootcamps organized by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://software-carpentry.org"&gt;Software
Carpentry&lt;/a&gt; for researchers in science
but is offered as a ten-week for-credit course. In addition to having a
traditional in-class component, students learn the basics of Python by
completing tutorials on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.codecademy.com"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;'s
Python track and practice their algorithmic thinking by tackling
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://projecteuler.net"&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt; problems. This approach of
incorporating online training may provide a different way of thinking
about the role of MOOCs in higher education. The early part of the
course focuses on skill-building, while the second half is devoted to
application of these skills to an independent research-level
computational physics project. Examples of recent projects and their
results will be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="education"></category><category term="physics"></category></entry></feed>