<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_krzysztof-dorosz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Payments processing in django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2013/payments-processing-in-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Krzysztof Dorosz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-19:pycon-pl-2013/payments-processing-in-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Payments processing in django
Prelegent/Speaker: Krzysztof Dorosz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk will cover many advanced aspects of processing payments in django and will be mainly focused on integration with django-getpaid application. Django-getpaid is carefully designed multi-broker payment processor for Django framework. It was designed to provide following features: * multiple payment brokers support - allows using simultaneously many payments methods at the same time, * multiple payments currency support (getpaid will automatically filter available backends list accordingly to the payment currency), * integration flexibility - makes minimal assumption on 3rd party code - requires only an existence of any single django model representing an order, * proper architecture design - all backends which requires fetching payment confirmation are enforced to use asynchronous celery tasks. Django-getpaid is a production ready solution with support for all main payment processing services in Poland. It is also easily extendable via pluggable backend system to support any other services. Project site: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cypreess/django-getpaid"&gt;https://github.com/cypreess/django-getpaid&lt;/a&gt; This talk will be an extended version of my 2013 DjangoCon talk: &amp;quot;Apps for advanced plans, pricings, billings and payments&amp;quot; concerning only payments topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Beyond millions of keys in memcached and redis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2013/beyond-millions-of-keys-in-memcached-and-redis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Krzysztof Dorosz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-17:pycon-pl-2013/beyond-millions-of-keys-in-memcached-and-redis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Beyond millions of keys in memcached and redis
Prelegent/Speaker: Krzysztof Dorosz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discus some advanced techniques that can be used to squeeze the last bit from memcached and redis when dealing with a very large scale. Talk will describe internal structure of memcached memory management and how to optimize configuration to a given use case. In terms of Redis some techniques of efficient hash store will be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: this talk has a very little in common with Python itself, but some examples are provided in Python, as well as both memcached and redis are industry standard for Python based projects. This is the same talk I gave for a very small audience of Pykonik (Kraków python group).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>DjangoCon EU 2013: Krzysztof Dorosz - Apps for advanced plans, pricings, billings and payments</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2013/djangocon-eu-2013-krzysztof-dorosz-apps-for-advanced-plans-pricings-billings-and-payments.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Krzysztof Dorosz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-05-15:djangocon-europe-2013/djangocon-eu-2013-krzysztof-dorosz-apps-for-advanced-plans-pricings-billings-and-payments.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Videos from DjangoCon Europe 2013 are kindly provided by Heroku, a cloud application platform -- a new way of building and deploying web apps: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://heroku.com/"&gt;http://heroku.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>