<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Santosh Kumar Radha</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python Meets Heterogeneous Computing: An Exploration of Distributed Computations (Sponsor: Covalent)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/python-meets-heterogeneous-computing-an-exploration-of-distributed-computations-sponsor-covalent.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will delve into the exciting world of advanced hardware
and its use for distributed computations. As the heterogeneous computing
landscape evolves with the introduction of quantum computers, GPUs, and
specialized hardware, we will explore the interesting patterns in Python
that allow us to interact with this heterogeneity and maximize
performance effectively. The talk will address the challenges of
distributed computations in the heterogeneous computing era, including
monitoring real-time calculations, rapid iteration, prototyping in
complex experiments, and ensuring smooth production runs with long
access queues in specialized hardware. However, we will not only
highlight the difficulties but also share valuable strategies for
overcoming these obstacles and achieving optimal performance in these
environments using open-source tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Santosh Kumar Radha</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/python-meets-heterogeneous-computing-an-exploration-of-distributed-computations-sponsor-covalent.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>No Data? No Problem: Zero-Data Model Training with Foundational Models (Sponsor: Covalent)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/no-data-no-problem-zero-data-model-training-with-foundational-models-sponsor-covalent.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we introduce a streamlined method for training smaller,
task-specific models without the need for new data by utilizing
foundational models. We'll cover the process of leveraging existing
open-source foundational large models to impart knowledge to more
compact models tailored for specific tasks. The focus will be on how
developers can apply these techniques using open-source tools to enhance
their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Santosh Kumar Radha</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/no-data-no-problem-zero-data-model-training-with-foundational-models-sponsor-covalent.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>