<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Savannah Ostrowski</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_savannah-ostrowski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Accelerate your workflow from local Python prototype to the cloud (Sponsor: Microsoft)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/accelerate-your-workflow-from-local-python-prototype-to-the-cloud-sponsor-microsoft.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Savannah Ostrowski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/accelerate-your-workflow-from-local-python-prototype-to-the-cloud-sponsor-microsoft.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever struggled taking a Python application from your local
machine to the cloud? Had a hard time figuring out what infrastructure
you need or how to configure it for your app? Spent too much time
researching how to set up your local development environment for cloud
development …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever struggled taking a Python application from your local
machine to the cloud? Had a hard time figuring out what infrastructure
you need or how to configure it for your app? Spent too much time
researching how to set up your local development environment for cloud
development? Learn how to use real-world cloud development application
templates via CLI to go from local development environment to the cloud.
Scaffold your application, provision resources, deploy code, monitor
your application health, and set up a CI/CD pipeline, all in a couple of
steps and just a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Enterprise-Ready Python for High-Performance Data Teams (Sponsor: Snowflake)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/enterprise-ready-python-for-high-performance-data-teams-sponsor-snowflake.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Savannah Ostrowski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-15:/pycon-us-2025/enterprise-ready-python-for-high-performance-data-teams-sponsor-snowflake.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll explore the challenges of running Python in enterprise data teams and share lessons learned from building for PyData developers at Snowflake, with an emphasis on flexibility, performance, and library compatibility. We'll focus on two key aspects: APIs and runtimes. First, we'll look at how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll explore the challenges of running Python in enterprise data teams and share lessons learned from building for PyData developers at Snowflake, with an emphasis on flexibility, performance, and library compatibility. We'll focus on two key aspects: APIs and runtimes. First, we'll look at how you can run pandas at all data scales using Modin, and how this interoperates with other tools in the PyData stack. Then, we'll discuss ways to manage runtime compatibility, from customizing environments to working within notebook-based workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>