<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Meag Doherty</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_meag-doherty.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Maximizing the Impact of User Feedback: Effective Practices for Community Management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/maximizing-the-impact-of-user-feedback-effective-practices-for-community-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Meag Doherty</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/maximizing-the-impact-of-user-feedback-effective-practices-for-community-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;User feedback is crucial to any community, as it helps shape the community’s direction and growth. However, managing and processing this feedback can be challenging, especially for large and active communities. This talk will discuss practices for community management teams to effectively handle user feedback and turn it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;User feedback is crucial to any community, as it helps shape the community’s direction and growth. However, managing and processing this feedback can be challenging, especially for large and active communities. This talk will discuss practices for community management teams to effectively handle user feedback and turn it into valuable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategies for gathering and prioritizing user feedback, including surveys, polls, and short interviews.
Techniques for analyzing and synthesizing user feedback, including data visualization and text analysis tools.
Methods for communicating and following up on user feedback, including the use of transparent and consistent processes for decision-making.
Best practices for engaging with users and fostering a sense of community ownership.
By the end of this session, attendees will have a better understanding of how to effectively manage user feedback and use it to drive the growth and success of their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience:
This conference proposal is suitable for community managers, moderators, and other professionals responsible for online communities. It is also relevant for anyone interested in understanding how to effectively process and use user feedback to shape the direction of their communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives:
To provide attendees with strategies for gathering and prioritizing user feedback.
To discuss techniques for analyzing and synthesizing user feedback.
To share community practices for communicating and acting on user feedback.
To explore ways to engage with users and foster a sense of community ownership and responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry></feed>