<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_maximilian-scholz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Linespots: Predicting Bugs in your Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/linespots-predicting-bugs-in-your-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maximilian Scholz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:europython-2017/linespots-predicting-bugs-in-your-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In times of increased awareness of technical debts, reviewing and
auditing code becomes more important. The main problem with code
review is the amount of time that is being spent searching the needle
in the haystack. You just don’t know what you are looking for and
where to find it. One possible solution to the problem to the idea of
bug prediction. If we could somehow know where bugs are in our code,
focusing reviewing efforts on that area should, in theory, increase
the effectiveness of our review. More bugs should be uncovered while
less time is spent reviewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what Linespots tries to offer. It is an algorithm developed
during my thesis that analyses a project’s history and calculates a
probability value for each line of code in the project, representing
the likeliness of a bug existing in that line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the probabilities, reviewers can focus on the areas that are at
a higher risk of containing bugs and spend less time on robust code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research done so far showed, that by analyzing 0.5% lines of code
with the highest risk values in a project, an average of 50% of the
bugs fixed in the next 150 commits were correctly predicted by
Linespots. This is an improvement by factor 10 compared to Bugspots,
an algorithm developed at Google, which Linespots is based upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basics and functionality of Linespots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros and cons of Linespots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results of a case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>