<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Maxime Liquet</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Interactive data exploration in a notebook with hvPlot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/interactive-data-exploration-in-a-notebook-with-hvplot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;hvPlot is a Python package part of the HoloViz suite of tools. Its original design was based on reproducing and extending the familiar and effective Pandas .plot API, allowing regular data practitioners to have easy access to powerful, but somewhat difficult to use, features offered by the HoloViz tools. This includes handling large data with Datashader, geographic data with GeoViews and many features of HoloViews such as its support of different plotting backends (Bokeh, Matplotlib, Plotly). hvPlot is nowadays no longer limited to its .plot API and provides two other and newer functionalities dedicated to making data exploration easier. With the .interactive API, Panel/IPyWidgets widgets can be injected into a processing pipeline (e.g. a pipeline of Pandas or Xarray methods) to interactively control its parameters; when a widget value changes .interactive takes care of re-evaluating the pipeline and updating its output. The latest addition to hvPlot is the Explorer, a graphical interface that offers a low-code experience to data exploration and with which it is simple to create customized plots, selecting the plot options directly from widgets. This talk will focus on describing in more details .interactive and the Explorer, and will then show how they can be used together with the .plot API to set up an approachable and interactive workflow to data exploration in a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maxime Liquet</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/interactive-data-exploration-in-a-notebook-with-hvplot.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Easily build interactive plots and apps with hvPlot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/easily-build-interactive-plots-and-apps-with-hvplot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Philipp Rudiger Maxime Liquet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Visualization
Do you use the &lt;cite&gt;.plot()&lt;/cite&gt; API of pandas or xarray? Do you ever wish it was easier for you or your collaborators to try out different combinations of the parameters in your data-processing pipeline? This tutorial will introduce you to [hvPlot](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hvplot.holoviz.org/"&gt;https://hvplot.holoviz.org/&lt;/a&gt;), a library that:
* supercharges the &lt;cite&gt;.plot&lt;/cite&gt; API with extra capabilities like interactive plots, rendering of very large datasets, and simple composition and linking of plots, and
* makes it really easy to build interactive web applications, whether to make data exploration easier for yourself or for sharing your results with others, by simply replacing arguments in your method calls with widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/38HQZ3"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/38HQZ3&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philipp Rudiger</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-12:/pycon-de-2022/easily-build-interactive-plots-and-apps-with-hvplot.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2022</category><category>PyCon</category><category>PyConDE</category><category>pyconde2022</category><category>pydata</category><category>PyDataBerlin</category><category>pydataberlin2022</category></item><item><title>hvPlot &amp; HoloViz</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/hvplot-holoviz.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python offers many powerful visualization tools, each with their own strengths and advantages, but few people have the time and interest to learn all the different APIs required to use these different tools. Luckily, a de-facto standard API for data plotting has emerged in the Pandas .plot() API, which is now supported by many different plotting packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will learn how to use hvPlot, a high-level interactive plotting library that exposes the power of Bokeh, Matplotlib, Plotly, Datashader, and Cartopy using the same .plot API you may already know from using Pandas or Xarray's plotting interface. We'll also show you how to turn nearly any expression you can write with that API into a web app with plots and tables by simply substituting widgets for any parameters you want users to be able to select. Thanks to the HoloViz tools on which hvPlot is built, the resulting apps can easily handle big data (up to billions of rows on an ordinary laptop), remote data (either in Jupyter or in standalone apps), streaming data (using streaming dataframe libraries), geographical data (building on the geoscience software stack), or multidimensional data (using Xarray).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hvPlot's high-level interface should be sufficient for nearly all of the common data-exploration and data-analysis tasks you want to do with Pandas or Xarray, but in keeping with the HoloViz philosophy of &amp;quot;&amp;quot;shortcuts rather than dead ends&amp;quot;&amp;quot;, we'll also show you how and when to drop down to lower-level APIs when you need to, such as when building more complex apps using Panel, doing complex graphical data calculations using Datashader, or integrating plotting and interactivity into your own libraries using Param and HoloViews. With the techniques you learn in the hands-on exercises in this tutorial, you'll get the tools and know-how to effectively explore, analyze and visualize simple or complex, small or large, and static or dynamic data easily, concisely, and reproducibly. We expect participants to have previously used some sort of plotting tool and to be comfortable with Python and at least one array-based library (Numpy, Pandas, Xarray, CuPy, cuDF, Dask, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://alisterburt.github.io/napari-workshops/Scipy-0722/intro.html"&gt;https://alisterburt.github.io/napari-workshops/Scipy-0722/intro.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bednar</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/hvplot-holoviz.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item></channel></rss>