<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Pedro Holanda</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DuckDB: Bringing analytical SQL directly to your Python shell</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/duckdb-bringing-analytical-sql-directly-to-your-python-shell.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2B on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/duckdb-bringing-analytical-sql-directly-to-your-python-shell"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/duckdb-bringing-analytical-sql-directly-to-your-python-shell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will present DuckDB. DuckDB is a novel data management system that executes analytical SQL queries without requiring a server. DuckDB has a unique, in-depth integration with the existing PyData ecosystem. This integration allows DuckDB to query and output data from and to other Python libraries without copying it. This makes DuckDB an essential tool for the data scientist. In a live demo, we will showcase how DuckDB performs and integrates with the most used Python data-wrangling tool, Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides learning about DuckDB's main charactestics, users will also experience a live demo of DuckDB and Pandas in a typical data science scenario, focusing on comparing their performance and usability while showcasing their cooperation. The demo is most interesting for an audience familiar with Python, the Pandas API, and SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pedro Holanda</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/duckdb-bringing-analytical-sql-directly-to-your-python-shell.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item></channel></rss>