<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Noah Dunn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_noah-dunn.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>GDIOCSpider: Extracting and Identifying IOCs from the GDriveverse</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/gdiocspider-extracting-and-identifying-iocs-from-the-gdriveverse.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Noah Dunn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-27:/pyohio-2025/gdiocspider-extracting-and-identifying-iocs-from-the-gdriveverse.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Google Drive in recent years has become one of the most abused
platforms for threat actors to conduct illegal and malicious activity.
Threat actors use Google accounts to launch, store, and log malware,
effectively turning Drive into a command and control center. On the
side of legal and ethical …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Google Drive in recent years has become one of the most abused
platforms for threat actors to conduct illegal and malicious activity.
Threat actors use Google accounts to launch, store, and log malware,
effectively turning Drive into a command and control center. On the
side of legal and ethical activity, Google Drive remains a popular
platform for security researchers to store these artifacts in
summarized write-ups and spreadsheets of malicious and illegal
activity observed. Much like an archaeologist looks for artifacts
providing clues of the history of civilization, security researchers
look for Indicators of Compromise (IOCs), which are clues to what a
threat actor has done. Security engineers have worked across decades
to build out tooling to analyze hard drives and network resources;
however, similar advances to analyze Google Drive resources have
remained underdeveloped. Along the same line, tools that aggregate and
summarize collections of records on IOCs stored in Google Drive by
researchers are also lacking.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The GDIOCSpider (Google Drive IOC Spider) provides a tool for both of
these use cases. This open-source, configurable, Python tool is
capable of crawling through an entire Google Drive, analyzing its file
contents, and searching for various defined IOC (Indicators of
Compromise) types to extract. This tool outputs a summary of all
discovered artifacts across all files, erasing the need for security
researchers to manually sift through cloud stores. Supplementing the
compromised account use case, the same tool can be used to aggregate
IOCs collected in personal or corporate Google Drive accounts in the
form of case records gathered by security researchers. This
‘environment agnostic’ approach is how GDIOCSpider enables security
researchers to perform efficient IOC research in Google Drive.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;GDIOCSpider supports capabilities for both user accounts and service
accounts through the Google Drive API. It has allowlist and denylist
capabilities for both folders and files to prevent access of files
with compliance and security restrictions. For those that are very
interested in performing local IOC analysis and extraction,
GDIOCSpider contains a build abstract tool ‘IOCFlagger’ within the
context of the source code. IOCFlagger offers a rich IOC parser that
is capable of both loose and strict matching for use cases where it is
necessary to search within a string, or simply match a string to an
IOC type exactly. The full suite of tools under the GDIOCSpider’s
umbrella enables the user or team operating it to enter the
“GDriveverse” of Google account incident response, and provide
meaningful data for case work and research.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2025"></category></entry></feed>