<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jerry Liu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jerry-liu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Keynote: Building an Advanced Knowledge Assistant</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/keynote-building-an-advanced-knowledge-assistant.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jerry Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/keynote-building-an-advanced-knowledge-assistant.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote: Building an Advanced Knowledge Assistant - Jerry Liu, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CEO, LlamaIndex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge promise for LLMs is being able to answer questions and solve tasks of arbitrary complexity over an arbitrary number of data sources. The world has started to shift from simple RAG stacks, which are mostly good …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote: Building an Advanced Knowledge Assistant - Jerry Liu, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CEO, LlamaIndex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge promise for LLMs is being able to answer questions and solve tasks of arbitrary complexity over an arbitrary number of data sources. The world has started to shift from simple RAG stacks, which are mostly good for answering pointed questions, to agents that can more autonomously reason over a diverse set of inputs, and interleave retrieval and tool use to produce sophisticated outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a reliable multi-agent system is challenging. There's a core question of developer ergonomics and production deployment - what makes sense outside a notebook setting. In this talk we outline some core building blocks for building advanced research assistants, including advanced RAG modules, event-driven workflow orchestration, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>