<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Petr Šimeček</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Word Wranglers &amp; News Navigators: Taming GPT-3 Beast for Media Monitoring</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/word-wranglers-news-navigators-taming-gpt-3-beast-for-media-monitoring.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-20]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/word-wranglers-news-navigators-taming-gpt-3-beast-for-media-monitoring"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/word-wranglers-news-navigators-taming-gpt-3-beast-for-media-monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of ChatGPT has led to an exponential growth of prospects and implementations in the field of Natural Language Processing (NLP). Various teams were struck with FOMO (Fear of Missing Out) and hastened to incorporate Large Language Models (LLMs) into their products. By using OpenAI models (text-curie-001, davinci, gpt-3.5-turbo), we successfully integrated them into our production on March 2, granting our users the ability to receive text summaries in their email reports and comprehend the essence of any article within our application. Three weeks later, we trained our own large language model for the same purpose. This talk will delve into our journey, exploring the lessons and insights gleaned from our hands-on experience with these cutting-edge tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Petr Šimeček</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/word-wranglers-news-navigators-taming-gpt-3-beast-for-media-monitoring.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Python alternatives to R/Shiny</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/python-alternatives-to-rshiny.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shiny is a web application framework for R that makes it easy to turn
analyses into interactive applications. When a user changes input
parameters using sliders, drop-down menus and text fields, the
changes are propagated through a reactivity graph into outputs like
plots, tables and summaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Python is generally more powerful and easier to use for a web
development than R, it lack a comprehensive Shiny-like framework.
Current tools are either too complex (Flask, Tornado) or too trivial
and lacking Shiny-like graph interactivity (Bokeh, Dash, Spyre,
Bowtie).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will demonstrate those tools on a web app that for a given face
find look-alike actors / actresses and scientists. Then we will show
how to implement Shiny-like reactivity in our Python module glossy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Karla Fejfarová</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:/pycon-cz-2017/python-alternatives-to-rshiny.html</guid><category>PyCon CZ 2017</category></item></channel></rss>