<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - John Sandall</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Postmodern Architecture - The Python Powered Modern Data Stack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/postmodern-architecture-the-python-powered-modern-data-stack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Modern Data Stack has brought a lot of new buzzwords into the data engineering lexicon: &amp;quot;data mesh&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;data observability&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;reverse ETL&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;data lineage&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;analytics engineering&amp;quot;. In this light-hearted talk we will demystify the evolving revolution that will define the future of data analytics &amp;amp; engineering teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our journey begins with the PyData Stack: pandas pipelines powering ETL workflows...clean code, tested code, data validation, perfect for in-memory workflows. As demand for self-serve analytics grows, new data sources bring more APIs to model, more code to maintain, DAG workflow orchestration tools, new nuances to capture (&amp;quot;the tax team defines revenue differently&amp;quot;), more dashboards, more not-quite-bugs (&amp;quot;but my number says this...&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data maturity journey is a well-trodden path with common pitfalls &amp;amp; opportunities. After dashboards comes predictive modelling (&amp;quot;what will happen&amp;quot;), prescriptive modelling (&amp;quot;what should we do?&amp;quot;), perhaps eventually automated decision making. Getting there is much easier with the advent of the Python Powered Modern Data Stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will cover the shift from ETL to ELT, the open-source Modern Data Stack tools you should know, with a focus on how dbt's new Python integration is changing how data pipelines are built, run, tested &amp;amp; maintained. By understanding the latest trends &amp;amp; buzzwords, attendees will gain a deeper insight into Python's role at the core of the future of data engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">John Sandall</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/postmodern-architecture-the-python-powered-modern-data-stack.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Architecture</category></item></channel></rss>