<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mo Athanasia Mowinckel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mo-athanasia-mowinckel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>CRAN-ial Expansion: Taking Your R Package Development to New Frontiers with R-Universe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/cran-ial-expansion-taking-your-r-package-development-to-new-frontiers-with-r-universe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mo Athanasia Mowinckel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/cran-ial-expansion-taking-your-r-package-development-to-new-frontiers-with-r-universe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say goodbye to installation headaches and hello to a universe of possibilities with R-Universe! Take your R package development to new frontiers by organizing and sharing packages beyond the bounds of CRAN. R-Universe's reliable package-building process strengthens installation and usage instructions, resulting in fewer support requests and an easy …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say goodbye to installation headaches and hello to a universe of possibilities with R-Universe! Take your R package development to new frontiers by organizing and sharing packages beyond the bounds of CRAN. R-Universe's reliable package-building process strengthens installation and usage instructions, resulting in fewer support requests and an easy installation experience for users. With webpages and an API for exploring packages, R-Universe creates a streamlined and tidy ecosystem for R-package constellations. Also, you can build a custom toolchain for your users, relieving your workload and empowering users to help themselves. Join me to learn how to explore the vastness of R-Universe and expand your package development possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>