<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Wenduo Zhou</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_wenduo-zhou.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>PyRS: Data Processing Software for Engineering Neutron Diffraction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2020/pyrs-data-processing-software-for-engineering-neutron-diffraction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wenduo Zhou</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-08:/scipy-2020/pyrs-data-processing-software-for-engineering-neutron-diffraction.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="SciPy 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Automatic Structural Refinement Platform</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/automatic-structural-refinement-platform.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wenduo Zhou</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/automatic-structural-refinement-platform.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern neutron powder diffraction experiments demand real-time qualitative analysis and material structural refinement results to steer the experiment. This requires automatic data processing capabilities spanning the neutron data’s life cycle. Automatic Structural Refinement Platform (ASRP) is a python-based software suite that will enable the real-time data reduction, analysis …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern neutron powder diffraction experiments demand real-time qualitative analysis and material structural refinement results to steer the experiment. This requires automatic data processing capabilities spanning the neutron data’s life cycle. Automatic Structural Refinement Platform (ASRP) is a python-based software suite that will enable the real-time data reduction, analysis, and visualization for neutron powder diffractometers at Oak Ridge National Laboratory. The core of ASRP is a platform that supports live data reduction, automatic analysis, and visualization workflow. Several machine-learning empowered powder diffraction data analysis tools are also developed inside ASRP.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>