<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Introduction to the Signal Processing and Classification Environment pySPACE</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/introduction-to-the-signal-processing-and-classif.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will give a basic introduction to the pySPACE framework and
its current applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pySPACE (Signal Processing And Classification Environment) is a modular
software for the processing of large data streams that has been
specifically designed to enable distributed execution and empirical
evaluation of signal processing chains. Various signal processing
algorithms (so called nodes) are available within the software, from
finite impulse response filters over data-dependent spatial filters
(e.g., PCA, CSP, xDAWN) to established classifiers (e.g., SVM, LDA).
pySPACE incorporates the concept of node and node chains of the Modular
Toolkit for Data Processing (MDP) framework. Due to its modular
architecture, the software can easily be extended with new processing
nodes and more general operations. Large scale empirical investigations
can be configured using simple text-configuration files in the YAML
format, executed on different (distributed) computing modalities, and
evaluated using an interactive graphical user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pySPACE allows the user to connect nodes modularly and automatically
benchmark the respective chains for different parameter settings and
compare these with other node chains, e.g., by automatic evaluation of
classification performances provided within the software. In addition,
the pySPACElive mode of execution can be used for online processing of
streamed data. The software specifically supports but is not limited to
EEG data. Any kind of time series or feature vector data can be
processed and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pySPACE additionally provides interfaces to specialized signal
processing libraries such as SciPy, scikit-learn, LIBSVM, the WEKA
Machine Learning Framework, and the Maja Machine Learning Framework
(MMLF).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mario Michael Krell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-27:pydata-berlin-2014/introduction-to-the-signal-processing-and-classif.html</guid></item></channel></rss>