<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Hugo Ramírez</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hugo-ramirez.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Charlas Relámpago - Día 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2020/charlas-relampago-dia-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hugo Ramírez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-11-27:/pycon-ar-2020/charlas-relampago-dia-2.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charlas Relámpago - Día 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pandas al Rescate del Gigante Excel por &amp;#64;Hugo Ramírez&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libros interactivos basados en JupyterBook por &amp;#64;sashakile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Como trabajar para afuera y no morir en el intento por &amp;#64;gonsan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Ar 2020"></category><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in algotrading lectures</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-latin-america-2019/python-in-algotrading-lectures.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hugo Ramirez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-10:/scipy-latin-america-2019/python-in-algotrading-lectures.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I teach Algorithmic trading in Master in quantitative finance at the universidad del Rosario. In this short talk I will share my experience teaching the elective lecture in algorithmic trading with the use of python, more specifically with Anaconda plus Spider. I will give a small recap of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I teach Algorithmic trading in Master in quantitative finance at the universidad del Rosario. In this short talk I will share my experience teaching the elective lecture in algorithmic trading with the use of python, more specifically with Anaconda plus Spider. I will give a small recap of the lecture including: Dataframe structures, datereaders for scrapping information online on the web, graphical technical analysis, a small reference to trading techniques as: momentum, crossover and pairs trading strategies, how to test the algorithms or robots with zipline backtesting and finally a small implementation with the neural networks of sklearn. From this lecture, some tesis projects arose and where implemented in python, so to end, I will talk shortly about the computational importance in financial research, such as neural networks in finance, Support vector machine in clustering financial information, finite difference to solve financial partial differential equations and applications to option pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy Latin America 2019"></category></entry></feed>