<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stemgraphic: A Stem-and-Leaf Plot for the Age of Big Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/stemgraphic-a-stem-and-leaf-plot-for-the-age-of-big-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.pydata.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData is a gathering of users and developers of data analysis tools
in Python. The goals are to provide Python enthusiasts a place to
share ideas and learn from each other about how best to apply our
language and tools to ever-evolving challenges in the vast realm of
data management, processing, analytics, and visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to be an accessible, community-driven conference, with
tutorials for novices, advanced topical workshops for practitioners,
and opportunities for package developers and users to meet in person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francois Dion</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/stemgraphic-a-stem-and-leaf-plot-for-the-age-of-big-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Datascience on the web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/datascience-on-the-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn to deploy your research as a web application. You have been
using Jupyter and Python to do some interesting research, build
models, visualize results. In this tutorial, you’ll learn how to
easily go from a notebook to a Flask web application which you can
share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter is a great notebook environment for Python based data science
and exploratory data analysis. You can share the notebooks via a
github repository, as html or even on the web using something like
JupyterHub. How can we turn the work we have done in the notebook into
a real web application?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francois Dion</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-14:pydata-carolinas-2016/datascience-on-the-web.html</guid></item></channel></rss>