<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Michał Wodyński</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Difficulties of Python code development:packages,virtualenvs and package mangers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/difficulties-of-python-code-developmentpackagesvirtualenvs-and-package-mangers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Develop your code effectively with well chosen tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;In this presentation I will show different packages that are used in Python. I will point out differences and explain the prons and cons of using them during code development.&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;After that we will jump to the topic of virtualenvs and  popular tools that are used for managing them. I will explain what is purpose of the virtualenvs in Python and why we should use them.
Finally we will focus on the most important topic without which development is not possible – package mangers. Package managers it is wide topic in Python world. There is many package mangers and  currently we have tools like pip, pipenv or poetry but it is not obvious which of them we should use in first place. Which of them are recommended to use? What are prons and cons of certain package mangers? Is there any other not well known packages mangers? How package mangers are packaging Python code? Which of the package mangers are good for data scientists? Is your package manger is resolving dependencies?
This questions can appear especially when you are beginner and just to want start working with Python. Unfortunately form the beginning you must face the problem which of the package manger you should use. In this presentation I will answer all of this questions. I will list popular package mangers and some not known. I will show differences and which of them are best for which case. Also I will explain differences between packages that are used by different packages mangers. If you are interested in code development and package mangers or you are just confused which of them you should use this presentation is definitely for you. During this presentation I will answer all questions and I will wipe out all doubts about packages, package mangers and virtualenvs.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Wodyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/difficulties-of-python-code-developmentpackagesvirtualenvs-and-package-mangers.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Beginners</category><category>Conda / conda forge</category><category>Development</category><category>Packaging</category><category>Virtual Env</category></item><item><title>Python security best practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/python-security-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python security best practises
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Michał Wodyński&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever have a feeling that you are able to write code that solves problem but your not sure whether is safe? How much of your time you spend on investigating whether your code is not vulnerable ? Do you know what kind of risks you can face during parsing XML files? If those questions appeared into your mind this presentation will clarify your doubts and bring your skills closer to writing more safe code. There are many repeatable routines during developing code like: saving user data, reading files or pickles. Those routines can lead to a drop in vigilance which may lead to very terrible consequences for our application or data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During presentation I will explain what are aims of the attackers and go through security issues that can appear in:
• not verified user input,
• parsing XML,
• assert statements,
• using temporary files,
• reading yaml and pickles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I will compare it OWASP TOP 10. In each of this topics I will:
• show examples of codes that can break your application,
• describe what are the risks and how to solve it,
• talk about tools that help detect issues in your code,
• present XML libraries overview which shows what specific library is vulnerable for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major of presentation will be focused on XML issues as it is wide problem not only in Python language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to increase your programming security skills, see how certain attacks can be performed and how to defend against them this presentation is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Wodyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/python-security-best-practices.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item></channel></rss>