<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tyler-brough.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python to Teach Computational Finance</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/using-python-to-teach-computational-finance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tyler Brough</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/using-python-to-teach-computational-finance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this demo-driven session, we will introduce the Probo package for
teaching Python programming and concepts from computational finance to
beginning programmers in the domain of finance. We'll show how Python is
the perfect tool for teaching computational thinking to develop deeper
quantitative reasoning. Jupyter notebooks, together with Python packages
such as NumPy and Pandas, provide the ideal learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start by introducing the Probo package for derivative pricing
and hedging. We will demo the pricing of European and American options
via the famous Black-Scholes option pricing model. Other examples
include Monte Carlo simulation and binomial trees. Using Probo, the
answers to derivative pricing problems are right at the students'
fingertips. Students can operationalize their understanding by going
directly from the mathematics of derivative pricing theories to their
implementation in clean and simple code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will end with a demonstration using Probo to teach the concept of
dynamic hedging. Dynamic hedging is perhaps &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; crucial concept in
modern financial derivatives theory. It is also one of the most
difficult concepts to grasp. We'll show how developing deeper intuition
is possible with computational thinking via Monte Carlo simulation of
delta-hedging. By leveraging the power and simplicity of Python and
Jupyter notebooks, the Probo package provides the ideal learning
platform for students of computational finance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Beginners"></category><category term="Business"></category><category term="Business Cases"></category><category term="Education"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category></entry></feed>