<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_joseph-lee.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Simpl framework, big impact!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/simpl-framework-big-impact.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joseph Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/simpl-framework-big-impact.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drawing upon decades of simulation and higher education experience, the
Alfred West Jr. Learning Lab at the Wharton School set out to create
it’s own in- house developed simulation platform to accelerate our
simulation delivery capabilities. However, what began as a white
boarding session two years ago, morphed into the first of its kind open
source simulation platform. Simpl will not only fuel the next generation
of simulations written at the Wharton School, but it is our hope it will
serve the foundation for countless other simulations at other schools
around the world. Our open source platform puts tools in the hands of
any developer who has the curiosity to create a simulation, tools that
were previously unobtainable due to cost. The Learning Lab partnered
with RevSys, and relying upon Python/Django and a slew of other open
source tools, we were able to deliver our first simulation written in
Simpl in November of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simpl‘s server side is built on Python/Django and open source WAMP
technologies. On the front end, Simpl uses JavaScript frameworks
including React, Redux, and Autobahn. Combined, these constitute a
framework for developing single and multiplayer simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you will learn about simulations in the higher education
space, how we developed and implemented Simpl, a demo of our first Simpl
simulation, and why we think this Python/Django fueled simulation
platform will have a seismic impact on the burgeoning edtech field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tentative outline of talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About the Learning Lab and simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The barrier to develop simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why we chose to develop Simpl and make it open source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simpl design process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience writing first Simpl simulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical deep dive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demo of first Simpl sim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where we are, next steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>