<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Explicit is Better than Implicit: Making Culture Visible with Team Charters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/explicit-is-better-than-implicit-making-culture-visible-with-team-charters.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever joined a new team, you know that there are hidden rules
for how the team operates: what they value in their day-today work, what
is important to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking news: teams are hard. We document our code... shouldn't we
document our team's values and ideals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beautiful is better than ugly.&lt;/em&gt; There is more to a team than just
throwing people together and telling them to ship code. The culture of
the team matters, Not company culture, but the culture and operating
rules of the group of people that spend their days together. That
culture can be amazing when it is mindfully considered. So how does that
happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;/em&gt; A team charter is documentation
written by a group of people to capture their purpose, their values,
their working rules, and their general processes. Making the invisible
visible is the purpose of the team charter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There should be one-- and preferably only one --obvious way to do it.&lt;/em&gt;
Your team charter will provide an anchor to keep your team true to their
ideals, even and &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; during periods of great stress by
providing a written record of how they aspire to work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the face of ambiguity, refuse the temptation to guess.&lt;/em&gt; Whether it
is establishing priorities or onboarding new team members, your team
charter will take the guesswork out of the non-code parts of working
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll explore what a team charter is, how to create one,
and view examples of charters teams have created and used in their
day-to-day work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher T. Miller</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-27:pyohio-2019/explicit-is-better-than-implicit-making-culture-visible-with-team-charters.html</guid></item></channel></rss>