<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andrea-fagan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Overview of Python Web Development, from Searching to Deployment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/overview-of-python-web-development-from-searching-to-deployment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Fagan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-05:pycon-ireland-2016/overview-of-python-web-development-from-searching-to-deployment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about helping people new to development &amp;amp; Python to
connect the dots between googling ”python web development” and
reaching deployment. When entering the world of development there is a
huge learning curve. It’s not just about understanding python syntax
and writing a function. How does everything fit together? This talk
will attempt to introduce the budding developer to the options
available and why you may choose one over another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will run through the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The major python web frameworks that exist. We will examine the pros and cons of the main
players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python itself, Apis vs Services, what goes where?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build restfully and the importance of adhering to correct http
protocols. How does javascript know what to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The merits of testing and running through the different testing
libraries that are available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief intro to Github and pointing to resources to help learn how to
commit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlighting any “gotchas”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosting, where to go?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to google for relevant answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python community for answers. (globally and local)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully those that attending will have a greater understanding of
the whole development system so they will know what to research for
each step and where to find answers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>