<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_johannes-ahlmann.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Spark Distributed Computing - Leveraging the Functional Model (PyData)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2015/spark-distributed-computing-leveraging-the-functional-model-pydata.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johannes Ahlmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-24:pycon-ireland-2015/spark-distributed-computing-leveraging-the-functional-model-pydata.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have heard the hype about Apache Spark using Python, and would like to learn more?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed Computing is becoming more and more prevalent with the rise of big data, multicore processors and scale-out architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give an introduction to Parallel Programming using Apache Spark and Python, how you can leverage it in you day-to-day programming, and the core Functional Principles that are making it scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to Merge Noisy Datasets</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/how-to-merge-noisy-datasets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johannes Ahlmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-06:pycon-ireland-2016/how-to-merge-noisy-datasets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acquiring large datasets is quite simple these days on the internet,
but data is often noisy and most of the value often lies in combining,
connecting and merging multiple datasets from different sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk gives an overview of Probabilistic Record Matching, i.e. the
challenges posed when dealing with noisy data, how to normalize data
and how to match noisy records to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the presentation is to give participants an understanding
of the possibilities and challenges of merging datasets, as well as
mention some of the amazing python libraries available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics discussed: normalization of attributes, approximate string
matching, performance, similarity clustering&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>