<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jennifer-leech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Diversity in Tech: Improving our Toolset</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--diversity-in-tech--improving-our-tool.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Leech</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--diversity-in-tech--improving-our-tool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity in Tech: Improving our Toolset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jennifer Leech&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities allow more diversity, they draw from a larger talent
pool, challenge each other more, and hit a higher bar in terms of
ingenuity and work-product. However questions surrounding diversity
often seem under- examined. What are the effects of diversity in the
community, or lack thereof? I intend to approach this topic from an
accessible and entertaining, yet analytical perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year there was a photo of Kate Moss shown during a PyCon
presentation which raised debate as to its appropriateness. This debate
brought up some interesting questions - but what I found most
interesting was that while it elicited strong opinions, the issue seemed
to be somewhat unexamined. This event sparked a desire for deeper
analysis on this topic in a more focussed setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I intend to address some of the core principles underlying
this debate. Discussion will include the following questions: Where does
responsibility lie in understanding these issues? What are the effects
of failing to do so? What are the effects of diversity in the community,
or lack thereof? What do we lose by being more homogenous or more
diverse? Gain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities allow more diversity, they draw from a larger talent
pool, challenge each other more, and hit a higher bar in terms of
ingenuity and work-product. However, diversity requires awareness and
tolerance on both the part of the dominant culture and on the part of
the new arrivals to smooth the inevitable rough edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to approach this topic from an accessible, inclusive and
entertaining, yet analytical perspective. The broader intent is to raise
the level of understanding and community discourse on this topic. It is
odd that diversity can so dramatically affect our lives and communities
and yet be unexamined, particularly in a community so highly intelligent
and educated as that which populates the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>