<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - cotton</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_cotton.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Challenge Building Management with Event Sourcing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/challenge-building-management-with-event-sourcing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>cotton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/challenge-building-management-with-event-sourcing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We introduce the Event Sourcing pattern used in stock account management by Doomoolmori's Boolileo, a robo-advisor service. Event Sourcing is used to stably manage states that are prone to change. An example that can be easily encountered in everyday life is a bankbook. If you look at all the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We introduce the Event Sourcing pattern used in stock account management by Doomoolmori's Boolileo, a robo-advisor service. Event Sourcing is used to stably manage states that are prone to change. An example that can be easily encountered in everyday life is a bankbook. If you look at all the deposit/withdrawal details of your bankbook and calculate from the first occurrence to the last occurrence, you can find out your current balance. In this lesson, we will talk about how the fictional character Ensome improves a building management project using Event Sourcing. We will not go into depth about Event Sourcing. The goal is to explain only the essential parts lightly so that you can naturally accept Event Sourcing. If there is anyone who is interested in Event Sourcing and wants to introduce it, we will find out whether this pattern is really necessary for the project you are trying to apply it to using the project Ensome conducted in the last part.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Development Method with Python"></category></entry></feed>