<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cutting-edge APIs using hypermedia at BSkyB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/cutting-edge-apis-using-hypermedia-at-bskyb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will explain what hypermedia enabled API means, I will
give an example of such an API and I will take you through the
implementation details and the usage of flask, dougrain and HAL in this
context. Also, I will present a brief comparison with an API that is not
hypermedia enabled and take you through the advantages of using the
hypermedia approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the technology community at the moment there is a lot of talk about
hypermedia enabled APIs and Web as an Architecture model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more applications nowadays try to adopt the loosely coupled and
distributed web like architecture by using hypermedia as an engine of
the application state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Sky we are successfully implementing this approach for some of our
components, and we’ve learnt that the major benefit for us is the
scalability that it offers: as an increasingly expanding business with a
constantly growing product portfolio, scalability of all our systems is
crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will share some of the things we learnt, I will explain
what hypermedia enabled API means, I will give an example of such an API
and I will take you through the implementation details and the usage of
flask, dougrain and HAL in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I will present a brief comparison with an API that is not
hypermedia enabled and take you through the advantages of using the
hypermedia approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adriana Vasiu</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/cutting-edge-apis-using-hypermedia-at-bskyb.html</guid></item></channel></rss>