<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>5 impossible things before breakfast</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2015/5-impossible-things-before-breakfast.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you're asked to deliver something that seems impossible, but
necessary in a given timeframe. Sometimes it's several seemingly
impossible things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing the prototype for the BBC Micro:bit - a pocket sized, child
programmable computer - was very much like this. It had 3 months to be
delivered in a form sufficiently robust and usable to be used by
children in schools across the country; to be sufficiently documented to
be completely understood from scratch by others; and to be a
sufficiently open and flexible design to allow any and all parts of the
system to change, while retaining its core principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was about 3 months to develop the entire stack from scratch. This
included a microcontroller based hardware stack, through firmware, a
python to C++ compiler (3-4 weeks), through django website, through to a
QT (PySide) client side application, through to publication of the
device as a network connected and controllable device via REST. Python
was involved in all layers - including at microcontroller level on a
device too small to run any python interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulk of the development period had just one developer for hardware
and software. For just 1 month there were 2 extra developers brought on
board, part time to assist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be a detailed overview of the various subsystems, and the
strategies taken to deliver a complete, mass produce-able, and
sufficiently scalable product such an aggressive timescale. The talk
title is a nod to the idea that while each of the various layers is
doable alone in 3 months, doing all the layers simultaneously using one
developer is ... challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be of interest to those interested in developing hardware and
software products, and especially those developing products that have
both a hardware and software element.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Sparks</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-19:pycon-uk-2015/5-impossible-things-before-breakfast.html</guid></item></channel></rss>