<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Deepak K Gupta</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hello World of Machine Learning Using Scikit Learn</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/hello-world-of-machine-learning-using-scikit-learn.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Welcome to the Machine Learning tutorial for absolute beginners.*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This tutorial will not make you an expert in Machine Learning but
will cover enough things to acquaint, enable and empower you to
understand, explore and exploits the concept and idea behind it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We'll be learning by generating our own data with bare minimal data
points (5 - 10) so that we can manually verify our machine learning
algorithms to understand it better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will also help us to see how changes in data can impact our
Machine Learning Algorithms. At the end of this tutorial, we'll also be
using one real-world Dataset and play with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this tutorial, I'll be covering at least 3 well-known ML
algorithms(KNN, Linear and Logistic Regression) along with all the maths
behind it. We'll end the tutorial with a real-world mapping application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is no major prerequisite for attending this, you just need to
know the basics of python language and I'll cover the rest. We'll be
using Scikit Learn for simplicity purpose, again, you don't need to have
any prior experience with Scikit Learn or for that matter with Machine
Learning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deepak K Gupta</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-02:/pycon-us-2019/hello-world-of-machine-learning-using-scikit-learn.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Speed Up Data Access with PyArrow (Apache Arrow) - Data is the new API</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/speed-up-data-access-with-pyarrow-apache-arrow-data-is-the-new-api.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Till now we’re used to accessing data over API’s and the API’s used to make sure that we get the data in the desired format which unfortunately requires data to go through serialization / deserialization cycle before being returned by the API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we can change or arrange the data in such a way where it neither needs an API nor any serialisation / deserialization to access and understand the data that too using multiple programming languages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it sounds interesting then welcome to the world of Apache Arrow which defines a language independent columnar memory format which supports zero-copy reads for lightning-fast data access without serialization overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The python library of the same is called PyArrow and can be integrated with python specific libraries like pandas and numpy and can propagate the benefits to the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this talk where you’ll learn about the architecture, use cases and reasons for using Apache Arrow using PyArrow. I’ll share how to as well as some of the interesting statistics of the difference it makes in our day to day access &amp;amp; analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll also talk about Apache Flight, which is a high performance wire protocol focused on bulk transfer for analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Session NOT a tutorial about PyArrow but a set of interesting improvements, facts and statistics which can help you to decide whether it makes sense to explore for the work you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deepak K Gupta</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/speed-up-data-access-with-pyarrow-apache-arrow-data-is-the-new-api.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category></item></channel></rss>