<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Eddie Mitchell</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_eddie-mitchell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Tune-Up Your Knowledge: A Beginner's Journey Under the Hood of Search Engines</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/tune-up-your-knowledge-a-beginners-journey-under-the-hood-of-search-engines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eddie Mitchell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-26:/pyohio-2025/tune-up-your-knowledge-a-beginners-journey-under-the-hood-of-search-engines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Many people drive their cars around all day and never look under the
hood. Likewise, search is used every day, millions of times, with very
little thought for how those results appear on your device. While I
can't build a car engine from scratch (yet), I can build a …&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Many people drive their cars around all day and never look under the
hood. Likewise, search is used every day, millions of times, with very
little thought for how those results appear on your device. While I
can't build a car engine from scratch (yet), I can build a search
engine! (mostly).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this talk, we'll take a beginner-friendly approach to discussing
how search engines work under the hood while building one from scratch
in Python along the way. We'll discuss some history of search,
demonstrate common data structures that make search engines fast and
effective, and review how we can get results in a meaningful order.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We'll also take a high-level look at machine learning models and how
vector embeddings can easily understand similarity and influence
search results.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk is for those interested in taking a beginner's peek under
the hood to understand some of the techniques used. No prior
experience with information retrieval required—just bring your
curiosity about what really happens when you type a query into that
search bar.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2025"></category></entry></feed>