<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kaitlin Bustos</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kaitlin-bustos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>What I Wish I Knew Before Becoming a Data Scientist</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/what-i-wish-i-knew-before-becoming-a-data-scientist.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kaitlin Bustos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/what-i-wish-i-knew-before-becoming-a-data-scientist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'm sharing my personal journey as a data scientist and the key lessons learned along the way. I'll emphasize the importance of finding a positive community of like minded-allies, persevering through setbacks as success is not linear, and exploring by embracing the broad nature of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'm sharing my personal journey as a data scientist and the key lessons learned along the way. I'll emphasize the importance of finding a positive community of like minded-allies, persevering through setbacks as success is not linear, and exploring by embracing the broad nature of the data science field. By sharing my experiences and acknowledging the challenges I've faced attendees will gain a fresh perspective on what it takes to succeed in a data science career and inspire them to pursue their passions in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this talk aims to provide a glimpse into the reality of a data science career. Attendees will take away a sense of motivation and empowerment to find their own unique path to success.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>