<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deep learning with Keras</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/deep-learning-with-keras.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has always been our dream to create machines that can think. In the
early phase of artificial intelligence, we solved the problems that
could have been described by a list of formal and mathematical rules.
The main motivation was solving the tasks that are trivial for people to
perform but difficult to describe formally, for example recognizing
objects in images or spoken words. Neural networks have been one
predominant area of research in artificial intelligence that stayed in
limelight over the past five decades or so. However, one major boost in
this domain happened around 2010 when the computers got much faster and
data sets got much bigger. The existing algorithms with some critical
tweaks and improvements became much more efficient and won several
challenges in computer vision, speech recognition, and natural language
processing. In this talk, I would briefly describe how neural networks
works and then move towards state-of-the-art approaches of deep
learning. I would describe in detail how to build deep learning models
and its training procedures using the deep learning library &amp;quot;Keras&amp;quot; that
removes all of the complexity, leaving you an API containing only what
you need to know to efficiently develop and evaluate neural network
models. This talk aims to present two use cases (facial recognition and
sequence prediction) that uses Keras for model building and evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shubhabrata Roy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-06:pycon-ireland-2016/deep-learning-with-keras.html</guid></item></channel></rss>