<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Choi Woojin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_choi-woojin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Serverless Python Web Services</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/serverless-python-web-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Choi Woojin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/serverless-python-web-services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will briefly introduce serverless Python web services. First, I will briefly review the meaning of serverless, and then I will explain the reasons why my current company built a serverless service (limited development resources, irregular server traffic patterns, cost reduction) and how I operate and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will briefly introduce serverless Python web services. First, I will briefly review the meaning of serverless, and then I will explain the reasons why my current company built a serverless service (limited development resources, irregular server traffic patterns, cost reduction) and how I operate and deploy Python web services in a serverless environment. In particular, I will introduce “Zappa,” an open source Python library that helps you conveniently build and deploy serverless Python web services. I will start by creating a very simple Django example project, and then show you the process of setting up “Zappa” and deploying it to an AWS serverless environment (API Gateway, Lambda, etc.). You will be able to experience deploying a Python web service serverless very easily with a single command through “Zappa.” Also, if you are considering building a Python-based serverless environment, I hope this session will be of some help to you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Web Service"></category></entry></feed>