<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Pierre Guilmin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pierre-guilmin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Simulating Quantum Systems with PyTorch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-simulating-quantum-systems-with-pytorch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pierre Guilmin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-simulating-quantum-systems-with-pytorch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I propose to explain why simulating quantum systems is a formidable challenge, and how leveraging modern hardware and software can result in notable performance improvement. PyTorch is ideally suited for this task, first because running solvers on GPUs results in a significant speed-up, and second because …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I propose to explain why simulating quantum systems is a formidable challenge, and how leveraging modern hardware and software can result in notable performance improvement. PyTorch is ideally suited for this task, first because running solvers on GPUs results in a significant speed-up, and second because numerous tasks related to the calibration and control of quantum systems require the computation of gradients based on the time-evolved quantum state. The emerging research effort to develop quantum computers heavily relies on such tools. The dynamiqs library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dynamiqs/dynamiqs"&gt;https://github.com/dynamiqs/dynamiqs&lt;/a&gt;) is a Python library powered by PyTorch, designed to address this challenge. It provides differentiable solvers for the &lt;em&gt;Schrödinger Equation&lt;/em&gt; which governs closed quantum systems, the &lt;em&gt;Lindblad Master Equation&lt;/em&gt; for open quantum systems and the &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Master Equation&lt;/em&gt; for continuously measured quantum systems. Gradients can be computed with PyTorch’s automatic differentiation, or using a constant memory cost method. The library is being developed by several PhD students in physics, most of whom have substantial experience in software development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2023"></category><category term="Lightning Talk"></category></entry></feed>