<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nikolas-tezak.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Synthesis and analysis of circuits in the IPython notebook</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/synthesis-and-analysis-of-circuits-in-the-ipython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nikolas Tezak</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/synthesis-and-analysis-of-circuits-in-the-ipython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building on the new IPython 2.0 widget model and the jsPlumb package we
create a schematic capture tool that allows graphically editing a
circuit as well as its components' parameters and then instantly
updating a domain specific modeling backend. This allows for an
integrated circuit modeling workflow and to extend widget-based user
interfaces for engineering and research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Circuits, i.e., a network of interconnected components with ports, have
found application in various scientific and engineering domains, ranging
from applications close to the physical implementation, such as
electrical circuits, photonic circuits for optical information
processing, superconducting quantum circuits for quantum information
applications to more abstract circuit representations of dynamical
systems, biological processes or even software algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has already led to the development of quite general
domain-independent circuit modeling toolkits such as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.modelica.org/"&gt;Modelica&lt;/a&gt;, but to date, there exist very
few open source graphical general circuit editing environments that can
be tightly integrated with custom, domain-specific implementation
simulation or analysis backends as well as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ipython.org"&gt;IPython&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we present our first attempt at creating such a tool as well as
some applications from our own research on nano-photonic quantum circuit
models. Our existing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mabuchilab.github.io/QNET/"&gt;QNET&lt;/a&gt;
software package allows to model these circuits in a purely symbolic
fashion and interfaces with various codes for numerical simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate that the extension of our package with a visual circuit
editor leads to a rich integrated simulation and analysis workflow in
which an engineer or researcher can receive very fast feedback when
making changes to his model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, it is much easier to build intuition for the
particular kinds of circuit models and find novel and creative solutions
to an engineering task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, given the broad range of applications for circuit models and
representations, we outline how our visual circuit editor can be adapted
to export a circuit for interfacing with other domain specific software
such as Modelica.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>