<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Data Science past, present and future</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-colombia-2018/data-science-past-present-and-future.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-09:pycon-colombia-2018/data-science-past-present-and-future.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Reinforcement learning in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2017/reinforcement-learning-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From AlphaGo beating the world’s top player to algorithms playing Atari games and Robots learning tasks and navigation, reinforcement learning has become the hottest area of AI. In this talk you will learn what RL is and how to use the most popular Python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-19:pytexas-2017/reinforcement-learning-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to large scale data analytics and interactive visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2014/introduction-to-large-scale-data-analytics-and-interactive-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NumPy, Pandas y Matplotlib, entre otros, han revolucionado el procesamiento, manipulación y visualización de datos en Python. ¿Pero, qué hacemos cuando nuestro dataset es demasiado grande para caber en la memoria de nuestro ordenador? ¿Usar una base de datos como Postgres o MongoDB, almacenar en disco con PyTables o BColz, o usar sistemas distribuidos como Hadoop o Spark?Cada una de estas opciones tiene sus ventajas e inconvenientes. Aprender cada una de estas herramientas consume tiempo que podría estar empleándose en el análisis de los datos en sí. La librería Blaze ofrece una interfaz común para una variedad de backends y abstracciones para el procesamiento y la migración de datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por otro lado, ¿cómo visualizamos nuestro dataset cuando tenemos más individuos que píxeles tiene nuestra pantalla? Bokeh es una librería para la visualización interactiva de datos en el navegador al estilo de D3.js en Python, que incluye la funcionalidad de Abstract Rendering para estos casos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La charla consistirá en una introducción al análisis y visualización de large datasets, cómo las librerías Blaze and Bokeh nos pueden facilitar el trabajo y un ejemplo práctico con un dataset de tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-06:pycon-es-2014/introduction-to-large-scale-data-analytics-and-interactive-visualization.html</guid><category>Blaze</category><category>Bokeh</category></item><item><title>Navigating the Data Science Python Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/navigating-the-data-science-python-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you feel lost with all the libraries being developed in the Python ecosystem for Data Science? Have you heard of scikit-learn, theano, dask, xray, blaze, gensim, bokeh, pymc3, numba, jupyter..., but don't know where to start or what each library is for? Do you ask yourself, what is Data Science anyway? Deep learning vs Machine learning? Then, this talk is for you! We'll learn what Data Science is, as well as, existing libraries, functionality and applications in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/navigating-the-data-science-python-ecosystem.html</guid><category>Track Científico</category></item><item><title>Scale your data, not your process: Welcome to the Blaze ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/scale-your-data-not-your-process-welcome-to-the-blaze-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christine Doig - Scale your data, not your process: Welcome to the Blaze ecosystem
[EuroPython 2015]
[21 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumPy and Pandas have revolutionized data processing and munging in
the Python ecosystem. As data and systems grow more complex, moving
and querying becomes more difficult. Python already has excellent
tools for in-memory datasets, but we inevitably want to scale this
processing and take advantage of additional hardware. This is where
Blaze comes in handy by providing a uniform interface to a variety of
technologies and abstractions for migrating and analyzing data.
Supported backends include databases like Postgres or MongoDB, disk
storage systems like PyTables, BColz, and HDF5, or distributed systems
like Hadoop and Spark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the Blaze ecosystem, which includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blaze (data querying): [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blaze.pydata.org/en/latest/][1"&gt;http://blaze.pydata.org/en/latest/][1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Odo (data migration): [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://odo.readthedocs.org/en/latest/][2"&gt;http://odo.readthedocs.org/en/latest/][2&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dask (task scheduler): [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dask.pydata.org/en/latest/][3"&gt;http://dask.pydata.org/en/latest/][3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DyND (dynamic, multidimensional arrays): [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/libdynd/dynd-python][4"&gt;https://github.com/libdynd/dynd-python][4&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datashape (data description): [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://datashape.pydata.org/][5"&gt;http://datashape.pydata.org/][5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will get the most out of this talk if they are familiar with
NumPy and Pandas, have intermediate Python programming skills, and/or
experience with large datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blaze.pydata.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://blaze.pydata.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://odo.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://odo.readthedocs.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dask.pydata.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://dask.pydata.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/libdynd/dynd-python"&gt;https://github.com/libdynd/dynd-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://datashape.pydata.org/"&gt;http://datashape.pydata.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-07:europython-2015/scale-your-data-not-your-process-welcome-to-the-blaze-ecosystem.html</guid></item><item><title>A Hitchhiker's Guide to Data Science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-madrid-2016/a-hitchhikers-guide-to-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Madrid 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the talks and workshop tutorials can be found here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyDataMadrid2016/Conference-Info"&gt;https://github.com/PyDataMadrid2016/Conference-Info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popularity of Python for data science has rocketed in recent years. Its ease of use, a great developer and user community and a solid core of scientific libraries, has attracted many users that were previously using other languages, commercial solutions, or had never wrote a line of code. In this talk, we will explore data science, the state of the Python ecosystem and how to get started. Data science is an interdisciplinary field concerned with extracting valuable insights from data. But, even before the term data science existed, many fields, such as statistics, science, and business intelligence, had already been dealing with data, and using it to discover interesting patterns. Data science is about bringing those communities together and Python has made the conversation easier by providing a common language. Our open source community has created awesome libraries that make the life of anyone searching for answers in data much easier. They have democratized knowledge extraction from data. The interest in the Python community for data science libraries has also caused the proliferation of many open source projects, making it hard for the novice to get their head around all the names and functionality. This talk is a “getting started” guide to the entire ecosystem, to help those struggling with navigating the waters. After the talk, attendees will be comfortable exploring on their own all the possibilities the community has to offer them. Each data science journey is different, the possibilities are infinite, figuring out which one is yours is on you. Follow your path, but get a map. This talk will be your start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-28:pydata-madrid-2016/a-hitchhikers-guide-to-data-science.html</guid></item><item><title>PyData 101: Essential data science skills for every programmer, from data to model to visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/pydata-101-essential-data-science-skills-for-every-programmer-from-data-to-model-to-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Andy Terrel, Christine Doig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Science is fun and with the PyData toolset something you can start to build with in an afternoon. Join us as we start with a few datasets, learn how to munge, model, and materialize into simple web applications for predictions. At the end of the day you will come away with a solid understanding of the PyData ecosystem and tools used everyday by data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andy Terrel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-29:pycon-us-2016/pydata-101-essential-data-science-skills-for-every-programmer-from-data-to-model-to-visualization.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Topic Modeling in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/introduction-to-topic-modeling-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Topic models are a suite of algorithms that uncover the hidden thematic
structure in document collections. These algorithms help us develop new
ways to search, browse and summarize large archives of texts. This talk
will introduce topic modeling and one of it's most widely used
algorithms called LDA (Latent Dirichlet Allocation). Attendees will
learn how to use Python to analyze the content of their text documents.
The talk will go through the full topic modeling pipeline: from
different ways of tokenizing your document, to using the Python library
gensim, to visualizing your results and understanding how to evaluate
them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/introduction-to-topic-modeling-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Visualizing Twitter Data with Blaze and Bokeh</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/visualizing-twitter-data-with-blaze-and-bokeh.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making nice interactive data visualizations in the browser should be
easy and fun! Let's explore tweets with simple IPython notebooks, a
Blaze interface and Bokeh plots!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a Python interactive visualization library that targets modern
web browsers for presentation. Its goal is to provide elegant, concise
construction of novel graphics in the style of D3.js, but also deliver
this capability with high-performance interactivity over very large or
streaming datasets. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaze provides a uniform and adaptable interface to access a variety of
backends, which include streaming Python, Pandas, SQLAlchemy, and Spark.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blaze.pydata.org/"&gt;http://blaze.pydata.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-05:pytexas-2014/visualizing-twitter-data-with-blaze-and-bokeh.html</guid></item><item><title>Topic Modeling with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/topic-modeling-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Topic models are a suite of algorithms that uncover the hidden thematic
structure in document collections. These algorithms help us develop new
ways to search, browse and summarize large archives of texts. This talk
will introduce topic modeling and one of it's most widely used
algorithms called LDA (Latent Dirichlet Allocation). Attendees will
learn how to use Python to analyze the content of their text documents.
The talk will go through the full topic modeling pipeline: from
different ways of tokenizing your document, to using the Python library
gensim, to visualizing your results and understanding how to evaluate
them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-15:pytexas-2015/topic-modeling-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Beginner's Guide to Machine Learning Competitions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/beginners-guide-to-machine-learning-competitions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will offer a hands-on introduction to machine learning and
the process of applying these concepts in a Kaggle competition. We will
introduce attendees to machine learning concepts, examples and flows,
while building up their skills to solve an actual problem. At the end of
the tutorial attendees will be familiar with a real data science flow:
feature preparation, modeling, optimization and validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packages used in the tutorial will include: IPython notebook,
scikit-learn, pandas and NLTK. We’ll use IPython notebook for
interactive exploration and visualization, in order to gain a basic
understanding of what’s in the data. From there, we’ll extract features
and train a model using scikit-learn. This will bring us to our first
submission. We’ll then learn how to structure the problem for offline
evaluation and use scikit-learn’s clean model API to train many models
simultaneously and perform feature selection and hyperparameter
optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of session, attendees will have time to work on their own to
improve their models and make multiple submissions to get to the top of
the leaderboard, just like in a real competition. Hopefully attendees
will not only leave the tutorial having learned the core data science
concepts and flow, but also having had a great time doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Doig</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/beginners-guide-to-machine-learning-competitions.html</guid><category>tutorial</category><category>machine learning</category><category>nltk</category><category>pandas</category><category>scikit-learn</category><category>ipython</category></item></channel></rss>