<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Christy Heaton</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Map it with Python! Intro to GIS and Python mapping modules.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/map-it-with-python-intro-to-gis-and-python-mapping-modules.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maps are powerful tools that we use every day. Come learn about how
Python can be used to handle spatial data and create beautiful maps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-04:/north-bay-python-2018/map-it-with-python-intro-to-gis-and-python-mapping-modules.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2018</category></item><item><title>PyLadies Panel: Talking about experiences and roles within the Python community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2024/pyladies-panel-talking-about-experiences-and-roles-within-the-python-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panelists: Christy Heaton, Mariatta, Lynn Root, Luciana Abud&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lynn Root</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-04-07:/pycascades-2024/pyladies-panel-talking-about-experiences-and-roles-within-the-python-community.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2024</category></item><item><title>Web Maps, 2 Ways with Streamlit and PyScript</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/web-maps-2-ways-with-streamlit-and-pyscript.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s use Python to make fun and interactive web maps! In this talk, we'll explore two easy ways to create web maps using Python: Streamlit and PyScript. We'll build a web app that helps you find the perfect hiking trail in Washington state, and in the process, learn how to integrate geographic data, visualize it interactively, and deploy it to the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each tool offers a unique approach to building interactive maps. With Streamlit, you’ll see how simple it is to set up a dashboard (that includes maps) with minimal code. Then, we’ll dive into PyScript, which enables you to run Python directly in the browser, allowing you to create and deploy a web map without having Python installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you'll understand two straightforward methods to create and deploy web maps with Python, with practical examples you can begin using right away!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-08:/pycascades-2025/web-maps-2-ways-with-streamlit-and-pyscript.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2025</category></item><item><title>Intro to Spatial Analysis and Maps with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/intro-to-spatial-analysis-and-maps-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will introduce Python as a spatial problem solving and data visualization tool. To demonstrate the power of Python for spatial analysis, we will solve a spatial problem and make a beautiful map of our results. Along the way, we will discuss considerations when dealing with spatial data and the wide range of Python tools available for spatial analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:/pycon-us-2018/intro-to-spatial-analysis-and-maps-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2018</category></item><item><title>Plan your next eclipse viewing with Jupyter and geopandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/plan-your-next-eclipse-viewing-with-jupyter-and-geopandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maps are powerful tools that we use every day. Python is well-equipped
to handle spatial data and with well documented robust libraries to help
you perform spatial analysis and create beautiful maps. In this talk,
we'll discover the fascinating world of spatial analysis by solving a
fun problem: where can we go to see an upcoming solar eclipse? Along the
way we'll learn about mapping topics like projections and coordinate
systems, best practices for map making, and intricacies of spatial data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:/pycon-us-2019/plan-your-next-eclipse-viewing-with-jupyter-and-geopandas.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Planea el próximo eclipse con Jupyter y geopandas.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/planea-el-proximo-eclipse-con-jupyter-y-geopandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Los mapas son herramientas poderosas que usamos todos los días. Python está bien equipado para manejar datos espaciales y tiene muchas bibliotecas para ayudarte a realizar un análisis espacial y crear hermosos mapas. En esta charla, descubriremos el fascinante mundo del análisis espacial resolviendo un problema divertido: ¿dónde podemos ir para ver el próximo eclipse solar? A lo largo del camino, aprenderemos sobre temas de mapeo como proyecciones y sistemas de coordenadas, mejores prácticas para hacer mapas y complejidades de datos espaciales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:/pycon-us-2019/planea-el-proximo-eclipse-con-jupyter-y-geopandas.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Build a Web Map with PyScript!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2023/build-a-web-map-with-pyscript.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyScript allows you to run Python code in a browser, like JavaScript
does. It also lets you import geospatial mapping libraries like Folium
and GeoPandas, all without actually installing anything! In this talk,
we'll discuss the benefits and ease of using PyScript for this task,
then we'll go through a basic geospatial analysis and display the
results in a web map. In the end we'll have an app that can be easily
shared, containing Python code that anyone can view and run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-12-16:/pyohio-2023/build-a-web-map-with-pyscript.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2023</category></item></channel></rss>