<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - George Stagg</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Magic with WebAssembly and webR</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/magic-with-webassembly-and-webr.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year the initial version of webR was released and users have begun building new interactive experiences with R on the web. In this talk, I'll discuss webR's TypeScript library and what it is able to do. The library allows users to interact with the R environment directly from JavaScript, which enables manipulation tricks that seem like magic. I'll begin by describing how to move objects from R to JS and back again, and discuss the technology that makes this possible. I'll continue with more advanced manipulation, such as invoking R functions from JS and talk about why you might want to do so. Finally, I'll describe how messages are sent over webR's communication channel and explain how this enables webR to work with Shinylive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">George Stagg</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/magic-with-webassembly-and-webr.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Updates from Posit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/updates-from-posit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;6:45 Hadley introduces the conference.
10:37 Hadley on Posit, PBC. Who are we, and what we do.
20:41 Charlotte Wickham on Quarto, an open-source scientific and technical publishing system.
31:05 George Stagg on webR, R for WebAssembly. Execute R code in your web browser.
43:34 James Blair with the latest on Posit's partnerships with Databricks and Snowflake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our first Posit Conf 2024 keynote, where we’ll tell you about our mission, our products, and some of the exciting things we’ve been working on over the last year. Hadley Wickham, Chief Scientist, will talk briefly about Posit’s mission and products, before introducing the three speakers who will update you on some of the coolest projects we’ve worked on over the last year. James Blair, Senior Product Manager, will give you the latest on our partnerships with Databricks and Snowflake, and how we’re building seamless integrations that let you focus on data science instead of dealing with technical details. Charlotte Wickham, Developer Educator, will show you what’s new in Quarto, focusing on new ways to build beautiful PDFs with Typst. Finally, George Stagg, Senior Software Engineer, will tell you about the latest innovations in teaching using webR, a tool that lets you compile your R code into standalone HTML files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hadley Wickham</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/updates-from-posit.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>