<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Enhancing your Python database experience with PostgreSQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2016/enhancing-your-python-database-experience-with-postgresql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a great programming language, and PostgreSQL is a great database. That's an overlap too good not to exploit! This talk will give an overview of how to use some of the PostgreSQL specific extensions in Python, to make your applications both easier and more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Magnus Hagander</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-09:pycon-se-2016/enhancing-your-python-database-experience-with-postgresql.html</guid></item><item><title>Data Driven Cache Invalidation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/data-driven-cache-invalidation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Magnus Hagander - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In todays world, nobody (should) deploy a web application facing the
internet without having a proper caching system in place. There are many
different solutions to choose from, from manual use of memcached through
framework integrated caching to external caches like Squid or Varnish.
Most modern frameworks come with integrated functionality for at least
one of these methods, and often more than one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, they often relies on all traffic going through the same
framework to work properly - a caching layer in Rails is hard to share
with one in Django. This talk will show a way to break the design rules
of these frameworks just a little, and have the database help solve this
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will use a small application written in Python using Django to
illustrate the examples, but the method is language independent.
Unsurprisingly, the database used is PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Magnus Hagander</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/data-driven-cache-invalidation.html</guid><category>cache</category><category>database</category><category>deploy</category><category>design</category><category>django</category><category>framework</category><category>web</category></item></channel></rss>