<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Pryce Turner</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pryce-turner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Orchestrating Bioinformatics Workflows Across a Heterogeneous Toolset with Flyte</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/orchestrating-bioinformatics-workflows-across-a-heterogeneous-toolset-with-flyte.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pryce Turner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/orchestrating-bioinformatics-workflows-across-a-heterogeneous-toolset-with-flyte.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Python excels at prototyping and iterating quickly, it’s not always performant enough for whole-genome scale data processing. Flyte, an open-source Python-based workflow orchestrator, presents an excellent way to tie together the myriad tools required to run bioinformatics workflows. Flyte is a k8s native orchestrator, meaning all dependencies …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Python excels at prototyping and iterating quickly, it’s not always performant enough for whole-genome scale data processing. Flyte, an open-source Python-based workflow orchestrator, presents an excellent way to tie together the myriad tools required to run bioinformatics workflows. Flyte is a k8s native orchestrator, meaning all dependencies are captured and versioned in container images. It also allows you to define custom types in Python representing genomic datasets, enabling a powerful way to enforce compatibility across tools. Computational biologists, or any scientists processing data with a heterogeneous toolset, stand to benefit from a common orchestration layer that is opinionated yet flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>