<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_carlos-de-las-heras.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Django's watching my back(end)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/djangos-watching-my-backend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos de las Heras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-09:pycon-cz-2017/djangos-watching-my-backend.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the advent of new amazing front-end frameworks and the
ever-increasing power of browsers and mobile processors, webapp users
expect a dynamic, seamless user experience where page refresh is out
of the question. We Pythonistas love Django for web development, but
server-side template rendering is not cool anymore. What do? Use
Django as a pure back-end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, technologies, strategies and third-party packages will
be discussed, which will enable you to hit the ground running when
tackling your first decoupled project or using Django in the context
of a hybrid architecture. Furthermore, we will discuss how web
development has changed through the years, aiming to find the mindset
that will keep Django (and by extension Python as a web development
language) relevant in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlos is a Pythonista and Django developer from Madrid, Spain.
Though he wouldn't consider programming his vocational calling
(probably music is), he loves open source and free software ever ince
he has discovered it. That led him to be an occasional teacher and
mentor, introducing rogramming and the hacker mindset to young
people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He believes, that real technological literacy, as opposed to
technological consumerism, is integral to building a better society:
developers are in a privileged position and openness, transparency
and ease of access are fundamental. Communities play a vital role
here: programming can be a cold, lonely and dehumanized enterprise,
but in communities we can find warmth and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year he spoke at DjangoCon Europe, where he delivered a speech
in the hope of being useful and giving a glimpse of his own
experiences with Django. Currently he works for a small data analysis
and intelligence start-up as the lead developer, which is quite a
challenge, but a learning experience with every step.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Django is watching my back(end)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/django-is-watching-my-backend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos de las Heras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/django-is-watching-my-backend.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the advent of new amazing front-end frameworks and the ever-increasing power of browsers and mobile processors, webapp users expect a dynamic, seamless user experience where page refresh is out of the question. We all love Django, but server template rendering is not cool anymore. What do? Use Django as a pure back-end. In this talk, technologies, strategies and third-party packages will be discussed, which will enable you to hit the ground running when tackling your first decoupled project. Also the (somewhat) dodgy question, ‘why Django?’ will be addressed and morphed into the less drastic question ‘where Django?’ by analyzing the advantages and disadvantages of Django opposed to other technologies, while seeking out to find the mindset that will keep Django relevant in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>