<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tim-orme.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Simplicity For Scale: Analyzing 15 Million DNA Samples With Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/simplicity-for-scale-analyzing-15-million-dna-samples-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Orme</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:pydata-la-2019/simplicity-for-scale-analyzing-15-million-dna-samples-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When confronted with large-scale data challenges, we often reach for
complex tools to help solve the problem. In the past 7 years, Ancestry
DNA has amassed the largest collection of consumer genomic data in the
world, creating a new scaling challenge in the genomics world. We'll
show how picking simple tools in the Python ecosystem helped us solve
massive scaling challenges in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With data sets growing larger by the day, and the number of big-data
tools growing right along with them, it can be daunting to select the
right tool for the job. Sometimes, too, it's tempting to apply the
latest-and-greatest ones to the problems we're working on. But, more
often than not, the simplest tool is the right one and, fortunately for
us, that's where Python shines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a short 7 years, Ancestry has collected nearly 15 million DNA
samples. Data of this magnitude has proved to be a massive scaling
challenge for the production pipeline that must analyze that data set to
produce customer results every single day. This talk will tell the story
of how that pipeline has evolved over the years, from a manual command
line process, to a scheduled Hadoop pipeline, and finally into the
Python-based, event-driven system we use today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will give a basic overview of our DNA test and cover our core
relative detection and ethnicity algorithms at a high level. I'll then
dive into the constraints and specific challenges the pipeline presents,
and how we decided to leverage Python &amp;amp; Celery to solve those problems.
Lastly, I'll describe the benefits of switching to Python, demonstrating
the simplicity, performance, and reduction in code it provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>