<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Felipe de Morais</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AfroPython: Using Django to change black people life in Brazil</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/afropython-using-django-to-change-black-people-life-in-brazil.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm Felipe de Morais, Co-CEO and co-founder of AfroPython. In this talk, I will share the path of AfroPython in Brazil(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://afropython.org/"&gt;http://afropython.org/&lt;/a&gt;) and how the Python community was involved in growing and building this community of black people in IT. And how we became a company to help people thrive using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe de Morais</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/djangocon-us-2023/afropython-using-django-to-change-black-people-life-in-brazil.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>AfroPython: empoderando a la población negra usando Python en Brasil</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/afropython-empoderando-a-la-poblacion-negra-usando-python-en-brasil.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Más que 50% de la población de Brasil son negros pero este numero no está representado en Tecnología. Brasil es el segundo país con más personas negras en el mundo, solo detrás de Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de esta charla es compartir una iniciativa creada en Brasil para incluir y empoderar las personas negras con a través de la tecnología.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe de Morais</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:/pycon-us-2019/afropython-empoderando-a-la-poblacion-negra-usando-python-en-brasil.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>diversity</category><category>afropython</category></item><item><title>🌐 Building Your First API with Django and Django Rest Framework</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/building-your-first-api-with-django-and-django-rest-framework.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us at PyCon US 2024 for an exciting tutorial 🎓, where we'll dive
into the world of web APIs using Python's beloved Django framework and
the Django Rest Framework. This session is perfect for Python
enthusiasts 🐍 eager to expand their web development skills in a
practical, hands-on environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What You Will Learn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔍 Introduction to API Development with Django: Understand the basics
of API construction and the role of Django and Django Rest Framework
in modern web development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📊 Django Models: Explore how to create and utilize Django models,
the backbone of data handling in Django applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔗 URL Mapping and Views: Master URL configuration for efficient API
endpoint creation and discover how Django views and ViewSets drive
your API's functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔄 Serializers in Action: Learn to implement serializers for
converting data formats, a critical step in RESTful API development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💻 Practical Application: Engage in hands-on coding to apply these
concepts in building a functional API from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why This Tutorial?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is tailored for those ready to step into API development
with Django. We focus not just on theoretical knowledge but also
emphasize practical skills. By the end of this session, you'll have a
clear understanding of the essential components of Django for API
development and hands-on experience in building an API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you already navigating the Django landscape and seeking to deepen
your expertise? 🌱 This tutorial provides an immersive opportunity to
advance your web development skills and explore the intricacies of API
development using Django and the Django Rest Framework. 🚀 Join us for
an enriching journey as we delve into mastering the art of building
powerful APIs with Django!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe de Morais</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-15:/pycon-us-2024/building-your-first-api-with-django-and-django-rest-framework.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>