<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Colossal Cave Adventure in Python... in the browser!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/colossal-cave-adventure-in-python-in-the-browser.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn about 36-bit integers and writing interpreters in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossal Cave (Adventure) is the original text adventure, written in FORTRAN IV. We explore using software archeology to write a Python interpreter for FORTRAN.  We use BeeWare's Batavia JS Python interpreter to run in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Swenson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-26:pycon-au-2018/colossal-cave-adventure-in-python-in-the-browser.html</guid></item><item><title>Multi-Factor Authentication: How it works and why you need to be using it yesterday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/multi-factor-authentication-how-it-works-and-why-you-need-to-be-using-it-yesterday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Multi-factor authentication (MFA) and two-factor auth (2FA) are becoming popular, but how do they work? What are the options, how secure are they, and how do you use them in your own applications?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll answer all these and more, covering everything from Django integration to cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Swenson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-24:pycon-au-2018/multi-factor-authentication-how-it-works-and-why-you-need-to-be-using-it-yesterday.html</guid></item><item><title>Colossal Cave Adventure in Python... in the browser!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/colossal-cave-adventure-in-python-in-the-browser.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colossal Cave, also known as Adventure or ADVENT, is the original text adventure. It was written in FORTRAN IV and there is practically no way to run the original program without translating it. We'll explore software archeology to write a Python interpreter to run the FORTRAN code as-is, without translating it. Come learn about pre-ASCII and 36-bit integers and writing interpreters in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, we'll show how to use BeeWare's Batavia Python interpreter (in JavaScript) to execute the program. FORTRAN IV in Python in JavaScript in your browser!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Swenson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/colossal-cave-adventure-in-python-in-the-browser.html</guid></item><item><title>Colossal Cave Adventure in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2017/colossal-cave-adventure-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The oldest known Colossal Cave source code we have is from 1977 and written for the then 11-year-old PDP-10 in a variant of FORTRAN IV that is now completely defunct and was specific to the PDP-10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll talk briefly about a history of video games, FORTRAN, and the PDP machines that led to this, and explain how the quirks of this machine were baked into its variant of FORTRAN IV. We'll look at some ancient PDP manuals to discover the secrets you need to know to read this amazing source code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll delve into how one goes about writing a simple interpreter in Python to run this FORTRAN IV code as-is: translating strings, implementing its odd arithmetic and conditional statements, reading in data from our &amp;quot;tape&amp;quot; drive, how we get input and send output using our &amp;quot;teletype&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a demo of this game playing right now, it is running on Heroku and accessible via SMS. Just text anything to +1 (669) 238-3683 (&amp;quot;669 ADVENT3&amp;quot;) to start a game. Send RESET to restart the game. Case doesn't matter when sending commands. It identifies you based on your phone number and will remember your game indefinitely. (We'll also talk about how we achieved this in Heroku.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Swenson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-12-02:north-bay-python-2017/colossal-cave-adventure-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>CPython internals and the VM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/cpython-internals-and-the-vm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christopher Swenson
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/145/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/145/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Ever wanted to know what CPython, the standard Python interpreter, is doing under the hood? What happens at startup before your code is run? How is your code translated to VM bytecode, what does that bytecode mean, and how is it run? In this talk, we'll dive into all of those fun parts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will help you understand what your code is doing under the hood, how to potentially optimize it, and to know the advantages and disadvantages of CPython and how they affect you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Swenson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/cpython-internals-and-the-vm.html</guid></item><item><title>Sage: Open Source Math in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/sage-open-source-math-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A quick introduction to Sage, an open-source mathematics package for
experimentation in all areas of mathematics. There will be some brief
remarks and demos of what Sage is capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Swenson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-09:pycon-us-2012/sage-open-source-math-in-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>