<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Brad Rees</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brad-rees.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>RAPIDS: Open Source GPU Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/rapids-open-source-gpu-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brad Rees</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:/pydata-la-2019/rapids-open-source-gpu-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;See how RAPIDS and the open source ecosystem are advancing data science.
In this session, we will explore RAPIDS, the open source data science
platform from NVIDIA. Come learn how to get started leveraging these
open-source libraries for faster performance and easier development on
GPUs. See the latest engineering …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;See how RAPIDS and the open source ecosystem are advancing data science.
In this session, we will explore RAPIDS, the open source data science
platform from NVIDIA. Come learn how to get started leveraging these
open-source libraries for faster performance and easier development on
GPUs. See the latest engineering work and new release features,
including benchmarks and software development roadmap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RAPIDS suite of open source software libraries gives the data
scientist the freedom to execute end-to-end data science and analytics
pipelines on GPUs. RAPIDS is incubatedby NVIDIA based on years of
accelerated analytics experience. RAPIDS relies on NVIDIA CUDA
primitives for low-level compute optimization and exposes GPU
parallelism and high-bandwidth memory speed through user-friendly Python
interfaces. Through a familiar DataFrame API that integrates with a
variety of machine learning algorithms, RAPIDS facilitates common data
preparations tasks while removing typical serialization costs. RAPIDS
includes support for multi-GPU deployments, enabling vastly accelerated
processing and training on large dataset sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join NVIDIA’s engineers as they walk through a collection of data
science problems that introduce components and features of RAPIDS,
including: feature engineering, data manipulation, statistical tasks,
machine learning, and graph analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData LA 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>GPU Accelerated Graph Analysis in Python Using cuGraph</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/gpu-accelerated-graph-analysis-in-python-using-cugraph.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brad Rees</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/gpu-accelerated-graph-analysis-in-python-using-cugraph.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graph analysis is used in a wide range of applications, from computational social science (social network analysis) to fraud detection and marketing. Just like within Machine Learning (ML), being able to load and analyze data quickly is the key to getting to a solution faster. Additionally, like ML, there …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graph analysis is used in a wide range of applications, from computational social science (social network analysis) to fraud detection and marketing. Just like within Machine Learning (ML), being able to load and analyze data quickly is the key to getting to a solution faster. Additionally, like ML, there is a lot of data prep, which we call graph ETL, that needs to be done. Join us for a talk on using RAPIDS and cuGraph to accelerate the full end-to-end graph analysis pipeline. We will dive into a COVID-19 social network example to illustrate the performance gains of using GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>