<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Artistic Python: Mixing Python Programming with Fashion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/artistic-python-mixing-python-programming-with-fashion.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are numerous ways to learn and introduce the world of programming
to new coders. One way is to embrace the world of art. Python offers an
ecosystem that can take any curious programmer to merge the world of art
and technology. Artistic Python: Mixing Programming with Fashion aims to
show how Python, some hardware, and numerous libraries can inspire
anyone to incorporate coding into their artistic endeavors and vice
versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one thinks of fashion, several things come to mind: fabric, sewing,
and fashion shows. Rarely does one think about leveraging programming
and available hardware as components in creating a final product.
Artistic Python will present the ideation, design, coding, and creation
process of an outfit that incorporated Python programming, lighting, and
small programmable computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Baldevia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/artistic-python-mixing-python-programming-with-fashion.html</guid><category>fashion</category><category>art</category><category>multimedia</category><category>music</category><category>social</category><category>Math</category></item><item><title>Discovering the world of Python through music</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/ria-baldevia-discovering-the-world-of-python-through-music-pycon-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ria Baldevia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to explain how music is a great way to learn Python with Pedro Kroger's  music programming library, Pyknon. In music programming, data structures are really important in order to organize notes, chords, durations, and rests. Eventually, a music programmer will utilize patterns and sequences in order to compose several bars of music.
This talk will utilize an animated presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Baldevia</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-31:pycon-us-2016/ria-baldevia-discovering-the-world-of-python-through-music-pycon-2016.html</guid></item></channel></rss>