<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SymEngine A Fast Symbolic Manipulation Library</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/symengine-a-fast-symbolic-manipulation-library-scipy-2016-ondrej-certik-isuru-fernando.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/symengine/symengine"&gt;SymEngine&lt;/a&gt; is to be the fastest C++ symbolic manipulation library (opensource or commercial), compatible with SymPy, that can be used from many languages (Python, Ruby, Julia, ...). We will present the current status of development, how things are implemented internally, why we chose C++, benchmarks, and examples of usage from Python (SymPy and Sage), Ruby and Julia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ondřej Čertík</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/symengine-a-fast-symbolic-manipulation-library-scipy-2016-ondrej-certik-isuru-fernando.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>symengine</category></item><item><title>Symbolic Computation with Python using SymPy (Beginner)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/symbolic-compution-with-python-using-sympy-beginner-scipy-2016-tutorial-ondrej-certik-et-al.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Materials for this tutorial are found here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/sympy/scipy-2016-tutorial"&gt;https://github.com/sympy/scipy-2016-tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ondřej Čertík</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-11:scipy-2016/symbolic-compution-with-python-using-sympy-beginner-scipy-2016-tutorial-ondrej-certik-et-al.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>tutorial</category><category>SymPy</category></item><item><title>Symbolic Computing with SymPy, SciPy2013 Tutorial, Part 1 of 6</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/symbolic-computing-sympy-scipy2013-tutorial-part-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SymPy is a pure Python library for symbolic mathematics. It aims to
become a full-featured computer algebra system (CAS) while keeping the
code as simple as possible in order to be comprehensible and easily
extensible. SymPy is written entirely in Python and does not require any
external libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we will introduce attendees to SymPy. We will start by
showing how to install and configure this Python module. Then we will
proceed to the basics of constructing and manipulating mathematical
expressions in SymPy. We will also discuss the most common issues and
differences from other computer algebra systems, and how to deal with
them. In the last part of this tutorial we will show how to solve
simple, yet illustrative, mathematical problems with SymPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This knowledge should be enough for attendees to start using SymPy for
solving mathematical problems and hacking SymPy's internals (though
hacking core modules may require additional expertise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect attendees of this tutorial to have basic knowledge of Python
and mathematics. However, any more advanced topics will be explained
during presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installing, configuring and running SymPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basics of expressions in SymPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;traversal and manipulation of expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;common issues and differences from other CAS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting up and using printers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;querying expression properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not only symbolics: numerical computing (mpmath)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematical problem solving with SymPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required Packages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 2.x or 3.x, SymPy (most recent version) Optional packages:
IPython, matplotlib, NetworkX, GMPY, numpy, scipy&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Meurer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-06-24:scipy-2013/symbolic-computing-sympy-scipy2013-tutorial-part-1.html</guid><category>mathematics</category><category>sympy</category></item><item><title>Reproducible, Relocatable, Customizable Builds and Packaging with HashDist Part1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/reproducible-relocatable-customizable-builds-an.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces HashDist, a critical component of the scientific
software development workflow. HashDist enables highly customizable,
source-driven, and reproducible builds for scientific software stacks.
HashDist builds can be made relocatable, allowing the easy
redistribution of binaries on all three major operating systems as well
as cloud and supercomputing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing scientific software is a continuous balance between not
reinventing the wheel and getting fragile codes to interoperate with one
another. Binary software distributions such as Anaconda provide a robust
starting point for many scientific software packages, but this solution
alone is insufficient for many scientific software developers. HashDist
provides a critical component of the development workflow, enabling
highly customizable, source-driven, and reproducible builds for
scientific software stacks, available from both the IPython Notebook and
the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, the Coastal and Hydraulics Laboratory at the US
Army Engineer Research and Development Center has funded the development
of HashDist in collaboration with Simula Research Laboratories and the
University of Texas at Austin. HashDist is motivated by a functional
approach to package build management, and features intelligent caching
of sources and builds, parametrized build specifications, and the
ability to interoperate with system compilers and packages. HashDist
enables the easy specification of &amp;quot;software stacks&amp;quot;, which allow both
the novice user to install a default environment and the advanced user
to configure every aspect of their build in a modular fashion. As an
advanced feature, HashDist builds can be made relocatable, allowing the
easy redistribution of binaries on all three major operating systems as
well as cloud, and supercomputing platforms. As a final benefit, all
HashDist builds are reproducible, with a build hash specifying exactly
how each component of the software stack was installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will feature an introduction to the problem of packaging
Python-based scientific software, a discussion of the basic tools
available to scientific Python developers, and a detailed discussion and
demonstration of the HashDist package build manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HashDist documentation is available from:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hashdist.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://hashdist.readthedocs.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt; HashDist is currently hosted
at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/hashdist/hashdist"&gt;https://github.com/hashdist/hashdist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andy Terrel</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/reproducible-relocatable-customizable-builds-an.html</guid><category>packaging</category><category>reproducible research</category></item></channel></rss>