<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jo Seong-bin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jo-seong-bin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How do asyncio libraries work?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/how-do-asyncio-libraries-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jo Seong-bin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-02:/pycon-korea-2022/how-do-asyncio-libraries-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We frequently use various libraries that support asyncio, such as asynchronous web frameworks, asynchronous database libraries, asynchronous web servers, and aiohttp, but the asyncio network API that makes up these frameworks is not often covered. In this session, we will cover network-related APIs provided by the asyncio library, such …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We frequently use various libraries that support asyncio, such as asynchronous web frameworks, asynchronous database libraries, asynchronous web servers, and aiohttp, but the asyncio network API that makes up these frameworks is not often covered. In this session, we will cover network-related APIs provided by the asyncio library, such as asyncio.Transport, asyncio.Protocol, and asyncio.Server.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Python Library"></category></entry><entry><title>Chatbot Framework with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/chatbot-framework-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jo Seong-bin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-13:/pycon-korea-2023/chatbot-framework-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will cover how chatbot frameworks work using &amp;quot;Rasa&amp;quot;, an open source chatbot framework in Python, and &amp;quot;LangChain&amp;quot;, an open source framework that helps build LLM applications easily. Chatbots need to perform tasks such as &amp;quot;intent classification&amp;quot; to identify the intent of a user's utterance, &amp;quot;entity …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will cover how chatbot frameworks work using &amp;quot;Rasa&amp;quot;, an open source chatbot framework in Python, and &amp;quot;LangChain&amp;quot;, an open source framework that helps build LLM applications easily. Chatbots need to perform tasks such as &amp;quot;intent classification&amp;quot; to identify the intent of a user's utterance, &amp;quot;entity recognition&amp;quot; to identify necessary information from the user's utterance, and &amp;quot;slot filling&amp;quot;. In addition, they need to generate appropriate responses from the classified intents, and they need to know how to deal with sudden changes in the user's utterance intent. In this session, we will look at how Rasa handles these problems. We will also briefly cover how to build a Chit-Chat application using LangChain, which helps build LLM applications easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seongbin Cho
Hello. I am Seongbin Cho, who loves Python. I majored in humanities, but I learned about the field of natural language processing late and fell in love with development. Thanks to many people who share their knowledge, I am able to keep moving forward day by day without giving up. I don't take for granted what I've received, and I hope it can be of some help to others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry></feed>