<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_allison-lacker.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How I learned Python while working at Eventbrite</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2015/how-i-learned-python-while-working-at-eventbrite.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allison Lacker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-01:pyohio-2015/how-i-learned-python-while-working-at-eventbrite.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you learn a new tech stack while shipping code at the same time?
When I joined Eventbrite I knew Java and Ruby (and don't ask me to
program in either of those anymore, I don't remember). I'll give some
tips and strategies while saying what worked -- and didn't -- for me
when I was learning Django at Eventbrite.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>How I learned Django while working at Eventbrite</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/how-i-learned-django-while-working-at-eventbrite.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allison Lacker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-28:djangocon-us-2015/how-i-learned-django-while-working-at-eventbrite.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How I learned Django while working at Eventbrite by Allison Lacker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all are constantly learning new technologies and strategies to be
more effective at our jobs, or just because they interest us. How do you
balance the need to stay on top of the latest and greatest changes in
our industry with making a product? How do you take a new hire with
amazing potential and help them learn everything they need to know,
while shipping at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shipping code as soon as possible isn't a cutthroat business decision.
It helps people learn faster, be more effective, feel more valued, and
keeps them centered on the right goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you balance learning with shipping code? Is there any reason they
have to be separate? Too often we feel that these are discrete tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benefits of learning technology by applying it to real world problems
are: - Fixing a real world problem - Learning something that is
immediately useful - Remembering it better than if you had learned the
theory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dangers to consider include: - Not everyone learns the same way - Real
world problems can be vastly more difficult than you expect, unless
you've already solved them - Revealing embarrassing legacy code and
decisions earlier than you'd like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HJch/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HJch/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>