<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Apoorv Garg</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reduce the environmental footprint of your Python programs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/reduce-the-environmental-footprint-of-your-python-programs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we witness the cutting-edge developments in Artificial Intelligence, the carbon footprint of our code base can no longer be brushed off as insignificant. In every respect, as developers, we have a responsibility to take the lead in implementing sustainable coding practices. This presentation explores Python techniques that can be embedded in one’s code that will help reduce cycles, lower resource dependencies, and decrease energy usage without degrading performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than just tech tips, this talk is going to focus on the why—looking into the expanding CO2 of the AI and tech space, what it means for our planet, and how it points to the importance of responsible development. The audience will discover that simple but conscious changes in one’s handy work, such writing better algorithms, datamodelling, and using greener tools can somehow make a positive impact to the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is not only about utilizing new technologies correctly, it is also about changing the perception of our field. Let’s be responsible — let’s develop projects that will not harm the environment. Together, we can progress and adapt our development processes to the current climate change crisis – the one in which development and innovative efforts go hand in hand with taking care of the environment. So let’s code with purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Apoorv Garg</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-17:/pycon-us-2025/reduce-the-environmental-footprint-of-your-python-programs.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item></channel></rss>