<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Yevgeniy Vorobeychik</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_yevgeniy-vorobeychik.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Election Control by Manipulating Issue Significance</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/election-control-by-manipulating-issue-significance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Estornell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/election-control-by-manipulating-issue-significance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Election Control by Manipulating Issue Significance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Estornell (Washington University in St Louis)*; Sanmay Das (Washington University in St. Louis); Edith Elkind (Oxford University); Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrity of elections is vital to democratic systems, but it is frequently threatened by malicious actors.
The study …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Election Control by Manipulating Issue Significance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Estornell (Washington University in St Louis)*; Sanmay Das (Washington University in St. Louis); Edith Elkind (Oxford University); Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrity of elections is vital to democratic systems, but it is frequently threatened by malicious actors.
The study of algorithmic complexity of the problem of manipulating election outcomes by changing its structural features is known as election control Rothe [2016].
One means of election control that has been proposed, pertinent to the spatial voting model, is to select a subset of issues that determine voter preferences over candidates.
We study a variation of this model in which voters have judgments about relative importance of issues, and a malicious actor can manipulate these judgments.
We show that computing effective manipulations in this model is NP-hard even with two candidates or binary issues.
However, we demonstrate that the problem becomes tractable with a constant number of voters or issues.
Additionally, while it remains intractable when voters can vote stochastically, we exhibit an important special case in which stochastic voting behavior enables tractable manipulation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Robust Collective Classification against Structural Attacks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/robust-collective-classification-against-structural-attacks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kai Zhou</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/robust-collective-classification-against-structural-attacks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Robust Collective Classification against Structural Attacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai Zhou (Washington University in St. Louis)*; Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collective learning methods exploit relations among data points to enhance classification performance. However, such relations, represented as edges in the underlying graphical model, expose an extra attack surface to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Robust Collective Classification against Structural Attacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai Zhou (Washington University in St. Louis)*; Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collective learning methods exploit relations among data points to enhance classification performance. However, such relations, represented as edges in the underlying graphical model, expose an extra attack surface to the adversaries. We study adversarial robustness of an important class of such graphical models, Associative Markov Networks (AMN), to structural attacks, where an attacker can modify the graph structure at test time. We formulate the task of learning a robust AMN classifier as a bi-level program, where the inner problem is a challenging non- linear integer program that computes optimal structural changes to the AMN. To address this technical challenge, we first relax the attacker problem, and then use duality to obtain a convex quadratic upper bound for the robust AMN problem. We then prove a bound on the quality of the resulting approximately optimal solutions, and experimentally demonstrate the e&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Robust Spatial-Temporal Incident Prediction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/robust-spatial-temporal-incident-prediction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ayan Mukhopadhyay</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/robust-spatial-temporal-incident-prediction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robust Spatial-Temporal Incident Prediction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayan Mukhopadhyay (Stanford University)*; Kai Wang (Harvard University); Andrew Perrault (Harvard University); Mykel Kochenderfer (Stanford University); Milind Tambe (Harvard University); Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatio-temporal incident prediction is a central issue in law enforcement, with applications in fighting crimes like poaching, human …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robust Spatial-Temporal Incident Prediction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayan Mukhopadhyay (Stanford University)*; Kai Wang (Harvard University); Andrew Perrault (Harvard University); Mykel Kochenderfer (Stanford University); Milind Tambe (Harvard University); Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatio-temporal incident prediction is a central issue in law enforcement, with applications in fighting crimes like poaching, human trafficking, illegal fishing, burglaries and smuggling. However, state of the art approaches fail to account for  evasion in response to predictive models, a common form of which is spatial shift in incident occurrence. We present a general approach for incident forecasting that is robust to spatial shifts. We propose two techniques for solving the resulting robust optimization problem: first, a constraint generation method guaranteed to yield an optimal solution, and second, a more scalable gradient-based approach. We then apply these techniques to both discrete-time and continuous-time robust incident forecasting. We evaluate our algorithms on two different real-world datasets, demonstrating that our approach is significantly more robust than conventional methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>