<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Strategies to Edit Production Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/strategies-to-edit-production-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Editing data in a production database is sometimes necessary. However, mistakes in running these queries can be disastrous. In this talk, you will learn strategies for making edits to a production database with examples from a Python stack that increase safety and auditability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, we all find ourselves at a SQL prompt making edits to the production database. We know it’s a bad practice and we always intend to put in place safer infrastructure before we need to do it again — what does a better system actually look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk progresses through 5 strategies for teams using a Python stack to do SQL writes against a database, to achieve increasing safety and auditability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a process for raw SQL edits (2) Run scripts locally (3) Run scripts on an existing server (4) Use a task runner (5) Build a Script Runner service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about the pros and cons of each strategy and help you determine which one is right for your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk you’ll be ready to start upgrading your infrastructure for making changes to your production database safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julie Qiu&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julie Qiu</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-24:djangocon-europe-2018/strategies-to-edit-production-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Strategies to Edit Production Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/strategies-to-edit-production-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At some point, we all find ourselves at a SQL prompt making edits to the production database. We know it's a bad practice and we always intend to put in place safer infrastructure before we need to do it again — what does a better system actually look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk progresses through 5 strategies for teams using a Python stack to do SQL writes against a database, to achieve increasing safety and auditability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a process for raw SQL edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run scripts locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy and run scripts on an existing server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a task runner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a Script Runner service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about the pros and cons of each strategy and help you determine which one is right for your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk you’ll be ready to start upgrading your infrastructure for making changes to your production database safely!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julie Qiu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/strategies-to-edit-production-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Build a Search Engine with Python + Elasticsearch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/build-a-search-engine-with-python-elasticsearch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most common actions that we take when visiting any website is search. A common service that powers search for many sites is Elasticsearch -  but what makes it so powerful? What can you do with Elasticsearch that you can’t with a regular database?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial starts with an introduction to Elasticsearch architecture, including what makes it great for search and not so great for other use cases. We will then build an application together with a search engine powered by Elasticsearch. We will also discuss how to optimize search queries and scale as the volume of data increases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julie Qiu</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-09:pycon-us-2018/build-a-search-engine-with-python-elasticsearch.html</guid><category>elasticsearch</category></item></channel></rss>