<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kim Jun-ki</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kim-jun-ki.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Migrating large Python projects to a monorepo using Pantsbuild</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/migrating-large-python-projects-to-a-monorepo-using-pantsbuild.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Jun-ki</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-02:/pycon-korea-2022/migrating-large-python-projects-to-a-monorepo-using-pantsbuild.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session introduces the process of migrating the Backend.AI open source project to a mono-repo using the Pantsbuild tool. The Backend.AI project is written with over 74,000 lines of Python code accumulated over 7 years, and has a code base with considerable complexity that requires combining …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session introduces the process of migrating the Backend.AI open source project to a mono-repo using the Pantsbuild tool. The Backend.AI project is written with over 74,000 lines of Python code accumulated over 7 years, and has a code base with considerable complexity that requires combining and installing multiple packages to develop and test the overall function. As the number of project participants increased and the internal code became more complex, managing the repository by package unit became a bottleneck in the development process, and to overcome this problem, we considered and decided to introduce a mono-repo. Although a mono-repo is not always the right answer in all cases, we considered various conditions such as the size of the development team, the current and expected complexity of internal dependencies, the way the organization operates, the scope of the impact of code changes, the release cycle, and the limitations of the project board function of GitHub, an issue management tool, and we thought it was a reasonable transition at this point. In particular, the process of writing and reviewing multiple pull requests in multiple repositories to resolve a single issue significantly increased the context switching overhead of developers, and there were repeated problems of forgetting to write pull requests for specific repositories or forgetting to unify branches, leading to errors. In the process of converting to a monorepo, Pantsbuild was introduced to explicitly and automatically manage internal and external dependencies as much as possible. Pantsbuild is a modern build tool that primarily supports the Python ecosystem, and it supports powerful caching and parallel execution of build and CI-related tasks. In this presentation, we will introduce how we merged existing Backend.AI repositories to enable seamless use of Pantsbuild, and the process of adapting to Pantsbuild by writing Pantsbuild plugins and responding to Backend.AI's dynamic module loading mechanism. We will also explain additional problems that the development team encountered after the basic migration and how we dealt with them. We hope that this session will provide you with examples and hints on configuring a monorepo for a large-scale Python project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Development Method with Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Improving Debuggability of Complex Asyncio Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/improving-debuggability-of-complex-asyncio-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Jun-ki</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/improving-debuggability-of-complex-asyncio-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important thing in debugging is observability and reproducibility. Despite the steady improvement of the asyncio standard library, it is still difficult to look inside a complex asyncio application at a production level. Especially when multiple 3rd-party libraries and frameworks that I cannot control are running, it is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important thing in debugging is observability and reproducibility. Despite the steady improvement of the asyncio standard library, it is still difficult to look inside a complex asyncio application at a production level. Especially when multiple 3rd-party libraries and frameworks that I cannot control are running, it is very difficult to debug resource issues caused by silently swallowed cancellation signals or arbitrarily created callbacks and coroutine tasks inside some external code. Moreover, these problems tend to occur only in production environments with actual workloads, rather than in development environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we present the aiomonitor-ng library, which is an improved version of the previously released aiomonitor library. The existing library helped to look inside the currently running asyncio process based on a simple telnet server and REPL, and it also helped in actual production debugging. However, after using it for more than a year, I realized that there were some features that were lacking, and I personally added various features, including the ability to directly trace the stack chain of task creation, cancellation, and termination. I also added a terminal UI with auto-completion for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using aiomonitor and the improved aiomonitor-ng, I was able to discover and analyze many production issues in practice. I hope you can use this experience to create more stable asyncio applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Jun-ki
He is currently the CTO of Lablup (&amp;quot;Lablup&amp;quot;), developing Backend.AI, and has experience in analyzing and implementing backend systems of various sizes. He has contributed to projects such as Textcube, iPuTTY, CPython, DPDK, pyzmq, aiodocker, and aiohttp through open source activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry></feed>