<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Dave Klein</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dave-klein.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Event-driven microservices with Python and Apache Kafka</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/event-driven-microservices-with-python-and-apache-kafka.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Klein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/event-driven-microservices-with-python-and-apache-kafka.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Event-driven microservices with Python and Apache Kafka - presented by Dave Klein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building distributed systems can be challenging, and that's what microservices are. With traditional request/response based architectures, it is easy to end up with services that are tightly coupled, making them …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Event-driven microservices with Python and Apache Kafka - presented by Dave Klein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building distributed systems can be challenging, and that's what microservices are. With traditional request/response based architectures, it is easy to end up with services that are tightly coupled, making them difficult to maintain and extend independently. While not a silver bullet, an event-based architecture makes it easier to maintain loose coupling. It also makes it easier to extend and evolve our systems without resorting to a rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we will look at an example of an event-driven microservices application and discuss some things to consider when adopting this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Event-Driven Microservices with Flask and Apache Kafka</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2022/event-driven-microservices-with-flask-and-apache-kafka.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Klein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-21:/pytexas-2022/event-driven-microservices-with-flask-and-apache-kafka.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementing complex systems with microservices can be a great decision, but if we’re not careful we can end up with a distributed monolith. Let’s see how to avoid that by building lightweight, loosely coupled microservices with the Flask framework and Apache Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dave Klein
After 28 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementing complex systems with microservices can be a great decision, but if we’re not careful we can end up with a distributed monolith. Let’s see how to avoid that by building lightweight, loosely coupled microservices with the Flask framework and Apache Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dave Klein
After 28 years as a developer, architect, project manager (recovered), author, trainer, conference organizer, and homeschooling dad, Dave Klein landed his dream job as a developer advocate at Confluent. Dave is marveling in and eager to help others explore the amazing world of event streaming with Apache Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Real-time Event Streaming with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/real-time-event-streaming-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Klein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/real-time-event-streaming-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Real-time Event Streaming with Python&amp;quot;
As real-time event streaming has become a necessity in many organizations, a plethora of libraries, frameworks, and applications have arisen to help meet that need. These different tools each have their own strengths and weaknesses, and you may end up deciding to use one …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Real-time Event Streaming with Python&amp;quot;
As real-time event streaming has become a necessity in many organizations, a plethora of libraries, frameworks, and applications have arisen to help meet that need. These different tools each have their own strengths and weaknesses, and you may end up deciding to use one or more of them, but many problems can be solved with a simpler approach.
Speaker: Dave Klein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 29 years as a developer, architect, project manager (recovered), author, trainer, conference organizer, and homeschooling dad, Dave Klein landed his dream job as a developer advocate at Confluent. Dave is marveling in and eager to help others explore the amazing world of event streaming with Apache Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2023"></category></entry></feed>