<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unit testing in the Scientific Python stack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2016/unit-testing-in-the-scientific-python-stack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unit testing in the Scientific Python stack by Antti Kaihola&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing unit tests for algorithms and data processing pipelines poses challenges distinct from those in the web or desktop application domain. A key reason for poor unit test coverage is that writing tests is hard and laborious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show some real-life unit test scenarios from Eniram along with tools we have developed to ease writing good tests. Many of the presented techniques also apply in other domains besides data processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics will include some or all of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;short overview of NumPy and Pandas testing tools
Eniram's testing tools for
asserting vector data
enhanced parametrized tests
two-dimensional parametrized tests
asserting mixed values and exceptions
readable diffs for text block assertions
discovery of configurations and input data for running data processing tests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author: Antti Kaihola is a Python developer working in the Infrastructure team at Eniram. He's been with Python for 17 years, first for web development and scripting before moving into data processing. Building a platform for data processing using great Open Source components keeps Antti and his colleagues busy at work. At home, he occasionally spices family life with a microcontroller here and some MicroPython there, or encourages his kids to experiment with programming and robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antti Kaihola</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-31:pycon-finland-2016/unit-testing-in-the-scientific-python-stack.html</guid></item></channel></rss>