<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Auxten Wang</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_auxten-wang.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>chDB: The Blazing Fast SQL Engine for Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/chdb-the-blazing-fast-sql-engine-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Auxten Wang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/chdb-the-blazing-fast-sql-engine-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chDB: The Blazing Fast SQL Engine for Data Science by Auxten Wang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/chdb-the-blazing-fast-sql-engine-for-data-science"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/chdb-the-blazing-fast-sql-engine-for-data-science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chDB, powered by the robust ClickHouse engine, is a high-performance in-process SQL engine designed for the Python data ecosystem. It supports direct interaction with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chDB: The Blazing Fast SQL Engine for Data Science by Auxten Wang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/chdb-the-blazing-fast-sql-engine-for-data-science"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/chdb-the-blazing-fast-sql-engine-for-data-science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chDB, powered by the robust ClickHouse engine, is a high-performance in-process SQL engine designed for the Python data ecosystem. It supports direct interaction with databases like MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, and MongoDB; streaming platforms such as Kafka; and key-value stores like Redis. With extensive support for various data sources and formats, chDB is highly adaptable to different data environments. It seamlessly integrates with structured formats like CSV and JSON as well as complex binary formats such as Parquet, Avro, and Arrow, enabling efficient data manipulation and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engine is ANSI SQL compliant, ensuring broad compatibility with existing SQL codebases and facilitating easy integration into diverse data pipelines. This comprehensive SQL support includes complex querying capabilities, enhancing the engine's utility in sophisticated data analysis tasks. chDB is particularly designed to accommodate the rapid prototyping of applications, allowing developers to transition smoothly and quickly from development to production environments with minimal adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its deep integration into Python, chDB interacts directly with popular Python libraries such as Pandas, NumPy, and others, streamlining the data science workflow. This integration enables direct data manipulation within Python scripts and notebooks, drastically reducing the need for data movement and conversion, thus accelerating the data analytics process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For organizations and developers leveraging Python, chDB offers an unmatched combination of performance, flexibility, and ease of use, making it an invaluable tool for building efficient, scalable, and robust data-driven applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry></feed>