<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jens-nie.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Empowered by Python - A success story</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/empowered-by-python-a-success-story.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jens Nie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/empowered-by-python-a-success-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jens Nie, Peer Wagner&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;jneines)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jens works primarily as a Technology Scout focusing on Big Data and Data Science at the ROSEN Technology &amp;amp; Research Center in Lingen, Germany. In this role he screens for latest developments in these areas and evaluates and demonstrates their possible use and benefit for the company. Looking back to more than 20 years in using Python and Linux, he considers him to be an Open Source enthusiast and committed Python advocate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing a new programming language in a company is always a daring task, usually involving a lot of effort and the will for change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to take you on a journey reflecting eight years of challenges, solutions and success ending in a best practice guide helping you to achieve the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROSEN is most recognized as a technology leader in the pipeline inspection business. To steadily achieve the best in class service for our customers, we are building and using the most sophisticated tools in the industry to perform the inspection services. This often results in very large volumes of data which have to be handled and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, we were always out to search for the latest technology and state of the art tools to aid us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a point where the most traditionally used tools for data analysis no longer scaled a handful of pioneers were brave enough to introduce a massive change in the scientific tool chain. This involved to address driving laboratory equipment, data processing, analysis and display, handling large volumes of data efficiently, building attractive graphical user interfaces, integrate with existing software applications and prepare for modern data analysis concepts based on machine learning to ensure both increasing result quality and faster data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've found Python to be the ideal foundation to achieve all this and started off with a few initial projects in order to prove. It turned out Python would be a real game changer for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="use-case"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Scale out from the very beginning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2017/scale-out-from-the-very-beginning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jens Nie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-06:pydata-london-2017/scale-out-from-the-very-beginning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Filmed at PyData London 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Most companies a very well aware of the potential behind Big Data solutions today and happily start collecting every piece of information building huge pools of Dark Data. How could Data Science teams create an initial overview on what's available? A simple search strategy, optimised and refined to scale could be a promising way to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In this talk the authors journey of making the pool of Dark Data available to teams with quite different goals is reflected, emphasising on creating a simple and robust set of tools matching each other and addressing the several needs of the teams based mainly on solutions such as dask distributed, dask based dataframes, bokeh and flask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to success was to prevent structuring too much at the very beginning and postpone this task into the several projects of the users consuming the results of these services giving them the freedom to create and use their own models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is shown how we implemented a distributed filesystem scanning utility to crawl for data in our 1.5 PB storage system every night ending up in a simple, yet useful table of contents, and how this result set is processed further to fulfill all the project teams requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These services are for example used to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;find expensive duplicates of datasets
create customer as well as product and service orientated views on the available data
find data suitable to test algorithms, software and procedures, and to derive current performance
serve training and education material
show the usage frequency of the datasets to support an optimised data tiering process
Finally the involved procedures helped to gain more awareness of the value the available data had, both helping to build more trust in Big Data based solutions and to reduce the volume of the data itself that is available online, which in turn keeps the corresponding costs at a reasonable rate.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>