<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Matteo Interlandi</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning Talk: Tensor Query Processing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-tensor-query-processing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The huge demand for computation in artificial intelligence (AI) is driving unparalleled investments in new hardware and software systems for AI. This leads to an explosion in the number of specialized hardware devices, which are now part of the offerings of major cloud providers. Meanwhile, by hiding the low-level complexity through a tensor-based interface, machine learning frameworks such as PyTorch allow data scientists to efficiently exploit the exciting capabilities offered by the new hardware. In this talk, we will present how databases can ride the wave of innovation happening in the AI space thanks to Tensor Query Processor (TQP): a SQL query processor leveraging the tensor interface of PyTorch. TQP can efficiently run the full TPC-H benchmark by implementing novel algorithms for executing relational operators on the specialized tensor routines provided by PyTorch. Meanwhile, TQP can target various hardware while only requiring a fraction of the usual development effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matteo Interlandi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-tensor-query-processing.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2023</category><category>Lightning Talk</category></item><item><title>ML.NET in Python with NimbusML</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/mlnet-in-python-with-nimbusml.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ML.NET is an open source, cross-platform, machine learning framework for .NET developers. ML.NET was originally developed in Microsoft Research and is now used across many products in Microsoft such as Windows, Bing, and PowerPoint. This talk introduces NimbusML, which brings the ML.NET library to Python. With NimbusML, developers familiar with the Scikit-learn API can start to take advantage of ML.NET performance just with few simple changes to their Scikit pipeline. The talk will also cover differentiators, such as NimbusML support for streaming datasets that don’t fit in memory, and featurizers/algorithms not easily available elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matteo Interlandi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/scipy-2019/mlnet-in-python-with-nimbusml.html</guid><category>SciPy 2019</category></item></channel></rss>