<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lumír Balhar</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python’s Journey: From Upstream to Enterprise</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/pythons-journey-from-upstream-to-enterprise.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — North Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python’s Journey: From Upstream to Enterprise by Lumír Balhar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pythons-journey-from-upstream-to-enterprise"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pythons-journey-from-upstream-to-enterprise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how Python gets from the first alpha version upstream to years of stability in your enterprise Linux systems? And what products and useful components are created for you along the way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Lumír will take you through the incredible journey of Python delivery from the first alpha version shipped to Fedora Linux a couple of days after the official upstream release, through containers developers can use for testing with many old and new Python releases in their CI, to Red Hat Enterprise Linux and its main and alternative Python application streams and containers with various Python versions ready to be deployed to production environments with years of required stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Lumír will talk about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python maintainers’ focus on speed of delivery in Fedora and stability and reliability in RHEL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use containers based on Fedora for early adoption of new Pythons in CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What challenges do we face during ten years of maintenance of old Python interpreters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and learn how you can benefit from our efforts, use a modern development environment, and deploy your apps with guaranteed stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lumír Balhar</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/pythons-journey-from-upstream-to-enterprise.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>How we started teaching Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/how-we-started-teaching-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Helping people feels great. As a volunteer firefighter, Lumir can
tell you all about that feeling. But there are also other ways to
help others, and some don't involve life-or-death situations. What
about changing a person's life by teaching them how to program?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching doesn't just give you a great feeling. It can also help you
make new friends, improve your presentation skills, and even make you
a better programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for two stories of how we started teaching Python, what it
means for us, what it can mean for you – and how we're making it
easier for you to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Petr Viktorin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:/pycon-cz-2017/how-we-started-teaching-python.html</guid><category>PyCon CZ 2017</category></item></channel></rss>