<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kim Soo-bin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kim-soo-bin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Nix for Python Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/nix-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Soo-bin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/nix-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will briefly introduce Nix for Python developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will first introduce the problems I have experienced in the Python environment, then I will introduce what Nix is, and how to set up a Python development environment using Nix. I will also briefly introduce how to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will briefly introduce Nix for Python developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will first introduce the problems I have experienced in the Python environment, then I will introduce what Nix is, and how to set up a Python development environment using Nix. I will also briefly introduce how to package Python packages and build OCI container images. Finally, I will share my personal experiences and reviews from using Nix for several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this session will be helpful to those who are experiencing the same problems as I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Soobin
I am Kim Soobin, who is developing backend and platforms using Python at Viva Republica. I am working with Python developers on the team and am thinking about a more convenient and consistent development environment and deployment environment, and I would like to share my experiences. There are many shortcomings, but I will prepare well :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Monorepo with Rye</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/monorepo-with-rye.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kim Soo-bin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/monorepo-with-rye.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the approach of operating a monorepo for various libraries and services in a Python project.
In the process, the team adopted Rye as their package manager, and the presentation will also cover the features of Rye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply approaching a monorepo might unnecessarily increase complexity, so the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the approach of operating a monorepo for various libraries and services in a Python project.
In the process, the team adopted Rye as their package manager, and the presentation will also cover the features of Rye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply approaching a monorepo might unnecessarily increase complexity, so the speaker will share methods the team considered and implemented to prevent this while maximizing the benefits. The speaker will also introduce their personal experience in building and operating monorepos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is recommended for those who need to build shared libraries using Python or operate multiple services in an MSA environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category><category term="library"></category><category term="core"></category></entry></feed>