<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pascal-van-kooten.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>When to use Machine Learning: Tips, Tricks and Warnings</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/when-to-use-machine-learning-tips-tricks-and-warnings.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pascal van Kooten</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/when-to-use-machine-learning-tips-tricks-and-warnings.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence, and machine learning in particular, is one of
the hottest topics in tech/business. I will explain the core of machine
learning, and the main goal of this talk will be to help you judge the
success whenever someone yells “I know! let’s solve this using machine
learning!”. I will also provide tips and tricks on how to increase the
success of such projects. The second part of the talk will be about 2
open-source python projects I’ve created, as well as a project I’m
working on regarding the trading of cryptocurrency… and their relation
to machine learning. Specifically, the challenges and findings in making
these cases work will be explored.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>DeepCare Chatbot - Generating answers to customers using Deep Learning and NLP</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-barcelona-2017/deepcare-chatbot-generating-answers-to-customers-using-deep-learning-and-nlp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-20T15:45:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-20T15:45:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Pascal van Kooten</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pydata-barcelona-2017/deepcare-chatbot-generating-answers-to-customers-using-deep-learning-and-nlp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DeepCare chatbot is capable of learning to answer customer questions. Using a hybrid approach of NLP and Deep Learning, it tries to combat logical fallacies that occur in pure deep learning bots, while still coming up with unique answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, it uses a sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) long-short-term-memory LSTM deep learning model to capture intricacies in questions. As organisations cannot afford a bot making logical mistakes, verification through NLP is used. This two-step model prevents the downside of &amp;quot;no control&amp;quot; on deep learning, as well as the too static nature of classical rule based NLP models, and thus enables potentially higher quality answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A live demo will be available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://deepcare.online"&gt;http://deepcare.online&lt;/a&gt; on the day of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="chatbot"></category><category term="nlp"></category><category term="deep learning"></category></entry></feed>