<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keeping the Lights on with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/keeping-the-lights-on-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scott Reeve - Keeping the Lights on with Python
[EuroPython 2016]
[19 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keeping-the-lights-on-with-python"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keeping-the-lights-on-with-python&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using Python to help the National Grid in the UK to balance
electricity production and usage. We do this by installing Python
powered devices at customers sites that allow us to monitor and set
control criteria to automatically turn on and off power consuming and
producing devices when there is a mismatch between electricity supply
and demand.
In this talk we will be talking about how and why we have used Python,
as well as where in our system we would like to use Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using Python to help the National Grid in the UK to balance
electricity production and usage. We do this by installing Python
powered devices at customers sites that allow us to monitor and set
control criteria to automatically turn on and off power consuming and
producing devices when there is a mismatch between electricity supply
and demand. These devices talk to our Python powered cloud based
system using the 3g network, giving us near real-time monitoring of
our customers assets.
Our entire infrastructure is written in Python, from our billing
systems, data analytics systems and customer portal all the way
through to our on site industrial system interfaces. In this talk we
will be talking about how and why we have used Python, where we have
had problems, as well as where in our system we would like to use
Python and why we cannot.  We will also be talking about what we are
going to do next, moving our system from near real time monitoring to
near real-time control, using Python for both system modelling and
control. We will discuss how we are using Python to creating a system
that monitors the balance between electricity supply and demand many
times per second and is able to provide a corrective control based on
the sum of the output of a dynamic set of our customer sites and the
challenges that presents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scott Reeve</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/keeping-the-lights-on-with-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>