<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kyle-chard.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Parsl: Enabling Scalable Interactive Computing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/parsl-enabling-scalable-interactive-computing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Chard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/parsl-enabling-scalable-interactive-computing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists and engineers like to use Python for interactive data
science, machine learning, and online computing. However, computations
that are simple to perform at small scales (e.g., on a laptop) can
easily become prohibitively difficult as data sizes and analysis
complexity grows. For example, efficient interactive analysis at scale
can require real-time management of parallel and/or cloud computing
resources, orchestration of remote task execution, and data staging
across wide area networks. In this talk we introduce Parsl (Parallel
Scripting Library), a pure Python library for orchestrating the
concurrent and parallel execution of interactive and many-task
workloads, and demonstrate how it integrates with the scientific Python
ecosystem and how it is being used in a variety of scientific domains.
The talk is intended for attendees interested in interactive and
parallel computing.Presenter(s): Speaker: Kyle Chard, Computation
Institute, University of Chicago and Argonne National Lab Speaker: Yadu
Babuji, University of Chicago Speaker: Ian Foster, University of Chicago
and Argonne National Laboratory Speaker: Daniel Katz, University of
Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Speaker: Mike Wilde, University of Chicago
Speaker: Anna Woodard, University of Chicago Speaker: Justin Wozniak,
Argonne National Laboratory&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>