<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>TDD mikroserwisów</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2016/tdd-mikroserwisow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Propozycja tego, jak można tworzyć mikroserwisy w Pythonie zakładając
pisanie testów najpierw, a dopiero potem właściwego kodu. Na każdym
etapie pracy. Żadne pseudo-TDD.Skupię się na testach funkcjonalnych
badających całych proces aplikacji z zewnątrz (pomogą w tym Docker i
Pytest) oraz testach kontraktowych pilnujących, że nikt w trakcie
developmentu nie zmienił zewnętrznych interfejsów naszej aplikacji. W
drugim przypadku wykorzystany będzie Swagger.Przykłady nie będą polegać
na silnej integracji z żadnym webowym frameworkiem. Poruszę też kwestię
mierzenia pokrycia testowego w nieco bardziej skomplikowanych
przypadkach (jak testy funkcjonalne).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Bultrowicz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-15:pycon-pl-2016/tdd-mikroserwisow.html</guid></item><item><title>Python microservices on PaaS done right</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/python-microservices-on-paas-done-right.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michał Bultrowicz - Python microservices on PaaS done right
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, there's a lot of talk about microservices but not enough
concrete examples and case studies. I want to change that by showing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how thinking in PaaS terms can lead to robust and scalable designs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what infrastructure and automation you need to set up to go along smoothly;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to get real time metrics of your apps;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what makes Python good for microservices;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is Python's performance relative to some alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites for the talk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some experience with web development in Python;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic knowledge of RESTful web services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Bultrowicz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-02:europython-2015/python-microservices-on-paas-done-right.html</guid></item><item><title>TDD of Python microservices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/tdd-of-python-microservices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michał Bultrowicz - TDD of Python microservices
[EuroPython 2016]
[22 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/tdd-of-python-microservices"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/tdd-of-python-microservices&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A framework-agnostic approach to creating Python microservices with a
tests-first approach.
I'll show how to utilize Docker and Swagger to create service and
contract tests that run your service as an independent process, as if
it was running in production, giving you and your team a higher degree
of confidence when introducing changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little bit of a broader microservice, TDD and work management
context will also be given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be my ideas on how to help a microservice-based (HTTP)
project by integrating testing into the development process (TDD).
I'll approach the testing pyramid presented in Martin Fowler's
&amp;quot;Microservice Testing&amp;quot; as well as the test variants in &amp;quot;Building
Microservices&amp;quot; (O'Reilly) and I'll show a way of how they can be
translated to real-life Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main focus will be on &amp;quot;service tests&amp;quot; (aka. out-of-process
component tests) and contract tests. They both can be run relatively
fast on a development machine and can give fast feedback to the
developer, preventing many kinds of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service tests run the whole application process without any internal
modifications, but have to present the service with a fake &amp;quot;outside
world&amp;quot;. I'll show how to fake external HTTP services with Mountebank
(similar to WireMock). Instead of faking other systems (like
databases) we can quickly spin up the real deal as a Docker container
from within the tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contract tests check if the contract (interface) of your service with
the outside world is kept, so no external services should be broken by
the changes you are introducing. It can also work the other way
around, proving that your collaborators are keeping their part of the
deal. In both cases, Swagger (a RESTful API description scheme) and a
few clever tricks can be used for significant advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Bultrowicz</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/tdd-of-python-microservices.html</guid></item></channel></rss>