<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Valerie Shoskes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_valerie-shoskes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How a popular MMORPG made me a better developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/how-a-popular-mmorpg-made-me-a-better-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valerie Shoskes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/how-a-popular-mmorpg-made-me-a-better-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - How a popular MMORPG made me a better developer - presented by Valerie Shoskes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will have special meaning for Final Fantasy fans, but anyone with nerdy non-coding hobbies should be able to enjoy it. The intended outcome is for attendees to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - How a popular MMORPG made me a better developer - presented by Valerie Shoskes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will have special meaning for Final Fantasy fans, but anyone with nerdy non-coding hobbies should be able to enjoy it. The intended outcome is for attendees to see their own hobbies in a new light, where they can find their own abstract lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MMO gaming is becoming a more mainstream hobby, and as a lifelong gamer, I have plenty of experiences and stories to share on how the genre helped my transformation from a shy bundle of nerves to a confident professional. I also have experience applying my problem solving skills from software development into solutions for the community to combat problems that arose within the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>