<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lukas-hurych.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hacking and social engineering with a 70% success rate</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-estonia-2019/hacking-and-social-engineering-with-a-70-success-rate.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lukáš Hurych</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-03:pycon-estonia-2019/hacking-and-social-engineering-with-a-70-success-rate.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lukáš is a product/marketing guy with a development background (Python is his biggest love but he went through Ruby, PHP, Swift, Javascript, Java). Studying psychology gave him a great knowledge of marketing, but the combination with Python is a killer for phishing, writing malware, hacking and all the fun stuff. He's doing all of this just as a hobby trying to test and protect his company and his team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get tickets for PyCon Estonia 2020 - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bit.ly/pycon2020"&gt;https://bit.ly/pycon2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is nearing 3 decades in existence (yes, kinda hard to believe). Where do we go from here? We have the same question, hence PyCon 2019 will be a peek into the future of Python. Come, hang out with an inspired crowd, have rich, direct conversations and who knows, maybe you’ll even find an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.ee"&gt;https://pycon.ee&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConEstonia"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConEstonia&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/vaba-lava/pycon-estonia-2019/318811955508926/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/vaba-lava/pycon-estonia-2019/318811955508926/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dark Python: Social engineering and hacking with 70% success rate</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2018/dark-python-social-engineering-and-hacking-with-70-success-rate.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lukáš Hurych</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-03:pycon-cz-2018/dark-python-social-engineering-and-hacking-with-70-success-rate.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the course of the last few years I launched a lot of different attacks in our company (60+ teammates) and with some of them, I had a success rate of 70%. From getting people’s Facebook accounts or access to their LastPass accounts to custom written malware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The threat that anyone can steal your customer data is a potential killer of any (financial) company. Being suspicious and aware of all potential phishing attacks and other traps is a must.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will look at the practical (dark) examples I have executed and why Python was the best language of choice. From social engineering (sophisticated phishing attacks), custom malware, dropping nasty USB drives on the street to technical/network attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to be really successful in doing social engineering you need to prepare the ultimate user experience. You can not make a mistake and you can not overlook little details (that usually happens if you develop your own apps/websites). Those little details make UX in your app/website awesome (if you are on the good side) but can be exploited pretty easily by the dark side.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="social engineering"></category></entry></feed>