<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_charles-merriam.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>BayPiggies January 2017 talk at LinkedIn: A Journey through Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/baypiggies-january-2017-talk-at-linkedin-a-journey-through-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Charles Merriam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-01-26:bay-piggies/baypiggies-january-2017-talk-at-linkedin-a-journey-through-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Charles Merriam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Python&amp;quot; encompasses a huge knowledge area of internals, libraries, tools, and philosophy. This talk maps the knowledge touching on the Zen of Python, decorators, dunders, Django, Jupyter and more. You will learn something new and map how Python fits together as a coherent whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Merriam has presented to BayPiggies and PyCon many times over the years, including a 2007 talk on this same subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor's note: this talk is really great. If you are a beginner, you will learn a lot about how to wrap your head around the Python language and ecosystem. If you are an experienced Python developer, the talk will leave you with renewed enthusiasm for Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Decorators From Basics to Class Decorators to Decorator Libraries (#138)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--decorators-from-basics-to-class-decor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Charles Merriam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--decorators-from-basics-to-class-decor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decorators from Basics to Class Decorators to Decorator Libraries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Charles Merriam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decorators simplify design and improve readability and reliability. This
tutorial starts from the beginning with basic decorators, showing how
simple tasks like restricting administration functions are clearer and
more readable with decorators, and exactly how the decorators work. A
simple library of decorators for tracing, logging, and caching results
is presented. This leads into writing your own decorators and
parameterized decorators either from scratch or by using libraries like
Simionato's Decorator Decorator and &amp;quot;&amp;#64;call_before(fn)&amp;quot;. Finally, using
Python 3.x class decorators in place of metaclasses for most common
dictionary modifications is covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Missing about 1 minute at start, because of technical
problems.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="decorators"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category></entry></feed>