<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building PCI compliant Django applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2012/building-pci-compliant-django-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you currently accept credit cards with your Django application today,
or you plan on accepting them in the future, then you will need to worry
about PCI DSS. Learn what you need to do to make sure that your
application is PCI DSS compliant, and if it is not, what you need to do
to bring it into compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PCI DSS is a set of twelve different security standards that are
required for any organization that handles credit or debit card
transactions. These standards are created by the Payment Card Industry
Security Standards Council and they require all organizations to
validate that they are compliant every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these rules and how they effect you is sometimes a
daunting task. The goals of this talk will be the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain PCI DSS, and quickly go over the rules that will effect your
application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show how to securely handle credit card transactions in your Django
application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storing credit card information isn't ideal, but if you need to, I'll
explain the different ways to securely store the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go over the different ways to limit your PCI DSS liability
(BrianTree, Akamai Edge Tokenization, Auth.net CIM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore the different tools you will need in order validate your PCI
compliance (Web application scans, IDS, Network Scan, firewalls)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to be PCI Complaint in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll close out the talk with some of the details on how I haver
personally satisfied PCI DSS Requirements on my projects in the past.
I'll cover some of the tools and services that I used, and why I decided
to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the conclusion of the talk you should have a better understanding of
PCI DSS, and what you need to do, in order for your Django application
to be certified as compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ken Cochrane</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-06:djangocon-us-2012/building-pci-compliant-django-applications.html</guid><category>django</category><category>pci-complicance</category></item><item><title>Django and Docker: a Marriage Made in Heaven</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/django-and-docker-a-marriage-made-in-heaven.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django and Docker: a Marriage Made in Heaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 11:30 a.m.--12:15 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker is a new tool that makes it easy to bundle and deploy your
applications to any host running Docker. In this talk I'll show you how
to get started with Docker, and how to use it to deploy your Django apps
to your different server environments. Abstract Overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to show you how you can use Docker to make your
life easier when developing Django apps. Developing Django apps is fun,
but there is a lot of other stuff you need to do in your day to day
work, that isn't fun. Let me show you how to let Docker help you make
those tasks more fun, and take less time, so you can get back to doing
the stuff you love. Outline: Intro to docker for the people who have
never heard of it. Show how easy it is to setup a docker server Explain
a little how docker works under the covers. Go over the steps that are
needed to convert a django application to use docker Show how easy it is
to deploy your newly converted docker application to any number of
docker servers (EC2, Rackspace, digital Ocean, local server, etc) with a
few easy commands. Go over the different use cases for using Docker in
your development environment (testing, deployment, etc) Questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ken Cochrane</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-01:djangocon-us-2013/django-and-docker-a-marriage-made-in-heaven.html</guid></item></channel></rss>