<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dr-ing-ratnani-ahmed.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Pyccel, a Fortran static compiler for scientific High-Performance Computing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/pyccel-a-fortran-static-compiler-for-scientific-high-performance-computing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Ing. Ratnani Ahmed</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/pyccel-a-fortran-static-compiler-for-scientific-high-performance-computing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pyccel&lt;/em&gt; is a new &lt;strong&gt;static compiler&lt;/strong&gt; for Python that uses &lt;strong&gt;Fortran&lt;/strong&gt;
as backend language while enabling High-Performance Computing &lt;strong&gt;HPC&lt;/strong&gt;
capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran is a computer language for scientific programming that is
tailored for efficient run-time execution on a wide variety of
processors. Even if the &lt;em&gt;2003&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;2008&lt;/em&gt; standards added major
improvements like &lt;em&gt;OOP, Coarrays, Submodules, do concurrent&lt;/em&gt; , etc ...
they are not covered by all available compilers. Moreover, the Fortran
developer still suffers from the lack of &lt;strong&gt;meta-programming&lt;/strong&gt; compared
to &lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt; ones. Therefore, it is more and more difficult for applied
mathematicians and computational physicists to write applications at the
&lt;em&gt;state of art&lt;/em&gt; (targeting CPUs, GPUs, MICs) while implementing
complicated algorithms or numerical schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyccel can be used in two cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to achieve the second point, we developed an internal DSL for
&lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;macros&lt;/em&gt;. The later is used to map sentences based on
&lt;em&gt;mpi4py&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;scipy.linalg.blas or lapack&lt;/em&gt; onto the appropriate calls in
Fortran. Moreover, two parsers, for &lt;em&gt;OpenMP&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;OpenACC&lt;/em&gt; , were added
too, allowing for explicit parallelism through the use of pragmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, Pyccel is an extension of &lt;strong&gt;Sympy&lt;/strong&gt;. Actually, it
converts a Python code to symbolic expressions/trees, from a Full Syntax
Tree ( &lt;em&gt;RedBaron&lt;/em&gt; ), then annotates the new AST using types or different
settings provided by the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, after a brief description of Pyccel, I will show different
applications including Finite Elements (1d, 2d, 3d), Semi-Lagrangian
schemes (4d), Kronecker linear solvers, diagnostics for 5D kinetic
simulations and Machine Learning for Partial Differential Equations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Astronomy"></category><category term="Parallel Programming"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Science"></category></entry></feed>