<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Samapriya Roy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_samapriya-roy.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Hands-on Satellite Imagery Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/hands-on-satellite-imagery-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Samapriya Roy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:/scipy-2019/hands-on-satellite-imagery-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Satellite data is more widely available than ever before, and it is now possible for the public to access sub-weekly and even daily imagery of the Earth's entire landmass. In this tutorial, gain hands-on experience exploring Planet’s publicly-available satellite imagery and using Python tools for geospatial and time-series …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Satellite data is more widely available than ever before, and it is now possible for the public to access sub-weekly and even daily imagery of the Earth's entire landmass. In this tutorial, gain hands-on experience exploring Planet’s publicly-available satellite imagery and using Python tools for geospatial and time-series analysis of medium- and high-resolution imagery data. Using free &amp;amp; open source libraries, learn how to perform foundational imagery analysis techniques and apply these techniques to real satellite data. At the end of the workshop, we’ll demonstrate how the skills you've learned can be applied to investigate real-world environmental and humanitarian challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2019"></category><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Bridging the gap between Earth Engine and the Scientific Python Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/bridging-the-gap-between-earth-engine-and-the-scientific-python-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Qiusheng Wu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/bridging-the-gap-between-earth-engine-and-the-scientific-python-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine's new data extraction interfaces seamlessly transfer geospatial data into familiar Python formats provided by NumPy, Pandas, GeoPandas, and Xarray. This integration empowers you to harness Earth Engine's vast data catalog and compute power directly within your preferred Python workflows. For example, the Xee library leverages Xarray's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine's new data extraction interfaces seamlessly transfer geospatial data into familiar Python formats provided by NumPy, Pandas, GeoPandas, and Xarray. This integration empowers you to harness Earth Engine's vast data catalog and compute power directly within your preferred Python workflows. For example, the Xee library leverages Xarray's lazy evaluation and Dask to streamline the extraction and analysis of Earth Engine data, offering a more Pythonic alternative to traditional image exports. Earth Engine's new data extraction interfaces unlock fresh geospatial analysis potential by leveraging the unique strengths of both the scientific Python ecosystem and Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>