<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python on Mars</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-on-mars.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ezio Melotti</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/python-on-mars.html</guid><category>pytango</category><category>space suit tango</category><category>tango</category><category>mars</category><category>scientific-computing</category><category>neural network</category><category>space suit</category></item><item><title>Python su Marte</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-su-marte.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ezio Melotti</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/python-su-marte.html</guid><category>tango</category><category>scientific-computing</category><category>pytango</category><category>neural network</category><category>tuta spaziale</category></item><item><title>Python, Gravitational Waves and the Dawn of Multimessenger Astrophysics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/python-gravitational-waves-and-the-dawn-of-multimessenger-astrophysics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following a multi-year upgrade programme and several months of
commissioning, the Advanced Virgo detector joined the LIGO Observation
Run 2 (O2) data-taking period on the 1st of August 2017. On August 14,
Advanced LIGO and Advanced Virgo detected the first triple-coincident
merger of a binary black hole system, demonstrating the best-ever
localization of gravitational-wave source on the sky. Three days later,
the same detectors recorded for the first time the signal from a merger
of a binary neutron star system. Counterparts of the event were also
observed in all bands of the electromagnetic spectrum. This represents
the first time that a cosmic event has been viewed in both gravitational
waves and light and marks the beginning of multimessenger astrophysics.
In this talk I will present an overview on the Advanced Virgo detector
focusing on the role that it has played in this stream of discoveries
and on the challenges we are still facing on the current upgrade and
commissioning phases. I will also provide a general overview on the
different uses of Python within the Virgo Projects highlighting its
current use for the detector supervisory control automation, slow sample
rate data acquisition and control room user interfaces development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Franco Carbognani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/python-gravitational-waves-and-the-dawn-of-multimessenger-astrophysics.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and the Commissioning of the Advanced Virgo Gravitational Waves Detector</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-and-the-commissioning-of-the-advanced-virgo-gravitational-waves-detector.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the announcement of the first direct detection of gravitational
waves on February 2016, the Virgo Collaboration is thriving to complete
the integration and commissioning of the Advanced Virgo detector in
order to provide, as soon as possible, its decisive contribution to the
international network of gravitational wave detectors. Having at least
three detectors working simultaneously is essential for the localization
of the sources in the sky. In this talk I will present an overview on
the status of the Advanced Virgo detector highlighting the challenges
encountered during its commissioning and how Python is helping in facing
them in particular for the detector supervisory control automation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Franco Carbognani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/python-and-the-commissioning-of-the-advanced-virgo-gravitational-waves-detector.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and the Dawn of Gravitational-Wave Astronomy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ukraine-2016/python-and-the-dawn-of-gravitational-wave-astronomy.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Franco Carbognani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-24:pycon-ukraine-2016/python-and-the-dawn-of-gravitational-wave-astronomy.html</guid></item><item><title>V-ERAS: Un ambiente virtuale per l'esplorazione planetaria</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/v-eras-un-ambiente-virtuale-per-lesplorazione-planetaria.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European MaRs Analogue Station for Advanced Technologies Integration (ERAS -- www.erasproject.org) is a program spearheaded by the Italian Mars Society (IMS) which main goal is to provide an effective test bed for field operation studies in preparation for manned missions to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preliminarily to ERAS construction, IMS has started the development of an immersive Virtual Reality (VR) simulation of the Station (V-ERAS). The major advantage of such virtualization isthat it will be possible to undertake training sessions with a crew that can interact with its future environment before the actual station is built. This way a more effective design of the station and associated missions and a strong reduction of costs could be obtained. The main objective of this activity will be the achievement of adequate fidelity simulations and validation of the data obtained during the training sessions so that they can be used for the design of the station itself. Many ergonomics and human factors will be considered in the virtual model in order to be verified and validated before the actual ERAS habitat construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development effort is currently divided in three main activities: • ERAS Station simulation using an appropriate game engine supporting a virtual reality headset • Upper body and hands gestures tracking • Integration of an omnidirectional treadmill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant part of the software development associated to V-ERAS will be undertaken by international students within the Google Summer of Code 2014 (GSoC) program were IMS participate as mentor organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final goal will be the construction of a classroom in which four (or six, depending on the targeted crew size) VR stations will be installed and the definition of appropriate crew rotations in which different training sessions are performed. The availability of a single VR station prototype is targeted for September 2014 and multi-user integration, able to support four stations, should be ready for October/November 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is the language of choice for the project, and the presentation will explain how is it used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ezio Melotti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-25:pycon-italia-2014/v-eras-un-ambiente-virtuale-per-lesplorazione-planetaria.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and the Dawn of Gravitational-Wave Astronomy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2016/python-and-the-dawn-of-gravitational-wave-astronomy.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Franco Carbognani</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:pycon-italia-2016/python-and-the-dawn-of-gravitational-wave-astronomy.html</guid></item><item><title>V-ERAS-14: Una missione di esplorazione marziana in realtà virtuale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-una-missione-di-esplorazione-marziana.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;European MaRs Analogue Station for Advanced Technologies Integration
(ERAS) è un programma guidata dall’Italian Mars Society (IMS), il cui
obiettivo principale è fornire un ambiente di test per studiare
operazioni sul campo in preparazione a una missione su Marte. Prima
della sua costruzione, IMS ha iniziato lo sviluppo di una simulazione
immersiva in realtà virtuale (VR) della stazione ERAS (V-ERAS). Il setup
iniziale di V-ERAS si basa sui seguenti elementi chiave: - Simulazione
della stazione ERAS usando un virtual reality headset - Full body
tracking - Integrazione con un treadmill omnidirezionale - Supporto per
il monitoraggio della salute dei membri della crew - Supporto per utenti
multipli Fin dall’inizio, Python è stato una delle tecnologie chiave che
ci ha permesso di sviluppare il sistema, grazie anche a un team
internazionale di studenti che hanno partecipato con l’IMS a Google
Summer of Code. Nel Dicembre 2014, quattro astronauti virtuali hanno
condotto per una settimana un programma di simulazioni immersive in
realtà virtuale durante la prima missione V-ERAS (V-ERAS-14). La
presentazione mostrerà i risultati della missione V-ERAS-14,
integrandoli con il ruolo che Python ha avuto nel supportare
l’infrastruttura del progetto.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ezio Melotti</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-09:pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-una-missione-di-esplorazione-marziana.html</guid></item><item><title>V-ERAS-14: A Virtual Reality Mars Exploration Mission (in English)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-a-virtual-reality-mars-exploration-mis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation reports on the outcomes of the V-ERAS-14 Mission while
focusing on the integral role played by the Python language in
supporting the project infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European MaRs Analogue Station for Advanced Technologies Integration
(ERAS) is a program spearheaded by the Italian Mars Society (IMS), whose
main goal is to provide an effective test bed for field operation
studies in preparation for human missions to Mars. Preliminarily to its
construction, IMS has started the development of an immersive Virtual
Reality (VR) simulation of the ERAS Station (V-ERAS). The initial V-ERAS
setup has been based on the following key elements: - ERAS Station
simulation using an appropriate game engine supporting a virtual reality
headset - Full body tracking - Integration of an omnidirectional
treadmill - Support for the crew members’ health monitoring -
Multiplayer Support Since the beginning, Python has been one of the key
technologies that allowed us to develop the system, also thanks to a
team of international students that participated with the IMS to Google
Summer of Code. In December 2014, four virtual astronauts have conducted
a sustained program of immersive virtual reality simulations during the
first week-long V-ERAS Mission (V-ERAS-14). The presentation will report
on the outcomes of the V-ERAS-14 Mission while fusing on the transversal
role played by the Python language in supporting the project
infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ezio Melotti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:pycon-italia-2015/v-eras-14-a-virtual-reality-mars-exploration-mis.html</guid></item></channel></rss>