<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tyler Morgan-Wall</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tyler-morgan-wall.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Quarto, AI, and the Art of Getting Your Life Back</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/quarto-ai-and-the-art-of-getting-your-life-back.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tyler Morgan-Wall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/quarto-ai-and-the-art-of-getting-your-life-back.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tired of endless server issues and maintenance headaches? Want to reclaim your time for coding, writing, and creating? Join me as I share my journey of switching from the server-based headaches of WordPress to Quarto with a little help from AI. In this talk, I’ll describe the simple …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tired of endless server issues and maintenance headaches? Want to reclaim your time for coding, writing, and creating? Join me as I share my journey of switching from the server-based headaches of WordPress to Quarto with a little help from AI. In this talk, I’ll describe the simple trick I used to convert an existing WordPress blog—complete with custom scripts, styles, and beautiful 3D data viz content—into a slick Quarto site. I'll then demonstrate some lesser-known features of Quarto to automate deploying a website entirely from a Quarto project file. Finally, I’ll show you how I used AI to customize and style my new Quarto site and provide several useful strategies to employ if you decide to get some help from AI on your own Quarto journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>