<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Gaurav Pandey</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_gaurav-pandey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Back to Basics: Revisiting Basics with few Tips and Tricks in Python3.10v!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/back-to-basics-revisiting-basics-with-few-tips-and-tricks-in-python310v.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gaurav Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/back-to-basics-revisiting-basics-with-few-tips-and-tricks-in-python310v.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to Basics: Revisiting Basics with few Tips and Tricks in
Python3.10v! - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at NewBie Python Programmers as well as Professional
Python Programmers to revise Python Basics and make fundamentals strong
for NewBie. During this talk, I’ll be revisiting Python Basics …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to Basics: Revisiting Basics with few Tips and Tricks in
Python3.10v! - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at NewBie Python Programmers as well as Professional
Python Programmers to revise Python Basics and make fundamentals strong
for NewBie. During this talk, I’ll be revisiting Python Basics with a
few Tips and Tricks and what’s new in Python3.10v. This talk is aimed at
NewBie Python Programmers as well as Professional Python Programmers to
revise Python Basics and make fundamentals strong for NewBie with new
end exciting features in Python3.10v. During this talk, I’ll be
revisiting Python Basics with a few Tips and Tricks. The talk is for
little experienced Python 3 programmers who have written a few lines of
code: Python experience is required. You can consider this talk as a
teaser of Python 3 features that you may have never used yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, I hope you’ll be inspired to use these Tips and Tricks
in Python3.10v and make your fundamentals strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python3.10v comes with a few new features and for that Python3
fundamentals need to be strong, and in this talk, I’ll be covering
Important Basics on Python, you will learn everything about Python3.10v!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python3.10 is pretty simple to understand, but it also comes with a lot
of different code syntax options you can use. In this talk, I’ll be
going to have a look at all of them. We start with the basic syntax and
then move on to all the different syntaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Gaurav Pandey&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Italia 2022"></category><category term="best practice"></category><category term="clean code"></category><category term="debugging"></category><category term="documentation"></category><category term="education"></category></entry></feed>