<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scegliere le armi per la battaglia del calcolo intensivo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/scegliere-le-armi-per-la-battaglia-del-calcolo-intensivo.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Enrico Franchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/scegliere-le-armi-per-la-battaglia-del-calcolo-intensivo.html</guid><category>bigdata</category><category>optimization</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>hpc</category><category>performance</category><category>scientific-computing</category></item><item><title>Never get in a battle of bits without ammunition.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/never-get-in-a-battle-of-bits-without-ammunition.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Enrico Franchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/never-get-in-a-battle-of-bits-without-ammunition.html</guid><category>cython</category><category>C/C++</category><category>nosql</category><category>mongodb</category><category>numeric</category><category>iPython</category><category>optimization</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>hpc</category><category>performance</category><category>scientific-computing</category><category>numpy</category></item><item><title>Social Network Analysis con Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/social-network-analysis-con-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Enrico Franchi - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Italiana Big
Mac &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La popolarità dell'analisi dei network è cresciuta molto con la recente
diffusione dei social network. Si tratta di un argomento
multidisciplinare, con importanti contributi dai ricercatori di svariate
aree come fisica, sociologia, matematica ed informatica&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuttavia, l'analisi dei network è anche uno strumento utile per i
programmatori. Le tecniche base che saranno introdotte in questo talk
possono infatti essere usate ad esempio per i) testare la robustezza e
la resistenza ai fallimenti di un network, e ii) comprendere a fondo la
struttura di un social network, cosa che può portare ad intuizioni su
mode e trend a partire dai moderni servizi di networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insieme a questi concetti, sarà mostrato del codice Python che sfrutterà
sia dei tool esistenti per l'analisi dei network che dei package di
calcolo numerico. L'attenzione sarà principalmente sul codice, mostrato
e discusso insieme alla teoria su cui è basato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gli unici prerequisiti consigliati per seguire questo talk sono delle
abilità matematiche di base e la conoscenza a livello introduttivo del
linguaggio di programmazione Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Enrico Franchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/social-network-analysis-con-python.html</guid><category>analysis</category><category>network</category></item><item><title>Interoperability: from Python to Clojure and the other way round</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/interoperability-from-python-to-clojure-and-the.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Enrico Franchi - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clojure is a modern Lisp dialect symbiotic with the Java Virtual Machine
and designed for concurrency. Clojure is compiled to byte-code and yet
is fully dynamic. It is very oriented towards functional programming and
manages state change in a controlled environment with software
transactional memory (STM). Since Clojure is a Lisp dialect, it retains
the code-as-data philosophy and has a powerful macro system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Jython, an implementation of the Python programming language
written in Java, it is possible to call Clojure from Python and call
Python from Clojure, using the JVM as an interoperability platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief introduction of the main Clojure features, the
presentation will show how Jython and Clojure can be used together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No previous knowledge of Clojure (or Lisp) is assumed nor required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Enrico Franchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/interoperability-from-python-to-clojure-and-the.html</guid><category>java</category><category>jvm</category><category>jython</category><category>memory</category></item><item><title>Social Network Analysis in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/social-network-analysis-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Enrico Franchi - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network Analysis has gained a huge recognition since the widespread
adoption of on-line social networking systems. It is a
cross-disciplinary subject with important contributions from researchers
of different areas such as physics, sociology, maths and computer
science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Network Analysis is also a useful tool for the working
programmer. The basic techniques which will be introduced in this talk
can be used, for example, both to i) test the robustness and resilience
to damage of a technological network and ii) understand the structure of
a social network, which can in turn lead to insight on trends and
preferences gathering information from modern on-line social networking
systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the concepts, working Python code is presented, both using
existing network analysis Python tools and numeric packages. The focus
is mainly placed on code, which will be shown and discussed together
with the formal theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic maths skills and basic knowledge of the Python programming
language are the only suggested prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Enrico Franchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/social-network-analysis-in-python.html</guid><category>analysis</category><category>network</category><category>networking</category></item></channel></rss>