<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jupyter, Django and Altair - Quick and dirty business analytics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2019/jupyter-django-and-altair-quick-and-dirty-business-analytics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django’s great for building web apps. Jupyter’s great for sharing reproducible analysis. Altair’s great for making analysis interactive, and easier to understand visually. Here’s how to use them all together.
For a large part of last year, I was working in a small, cross disciplinary team in a business information company, building data products to help make sense of public spending data.
Our shared language across the team was python, and over the year, we came up with a workflow that let our analysts and data science specialists work with Jupyter notebook to carry out analysis, and build interactive data viz using Altair to explore data, before taking the same code used to generate these charts, and incorporate them in the main django app as data products for our customers.
This talk outlines why these tools are useful together, explaining how Altair packages up some of the most recent advances in thinking about data vizualisation techniques, and makes them accessible to python developers for exploratory analysis of data using Jupyter and Django together.
We’ll finish by showing how, once you’re happy with them, you can then integrate these same interactive visualisations into an existing django application, and make them accessible to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Adams</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-21:djangocon-europe-2019/jupyter-django-and-altair-quick-and-dirty-business-analytics.html</guid></item><item><title>Planet friendly web development with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the quote “Software is eating the world” to describe
how services like Airbnb, Uber, Slack and Skype are replacing the likes
of hotels, taxis and the office commute. As software engineers, part of
our job is accelerating this shift.And it’s easy to think that a shift
from moving atoms, to moving bits, is a net win for the planet.However,
moving all those bits for our sites around takes servers. And these
servers run on electricity. And most of this electricity powering our
servers comes from burning fossil fuels. And burning these is a key
driver of climate change - the kind of disruption we don’t want.So, what
can we do? We’re not going to stop sharing cat pics anytime soon, but we
can change how we build online services to make them greener, load
faster, and convert better, by borrowing techniques from web performance
optimisation and containerisation, as well as good old common sense.
This talk will show how we can start on the journey to more planet-
friendly, sustainable django web development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Adams</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</guid></item><item><title>Building a planet friendly web – what we can do as developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/building-a-planet-friendly-web-what-we-can-do-as-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the quote “Software is eating the world” to
describe how services like Airbnb, Uber, Slack and Skype are
replacing the likes of hotels, taxis and the office commute. As
software engineers, part of our job is accelerating this shift. And
it’s easy to think that a shift from moving atoms, to moving bits, is
a net win for the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, moving all those bits for our sites around takes servers.
And these servers run on electricity. And most of this electricity
powering our servers comes from burning fossil fuels. And burning
these is a key driver of climate change – the kind of disruption we
don’t want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what can we do? We’re not going to stop sharing cat pics anytime
soon, but we can change how we build online services to make them
greener, load faster, and convert better, by borrowing existing
techniques from web performance optimisation, containerisation, and
serverless, as well as good old common sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will show how we can use the tools in the python
developer's toolbox today for more planet-friendly, sustainable web
development, and how this is also good engineering practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Adams started using Django in 2008. Over the past ten years
he's worked in startups and agencies, as a sysadmin, product manager,
developer, and user researcher, and UX consultant, but keeps coming
back to Python and Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Adams</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-09:pycon-cz-2017/building-a-planet-friendly-web-what-we-can-do-as-developers.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks - Wednesday - part 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-1.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Quinn</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-1.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Planet friendly web development with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the quote &amp;quot;Software is eating the world&amp;quot; to describe how services like Airbnb, Uber, Slack and Skype are replacing the likes of hotels, taxis and the office commute. As software engineers, part of our job is accelerating this shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's easy to think that a shift from moving atoms, to moving bits, is a net win for the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, moving all those bits for our sites around takes servers. And these servers run on electricity. And most of this electricity powering our servers comes from burning fossil fuels. And burning these is a key driver of climate change - the kind of disruption we don't want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what can we do? We're not going to stop sharing cat pics anytime soon, but we can change how we build online services to make them greener, load faster, and convert better, by borrowing techniques from web performance optimisation and containerisation, as well as good old common sense. This talk will show how we can start on the journey to more planet-friendly, sustainable django web development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Adams</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/planet-friendly-web-development-with-django.html</guid></item></channel></rss>