<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Marco Valtorta</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Learning LWF Chain Graphs: A Markov Blanket Discovery Approach</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/learning-lwf-chain-graphs-a-markov-blanket-discovery-approach.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Learning LWF Chain Graphs: A Markov Blanket Discovery Approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mohammad Ali Javidian (University of South Carolina)*; Marco Valtorta (University of South Carolina); Pooyan Jamshidi (University of South Carolina)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper provides a graphical characterization of Markov blankets in chain
graphs (CGs) under the Lauritzen-Wermuth-Frydenberg (LWF) interpretation.  The characterization is different from the well-known one for Bayesian networks and generalizes it.  We provide a novel scalable and sound algorithm
for Markov blanket discovery in LWF CGs and prove that the Grow-Shrink algorithm, the IAMB algorithm, and its variants are still correct for Markov blanket discovery in LWF CGs under the same assumptions as for Bayesian networks. We provide a sound and scalable constraint-based framework for learning the structure of LWF CGs from faithful causally sufficient data and prove its correctness when the Markov blanket discovery algorithms in this paper are used. Our proposed algorithms compare positively/competitively against the state-of-the-art  LCD (Learn Chain graphs via Decomposition) algorithm, depending on the algorithm that is used for Markov blanket discovery. Our proposed algorithms make a broad range of inference/learning problems computationally
tractable and more reliable because they exploit locality.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mohammad Ali Javidian</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/learning-lwf-chain-graphs-a-markov-blanket-discovery-approach.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item></channel></rss>