<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Michael Meng</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>API documentation: Exploring the information needs of software developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2016/api-documentation-exploring-the-information-needs-of-software-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The success of an API crucially depends on how well its documentation
meets the information needs of software developers. But what information
do developers need? What information do they want, and what information
are they actually using when starting to learn a new API and solve
programming tasks with it? In this talk, I will present the results of
some empirical studies I conducted with my team to better understand the
information needs of software developers. One the one hand, we ran more
than 20 semi-structured interviews with junior and senior developers and
asked them – among other things – to tell us about the questions they
raise first when approaching a new API, the type of documentation they
look for, and general expectations and experiences regarding API
documentation. Key findings derived from the interviews were then
followed up on by a standardized survey in which more than 110
developers participated. Our second study took a different approach.
Instead of asking developers what they find important about API
documentation, we asked them to solve a few tasks on a simple (REST)-API
that was unfamiliar to them. The goal of this study was to observe how
the developers approach the tasks and which pieces of the documentation
provided with the test API they actually use. Besides presenting the
design and main findings of our studies, I will also discuss
implications the results may have regarding the contents, structure and
design of API documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Meng</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:/write-the-docs-europe-2016/api-documentation-exploring-the-information-needs-of-software-developers.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Europe 2016</category></item></channel></rss>