<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynote: PEP 581 and PEP 588: Migrating CPython's Issue Tracker - Mariatta Wijaya</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2019/keynote-pep-581-and-pep-588-migrating-cpythons-issue-tracker-mariatta-wijaya.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Mariatta Wijaya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyConDE
The acceptance of PEP 581, by Python steering council means that another big workflow change is impending. Let's hear about some of the proposed plans on improving CPython's workflow, and learn how you can help and take part in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/DFCU3K"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/DFCU3K&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-09:pycon-de-2019/keynote-pep-581-and-pep-588-migrating-cpythons-issue-tracker-mariatta-wijaya.html</guid></item><item><title>What is a Python Core Developer?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/what-is-a-python-core-developer.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-03:north-bay-python-2018/what-is-a-python-core-developer.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Don't Be a Robot; Build the Bot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/dont-be-a-robot-build-the-bot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Managing a large open source project like CPython is no easy task. Learn
how the Python core team automated their GitHub workflow with bots,
making it easier for maintainers and contributors to collaborate
together. Even if you’re not managing a large project, you can still
build your own bot! Hear some ideas on what you can automate on GitHub
and personalize your bot based on your own workflow. All you need is
Python. Don’t be a robot; build the bot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-17:djangocon-us-2018/dont-be-a-robot-build-the-bot.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>PEP Talk - (Closing Keynote)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2017/pep-talk-closing-keynote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python Core Developer &amp;amp; Software Engineer at Sony Pictures Imageworks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mariatta is a Python Core Developer and a Software Engineer at Sony Pictures Imageworks. She helps organize Vancouver PyLadies and PyCascades conference. She moved to Canada almost two decades ago and now considers Vancouver as her home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-19:pycon-ca-2017/pep-talk-closing-keynote.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>What is a Python Core Developer?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/what-is-a-python-core-developer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you become a Python core developer? How can I become one? What is it like to be a Python core developer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the questions I often receive ever since I became a Python core developer a year ago. Contributing to Python is a long journey that does not end when one earns the commit privilege. There are responsibilities to bear and expectations to live up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past year, I've been learning more about what it really means to be a Python core developer. Let me share all of that with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/what-is-a-python-core-developer.html</guid></item><item><title>Build-a-GitHub-Bot Workshop</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/build-a-github-bot-workshop.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHub provides a great platform for collaborating. You can take it to the next level by creating custom GitHub bots. By delegating some of the chores to a bot, you get to spend more time developing your project and collaborating with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to automate your workflow by building a personal GitHub assistant for your own project. We'll use libraries called &lt;cite&gt;gidgethub&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;aiohttp&lt;/cite&gt; to write a GitHub bot that does the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greet the person who created an issue in your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say thanks when a pull request has been closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply a label to issues or pull requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives a thumbs up reaction to comments &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; made. (becoming your own personal cheer squad).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part is, you get to do all of the above using Python 3.6! F-strings included!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/build-a-github-bot-workshop.html</guid></item><item><title>Dial M For Mentor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about Python community, is the availability of
mentors willing to help you. Various mentors have helped me navigate the
open source community and help advanced my skills. I realized finding a
mentor is not as easy as it seems, and it takes a lot of courage to
reach out in the first place. And then, there is impostor syndrome,
where one may feel like they don’t deserve the help.In this talk, I will
provide advice about working with mentor.Asking for help is not a
failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</guid></item><item><title>PEP 498: The Monologue</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/pep-498-the-monologue.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3.6 was released in December 2016, and it includes 16 new PEPs! In this talk, we will focus on PEP 498 - Literal String Interpolation, affectionately known as f-strings. Let's learn about f-strings. See some examples, and know the gotchas. You’ll want to upgrade to Python 3.6 just for this!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/pep-498-the-monologue.html</guid></item><item><title>Dial M For Mentor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about Python community, is the availability of mentors willing to help you. Various mentors have helped me navigate the open source community and help advanced my skills. I realized finding a mentor is not as easy as it seems, and it takes a lot of courage to reach out in the first place. And then, there is impostor syndrome, where one may feel like they don't deserve the help.
In this talk, I will provide advice about working with mentor.
Asking for help is not a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</guid></item><item><title>Making the Most out of Code Reviews</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/vancouver-python-developers/making-the-most-out-of-code-reviews.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code review is like a buzzword in the programming world. Developers often talk about how important it is. But what really happens during code review? What do you achieve out of it? How can we learn during code review? This talk will present ideas of what should be the goals of a code review, and how developers can learn during code review process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code reviewing is considered to be an important phase in software development to ensure code quality. Generally during code review, the goal is to find mistakes, if any was made. This can create a negative experience to the team. It’s likely that some team member is not comfortable with the idea of having their work scrutinized. Junior developers may feel like they are not qualified enough to provide feedback. This talk will explore the different goals of code review process. In addition to ensure code quality, code review should be considered as a learning tool. It should be considered a positive and rewarding experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-04:vancouver-python-developers/making-the-most-out-of-code-reviews.html</guid></item><item><title>Dial M For Mentor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about Python community is the availability of
mentors willing to help you. Various mentors have helped me navigate the
open source community and help advanced my skills. I realized finding a
mentor is not as easy as it seems, and it takes a lot of courage to
reach out in the first place. And then, there is impostor syndrome,
where one may feel like they don’t deserve the help. In this talk, I
will provide advice about working with a mentor. Asking for help is not
a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-19:pycon-us-2017/dial-m-for-mentor.html</guid></item><item><title>Making the Most Out of Code Reviews</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/making-the-most-out-of-code-reviews.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making the Most Out of Code Reviews by Mariatta Wijaya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code review is like a buzzword in the programming world. Developers often talk about how important it is. But what really happens during code review? What do you achieve out of it? How can we learn during code review? This talk will present ideas of what should be the goals of a code review, and how can developers learn during code review process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mariatta Wijaya</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:djangocon-us-2016/making-the-most-out-of-code-reviews.html</guid></item></channel></rss>