<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_konstantin-benz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The Fabric that holds the cloud together</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2015/the-fabric-that-holds-the-cloud-together.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Konstantin Benz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-19:pycon-uk-2015/the-fabric-that-holds-the-cloud-together.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's this session about? Fabric is a Python library that offers a
simple API to manage remote connections to distant servers and PCs via
SSH protocol. Although it is a simple library, fabric is an extremely
powerful tool for managing virtual machines in the cloud. Fabric can be
used to login to virtual machines, upload files to them, install
software packages on them or download files of them. Furthermore fabric
can be extended to a fully-fledged (but still lightweight) configuration
management tool. Fabric can be combined with the Python cuisine library
and Python's &amp;quot;native&amp;quot; capabilities like serializing objects, writing
data to JSON files and manipulating regular expressions. By employing
this capabilities almost every VM administration task can be automated.
VMs can be connected to each other, they can authenticate with each
other and they can communicate to each other. In short: fabric is the
&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot; that holds your VM environment together. If you're involved into
DevOps, fabric is your tool to manage the cloud. You will get to know to
do this in this session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview In this talk we will show you fabric's capability to manage and
configure virtual machines in the popular Python-based cloud operating
system OpenStack. Thereby we will show you how to do password-based and
public key authentication with fabric, remote software installation with
package managers, management of users and groups, management of file
permissions, file uploads and downloads, configuration file manipulation
with regular expressions (Python re module), serialization with pickle
or JSON and manage communication between VMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this session you will know _ How to connect to OpenStack virtual
machines via fabric API _ How to create private/public keypairs and
authenticate to virtual machines _ How to combine fabric and cuisine to
configure virtual machines _ How to use the Fabric API to employ
package managers (like apt, yum, zypper, pacman) which install software
packages on virtual machines _ How to add users and groups via Fabric
to your virtual machines and set the right permissions to files and
directories _ How to upload files to virtual machines or download files
from virtual machines to your local computer _ How to use regular
expressions and configuration file templates to create custom
configuration files _ How to serialize objects with pickle or JSON and
use serialization let VMs communicate to each other&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>