<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Dhanshree Arora</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Federated Machine Learning with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/federated-machine-learning-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Federated Machine Learning with Python
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Dhanshree Arora&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where all the data generated on your phone and on your wearables never left these devices without compromising your user experience. Or, a world where AI collaboration between data owners and developers did not have to be slowed by bureaucracy and data compliance laws like the GDPR. Federated Machine Learning, originally introduced in 2015, aims to create this world. It is the gift of distributed computing to Artificial Intelligence for training models without compromising data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federated Machine Learning is a model training technique in which the data never leaves the source (for example, a data silo, a smartphone, or an IoT device) and a copy of a global model is trained at source while sharing only the learning with the global model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will present an introduction to privacy preserving machine learning with a focus on federated ML, and make a case for federated ML beyond just Gboard and into enterprises. The session will aim to demystify the jargon around Federated Machine Learning, specifically terms such as horizontal vs vertical federated ML, cross device/cross silo training, centralized vs decentralized training, and data centric vs model centric federated learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will briefly introduce existing FedML implementations in Python and also demonstrate a live code walk-through for a minimal centralized federated learning system built using python-socketio and confluent kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will discuss the challenges faced by enterprises in incorporating federated machine learning. The most notorious difficulty with Federated ML is non-IID data. Other technical difficulties include network latencies affecting training coordination, single point of failure in centralized federated learning systems, computational limitations at source nodes, etc. Additionally, in data centric federated ML, where a data provider allows AI developers to use their data to build models, federated ML poses challenges for early stage EDA and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to talk about federated ML, which is ripe with opportunities for research and development, and the tech community is finally ready to adopt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dhanshree Arora</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/federated-machine-learning-with-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item><item><title>Jupyter - Under the Hood</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/jupyter-under-the-hood.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Jupyter - Under the Hood - presented by Dhanshree Arora&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 2 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks at their core are just JSON documents that contain all your code, markdown styles and outputs. Yet when you run a notebook, there's a lot that's happening under the hood - from starting a session with the notebook server, to launching an IPython kernel, and a rich Web UI communicating with the notebook server and the IPython kernel using Jupyter's REST APIs and ZMQ websockets. We will explore the Jupyter ecosystem and see how this system comes together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture of all the offerings in the Jupyter Project (such as the classic Jupyter Notebook), the newer JupyterLab IDE, or the scalable multi-user environment - JupyterHub is completely distributed.
At their core, there's a front end client like a web browser or a qt console that talks to the Notebook server using its many APIs (like the kernel API) and to the language kernel (in our case IPython) using ZMQ Sockets, allowing the Jupyter architecture to scale easily.
In this presentation, we look closely at these REST API calls, and the ZMQ socket traffic using simple tools like the browser's network tab. We will also try to manipulate a notebook using simple code to get a full appreciation of these internals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dhanshree Arora</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/jupyter-under-the-hood.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item></channel></rss>