<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Adam Hill</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Create a full stack, reactive website in Django without JavaScript</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/create-a-full-stack-reactive-website-in-django-without-javascript.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is a great web framework for &amp;quot;perfectionists with deadlines&amp;quot; and provides a lot of built-in functionality when building server-side websites. However, a lot has changed on the web since its inception in 2005, and now it has become somewhat common advice for modern web applications to only use it as an API backend, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few Django packages that enable building a reactive website while still utilizing all of the strengths of Django. This talk will cover the benefits of this approach, a brief overview of how other programming languages are solving this same problem, and a few Django projects which can help developers build interactive websites without writing any custom JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repository with example code, slides, and a transcript: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/adamghill/djangocon-eu-2021-conference-talk"&gt;https://github.com/adamghill/djangocon-eu-2021-conference-talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Hill</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-03:/djangocon-europe-2021/create-a-full-stack-reactive-website-in-django-without-javascript.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2021</category><category>Django</category><category>DjangoConEU</category><category>djangoconeu2021</category></item><item><title>Searching for Shady Patterns: Shining a light on UK corporate ownership</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2018/searching-for-shady-patterns-shining-a-light-on-uk-corporate-ownership.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2016 the UK government launched the world’s first “beneficial
ownership” register; a requirement for all UK companies to register who
controlled them. The register comprises of in excess of 4.5 million
companies and 4 million individual people. We present how we built a
graph database mapping the UK network of control structures using Python
and a Neo4j graph database, and the first insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Hill</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-29:/pydata-london-2018/searching-for-shady-patterns-shining-a-light-on-uk-corporate-ownership.html</guid><category>PyData London 2018</category></item></channel></rss>