<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Johan Euphrosine</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Web API Mashups in a Python Application</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/web-api-mashups-in-a-python-application.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Johan Euphrosine - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover: - How to use OAuth into your webapp so users can
give permission to access their data stored in third party web
application. - How your webapp can interact with their Web API using
RESTful JSON protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is suitable for beginners already familiar with any WSGI web
framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be illustrated with code samples using Google App Engine
and Google APIs client library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Johan Euphrosine</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:/europython-2011/web-api-mashups-in-a-python-application.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2011</category><category>api</category><category>google</category><category>json</category><category>oauth</category><category>web</category><category>wsgi</category></item><item><title>Accelerating the Open Source Silicon Ecosystem with Jupyter Notebooks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/accelerating-the-open-source-silicon-ecosystem-with-jupyter-notebooks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this interactive session we showcase our recent work to leverage Jupyter Notebooks and Conda packages to publish and share interactive design experiments and tutorials using open source silicon toolchains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notebooks published at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/silicon-notebooks"&gt;https://github.com/chipsalliance/silicon-notebooks&lt;/a&gt; demonstrate how run fully open source silicon flows from design to gds using publicly-hosted notebooks without having to install any tool locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally we show how those notebooks can be scaled on a public cloud provider to explore the parameters space of various silicon designs:
- We deploy an opensource terraform solution &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/rad-lab"&gt;https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/rad-lab&lt;/a&gt; to provision jupyter notebooks with all the necessary tools pre-installed to model our experiments w/ design and flow parameters.
- Between each batch of experiments we report estimated performance metrics to a blackbox and hyperparameter optimization service (which has also an opensource implementation &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/google/vizier"&gt;https://github.com/google/vizier&lt;/a&gt;) allowing it to suggest new parameters for future batches.
- We observe that the experiments quickly converge toward the best metrics for the given designs.
- Each of the jobs result in a standalone notebook allowing us to share, aggregate and reproduce every experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Johan Euphrosine</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/accelerating-the-open-source-silicon-ecosystem-with-jupyter-notebooks.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item></channel></rss>