<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_juan-santos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PEP yourself: 10 PEPs you should pay attention to</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/pep-yourself-10-peps-you-should-pay-attention-to.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Santos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/pep-yourself-10-peps-you-should-pay-attention-to.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading standards documents can be a dull task. But like in other
fields, standards in Python play a big part. Python Enhancement
Proposals (PEPs) are defined, improved, and eventually implemented by
the community. They apply to mostly anything related to Python, from the
more abstract and general to the more concrete and specific. Paying
attention to them, and knowing which ones to read beforehand is a vital
task that should take place prior to writing the first lines of code in
a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will go over a condensed list of the most important PEPs
to this date and see how they influence everyday coding. From style
guides and docstring conventions to data classes and assignment
expressions, we will see how these PEPs affect (or can affect) the code
we write, and how can we use them to improve our code and make
developing easier and more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, attendees will have a better grasp on why PEPs are
important to Python, which are a must read, and which ones they should
use as a guide in the future, both for coding and refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Clean Code"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category><category term="Python general"></category></entry></feed>