<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deconstructing Feather</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/deconstructing-feather.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/wlattner/PyData_Chi_2016"&gt;https://github.com/wlattner/PyData_Chi_2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feather, Avro, Parquet, Arrow... all these new file formats, what's wrong with good old CSVs? In this talk, we will cover why CSV files are not always the optimal storage format for tabular data and what optimizations each of these formats make. We will do a deep dive on Feather, a cross-language format created by Wes McKinney and Hadley Wickham.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Lattner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-27:pydata-chicago-2016/deconstructing-feather.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and R Together at Last: Writing Cross Language Tools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/python-and-r-together-at-last-writing-cross-language-tools-scipy-2016-bill-lattner.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Python and R boast large data science communities. Each have developed a fantastic collection of packages from reading/writing data to plotting and visualization. Unfortunately, some tools are only available in one language or the other, but not both. Python and R provide relatively simple mechanisms for interacting with C, C++, and Fortran. There are many tools that take advantage of this interoperability. While not a simple matter, developing data science tools in these low level languages and providing Python and R wrappers allows code reuse between languages, speed benefits notwithstanding. In this talk we will discuss strategies and lessons learned from porting existing packages to Python from R and writing cross language tools from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Lattner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/python-and-r-together-at-last-writing-cross-language-tools-scipy-2016-bill-lattner.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category></item></channel></rss>