<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Rob Richardson</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rob-richardson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Definitive Deep Dive into the .git Folder</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2021/the-definitive-deep-dive-into-the-git-folder.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Richardson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-03-22:/python-web-conf-2021/the-definitive-deep-dive-into-the-git-folder.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Definitive Deep Dive into the .git Folder&amp;quot; by: Rob Richardson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s in the .git folder? How are commits stored? How do branches work? We’ll dive deep into the objects folder, unpack commits, look at the types of DAG nodes, examine object content, and build a complete …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Definitive Deep Dive into the .git Folder&amp;quot; by: Rob Richardson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s in the .git folder? How are commits stored? How do branches work? We’ll dive deep into the objects folder, unpack commits, look at the types of DAG nodes, examine object content, and build a complete visualization of the stored content. We’ll also quickly look through Git hooks, Git config, and ref logs. Come experience the zen of git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2021 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2021.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2021"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Stateful Workloads in Kubernetes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/building-stateful-workloads-in-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Richardson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/building-stateful-workloads-in-kubernetes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s day 2. Kubernetes is running. You have your deployments and services set. Now how do you migrate the data store? Let’s journey together on this code-focused tour through Persistent Volumes, Persistent Volume Claims, and StatefulSets. We’ll craft and launch a strategy to care for your …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s day 2. Kubernetes is running. You have your deployments and services set. Now how do you migrate the data store? Let’s journey together on this code-focused tour through Persistent Volumes, Persistent Volume Claims, and StatefulSets. We’ll craft and launch a strategy to care for your users’ data in this new container world. You can power your business on Kubernetes: stateless or stateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s (relatively) easy to build stateless web properties in containers, but it’s a much different beast to build data stores in Kubernetes. We’ll disambiguate PV, PVC, and Stateful Sets in simple ways so you can get past this next hurdle of K8s knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>