<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Guy Royse</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Understanding Probabilistic Data Structures with 112,092 UFO Sightings</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2020/understanding-probabilistic-data-structures-with-112092-ufo-sightings.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2020 Online Edition. It’s the 5th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DESCRIPTION
There are three reactions to the title of this talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What the heck’s a probabilistic data structure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO Sightings… wha?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;112,092 is an oddly specific number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a talk about the first bullet point with the second thrown in just for fun. I like weird stuff—UFOs, Bigfoot, peanut butter and bologna on toast—maybe you do too? As far as the third bullet point, well, that’s how many sightings I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you’re like most developers, you probably have no idea what probabilistic data structures are. In fact, I did a super-scientific poll on Twitter and found that out of 119 participants, 58% had never heard of them and 22% had heard the term but nothing more. I wonder what percentage of that 22% heard the term for the first time in the poll. We’re a literal-minded lot at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow. That’s 4 out of 5 developers or, as I like to call it, the Trident dentist ratio. (It’s actually a manifestation of the Pareto principle but I’m a 70s kid). That’s a lot of folks that need to be educated. So, let’s do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A probabilistic data structure is, well, they’re sort of like the TARDIS—bigger on the inside—and JPEG compression—a bit lossy. And, like both, they are fast, accurate enough, and can take you to interesting places of adventure. That last one might not be something a JPEG does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More technically speaking, most probabilistic data structures use hashes to give you faster and smaller data structures in exchange for precision. If you’ve got a mountain of data to process, this is super useful. In this talk, we’ll briefly go over some common probabilistic data structures; dive deep into a couple (Bloom Filter, MinHash, and Top-K); and show a running application that makes use of Top-K to analyze the most commonly used words in all 112,092 of my UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we’re done, you’ll be ready to start using some of these structures in your own applications. And, if you use the UFO data, maybe you’ll discover that the truth really is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPEAKER BIO
Guy works for Redis Labs as a Developer Advocate. Combining his decades of experience in writing software with a passion for sharing what he has learned, Guy goes out into developer communities and helps others build great software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching and community have long been a focus for Guy. He is President of the Columbus JavaScript Users Group, an organizer for the Columbus Machine Learners, and has even has helped teach programming at a prison in central Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his personal life, Guy is a hard-boiled geek interested in role-playing games, science fiction, and technology. He also has a slightly less geeky interest in history and linguistics. In his spare time, he volunteers for his local Cub Scout Pack, goes camping, and studies history and linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guy lives in Ohio with his wife, his three teenage sons, and an entire wall of games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPONSOR ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
The post production of this and other PyBay2020 videos are made possible by our sponsors:
- IBM &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://community.ibm.com/community/user/datascience/home"&gt;https://community.ibm.com/community/user/datascience/home&lt;/a&gt;
- Rookout &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rookout.com/"&gt;https://rookout.com/&lt;/a&gt;
- Anyscale &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anyscale.com"&gt;https://anyscale.com&lt;/a&gt;
- Twilio &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twilio.com/"&gt;https://twilio.com/&lt;/a&gt;
- JetBrains &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.jetbrains.com"&gt;https://www.jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;
- Linode &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://linode.com"&gt;https://linode.com&lt;/a&gt;
- Pearson Informit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.informit.com/"&gt;https://www.informit.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVENT PRODUCER ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
This community conference is produced by organizers of SF Python meetup and volunteers from around the SF Bay Area and beyond. See upcoming events here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sfpythonmeetup.com"&gt;https://sfpythonmeetup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guy Royse</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-17:/pybay-2020/understanding-probabilistic-data-structures-with-112092-ufo-sightings.html</guid><category>PyBay 2020</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning Like a Viking: Building Convolutional Neural Networks with Keras</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/deep-learning-like-a-viking-building-convolutional-neural-networks-with-keras.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session, we are going to build a Convolution Neural Network to
recognize hand-written runes from the Younger Futhark. We'll be using
Keras to write easy to understand Python code that creates and trains
the neural network to do this. We'll wire this up to a web application
using Flask and some client-side JavaScript so you can write some runes
yourself and see if it recognizes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vikings came from the land of ice and snow, from the midnight sun,
where the hot springs flow. In addition to longships and bad attitudes,
they had a system of writing that we, in modern times, have dubbed the
Younger Futhark (or ᚠᚢᚦᚬᚱᚴ if you're a Viking). These sigils are more
commonly called runes and have been mimicked in fantasy literature and
role-playing games for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, having an alphabet, runic or otherwise, solves lots of
problems. But, it also introduces others. The Vikings had the same
problem we do today. How were they to get their automated software
systems to recognize the hand- carved input of a typical boatman? Of
course, they were never able to solve this problem and were instead
forced into a life of burning and pillaging. Today, we have deep
learning and neural networks and can, fortunately, avoid such a fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we're done, you'll understand how Convolution Neural Networks work,
how to build your own using Python and Keras, and how to make it a part
of an application using Flask. Maybe you'll even try seeing what it
thinks of the Bluetooth logo?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guy Royse</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:/pyohio-2019/deep-learning-like-a-viking-building-convolutional-neural-networks-with-keras.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2019</category></item><item><title>Mystery ML: Classifying Text w/ Recurrent Neural Networks, Keras, Scoob and the Gang</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2021/mystery-ml-classifying-text-w-recurrent-neural-networks-keras-scoob-and-the-gang.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Mystery Machine Learning: Classifying Text with Recurrent Neural Networks, Keras, and Scoob and the Gang&amp;quot; by: Guy Royse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jinkies! Spoiler Alert! If you’ve seen Scooby-Doo, you know who the monster always is—Old Man Withers, the guy who runs the amusement park. Amusement park operators like Old Man Withers have caused Mystery, Inc. all sorts of problems over the years. Problems that could be avoided with a properly trained recurrent neural network. With RNNs, Scoob and the Gang could have built a model to classify everyone’s speech. This would show them that Old Man Withers and Redbeard’s Ghost sounded a lot alike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can help Mystery, Inc. with this problem by building a recurrent neural network to do just that. You know we got a mystery to solve, and we’re going to solve it by building our model using lines from Scooby-Doo, Keras, and TensorFlow. Once we have our model, we’ll host it on RedisAI so we can quickly build an application to make use of it. Well, we’ve got some work to do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also explain what neural networks are in general, what recurrent neural networks are in particular, and discuss some practical use of this technology. When we’re done, you’ll know how to build RNNs with Keras, use them to classify text, and integrate them into your application. But more importantly, you’re going to have yourself a Scooby snack! That’s a fact!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2021 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2021.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guy Royse</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-03-22:/python-web-conf-2021/mystery-ml-classifying-text-w-recurrent-neural-networks-keras-scoob-and-the-gang.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2021</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2021</category></item></channel></rss>