<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_thierry-carrez.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Lessons from a massive, openly-developed project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/lessons-from-a-massive-openly-developed-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thierry Carrez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/lessons-from-a-massive-openly-developed-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is a massive open source project, formed of multiple
components written in Python. Created in 2010, it attracted thousands of
developers which produced hundreds of thousands of commits. It is
completely openly-developed: there is no single organization owning it,
and anyone can participate on a level playing ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this wild ride, we discovered new classes of issues, crafted
novel solutions, made mistakes and learned lessons, most of them
applicable to other open source projects. Come learn about software
engineering best practices, open collaboration advice and other fun tips
and tricks based on our experience ! No prior experience with OpenStack
is needed to attend this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="quality-assurance"></category><category term="project-management"></category><category term="continuous-integration"></category><category term="#lessonslearned"></category><category term="collaboration"></category><category term="principles"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="OpenStack"></category><category term="release-engineering"></category></entry><entry><title>How OpenStack makes Python better (and vice-versa)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/how-openstack-makes-python-better-and-vice-versa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thierry Carrez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/how-openstack-makes-python-better-and-vice-versa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thierry Carrez/Doug Hellmann - How OpenStack makes Python better (and vice-versa)
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-openstack-makes-python-better-and-vice-versa"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-openstack-makes-python-better-and-vice-versa&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is an infrastructure stack mostly developed in Python. In
this talk, Thierry Carrez and Doug Hellmann, both Python Software
Foundation fellows and OpenStack Technical Committee members, will
look at the symbiotic relationship between OpenStack and Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is an open source stack that can be deployed on raw
computing resources to privately or publicly present Infrastructure as
a Service. It now consists of more than 4.5 million lines of code, 85%
of which is Python. In this talk, Thierry Carrez and Doug Hellmann,
both Python Software Foundation fellows and OpenStack Technical
Committee members, will look at the symbiotic relationship between
OpenStack and Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll go back in history and explain why OpenStack originally picked
Python as its main language 6 years ago, and explore what does Python
bring to OpenStack. We'll dive into examples of OpenStack pushing
Python libraries to their limits and exposing new bugs. We'll look
into the massive cloud-based continuous integration system that
OpenStack uses and explain how it exposes bugs in Python libraries in
the minutes after they are published to PyPI. We'll look into Python
libraries that were created by the OpenStack community and libraries
that the OpenStack community took over. Finally we'll expose a few
best practices that Python developers can follow to get the most of
this symbiotic relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Snakes on a cloud: the OpenStack project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/snakes-on-a-cloud-the-openstack-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thierry Carrez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/snakes-on-a-cloud-the-openstack-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Thierry Carrez - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is an innovative open source project written in Python, backed
by Rackspace Hosting and NASA, building a massively-scalable and
reliable cloud computing platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of this talk will clarify the place of OpenStack in the
general &amp;quot;cloud&amp;quot; landscape and explain why a fully open cloud
infrastructure stack is necessary to avoid vendor lock-in. We'll then
focus on the OpenStack project goals, its developer community, its open
design and release processes, and the developer tools it chose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the talk will present into more technical details the
different components of OpenStack: Nova (compute) and Swift (storage),
including the Python libraries that are used (libvirt, SQLAlchemy,
eventlet…). A Q&amp;amp;A session at the end of the talk will give the audience
a chance to clear any remaining dark area.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="cloud"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="openstack"></category><category term="python,"></category></entry></feed>