<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tom Claassen</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Constraint-Based Causal Discovery using Partial Ancestral Graphs in the presence of Cycles</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/constraint-based-causal-discovery-using-partial-ancestral-graphs-in-the-presence-of-cycles.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Constraint-Based Causal Discovery using Partial Ancestral Graphs in the presence of Cycles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joris M. Mooij (University of Amsterdam)*; Tom Claassen (Radboud University Nijmegen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While feedback loops are known to play important roles in many complex systems, their existence is ignored in a large part of the causal discovery literature, as systems are typically assumed to be acyclic from the outset. When applying causal discovery algorithms designed for the acyclic setting on data generated by a system that involves feedback, one would not expect to obtain correct results. In this work, we show that---surprisingly---the output of the Fast Causal Inference (FCI) algorithm is correct if it is applied to observational data generated by a system that involves feedback. More specifically, we prove that for observational data generated by a simple and sigma-faithful Structural Causal Model (SCM), FCI is sound and complete, and can be used to consistently estimate (i) the presence and absence of causal relations, (ii) the presence and absence of direct causal relations, (iii) the absence of confounders, and (iv) the absence of specific cycles in the causal graph of the SCM. We extend these results to constraint-based causal discovery algorithms that exploit certain forms of background knowledge, including the causally sufficient setting (e.g., the PC algorithm) and the Joint Causal Inference setting (e.g., the FCI-JCI algorithm).&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joris M. Mooij</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/constraint-based-causal-discovery-using-partial-ancestral-graphs-in-the-presence-of-cycles.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item><item><title>MASSIVE: Tractable and Robust Bayesian Learning of Many-Dimensional Instrumental Variable Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/massive-tractable-and-robust-bayesian-learning-of-many-dimensional-instrumental-variable-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;MASSIVE: Tractable and Robust Bayesian Learning of Many-Dimensional Instrumental Variable Models&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ioan Gabriel Bucur (Radboud University Nijmegen)*; Tom Claassen (Radboud University Nijmegen); Tom Heskes (Radboud University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent availability of huge, many-dimensional data sets, like those arising from genome-wide association studies (GWAS), provides many opportunities for strengthening causal inference. One popular approach is to utilize these many-dimensional measurements as instrumental variables (instruments) for improving the causal effect estimate between other pairs of variables. Unfortunately, searching for proper instruments in a many-dimensional set of candidates is a daunting task due to the intractable model space and the fact that we cannot directly test which of these candidates are valid, so most existing search methods either rely on overly stringent modeling assumptions or fail to capture the inherent model uncertainty in the selection process. We show that, as long as at least some of the candidates are (close to) valid, without knowing a priori which ones, they collectively still pose enough restrictions on the target interaction to obtain a reliable causal effect estimate. We propose a general and efficient causal inference algorithm that accounts for model uncertainty by performing Bayesian model averaging over the most promising many-dimensional instrumental variable models, while at the same time employing weaker assumptions regarding the data generating process. We showcase the efficiency, robustness and predictive performance of our algorithm through experimental results on both simulated and real-world data.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ioan Gabriel Bucur</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/massive-tractable-and-robust-bayesian-learning-of-many-dimensional-instrumental-variable-models.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item><item><title>Establishing Markov Equivalence in Cyclic Directed Graphs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/establishing-markov-equivalence-in-cyclic-directed-graphs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Establishing Markov Equivalence in Cyclic Directed Graphs&amp;quot;
Tom Claassen, Joris Mooij
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/claassen23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/claassen23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
We present a new, efficient procedure to establish Markov equivalence between directed graphs that may or may not contain cycles. It is based on the Cyclic Equivalence Theorem (CET) in the seminal works on cyclic models by Thomas Richardson in the mid ’90s, but now rephrased from an ancestral perspective. The resulting characterization leads to a procedure for establishing Markov equivalence between graphs that no longer requires explicit tests for d-separation, leading to a significantly reduced algorithmic complexity. The conceptually simplified characterization may help to reinvigorate theoretical research towards sound and complete cyclic discovery in the presence of latent confounders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/504-oral-slides.pdf"&gt;https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/504-oral-slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Claassen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/establishing-markov-equivalence-in-cyclic-directed-graphs.html</guid><category>UAI 2023</category></item></channel></rss>