<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Chin Hwee Ong</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_chin-hwee-ong.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Speed Up Your Data Processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/speed-up-your-data-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chin Hwee Ong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/speed-up-your-data-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parallel and Asynchronous Programming in Data Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a data science project, one of the biggest bottlenecks (in terms of time) is the constant wait for the data processing code to finish executing. Slow code, as well as connectivity issues, affect every step of a typical data science workflow …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parallel and Asynchronous Programming in Data Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a data science project, one of the biggest bottlenecks (in terms of time) is the constant wait for the data processing code to finish executing. Slow code, as well as connectivity issues, affect every step of a typical data science workflow — be it for network I/O operations or computation-driven workloads. In this talk, I will be sharing about common bottlenecks in data processing within a typical data science workflow, and exploring the use of parallel and asynchronous programming using concurrent.futures module in Python to speed up your data processing pipelines so that you could focus more on getting value out of your data. Through real-life analogies, you will learn about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequential vs parallel processing,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synchronous vs asynchronous execution,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network I/O operations vs computation-driven workloads in a data science workflow,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When is parallelism and asynchronous programming a good idea,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to implement parallel and asynchronous programming using concurrent.futures module to speed up your data processing pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk assumes basic understanding of data pipelines and data science workflows. While the main target audience are data scientists and engineers building data pipelines, the talk is designed such that anyone with a basic understanding of the Python language would be able to understand the illustrated concepts and use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="ASYNC / Concurreny"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Multi-Processing"></category><category term="Multi-Threading"></category></entry><entry><title>Designing Functional Data Pipelines for Reproducibility and Maintainability</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/designing-functional-data-pipelines-for-reproducibility-and-maintainability.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chin Hwee Ong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/designing-functional-data-pipelines-for-reproducibility-and-maintainability.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing Functional Data Pipelines for Reproducibility and Maintainability
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Chin Hwee Ong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building data pipelines at scale, it is crucial to design data pipelines that are reliable, scalable and extensible according to evolving business needs. Designing data pipelines for reproducibility …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing Functional Data Pipelines for Reproducibility and Maintainability
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Chin Hwee Ong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building data pipelines at scale, it is crucial to design data pipelines that are reliable, scalable and extensible according to evolving business needs. Designing data pipelines for reproducibility and maintainability is a challenge, as testing and debugging across compute units (threads/cores/computes) are often complex and time-consuming due to dependencies and shared states at runtime. In this talk, Chin Hwee will be sharing about common challenges in designing reproducible and maintainable data pipelines at scale, and exploring the use of functional programming in Python to build scalable production-ready data pipelines that are designed for reproducibility and maintainability. Through analogies and realistic examples inspired by data pipeline designs in production environments, you will learn about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Functional Programming, and how it differs from other programming paradigms
Key Principles of Functional Programming
How &amp;quot;control flow&amp;quot; is implemented in Functional Programming
Functional design patterns for data pipeline design in Python, and how they improve reproducibility and maintainability
Whether it is possible to write a purely functional program in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk assumes basic understanding of building data pipelines with functions and classes/objects. While the main target audience are data scientists/engineers and developers building data-intensive applications, anyone with hands-on experience in imperative programming (including Python) would be able to understand the key concepts and use-cases in functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Speed Up Your Data Processing: Parallel and Asynchronous Programming in Data Sci – PyCon Taiwan 2020</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2020/speed-up-your-data-processing-parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-in-data-sci-pycon-taiwan-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chin Hwee Ong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-06:/pycon-taiwan-2020/speed-up-your-data-processing-parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-in-data-sci-pycon-taiwan-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R3 11:10–11:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly waiting for your data processing code to finish executing? Through real-life stories, we will explore how to leverage on parallel and asynchronous programming in Python to speed up your data processing pipelines - so that you could focus more on getting value …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, R3 11:10–11:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly waiting for your data processing code to finish executing? Through real-life stories, we will explore how to leverage on parallel and asynchronous programming in Python to speed up your data processing pipelines - so that you could focus more on getting value out of your data. While this talk assumes a basic understanding of processes in data pipelines and data science workflows, anyone with a basic understanding of the Python language would be able to understand the concepts and use cases illustrated with analogies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/ongchinhwee/speed-up-your-data-processing-parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-in-python"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/ongchinhwee/speed-up-your-data-processing-parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Chin Hwee Ong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ong Chin Hwee is a data engineer, aspiring polymath and Industry 4.0 enthusiast who happens to be interested in things that fly (and stuff that burn to keep things flying). Hailing from a background in aerospace engineering and computational modelling, Chin Hwee has experience working on innovative projects in collaboration with academia and industry partners. Chin Hwee is a contributor to the documentation for pandas 1.0 and enjoys sharing her experiences at meetups and conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2020"></category></entry></feed>