<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lindsay Muscato</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lindsay-muscato.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>No Community Members Were Harmed in the Making of This Doc Sprint: How we ran a 48-hour event to collect community wisdom into a guidebook for newsroom developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/no-community-members-were-harmed-in-the-making-of-this-doc-sprint-how-we-ran-a-48-hour-event-to-collect-community-wisdom-into-a-guidebook-for-newsroom-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Pitts</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/no-community-members-were-harmed-in-the-making-of-this-doc-sprint-how-we-ran-a-48-hour-event-to-collect-community-wisdom-into-a-guidebook-for-newsroom-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For developers in newsrooms, whose work supports great writing and
journalism all day long, writing their own docs often falls by the
wayside. News deadlines can leave little time for cleanup and
documentation (much less the planning that leads to reusable code). At
OpenNews, these developers, designers, and data …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For developers in newsrooms, whose work supports great writing and
journalism all day long, writing their own docs often falls by the
wayside. News deadlines can leave little time for cleanup and
documentation (much less the planning that leads to reusable code). At
OpenNews, these developers, designers, and data analysts are our
community, and we designed a series of small events to address that time
crunch. We bring people together a few times a year to refine, document,
and release open-source projects, because a common set of tools means
more time spent covering the news, less time on recreating code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these events, we''ve seen a common set of cultural and technical
questions come up before, during, and after projects--but our community
didn''t have a common pool of answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last year, we did something about it. Inspired by collaborative book-
writing projects, we put together a community documentation sprint in
December 2016. The goal: to draft a guidebook for releasing newsroom
code. Over two intensive days, 11 contributors gathered with us in
Washington, D.C., and another dozen signed on as remote editors.
Together, they captured our community''s best practices for
open-sourcing software, specifically in the context of newsrooms and
journalism. They worked in pairs or small groups, clustered around
laptops, collaborating for long stretches of writing. We fed them many
snacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Field Guide to Open Source in the Newsroom launched in February, and
we learned a lot as it came together. We''d love to tell you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we recruited and prepared a diverse, expert team of participants
for a productive event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we ran the two-day documentation sprint, with a flexible,
supportive structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we built in time for followthrough after the event, with plans
for outreach, adoption and onboarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And how we made the whole thing human-friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Portland 2017"></category></entry></feed>