<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hacking Mailing Lists - The Mailman 3 API Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pune-2017/hacking-mailing-lists-the-mailman-3-api-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mailman, the well-known and trusted Mailing list manager, introduced a
number of APIs in version 3.0 that make it a much more modular system
than previous versions. These APIs can be used to manage your Mailman
instance and to access mailing list posts as they travel through the
system. This talk is an introduction to those APIs and how you can use
them to integrate Mailman 3 into your own applications and integrate it
with your own business processes and systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About Mailman 3’s basic architecture and which LMTP-, REST- and
Python-based APIs are available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Mailman 3 uses its APIs internally for its management web UI
(Postorius) and archiver (HyperKitty)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can use Mailman 3’s REST API to programatically create new
lists, subscribe users, change settings and preferences and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can access list posts for further processing before they
leave the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about some interesting new sub projects that use and enhance
these APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll sprint on Mailman at the developer sprints - come hack with me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Florian Fuchs</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-16:pycon-pune-2017/hacking-mailing-lists-the-mailman-3-api-ecosystem.html</guid></item><item><title>GNU Mailman 3 and Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2014/gnu-mailman-3-and-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GNU Mailman, the popular mailing list manager has undergone a major
redesign. One of the changes is the separation of the web user
interfaces from the core engine and the use of Django for list
management and archiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk shows how these interfaces use Mailman's internal APIs, how
they can be integrated into existing Django projects and how they can be
customized and extended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/FNEp/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/FNEp/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Florian Fuchs</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-09-13:djangocon-us-2014/gnu-mailman-3-and-django.html</guid></item></channel></rss>