<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_portia-burton.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python Blockchain and Byte-Size Change</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/python-blockchain-and-byte-size-change.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Portia Burton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/python-blockchain-and-byte-size-change.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 keynote by Portia Burton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will answer the question of what is bitcoin and the blockchain and will end with a quick tutorial on how to create a blockchain application in Flask. We will not only make a bitcoin application, but we will also reflect upon the implications of this cutting edge technology to the greater society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin and blockchain technology has been in the news as of late, such as the hard fork of Ethereum to the hack of Bitifnex. This talk will cover the basics of blockchain technology and we will learn how to build an application that accepts bitcoin. Armed with a little knowledge of Flask and REST we will be able to use Python to bridge the gap between current events and technology. As Python developers we will be able to add to the narrative of bitcoin/blockchain technology in a unique and meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bitcoin"></category><category term="blockchain"></category></entry><entry><title>Know Thy Neighbor: Scikit and the K-Nearest Neighbor Algorithm</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/know-thy-neighbor-scikit-and-the-k-nearest-neigh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Portia Burton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-13:pycon-us-2014/know-thy-neighbor-scikit-and-the-k-nearest-neigh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the great features of Python is its machine learning
capabilities. Scikit is a rich Python package which allows developers to
create predictive apps. In this presentation, we will guess what type of
music do Python programmers like to listen to, using Scikit and the
k-nearest neighbor algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>