<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Rainu Ittycheriah</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Remote Collaboration: How to Build Human Connection Across Pixels</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2022/remote-collaboration-how-to-build-human-connection-across-pixels.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thesis/Description: At the core of all learning is human connection and
vulnerability. We have to encourage folks to ease the anxiety and fear
with imposter syndrome by knowing each other well. This leads to better
code, better culture, and better products by intentional collaboration
and learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rainu Ittycheriah</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-30:/pyohio-2022/remote-collaboration-how-to-build-human-connection-across-pixels.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2022</category></item><item><title>Data Engineering: The World Between Worlds</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2024/data-engineering-the-world-between-worlds.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data engineering is an often misunderstood, conflated range of skills
from database administration, analytics, ETL, cloud infrastructure, big
data and back. As someone who worked as a data engineer for just over 5
years, I’d love to share my stories about my time as a data engineer to
pull back the curtain on what kind of value you might be able to get
from data engineering as the heat of ML Ops and AI takes flight, both as
organization and individual. Notably, many data engineering teams
heavily leverage Python due to the depth and breadth of the data
libraries, and the ease by which folks can learn Python to start
creating value within the space. We'll also talk about a few of the key
libraries that you can learn to set yourself apart if you decide data
engineering is for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rainu Ittycheriah</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-27:/pyohio-2024/data-engineering-the-world-between-worlds.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2024</category></item></channel></rss>