<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Echopype: Enhancing the Interoperability and Scalability of Ocean Sonar Data Processing for Biological Information</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/echopype-enhancing-the-interoperability-and-scalability-of-ocean-sonar-data-processing-for-biological-information.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instrumentation advancements in the last decade have produced a deluge of ocean sonar data. These data provide opportunities to study the marine ecosystems at unprecedented spatial and temporal scales. However, to date, these data remain significantly under-utilized, mainly due to the lack of data interoperability and scalable analysis workflow. We address these challenges by developing an open-source Python package, echopype, which defines an interoperable netCDF file format and leverages the power of Xarray and Dask for explicit and efficient sonar data analysis in the Jupyter environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wu-Jung Lee</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/echopype-enhancing-the-interoperability-and-scalability-of-ocean-sonar-data-processing-for-biological-information.html</guid></item><item><title>From Novice to Data Ninja</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2017/from-novice-to-data-ninja.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial aims to introduce beginner Python learners to the diverse types of data a data scientist may face at work: time series, images, videos, text, graphs, geospatial data. In two hours participants will become comfortable handling each type of data and extracting interesting information from it. Participants will also learn tips and tricks how to handle large datasets of each kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are all around us and come in all sizes and shapes. As a beginner Python learner you often dream to become a master of all data types and handle them with ease: but soon you get intimidated by piles of libraries and unfamiliar jargon surrounding specific data formats and processing tools. The good news is that once you overcome the initial hurdles, you realize that you can analyze these diverse datasets using similar methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this tutorial is to provide participants with hands-on experience working with diverse types of data: text, sound, video, graphs, GIS. Each data module will include an example with a small dataset to introduce the properties of the data type, and one with a larger dataset to equip the learners with tools to handle the vast data in the wild. Throughout the tutorial we will illustrate how same data mining techniques can be used on different types of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/valentina-s/Novice2DataNinja"&gt;https://github.com/valentina-s/Novice2DataNinja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valentina Staneva</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-06:pydata-seattle-2017/from-novice-to-data-ninja.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item></channel></rss>