<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modeling Search Term Revenue: Using Embedding Layers to Manage High Cardinality Categorical Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/modeling-search-term-revenue-using-embedding-layers-to-manage-high-cardinality-categorical-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At System1, data scientists are faced with the task of predicting
revenue and cost per click across millions of unique keywords that drive
traffic to our sites or monetize on a pay per click basis. This talk
will show a variety of techniques we use to extract the most information
from categorical variables, especially anonymized, sparse, high
cardinality categorical variables, like search terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Categorical variables are easily interpretable by data scientists and
non- technical people, but they can also be difficult to translate into
machine learning algorithms. Categorical variables need to be converted
to quantitative values to be used in machine learning models and can
very quickly explode the feature space of a model, add noise or
unintended signals to the data, or simply not include all the meaning
and predictive power that feature provides for the dependent variable.
There are many popular and effective libraries that abstract categorical
variable feature creation. However, if a model is sensitive from a
financial, data ethics, or some level of public visibility standpoint,
or simply prone to overfitting, it is vital to understand how the model
is capturing all features and how to tune model parameters or input
data. Furthermore, if dealing with personal or sensitive data, machines
need to be able to handle anonymized categories while still allowing a
human to interpret the source data. One of the problems we face at
System1 is that individual keywords can receive very little traffic,
sometimes less than a click per day; however, across millions of
keywords, these long- tail keywords comprise significant revenue.
Furthermore, data science models need to be proactive and adjust bids
and traffic based on seasonal components even if there is no data from
the prior season. This talk will present a variety of practical
techniques to extract and retain information and predictive power for
categorical variables. We will talk about model selection, feature
creation and techniques for converting categorical variables to
quantitative values for modeling. Finally, the talk will present an
interesting technique that utilizes embedding layers and transfer
learning in a neural network framework to predict cost per click values
on search terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fletcher Riehl</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:pydata-la-2019/modeling-search-term-revenue-using-embedding-layers-to-manage-high-cardinality-categorical-data.html</guid></item></channel></rss>