<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Analyse Yourselves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2015/analyse-yourselves.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract: In today's mundane usage of digital services, from ecommerce
to day- to-day email, one might imagine that we generate a considerable
amount of data. We access the internet, our phones are constantly
generating information and sharing that with services, sometimes without
us being total aware of such, and even our household appliances are
starting to become more and more self sufficient and connected, the so
called internet of things or internet of everything. Can we start
getting in control of that data? What tools do we have available to
start getting a sense of what's the size/shape/kind of data that we
generate? Where does it come from and where do we send it to? Although
the talk title might suggestion topics around introspection and
psychoanalysis we are not going to get into that (not in psychological
ground at least) but we will look into in which ways could we build
small sets of applications that could give us a better sense of our
digital footprint and content that flows at our broadband connection. We
will be analysing samples of email, internet traffic, webapps and mobile
apps data connections and inflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning objectives: Use simple python libraries we will be looking into
what we can do tap on our devices and keep track of our digital inflows
like scapy and httplib2 Tools available to analyse and store and this
data, mostly around pandas and mongodb Libraries to present and
visualize this information like seaborn and matplotlib Tools for
predictive analytics like anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is practical session where we will be discussing some of these
general aspects of the data crossing &amp;quot;our pipes&amp;quot; and what we can do with
that to learn a bit more of ourselves or which type of interactions do
we do in a quantifiable manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be using quantifiable and measurable traffic from several
different feeds including your facebook timeline, twitter feeds, email
and internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Norberto Leite</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-20:pycon-uk-2015/analyse-yourselves.html</guid></item></channel></rss>