<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Harsh Bardhan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_harsh-bardhan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Build Serverless Python Applications using AWS Chalice</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/build-serverless-python-applications-using-aws-chalice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Harsh Bardhan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/build-serverless-python-applications-using-aws-chalice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build Serverless Python Applications using AWS Chalice
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Ni]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Harsh Bardhan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of Serverless Applications, Developers now focus on developing the Code Logic and allow their Cloud Service Provider to focus on the deployment. Serverless exactly doesn’t mean that there are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build Serverless Python Applications using AWS Chalice
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Ni]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Harsh Bardhan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of Serverless Applications, Developers now focus on developing the Code Logic and allow their Cloud Service Provider to focus on the deployment. Serverless exactly doesn’t mean that there are no servers. It just means that we don’t need to provision and maintain them. The Cloud Service Provider takes care of packaging and deployment almost instantaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) released an interesting Micro Web-Framework named: Chalice. It features everything would want from a Serverless Framework to develop and deploy applications using Python. With an easy to understand syntax, a unified Command Line Interface to create and deploy applications with ease of development experience, Chalice is a must.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk would introduce you to the Serverless Environment on Amazon Web Services and how you can develop and deploy Python-based Production Grade RESTful API Services using Chalice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Serverless?
Background to AWS Lambda
Setting up a Project on Chalice
Developing a REST API Service
Deploying the Application on AWS
Testing the API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the talk, we will learn how you can run your Code on Serverless Platforms like AWS. We will also have set up an API on AWS tied up with various other AWS Services at ease. Finally, we will be taking a look at how Chalice aims to improve the developer experience with ease through the intuitive use of Serverless Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry></feed>