<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Practical API Security</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/practical-api-security.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the dominance of Mobile Apps, Single Page Apps for the Web, and
Micro-Services, we are all building more APIs than ever before. Like
many other developers, I had struggled with finding the right mix of
security and simplicity for securing APIs. Some standards from the IETF
have made it possible to accomplish both. Let me show you how to utilize
existing libraries to lock down you API without writing a ton of code.
In this tutorial, you will learn how to write a secure API with future
proof security utilizing JOSE. JOSE is a collection of complimentary
standards: JWT, JWE, JWS, JWA, and JWK. JOSE is used by OAuth, OpenID,
and others to secure communications between APIs and consumers. Now you
can use it to secure your API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Englander</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-02:pycon-us-2019/practical-api-security.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Practical API Security</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/practical-api-security.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the dominance of Mobile Apps, Single Page Apps for the Web, and Micro-Services, we are all building more APIs than ever before. Like many other developers, I had struggled with finding the right mix of security and simplicity for securing APIs. Some standards from the IETF have made it possible to accomplish both. Let me show you how to utilize existing libraries to lock down you API without writing a ton of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will learn how to write a secure API with future proof security utilizing JOSE. JOSE is a collection of complimentary standards: JWT, JWE, JWS, JWA, and JWK. JOSE is used by OAuth, OpenID, and others to secure communications between APIs and consumers. Now you can use it to secure your API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Englander</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-09:pycon-us-2018/practical-api-security.html</guid><category>jose</category></item><item><title>Got Python I/O: IoT Development in Python via GPIO</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2016/got-python-io-iot-development-in-python-via-gpio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build real Internet of Things (IoT) applications with pure Python and General Purpose Input/Output (GPIO). Thanks to devices like the Raspberry Pi and Intel Edison, full Linux systems with GPIO are accessible to the masses. Learn how build a true IoT device using only hardware and core Python libraries and hardware costing less than $50 US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Englander</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-31:pyohio-2016/got-python-io-iot-development-in-python-via-gpio.html</guid></item></channel></rss>