<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - David Koop</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Notebook Archaeology: What does an ipynb file not tell us?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/notebook-archaeology-what-does-an-ipynb-file-not-tell-us.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks store code, results, and explanations, making them important artifacts in understanding how insights were achieved. However, these notebooks often do not record the full history of how ideas developed or analyses evolved. In many cases, approaches have been refined over time, and cells are repeated, reordered, or removed. This talk will examine both what we can learn from the details stored in .ipynb files and associated artifacts like IPython session histories as well as techniques to better record the evolution of notebooks in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inferring Past Events
A notebook represents the current state of one's work, but it also maintains information that helps us learn about what happened in the past. Specifically, the execution counts (those bracketed numbers in the left margin of the notebook) not only provide information about the order cells were executed but also can tell us when a result can no longer be seen. IPython session histories store every block of executed code but are not unambiguously connected to the notebook cells and outputs. However, notebooks and histories together provide information about patterns in notebook development including how often authors edit cells or revisit a notebook at a later date. We can infer a probable history based on these patterns, and improve our prediction when the two artifacts are connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving Future Records
While algorithms to figure out what happened in the past are useful in understanding existing notebooks, we can also simply record all of the steps in a notebook's evolution---a version history. There are a number of solutions in this space, ranging from alternate notebook formats that mesh better with version control systems to tools that automatically store each version of a cell and its outputs. We will discuss the pros and cons of these different approaches in terms of what is recorded and how it is made available. While having the full history can be useful during development, there may be cases where sharing that history is not desired. At the same time, we will discuss opportunities to move beyond documenting history to using that information to improve work in a notebook. For example, knowing how a user has made changes in the past could allow suggestions for updates in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Koop</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/notebook-archaeology-what-does-an-ipynb-file-not-tell-us.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item><item><title>VisTrails: A Python-Based Scientific Workflow and Provenance System (#172)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/vistrails-a-python-based-scientific-workflow-and.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;VisTrails: A Python-Based Scientific Workflow and Provenance System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by David Koop (University of Utah and VisTrails, Inc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will give an overview of VisTrails
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vistrails.org/"&gt;http://www.vistrails.org&lt;/a&gt;), a
python-based open- source scientific workflow that transparently
captures provenance (i.e., lineage) of both data products and the
processes used to derive these products. We will show how VisTrails can
be used to streamline data exploration and visualization. Using real
examples, we will demonstrate key features of the system, including the
ability to visually create information processing pipelines that combine
multiple tools and Iibraries such as VTK, pylab, and matplotlib. We will
also show how VisTrails leverages provenance information not only to
support result reproducibility, but also to simplify the creation and
refinement of pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Koop</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:/pycon-us-2010/vistrails-a-python-based-scientific-workflow-and.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2010</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>scientific</category><category>vistrails</category></item><item><title>Dataflow Notebooks Encoding and Using Cell Dependencies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/dataflow-notebooks-encoding-and-using-cell-dependencies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dataflow notebooks extend the Jupyter Notebook environment and IPython kernel to allow users to construct clear dependencies between cells, making it possible to construct a graph that details all defined dependencies between cells. In this environment, unique, persistent cell identifiers make references between cells more robust than existing solutions. Using the dependency graph, we can dynamically update upstream dependencies for a cell or select downstream cells that depend on the current one. This helps users better organize their work, allows for non-linear orderings of cells, and enables greater reproducibility and more opportunities for reuse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Koop</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:/scipy-2017/dataflow-notebooks-encoding-and-using-cell-dependencies.html</guid><category>SciPy 2017</category></item></channel></rss>