<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Coding as Enrichment: How to Empower Students with Creative Coding Experiences</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/coding-as-enrichment-how-to-empower-students-with-creative-coding-experiences.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My goal is to share resources, pedagogy, best practices and lessons
learned in bringing hands-on coding workshops to underserved K-12
students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fall 2017 over ten weeks, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codeparkhouston.org/"&gt;Code Park Houston&lt;/a&gt;, a a 501(c)(3)
non-profit organization piloted a free after-school Creative Coding
program at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.bakerripley.org/locations/leonel-castillo-community-center"&gt;BakerRipley - Leonel Castillo | BakerRipley&lt;/a&gt;. We focused
on &lt;strong&gt;Coding as Enrichment&lt;/strong&gt; by encouraging our students to pursue
creative endeavors such as storytelling with Minecraft and making
procedural art with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://p5js.org/get-started/"&gt;p5.js | get started&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of traversing a
programming language’s syntax peculiarities, our students drew colorful
lines, made interactive buttons, and shared their creations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also worked to provide a positive and collaborative learning
environment. Our students were encouraged to learn by making mistakes
and exploring his or her own interests. In the process, we just happened
to facilitate knowledge in coding, problem-solving, electronics science
and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to technology, the arts can be an unusual pathway to
success. But we know and see that creativity is the secret sauce that
inspires the next generation of diverse and passionate students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program was a rewarding experience for everyone involved. We faced
and overcame many challenges. For the talk I would like to share:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools of the Trade&lt;/strong&gt; — what software and hardware we used and why.
&lt;strong&gt;Classroom Set Up&lt;/strong&gt; — how to provide a positive and encouraging
learning environment. &lt;strong&gt;Best Practices for Tech Educators&lt;/strong&gt; — why we are
learning facilitators. &lt;strong&gt;Open Source Creative Coding Curriculum&lt;/strong&gt; — open
source curriculum to be used in your own classroom!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wanjun Zhang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/coding-as-enrichment-how-to-empower-students-with-creative-coding-experiences.html</guid></item></channel></rss>