<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Michael Winser</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>State of Python Supply Chain Security (Sponsor: Alpha-Omega)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/state-of-python-supply-chain-security-sponsor-alpha-omega.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alpha-Omega is investing in the security of open source software
ecosystems like Python by staffing security champions focused on
improving software supply chain security. In this session attendees will
hear from the inaugural PSF Security Developer-in-Residence about
improvements that have been made to Python and how through collaboration
and knowledge sharing the tides are raised for all ecosystems and users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Seth Michael Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/state-of-python-supply-chain-security-sponsor-alpha-omega.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Reviewing another year of security partnership between the PSF &amp; Alpha-Omega (Sponsor: Alpha-Omega)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/reviewing-another-year-of-security-partnership-between-the-psf-alpha-omega-sponsor-alpha-omega.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alpha-Omega's mission is to protect society by catalyzing sustainable security improvements to the most critical open source software projects and ecosystems. Funded by Amazon AWS, Google, Microsoft, and Citi, Alpha-Omega has partnered with the Python Software Foundation to support two critical security-focused roles for the Python Ecosystem. Last year's talk with Seth Larson and Michael Winser was the origin story of this effort and showed the road ahead. This year's talk will be at least 50% more interesting and entertaining because we're adding Mike Fiedler. Together we have a lot to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Winser is the co-founder of Alpha-Omega. Seth Larson is the Python Security Developer in Residence and Mike Fiedler is the PyPI Safety and Security Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Seth Michael Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-15:/pycon-us-2025/reviewing-another-year-of-security-partnership-between-the-psf-alpha-omega-sponsor-alpha-omega.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item></channel></rss>