<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sarah-bird.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The Web is Terrifying! Using the PyData stack to spy on the spies.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/the-web-is-terrifying-using-the-pydata-stack-to-spy-on-the-spies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/the-web-is-terrifying-using-the-pydata-stack-to-spy-on-the-spies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all know the internet can be a scary place. In this talk I’ll focus
on two ways I’ve found it positively terrifying. First, digging into
tracking technologies, I have learned about the breadth and depth of
ways our online activity is monitored, stored, and repackaged. Second,
when starting out to learn a new skill, the tidal wave of information
available online can be overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the PyData stack to explore and visualize different data sources,
including a new dataset from Mozilla, we’ll examine some of the many
types of online tracking. My goal is to leave the audience with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A sense of the breadth of tools in the PyData toolbox that can be
applied to a real-world analysis 2) An understanding of a few methods
of online tracking so they can be more informed internet citizens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, now that the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation
(GDPR) has come into force, we can explore the data in light of EU
citizens’ new rights, and the new responsibilities of companies
worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I’ll also talk about becoming a software engineer, then a
builder of data science tools, and my new journey into data science.
Being self-taught can be, lonely, scary, and full of embarrassing
pitfalls. I’ll share some stories about my learning journey, and the
people and resources that have supported me.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The web is terrifying</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2018/the-web-is-terrifying.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-05:pycon-israel-2018/the-web-is-terrifying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using PyData tools and a new dataset from Mozilla, we can explore some of the many ways we are tracked around the internet, and look at what this means now that the EU's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) has come into force. Sarah will also talk about becoming a software engineer, then a builder of data science tools, and her new journey into a data science.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting started with Bokeh / Let's build an interactive data visualization for the web..in Python!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-19:pydata-london-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bokeh data visualization library allows you to build interactive
visualizations for the web in python. This training gives a quick
introduction to Bokeh's unique features. We'll do exercixes building
up a variety of visualizations and finish discussing topics and
questions from participants related to their own datasets &amp;amp; needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/"&gt;Bokeh data visualization library&lt;/a&gt;
allows you to build interactive visualizations for the web in python. It
has a range of capabilities from quick &amp;quot;one-line&amp;quot; charts to streaming
datasets to integrating with your existing plot libraries such as
matplotlib or ggplot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This training gives a quick hands-on introduction to Bokeh's core
features. We'll do exercises building up a variety of visualizations and
finish up discussing topics and questions from participants related to
their own datasets &amp;amp; needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the planned outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes) Bokeh feature walk-through. The relationship between
bokeh, bokehjs and bokeh-server. The various API levels of bokeh
(models, plotting, charts). And, examples of a variety of
visualizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): Exercises - 1 - The charts &amp;amp; plotting interface. Get
quickly plotting in an ipython notebook. Different types of data
accepted, and how to customize a plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(10 minutes): Tips for navigating the Bokeh docs and examples as
you're getting up to speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): Exercises - 2 - (a) The models interface. Build a
custom plot from the ground up using the Models API. (b) Quick, yet
custom, using the charts interface and models together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(10 minutes): Sharing your plots. Overview of the different ways to
share your plots with your colleagues and the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): Exercises - 3 - Add custom interactivity - Customize
your hover and selections. Implement linked selection, brushing, and
panning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(20 minutes): open space for questions and interactively solving
Bokeh problems on your real-life problems &amp;amp; data as time permits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Let it shine - telling your data story</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/let-it-shine-telling-your-data-story.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/let-it-shine-telling-your-data-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You work for weeks on a new analysis, collecting, cleaning data,
modeling it, you arrive at a new result. What happens next? How many
people explore your results--and wider work? Bokeh is a data
visualization library that gives you the power of web-based custom
interactive visualizations, but lets you build them in Python. We'll
talk about moving seamlessly from analysis to engaging presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You work for weeks, maybe months, on a new analysis: collecting data,
cleaning it, extracting your features and modeling it, and you finally
come up with some meaningful results... What happens next? How many
people dig into and explore your work and your results?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a data visualization library that gives you the power of
custom interactive visualizations that you can publish on the web, but
lets you build them in python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting Started with Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/getting-started-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-14:pydata-carolinas-2016/getting-started-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a python interactive visualization library that uses web
browsers for its presentation. Bokeh supports a wide variety of
visualization tasks from basic exploration through to building
advanced data applications. In this tutorial we'll cover Bokeh's basic
concepts and go from plotting a scatter plot to building an
interactive dashboard that can run a clustering algorithm from a
dropdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a python interactive visualization library that uses web
browsers for its presentation. Bokeh supports a wide variety of
visualization tasks from basic exploration through to building
advanced data applications. In this tutorial we'll cover Bokeh's basic
concepts and go from plotting a scatter plot to building an
interactive dashboard that can run a clustering algorithm from a
dropdown - you'll be surprised how easy that is.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting started with Bokeh / Let's build an interactive data visualization for the web..in Python!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-06:europython-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Bird - Getting started with Bokeh / Let's build an interactive data visualization for the web..in Python!
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: [birdsarah.github.io/europython-2015-bokeh][1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a web developer, I find myself being asked to make increasing
numbers of data visualizations, interactive infographics, and more.
d3.js is great, as are many other javascript toolkits that are out
there. But if I can write more Python and less JavaScript... well,
that makes me happy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a new Python library for interactive visualization. Its
origins are in the data science community, but it has a lot to offer
web developers. In this mini-tutorial, I'll run through how to build a
data visualization in Bokeh and how to hook it into your web
application. This will be a real-world example, that was previously
built in d3.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I'll provide tips and tricks that I've discovered in my
experience including how Bokeh works wonderfully with the iPython
notebook which I use to prototype my visualizations, and many data
science people use as their native way to explore data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who already know a little Bokeh, I'll be covering the
new &amp;quot;actions framework&amp;quot; that lets you write JS callbacks in your
python code so you can do lots of interactions all on the client side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://birdsarah.github.io/europython-2015-bokeh/"&gt;http://birdsarah.github.io/europython-2015-bokeh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive data for the web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/interactive-data-for-the-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-12:pycon-us-2015/interactive-data-for-the-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interactive data visualization libraries are mostly a JavaScript
stronghold. The new Python library, Bokeh, provides a simple, clean way
to make more shiny things. Although it comes from the data science
community, it has a lot to offer web developers. For a visualization you
might have built in d3.js, I'll show how to build it in Bokeh, how to
test it, and how to hook it into your web app.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>