<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_adam-paszke.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PyTorch as a scientific computing library: past, present and future</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/pytorch-as-a-scientific-computing-library-past-present-and-future.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Paszke</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/pytorch-as-a-scientific-computing-library-past-present-and-future.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is very well known for its ecosystem of mature scientific
computing packages. Despite that, the rapidly rising popularity of deep
learning resulted in creation of a number of new libraries, including
PyTorch. Although originally they were meant to provide better support
for those domain specific use cases, one can come to a conclusion, that
they can actually have wider applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll showcase the main ideas behind PyTorch - a relatively
new library focusing on usability and good integration with other Python
packages. I’ll cover some interesting use cases, ranging from ones more
specific to machine learning, to those more generally applicable in
other scientific computing areas. I’ll also cover some recently added
features, and talk a bit about our future roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyTorch: a modern scientific computing library for Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/pytorch-a-modern-scientific-computing-library-for-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Paszke</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/pytorch-a-modern-scientific-computing-library-for-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is very well known for its ecosystem of mature scientific
computing packages. They range from low-level providers of generic
functionality like NumPy to very domain specific tools like
scikit-learn. A few years back, machine learning frameworks could be
easily classified into the second category, but this is changing now.
They become increasingly powerful and start to be applied in a whole
variety of settings different than their original purpose. In this talk,
I’ll present a basic tour of PyTorch, a relatively new library that has
already gathered a significant user base. I’ll describe features useful
both in machine learning and other domains, explain how it fits into the
Python landscape, and showcase scenarios where it provides benefits over
existing tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;domenica 22 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="Pytorch"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry></feed>