<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Curse of the Django Podcast by Elena Williams</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/the-curse-of-the-django-podcast-by-elena-williams.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Django community is full of amazing, enthusiastic and multi-talented
individuals who love to take on exciting new extra-curricular projects
in their massive amounts of spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Django podcast is an excellent example of this kind of project and it
is one that has been taken up no less than 5 times so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the latest to take up this torch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has so far been an amazing, educational, exhilarating experience: I
have had the honour of gathering the thoughts of some of the best,
brightest and most prolific in our community. It's been a load of work
but also a load of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come hear the story of how this has happened, and come to learn how you
can be part of the greater Django information and communication
machinery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon Australia is the national conference for users of the Python
Programming Language. In August 2014, we're heading to Brisbane to bring
together students, enthusiasts, and professionals with a love of Python
from around Australia, and all around the World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 1-5, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elena Williams</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-11:pycon-au-2014/the-curse-of-the-django-podcast-by-elena-williams.html</guid></item><item><title>Hitchhikers Guide to Participating in Open Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/hitchhikers-guide-to-participating-in-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curious about being involved in open source, but haven't had the time to
make the plunge? Involved with open source but a bit hazy on the way it
all works? Open source legend Andrew Tridgell runs an annual week-long
post-graduate primer course teaching &amp;quot;&amp;quot;Free and Open Source Software
Development &amp;quot;&amp;quot;. This talk will convey as much of this course as possible
in the time available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elena Williams</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-13:pycon-us-2014/hitchhikers-guide-to-participating-in-open-source.html</guid></item></channel></rss>