<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jose-dominguez.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Introduction to Image classification in Python: from API calls to Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/introduction-to-image-classification-in-python-from-api-calls-to-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dominguez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-06:pycon-ireland-2016/introduction-to-image-classification-in-python-from-api-calls-to-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world full of user generated media content, automated image and
video processing plays a prominent role, both in social media apps
(face, object, and place detection), and in local applications that
automatically sort media collections, among other uses. In the last
few years, a number of startups such as Clarifai and Indico, and much
bigger players such as Google and Microsoft, have launched their own
'machine learning as a service' offerings, including 'vision' products
that can recognise objects present in image and video footage and
automatically tag them, provide optical character recognition (OCR)
services, and even not safe for work (NSFW) classifiers that can be
used to omit content from internal networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on 'food' recognition within images, and will
walk through the basics of how to get started with image
classification, from using APIs and SDKs for some of the commercial
(but free) offerings available, to trying and recreate those services
locally, first by walking through and example of the 'bag of features'
technique, using a mix of supervised and unsupervised methods in
scikit-learn and OpenCV, and secondly showing examples based on
'transfer learning', a 'deep learning' technique to reuse pre-trained
convolutional neural networks to customise classification from smaller
training datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>