<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tiago Montes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tiago-montes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Don't do this at work</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/dont-do-this-at-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tiago Montes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:/europython-2019/dont-do-this-at-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I reframe a computer programming workshop for kids I
delivered earlier this year, exploring and sharing my experience
throughout that journey, from preparation to delivery, by recreating a
simple yet engaging enough game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that I'll both demonstrate several Python related techniques and
tools many may …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I reframe a computer programming workshop for kids I
delivered earlier this year, exploring and sharing my experience
throughout that journey, from preparation to delivery, by recreating a
simple yet engaging enough game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that I'll both demonstrate several Python related techniques and
tools many may not be aware of, on one hand, and, on the other, extract
provocative questions about general learning processes, especially when
targeted at professional developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise zero slides and a somewhat fast-paced live (re)coding session,
intertwined with comments on good/bad techniques, along with a
surprising exploration of the turtle module in the Standard Library --
it is more capable than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrap up with a self-code review and with thoughts on how such a game
could be improved, what implications that could have for both beginners
and seasoned professionals: should you do this at work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeting 10 minute Q&amp;amp;A / discussion by the end!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2019"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Education"></category><category term="Learning"></category><category term="Life"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category></entry><entry><title>Native Packaging of GUI Apps on Windows and macOS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/native-packaging-of-gui-apps-on-windows-and-macos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tiago Montes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/native-packaging-of-gui-apps-on-windows-and-macos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Native Packaging of GUI Apps on Windows and macOS - presented by Tiago Montes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributing Python GUI applications to end users is a challenge: will they need to install Python? If so, which version? If not, how do they install the application? From …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Native Packaging of GUI Apps on Windows and macOS - presented by Tiago Montes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributing Python GUI applications to end users is a challenge: will they need to install Python? If so, which version? If not, how do they install the application? From a random ZIP file? How native does the process feel? Will their system trust your code? For a fluid experience, it needs to be signed and (on macOS) notarized beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;cite&gt;pup&lt;/cite&gt; (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.org/project/pup/"&gt;https://pypi.org/project/pup/&lt;/a&gt;), the tool that the Mu Editor (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codewith.mu/"&gt;https://codewith.mu/&lt;/a&gt;) development team has created to package and distribute it in platform-native formats to Windows and macOS users around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session I will show how &lt;cite&gt;pup&lt;/cite&gt; can be used to package GUI Applications for distribution: natively on Windows and macOS, and in early stages of development for distribution-agnostic Linux artifacts. In short, if it's &lt;cite&gt;pip&lt;/cite&gt;-installable it is &lt;cite&gt;pup&lt;/cite&gt;-packageable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will then describe the way &lt;cite&gt;pup&lt;/cite&gt; works (and how it differs from comparable tools) leading on to a call-for-action moment, where I'll share its current state of development, what's good, what's bad, and where I'd like it to be headed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll wrap up the talk with a set of future-looking thoughts that &lt;cite&gt;pup&lt;/cite&gt; has helped identify not only on the specifics of CPython's distribution, but also on the Python ecosystem as whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>