<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How GPU Computing literally saved me at work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/how-gpu-computing-literally-saved-me-at-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distributed/Parallel computing is at the heart of new technology. Every
company, big or small want to make most of the technology available to
them. One such niche technology is GPU computing. Here, I present to you
a real- world application on how GPU can save computing efforts and
reduce the computation time from 2 days to 20 seconds. Shared is a live
application from Retail domain utilizing GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed/Parallel computing is at the heart of new technology. Every
company, big or small want to make most of the technology available to
them. One such niche technology is GPU computing. If used cautiously can
save a lot of computing efforts and time across the applications.
Business, with the boom in Machine learning/Deep learning techniques,
are on the way to leverage this technology in their day to day work.
Here, I present to you a real-time application on how GPU can save
computing efforts and reduce the computation time from 2 days to 20
seconds. The talk will cover the best case scenarios and use case for
the GPU implementing for recommendations at scale. The talk will start
with the overview of the problem at hand, comparing CPU and GPU
processing time and best fit to utilize GPU for the task in hand or any
other scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those, interested in delving into the detailed code utilized for the
same, here’s the link to my blog containing the same,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/walmartlabs/how-gpu-computing-literally-saved-me-at-work"&gt;https://medium.com/walmartlabs/how-gpu-computing-literally-saved-me-at-work&lt;/a&gt;-
fc1dc70f48b6&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abhishek Mungoli</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-03:pydata-delhi-2019/how-gpu-computing-literally-saved-me-at-work.html</guid></item></channel></rss>