<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jadey Ryan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jadey-ryan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Parameterized Quarto Reports Improve Understanding of Soil Health</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/parameterized-quarto-reports-improve-understanding-of-soil-health.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jadey Ryan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/parameterized-quarto-reports-improve-understanding-of-soil-health.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use R and Quarto parameterized reporting in this four-step workflow to automate custom HTML and Word reports that are thoughtfully designed for audience interpretation and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soil health data are notoriously challenging to tidy and effectively communicate to farmers. We used functional programming with the tidyverse …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use R and Quarto parameterized reporting in this four-step workflow to automate custom HTML and Word reports that are thoughtfully designed for audience interpretation and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soil health data are notoriously challenging to tidy and effectively communicate to farmers. We used functional programming with the tidyverse to reproducibly streamline data cleaning and summarization. To improve project outreach, we developed a Quarto project to dynamically create interactive HTML reports and printable PDFs. Custom to every farmer, reports include project goals, measured parameter descriptions, summary statistics, maps, tables, and graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our case study presents a workflow for data preparation and parameterized reporting, with best practices for effective data visualization, interpretation, and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk materials: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://jadeyryan.com/talks/2023-09-25_posit_parameterized-quarto/"&gt;https://jadeyryan.com/talks/2023-09-25_posit_parameterized-quarto/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>