<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_barbara-shaurette.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Things that are tired: Uggs, Segways and YOU! Coming back from burnout</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/things-that-are-tired-uggs-segways-and-you-by.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Barbara Shaurette</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-19:djangocon-us-2015/things-that-are-tired-uggs-segways-and-you-by.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things That are Tired: Uggs, Segways and you! Coming Back from Burnout
by Barbara Shaurette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is burnout such a bad thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I see that question on paper, the answer seems obvious. But in
nearly a decade in this community, I've seen people run themselves into
the ground without realizing that they can - and should - take the time
to rest. Why? Well, the short answer is that, if you don't take a break
once in a while, the quality of your work suffers. But the long and more
involved answer? Well, as a wise man once said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Life moves pretty fast. If you don't stop and look around once in a
while, you could miss it.&amp;quot; Burnout leads to exhaustion, and that leads
to terrible performance. And no one wants to be known for performing
terribly - we all have too much pride for that. History is full of
examples of times when exhaustion led to disaster - remember the Exxon
Valdez? Imagine your open source project taking a header like that. I'm
actually going to get a little science-y here and cite a few studies, in
particular a recent one from Washington State University that shows how
sleep-deprived people have an impaired ability to take in new
information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can get plenty of sleep and still be burned out. If your
waking hours are consumed with community work, your relationships can
suffer, and your sanity will erode pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After nearly a decade in the Python and Django communities, I've
experienced periods of overwork that have made me hate everything I was
doing. I have a lot of good anecdotes, stories that will probably sound
familiar to everyone in the room. Luckily, I've also learned some
tactics for stepping back and recovering. It can be done, and it's
easier than people think. What you're going to hear from this talk is
just plain common sense. But sometimes when you're mired in work with no
obvious way out, you need to hear it from someone else. So I'm giving
everyone permission to let go. (And no, I promise, there will be no
'Frozen' references in my slides.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do you let go? And when?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnout is pretty easy to recognize if you know what to look for. Are
you staying up every night reading pull requests ... and is that your
primary method of interaction with other human beings? Your user group
may only meet once a month, but is that group still responsible for the
bulk of your email? Do you secretly blame them for your inability to get
to inbox zero? Is the only travel you're doing for conferences? Have you
given up on vacations and just decided to see the world one PyCon or
DjangoCon at a time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest indicator of burnout in the community is how you feel about
the community around you. When you find yourself starting to cringe
every time you get a new Twitter follower, it may be time to start
saying no to things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important piece of advice I have is to stop looking at what
other people are doing. We all know that person who seems to have a hand
in every project, but you can't judge your own performance by what you
imagine theirs to be. You don't know how they may be scrambling behind
the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember that just because you're invited into a conversation
doesn't mean that you have to contribute to it - sometimes listening is
enough. Emails can sometimes go unanswered - so can phone calls! Think
about what's most important in your life, and start directing your
energy towards those things instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't write so much code in your free time. Take a few nights off, go
outside - there's a lot to see out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your collaborators WILL understand. Especially if you announce your
intentions to the world. Send an email, tweet it out, let people know
you need some time off. You'll be surprised how much understanding
you'll get and how well people will respect your boundaries (you just
need to set them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HHB2/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HHB2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - Saturday evening</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/saturday-evening-lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katie Cunningham</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-16:pycon-us-2013/saturday-evening-lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks from Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=0m"&gt;00:00&lt;/a&gt; - Young Coders at PyCon 2013 - Katie Cunningham and
Barbara Shaurette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=5m53s"&gt;05:53&lt;/a&gt; - Raspberry Pi connected to sensors - Jack
Minardi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=8m23s"&gt;08:23&lt;/a&gt; - Python &amp;amp; ArcGIS for Transit Data Analysers -
Amy Smith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=13m58s"&gt;13:58&lt;/a&gt; - Software Version Management - Quinn Weaver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=19m48s"&gt;19:48&lt;/a&gt; - Parts and Scons - Jason Kenny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=25m13s"&gt;25:13&lt;/a&gt; - Debugging Python on Linux with Visual Studio
- Steve Dower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=37m35s"&gt;37:35&lt;/a&gt; - Titan Files for App Engine - Mike Fotinakis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ft6-r_vksDI#t=43m40s"&gt;43:40&lt;/a&gt; - Using git as a mercurial client - Dusty
Phillips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>The Young Coder: Let's Learn Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/the-young-coder-lets-learn-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Barbara Shaurette</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-12:pycon-us-2014/the-young-coder-lets-learn-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since PyCon 2013, interest in the Young Coders class has intensified.
Several Python conferences have run their own, and classes outside of
conferences - from one-time workshops to after school clubs - have
sprung up as well. With more people than ever interested in teaching
Python to kids, we're here to address how to organize a class. It takes
some effort to set up, but the payoff is enormous.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>