<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Reuven M. Lerner</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What happens when you import a module?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/what-happens-when-you-import-a-module.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - What happens when you import a module? - presented by Reuven M. Lerner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modules are a key feature of Python, allowing us to easily reuse our own code and take advantage of publicly available modules from PyPI. It's a rare program that doesn't include at least one &amp;quot;import&amp;quot; statement. But what actually happens when we import a module? How does Python find our file? How does it decide whether it should even try to find our module? And after it finds our module file, how does Python load it into memory, assigning to its attributes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll walk you through what happens when you &amp;quot;import&amp;quot; a module into Python. The mechanism is surprisingly complex, in no small part because it has to take so many possibilities into consideration. We'll talk about finders and loaders, and about the many ways in which you can customize the module-loading mechanism if you find a need to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've ever imported a module, then this talk will pull back the curtain a bit, helping you to understand what's happening under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/what-happens-when-you-import-a-module.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Stop using print! Understanding and using the "logging" module</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/stop-using-print-understanding-and-using-the-logging-module.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/stop-using-print-understanding-and-using-the-logging-module"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/stop-using-print-understanding-and-using-the-logging-module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're like me, then you've long known about Python's &amp;quot;logging&amp;quot; module, but you've ignored it because it seemed too complex. In this talk, I'll show you that &amp;quot;logging&amp;quot; is easy to learn and use, giving you far more flexibility than you can get from inserting calls to &amp;quot;print&amp;quot; all over your code. I'll show you how you can start to use &amp;quot;logging&amp;quot; right away -- but also how you can use it to create a sophisticated logging system that sends different types of output to different destinations. After this talk, you'll know how to use &amp;quot;logging&amp;quot;, and you'll be less likely to use &amp;quot;print&amp;quot; in your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/stop-using-print-understanding-and-using-the-logging-module.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>The PyArrow revolution in Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/the-pyarrow-revolution-in-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2A on 2024-07-10 ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PyArrow revolution in Pandas by Reuven M. Lerner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/the-pyarrow-revolution-in-pandas"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/the-pyarrow-revolution-in-pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandas has long used NumPy for its back-end storage. But things are changing, and the future of Pandas will likely be tied closely with PyArrow. What are Arrow and PyArrow? How do they affect Pandas users today, and how will they affect us in the future? In this talk, I introduce PyArrow, tell you what it does, how we can already use it in our Pandas work, and whether that's a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/the-pyarrow-revolution-in-pandas.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>Function Dissection Lab - Learn How Functions Work...｜Reuven M. Lerner｜PyCon APAC 2022</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2022/function-dissection-lab-learn-how-functions-workreuven-m-lernerpycon-apac-2022.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon APAC 2022｜一般演講 Talks｜國泰金控 Cathay Financial Holdings / 美光科技 Micron 冠名贊助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✏️ 共筆 Note：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/rJdGvpX1j"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/rJdGvpX1j&lt;/a&gt;
🖐🏻 Slido：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://app.sli.do/event/kS1oHFhANeSMmXLNnHfbmM"&gt;https://app.sli.do/event/kS1oHFhANeSMmXLNnHfbmM&lt;/a&gt;
💬 語言 Language：英文 English
🎯 層級 Level：中階 Intermediate
🔎 分類 Category：Python 核心 Python Core&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 摘要 Abstract 💡
What happens when you call a function? For that matter, what happens when you define a function? In this talk, we'll look at function objects, how they are built, and how they behave, with a particular emphasis on the different types of parameters we can define.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 講者介紹 About Speaker - Reuven M. Lerner 🚀
Teaching Python and data science around the world since 1995. Author of the books &amp;quot;Python Workout&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Pandas Workout&amp;quot;. Publisher of the &amp;quot;Better developers&amp;quot; newsletter. I spend each day trying to help people improve their Python skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#python #pycontw #pyconapac2022 #functiondissectionlab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycontw.blogspot.com"&gt;https://pycontw.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-03:/pycon-apac-2022/function-dissection-lab-learn-how-functions-workreuven-m-lernerpycon-apac-2022.html</guid><category>PyCon APAC 2022</category></item><item><title>When Is an Exception Not an Exception? Using Warnings in Python｜Reuven M. Lerner｜PyCon APAC 2022</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2022/when-is-an-exception-not-an-exception-using-warnings-in-pythonreuven-m-lernerpycon-apac-2022.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon APAC 2022｜一般演講 Talks｜國泰金控 Cathay Financial Holdings / 美光科技 Micron 冠名贊助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✏️ 共筆 Note：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/BkUzP6Xyj"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/BkUzP6Xyj&lt;/a&gt;
🖐🏻 Slido：&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://app.sli.do/event/4kNcBDETXQmm6Erje8Hjyp"&gt;https://app.sli.do/event/4kNcBDETXQmm6Erje8Hjyp&lt;/a&gt;
💬 語言 Language：英文 English
🎯 層級 Level：中階 Intermediate
🔎 分類 Category：Python 核心 Python Core&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 摘要 Abstract 💡
Python's warnings are exceptions — but they're also distinct from exceptions, and are both used and trapped differently. In this talk, I'll introduce warnings, how to raise, trap, and redirect them, and show you best practices for their use. Many experienced developers don't know that Python's warning system supports filtering and suppressing warnings quite flexibly, based on a variety of parameters. You can thus turn certain warnings into (potentially fatal) exceptions, or ignore them entirely -- or enjoy the default behavior, in which they appear on the screen. In addition to showing you how you can create and display warnings, I'll also show you how you can create your own, and (perhaps even more significantly) give examples of when they're appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 關於講者 About Speaker - Reuven M. Lerner 🚀
Teaching Python and data science around the world since 1995. Author of the books &amp;quot;Python Workout&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Pandas Workout&amp;quot;. Publisher of the &amp;quot;Better developers&amp;quot; newsletter. I spend each day trying to help people improve their Python skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#python #pycontw #pyconapac2022 #exception #pythonwarning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycontw.blogspot.com"&gt;https://pycontw.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-03:/pycon-apac-2022/when-is-an-exception-not-an-exception-using-warnings-in-pythonreuven-m-lernerpycon-apac-2022.html</guid><category>PyCon APAC 2022</category></item><item><title>Practical decorators</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/practical-decorators.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decorators are one of Python's most powerful features. But even if you
understand what they do, it's not always obvious what you can do with
them. Sure, from a practical perspective, they let you remove repeated
code from your callables. And semantically, they let you think at a
higher level of abstraction, applying the same treatment to functions
and classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can you actually do with them? For many Python developers I've
encountered, ecorators sometimes appear to be a solution looking for a
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show you some practical uses for decorators, and how
you can use them to make your code more readable and maintainable, while
also providing more semantic power. Moreover, you'll see examples of
things would be hard to do without decorators. I hope that after this
talk, you'll have a good sense of how to use decorators in your own
Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:/pycon-us-2019/practical-decorators.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Function dissection lab -- learn how functions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2020/function-dissection-lab-learn-how-functions.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-04-17:/pycon-us-2020/function-dissection-lab-learn-how-functions.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2020</category></item><item><title>When is an exception not an exception? Using warnings in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/when-is-an-exception-not-an-exception-using-warnings-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your code encounters a big problem, then you probably want to raise an exception. But what should your code do if it finds a small problem, one that shouldn't be ignored, but that doesn't merit an exception? Python's answer to this question is warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll introduce Python's warnings, close cousins to exceptions but still distinct from them. We'll see how you can generate warnings, and what happens when you do. But then we'll dig deeper, looking at how you can filter and redirect warnings, telling Python which types of warnings you want to see, and which you want to hide. We'll also see how you can get truly fancy, turning some warnings into (potentially fatal) exceptions and handling certain types with custom callback functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, you'll be able to take advantage of Python's warning system, letting your users know when something is wrong without having to choose between &amp;quot;print&amp;quot; and a full-blown exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/reuven/when-is-an-exception-not-an-exception-using-pythons-warnings"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/reuven/when-is-an-exception-not-an-exception-using-pythons-warnings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/when-is-an-exception-not-an-exception-using-warnings-in-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>Understanding attributes (Or: They're not nearly as boring as you think!)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/understanding-attributes-or-theyre-not-nearly-as-boring-as-you-think.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attributes in Python, which we use dozens of times each day, seem boring, obvious, and not worthy of attention. But it turns out that they're key to the Python language: Every time you say a.b in Python, that little dot is hiding a lot of work, from searching across multiple objects to silently rewriting things. And it turns out that what happens with attributes, while not always obvious to developers, determines a great deal of behavior in the Python language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll discuss what attributes are (and aren't), what Python does when you use a dot (.) in your code, and how you can take advantage of it. We'll talk about attribute lookup, about inheritance, and about methods vs. functions. We'll also look into properties, and how they allow us to have attributes that look like data but behave like setters and getters. Finally, we'll look at the descriptor protocol, which makes so much of Python's functionality possible, including the automatic insertion of &amp;quot;self&amp;quot; as the first argument in method calls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/understanding-attributes-or-theyre-not-nearly-as-boring-as-you-think.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Generators, coroutines, and nanoservices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/generators-coroutines-and-nanoservices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generator functions have been a part of Python for many years already,
and are a well known technique for creating iterators. But generators
have a few lesser-known aspects, including their “send” method and the
“yield from” syntax. Many Python developers shy away from using them,
unsure of what they would do, or how they would be useful — seeing
coroutines as a solution looking for a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll tell you why coroutines can be useful, and how
thinking about them as in-process “nanoservices” puts us in the right
frame of mind to determine when they would and wouldn’t be appropriate.
Among the topics we’ll explore are:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/generators-coroutines-and-nanoservices.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Comprehending comprehensions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/comprehending-comprehensions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comprehensions are one of the most important — and misunderstood — parts
of Python. In this tutorial, I'll walk you through comprehensions,
including how to write them, and why you would want to do so. By the
time you finish this tutorial, you'll fully understand list, set and
dict comprehensions, as well as nested comprehensions and generator
expressions. You'll understand the differences between regular &amp;quot;for&amp;quot;
loops and comprehensions, and where to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-19:/pycon-us-2023/comprehending-comprehensions.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Times and dates in Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/times-and-dates-in-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is famously flexible and capable at analyzing numeric data. But
Pandas is also flexible and capable at working with times and dates. In
this talk, I'll describe the dtypes associated with times and dates, the
sorts of calculations you can perform, issues with parsing and importing
datetime data, and how you can perform more complex tasks, such as
grouping, pivoting, and resampling. By the time this talk is over,
you'll be able to work with time-based data in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;times and dates work, from handling inputs to performing sophisticated
analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/times-and-dates-in-pandas.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>All about decorators</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/all-about-decorators.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decorators are one of Python's most powerful features. But for many
developers, they remain somewhat mysterious and intimidating. In this
tutorial, you'll learn what decorators are, how they work, how to write
them, and when you should use them. Along the way, you'll write a bunch
of decorators that will demonstrate their power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/all-about-decorators.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>The PyArrow revolution in Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/the-pyarrow-revolution-in-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas has long used NumPy for its back-end storage. But things are changing, and the future of Pandas will likely be tied closely with PyArrow. What are Arrow and PyArrow? How do they affect Pandas users today, and how will they affect us in the future? Is PyArrow always faster than the current Pandas backend? In this talk, I introduce PyArrow, tell you what it does, how we can already use it in our Pandas work, and when it's appropriate for you to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven M. Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/the-pyarrow-revolution-in-pandas.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item></channel></rss>