<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jill MacKay</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jill-mackay.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>You Can Lead a Horse to Water...Changing the Data Science Culture for Veterinary Scientists</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/you-can-lead-a-horse-to-waterchanging-the-data-science-culture-for-veterinary-scientists.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jill MacKay</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/you-can-lead-a-horse-to-waterchanging-the-data-science-culture-for-veterinary-scientists.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A retrospective look at supporting data science skills in a research-focussed veterinary school&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a talk about environment management, but not in the way you're thinking. In many industries, domain-specific experts need enough understanding of data science to support their work and communicate with data scientists, but often …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A retrospective look at supporting data science skills in a research-focussed veterinary school&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a talk about environment management, but not in the way you're thinking. In many industries, domain-specific experts need enough understanding of data science to support their work and communicate with data scientists, but often have insufficient training in these skills, and limited time with which to obtain data science skills and practice them. This is particularly challenging for those who are interdisciplinary and have limited control over their workload, such as medics and field scientists. In this talk, an educational scientist describes the previous 10 years of supporting veterinary scientists to adopt open science practices surrounding data science. What worked, what failed miserably, and reflections on why it can be so hard to get a horse to drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jillymackay/positconf2023_vetdata"&gt;https://github.com/jillymackay/positconf2023_vetdata&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://jillymackay.com/post/positconf2023/"&gt;https://jillymackay.com/post/positconf2023/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>