<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mengtao Yuan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ExecuTorch Beta and on-Device Generative AI Support</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/executorch-beta-and-on-device-generative-ai-support.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ExecuTorch Beta and on-Device Generative AI Support - Mergen Nachin &amp;amp; Mengtao (Martin) Yuan, Meta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this session, we will discuss real-life case studies focusing on the productionization of PyTorch models onto edge devices and welcome the community to begin adopting ExecuTorch. Since announcing the ExecuTorch MVP at the previous PTC, we have made significant progress in terms of stability, model coverage, accelerator performance, and developer experience, reaching a milestone that marks the transition to beta status. In addition to the above improvements, we continue to support generative AI models. Since the alpha launch that initially enabled support for LLama2/3 models, we have now expanded our capabilities to include multimodal use cases and developed mobile demo apps showcasing these new features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mergen Nachin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/executorch-beta-and-on-device-generative-ai-support.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category></item><item><title>Keynote: PyTorch Technical Deep Dive</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/keynote-pytorch-technical-deep-dive.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote: PyTorch Technical Deep Dive - Piotr Bialecki, NVIDIA; Peng Wu, Will Constable, Kartikay Khandelwal &amp;amp; Mengtao (Martin) Yuan, Meta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Deep Dive provides an update on PyTorch development since last conference and dives into the key new features coming in PyTorch 2.5 and beyond.  We will explore how advancements across a number of PyTorch features combine to better support the full model development lifecycle across training, fine-tuning, and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Piotr Bialecki</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/keynote-pytorch-technical-deep-dive.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category></item></channel></rss>