<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stephan-gramlich.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>From an old-school data managing company to data analytics with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/from-an-old-school-data-managing-company-to-data-analytics-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Henrik Hain</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:europython-2017/from-an-old-school-data-managing-company-to-data-analytics-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to manage a huge amount of communication and document
data in large scale industry projects by providing web based project
management systems. The increasing amount of communication creates
the desire for a GPS helping us and our customers to navigate through
the communication stream. Our R&amp;amp;D projects are focusing on topics
like clustering, event detection, and network analysis (Who knows
who, domain experts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling the wild side of NLP, Data Science, and Analytics, we
stumbled across amazing Python tools supporting us in our goal to
navigate the project communication and therefor supporting our
clients in Project &amp;amp; Risk Management avoiding wrong turns. We
would like to share some of our approaches to answer our research
topics and challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges, amongst others, is to utilize and adapt up to
date clustering algorithms for social stream data and to expose them
as reentrant services. Another one is to tailor them for the current
application domain, improving clustering precision by parametrization
and other means. Furthermore the integration of a Python based
analytics system into an existing JAVA based application environment
and eco system is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we would also like to share some of our &amp;quot;traffic jams&amp;quot;
experienced during our travel starting as traditional Java/SQL
focusing company that integrated Python into its development
portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>