<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - KHVATOVA KRISTINA</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Predictive maintenance: from data collection to ML key approaches</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/predictive-maintenance-from-data-collection-to-ml-key-approaches.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predictive maintenance: from data collection to ML key approaches -
PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predictive Maintenance (PM) prevents future system failures and helps to
reduce the maintenance costs. Machine Learning with the use of IoT
Sensors is the most efficient approach. Come to see some case study
solved by Vedrai - one of the top AI startups in Europe - and how it
addresses the topic. PROBLEM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world we live in today is highly dependent on the functioning of
machines and systems. Breakdown of machinery and tools should never come
as a surprise. When predictive maintenance is working effectively,
maintenance is only performed on machines when it is required. That is,
just before failure is likely to occur. This brings reduction of the
downtime and cost, maximizes component utilization and residual useful
life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOLUTION.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning-based PdM is one of the best-known data-based
analytical approaches for monitoring industrial systems to maximize
reliability and efficiency. It is the most efficient method as it allows
the maintenance team to anticipate failure predictions, reduce equipment
downtime, increase reliability and improve performance by reducing
operations and maintenance expenses. The talk will outline the
methodologies applied by Vedrai Team - one of the top AI startups in
Europe - that allow it to overcome the most common obstacles of ML-based
PdM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TALK OUTLINE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this presentation is to show how to build and use
PdM models in their entirety, and it will be based on the following
steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collect OT (operational technology), IT (informational technology)
data and other information about manufacturing processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search patterns and detect anomalies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;train ML model to provide early warning notifications and diagnosis
of equipment problems days, weeks or months in advance of the fault&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;present key studies that show how ML algorithms can effectively
estimate the maintenance plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: KHVATOVA KRISTINA&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">KHVATOVA KRISTINA</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/predictive-maintenance-from-data-collection-to-ml-key-approaches.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>case study</category><category>education</category><category>iot</category><category>machine learning</category><category>predictions</category></item></channel></rss>