<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mikko Koivisto</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Revisiting Bayesian Network Learning with Small Vertex Cover</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/revisiting-bayesian-network-learning-with-small-vertex-cover.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Revisiting Bayesian Network Learning with Small Vertex Cover&amp;quot;
Juha Harviainen, Mikko Koivisto
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/harviainen23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/harviainen23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
The problem of structure learning in Bayesian networks asks for a directed acyclic graph (DAG) that maximizes a given scoring function. Since the problem is NP-hard, research effort has been put into discovering restricted classes of DAGs for which the search problem can be solved in polynomial time. Here, we initiate investigation of questions that have received less attention thus far: Are the known polynomial algorithms close to the best possible, or is there room for significant improvements? If the interest is in Bayesian learning, that is, in sampling or weighted counting of DAGs, can we obtain similar complexity results? Focusing on DAGs with bounded vertex cover number—a class studied in Korhonen and Parviainen’s seminal work (NIPS 2015)—we answer the questions in the affirmative. We also give, apparently the first, proof that the counting problem is #P-hard in general. In addition, we show that under the vertex-cover constraint counting is #W[1]-hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/342-oral-slides.pdf"&gt;https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/342-oral-slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juha Harviainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/revisiting-bayesian-network-learning-with-small-vertex-cover.html</guid><category>UAI 2023</category></item><item><title>UAI 2023 Oral Session 6: On Inference and Learning With Probabilistic Generating Circuits</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/uai-2023-oral-session-6-on-inference-and-learning-with-probabilistic-generating-circuits.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;On Inference and Learning With Probabilistic Generating Circuits&amp;quot;
Juha Harviainen, Vaidyanathan Peruvemba Ramaswamy, Mikko Koivisto
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/harviainen23b.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/harviainen23b.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Probabilistic generating circuits (PGCs) are economical representations of multivariate probability generating polynomials (PGPs). They unify and extend decomposable probabilistic circuits and determinantal point processes, admitting tractable computation of marginal probabilities. However, the need for addition and multiplication of high-degree polynomials incurs a significant additional factor in the complexity of inference. Here, we give a new inference algorithm that eliminates this extra factor. Specifically, we show that it suffices to keep track of the highest degree coefficients of the computed polynomials, rendering the algorithm linear in the circuit size. In addition, we show that determinant-based circuits need not be expanded to division-free circuits, but can be handled by division-based fast algorithms. While these advances enhance the appeal of PGCs, we also discover an obstacle to learning them from data: it is NP-hard to recognize whether a given PGC encodes a PGP. We discuss the implications of our ambivalent findings and sketch a method, in which learning is restricted to PGCs that are composed of moderate-size subcircuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/353-oral-slides.pdf"&gt;https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/353-oral-slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juha Harviainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/uai-2023-oral-session-6-on-inference-and-learning-with-probabilistic-generating-circuits.html</guid><category>UAI 2023</category></item></channel></rss>