<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_shaun-mccance.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Crossing the Streams: Enabling Collaboration Between Products and Upstreams</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/crossing-the-streams-enabling-collaboration-between-products-and-upstreams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shaun McCance</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:write-the-docs-2016/crossing-the-streams-enabling-collaboration-between-products-and-upstreams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shaun McCance
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzry/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzry/&lt;/a&gt;
Open source projects have documentation communities made up of volunteer enthusiasts and people from different companies. Good open source documentation is essential to the success of a project, and working within an open source community is entirely unlike working inside a single company.
At Red Hat, our products are based on dozens of open source projects and built on the hard work of hundreds more. Our documentation has to serve the needs of our customers and add value to our products. At the same time, we need our upstream projects to be healthy and vibrant, and that includes having excellent documentation and documentation communities.
Shaun McCance will talk about how to balance upstream and downstream documentation and how multiple teams can work together to create better documentation for everyone. He&amp;amp;#39;ll show examples from inside Red Hat, as well as from over a decade in working with open source documentation communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>