<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Luke Leighton</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Libre-SOC Project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/the-libre-soc-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Libre-SOC Project
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Luke Leighton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Libre-SOC Project aims to bring to market a mass-volume System-on-a-Chip suitable for use in smartphones netbooks tablets and chromebooks, which is end-user programmable right to the bedrock. No spying backdoors, no treacherous DRM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python and standard Libre Project Management is used throughout:
* nmigen, a python-based HDL, is a fundamental and critical strategic choice in creating the hardware.
* An IEEE754 FP hardware library has been developed using nmigen/python, as are hundreds of thousands of unit tests
* An OpenPOWER ISA simulator is written in python, and is actually a PLY compiler based on the GardenSnake example
* Several thousand unit tests for the HDL and simulator are written in python
* coriolis2, the VLSI ASIC layout toolchain, is a mixed c++ python application
* cocotb, a hardware co-simulation system, is used to verify the HDL is correct, down to the gate level
* a JTAG &amp;quot;remote&amp;quot; system has been written in python which allows the simulated processor to be connected to with openocd.
* Even the Standard Cell Library being used, called FlexLib, by Chips4Makers, is in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that python is critical to the project would be a massive understatement.  This talk will give a brief overview of the above areas and give a glimpse into why python was chosen for each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luke Leighton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/the-libre-soc-project.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item></channel></rss>