<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sangarshanan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Interactive Mapmaking with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/interactive-mapmaking-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sangarshanan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/DVV7W8"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/DVV7W8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Introduction (2 mins)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who am I?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting the expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Working with Geodataframes (5 mins)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Spatial data as a GeoDataframe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The awesomeness of GeoDataframes (An overview of some of the amazing things you can do with a single line of code eg: Spatial joins, Manipulations and transformations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now that we has established our love for geopandas lets map geodataframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Let the Mapmaking begin (10 mins)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Non-Interactive maps with Geopandas and Matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Creating basic interactive maps with Folium, Plotly &amp;amp; Kepler (GeoJSONPlots, Clustermaps, Heatmaps, H3gridmaps)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conforming geodataframes to a format accepted by these libraries (usually JSON or a list of lists)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting the right parameters for different plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jazzing up the maps with additional layers, custom styles, tooltips, popups, colors etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatiotemporal Maps with Kepler.gl + Jupyter for handling huge datasets with ease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we make it any easier ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why can't making interactive maps be as easy as gdf.folium.plot()?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Enter Geopatra (8 mins)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for Geopatra (Could it be any Easier and Faster)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrapping up popular mapmaking libraries for GeoDataframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create interactive maps with just a single line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future work and Discussion :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Sangarshanan/geopatra"&gt;https://github.com/Sangarshanan/geopatra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep  4 17:10:00 2020 at Curlyboi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sangarshanan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/interactive-mapmaking-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2020</category><category>PyCon</category><category>PyConAU</category><category>PyConline</category><category>Python</category><category>Sangarshanan</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2020</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talk: Jazzit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2020/lightning-talk-jazzit.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sangarshanan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-02:/pycon-india-2020/lightning-talk-jazzit.html</guid><category>PyCon India 2020</category></item><item><title>Build-a-Database with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/build-a-database-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will help unlock the internal workings of a Database by breaking down the abstractions that make it. We will use Python as our weapon of choice to slowly discuss how you would go about building the different components of a database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking to your Database: We start by building out an interface and a language that helps us communicate with our database. We will use Prompt toolkit to build a REPL &amp;amp; use a simple SQL-based language with basic regular expressions that can parse it to instruction to execute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with Data: Now that we can communicate with our database using instructions. we start the actual work in building out the Datastore, We initially store all the data in a simple in-memory dictionary and then move to persist this data to disk. We now read the data from the disk to memory every time we query the data and write back the data to the disk but this makes things very slow :( This problem is our entry into the beautiful world of Indexes so by building a very basic Btree index to store references in memory to quickly access only what we require from the data on disk we can actually speed up our access times for basic row access queries from O(N) to O(1) where N is the number of rows in a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future: We can now proudly demo our new and polished database that can store data, persist it, and can run queries that are quite fast thanks to our Btree Indexes. We also discuss how this Database can be improved in the future by supporting full ACID Transactions, allowing concurrency, and handling locks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to understand something is to build it yourself :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sangarshanan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/build-a-database-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Spatial thinking with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/spatial-thinking-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data scientists work with all kinds of data, It could be a text an image or
maybe it is a bunch of coordinates. Though computer vision and natural
language processing have hit it off spatial data science doesn’t get the
attention it deserves. Spatial data has both social and industrial impact.
Spatial data is useful in agriculture and for observing weather patterns to
predict natural disasters. It is also very important for industries that
deal with logistics and supply chain management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I would talk about spatial data it’s importance and elaborate
on how to store, manipulate and visualize such data. I would talk about the
use of Python and several related modules (GDAL, Shapely, Fiona etc) in
processing geospatial data. I would also like to discuss QGIS, a desktop
based open source GIS platform and a variety of useful operations that can
be done with it. I would also like to talk about building geospatial
dashboards to share and serve  spatial layers and discuss the geospatial
support provided by the various open source projects like postgis, geonode,
elastic stack V7.0 and much more&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sangarshanan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-05:/pygotham-2019/spatial-thinking-with-python.html</guid><category>PyGotham 2019</category></item></channel></rss>