<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Andrew Bray</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andrew-bray.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Closeread: bringing Scrollytelling to Quarto</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/closeread-bringing-scrollytelling-to-quarto.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Bray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/closeread-bringing-scrollytelling-to-quarto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scrollytelling is a style of web design that transitions graphics and text as a user scrolls, allowing stories to progress naturally. Despite its power, scrollytelling typically requires specialist web dev skills beyond the reach of many data scientists. Closeread is a Quarto extension that makes a wide range of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scrollytelling is a style of web design that transitions graphics and text as a user scrolls, allowing stories to progress naturally. Despite its power, scrollytelling typically requires specialist web dev skills beyond the reach of many data scientists. Closeread is a Quarto extension that makes a wide range of scrollytelling techniques available to authors without traditional web dev experience, with support for cross-fading plots, graphics and other chunk output alongside narrative content. You can zoom in on poems, prose and images, as well as highlighting important phrases of text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Closeread allows authors with experience in Observable JS to write their own animated graphics that update smoothly as scrolling progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>