<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Neil Mitchell</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_neil-mitchell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>High-Performance Python: Faster Type Checking and Free Threaded Execution (Sponsor: Meta)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/high-performance-python-faster-type-checking-and-free-threaded-execution-sponsor-meta.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sam Gross</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-15:/pycon-us-2025/high-performance-python-faster-type-checking-and-free-threaded-execution-sponsor-meta.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta's Commitment to the Python Community: Empowering Innovation and Collaboration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Meta, we're dedicated to advancing the Python ecosystem through open-source contributions and community engagement. Our mission is to improve the tooling and runtime, making the language more efficient, scalable, and accessible for developers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing Pyrefly: A Scalable …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta's Commitment to the Python Community: Empowering Innovation and Collaboration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Meta, we're dedicated to advancing the Python ecosystem through open-source contributions and community engagement. Our mission is to improve the tooling and runtime, making the language more efficient, scalable, and accessible for developers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing Pyrefly: A Scalable Type Checker for a Unified IDE Experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to introduce Pyrefly, a new type checker designed with scalability in mind. Built from the ground up using Rust, Pyrefly provides a faster and more efficient type checking experience, enabling developers to write better code with confidence. With Pyrefly, we aim to deliver a unified IDE experience power type hints and code navigation on a new type checking engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlocking Better Performance with Free-Threaded Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with the Python community, we've been working on making free-threaded Python (No-GIL) available in Python 3.13. This significant milestone allows developers to take full advantage of modern multi-core processors directly from Python. More recently, our efforts have focused on improving the single-threaded performance of the free threading build, ensuring that Python remains a top choice for developers seeking high-performance capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>