<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Michael Riley</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michael-riley.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Upgrading EOL Django: A Journey from V1 to V5</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/upgrading-eol-django-a-journey-from-v1-to-v5.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Riley</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-24:/djangocon-us-2024/upgrading-eol-django-a-journey-from-v1-to-v5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding out that an application is using a legacy version of a framework can be a stressful and intimidating task, knowing that you're going to be responsible for bringing the application back to a supported version.  This talk will cover what this type of journey would look like in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding out that an application is using a legacy version of a framework can be a stressful and intimidating task, knowing that you're going to be responsible for bringing the application back to a supported version.  This talk will cover what this type of journey would look like in the Django ecosystem by using a real world example of a small Django project that was acquired from its original developer. We will be covering multiple different scenarios and also be providing helpful tips for approaching legacy applications in general along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the talk, the attendees will be able to:
- Know where to find critical documentation for moving between Django versions
- Identify the ideal upgrade path
- Learn and Explore ways to deal with legacy code
- How to effectively evaluate which version of dependencies need to be upgraded to.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>