<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Andy Piper</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Try Something Different: Explore MicroPython (a rough guide for newcomers)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/try-something-different-explore-micropython-a-rough-guide-for-newcomers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Try Something Different: Explore MicroPython! (a rough guide for newcomers) -  presented by Andy Piper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 2 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MicroPython is a reimplementation of Python for microcontrollers, originally developed as a result of a Kickstarter campaign. Today, it is an approachable way into programming for many young people, via boards like the Raspberry Pi Pico, the BBC micro:bit and the CodeBug - you can even run it on LEGO bricks! It is increasingly being used in commercial fields as well. MicroPython is helping Python to get into even more places, and making programmers more efficient as it does so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Piper wanted to learn more, so he spent some time travelling and adventuring on the internet, to discover the community and projects around MicroPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this session is to briefly explain the What, Why and How of MicroPython. There &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be circuit boards, and discussion of microcontrollers! We will take a look at examples, from established development boards to brand new ones. We will also acknowledge how MicroPython has been built upon, to enable different ways of working (with CircuitPython), and LEGO robots (via PyBricks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, and most importantly, you'll get a good sense of the places you can find and learn from the MicroPython community, and how you can get involved and contribute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andy Piper</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/try-something-different-explore-micropython-a-rough-guide-for-newcomers.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item></channel></rss>