<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Leah Wasser</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Friends don't let friends package alone</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/friends-dont-let-friends-package-alone.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python packaging can be a scary and confusing endeavor. The ecosystem
can be thorny and filled with many decisions around which tool or
approach to use. You’re also likely to get pricked by an approach or
tutorial that doesn't work as expected. However, the packaging journey
doesn’t have to be prickly - particularly for pure Python packages. By
building community consensus around user goals and moderating healthy
discussion, pyOpenSci is paving a smooth, thorn-free path for successful
packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk presents pyOpenSci’s people-first approach to guiding the
scientific community through thorny packaging decisions. First, we
engaged with the broader community to understand packaging needs.
Second, we brought together packaging experts, tool maintainers, and
beginning-to-advanced users to successfully build consensus around tools
and best practices. Community outreach helped us understand both user
needs and the packaging tool ecosystem. Finally, consensus around tools
and needs was transformed into accessible recommendations in our
community-driven Packaging Guide. Guidebook pull requests go through
extensive, open community review with 38 people and thousands of
comments contributing to the guidebook’s current state. Careful
moderation ensures healthy and productive conversations and also drives
consensus-building around beginner-friendly content. Our guidebook’s
development process allows us to harness community expertise to create
an accessible and accurate packaging guide that smooths out the
packaging path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will will walk away from this talk with a better understanding of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why consensus-building and user-focused content development is
critical for tackling thorny topics such as packaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to decide which packaging tools satisfy your packaging needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to find more information and support around packaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to package alone. The vibrant Python community is here
to help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leah Wasser</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/friends-dont-let-friends-package-alone.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks DAY 3 | SciPy 2023</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Axel Donath</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>The power of community in solving scientific Python’s most challenging problems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/the-power-of-community-in-solving-scientific-pythons-most-challenging-problems.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific software drives open research. However, developing and maintaining a Python package is a tricky endeavor. You need to navigate a thorny packaging ecosystem, often in an academic environment that doesn’t traditionally value software. pyOpenSci has learned that an inclusive community can be empowered to make Python packaging more accessible, and that constructive peer review supports maintainers in creating better software, while also providing academic credit. In this talk you’ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build consensus around thorny topics like packaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to find beginner-friendly packaging support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How constructive peer review can support better code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get involved with pyOpenSci.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leah Wasser</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/the-power-of-community-in-solving-scientific-pythons-most-challenging-problems.html</guid><category>SciPy 2024</category></item></channel></rss>