<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Joshua J. Cook</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_joshua-j-cook.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Quarto: A Multifaceted Publishing Powerhouse for Medical Researchers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/quarto-a-multifaceted-publishing-powerhouse-for-medical-researchers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joshua J. Cook</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/quarto-a-multifaceted-publishing-powerhouse-for-medical-researchers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional medical research dissemination is slow and cumbersome, often culminating in a diverse array of outputs: reports for our sponsors and regulators, manuscripts for peer-reviewed journals, summaries for online platforms, and presentations for conferences. However, it takes a great deal of time and effort to organize all these outputs …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional medical research dissemination is slow and cumbersome, often culminating in a diverse array of outputs: reports for our sponsors and regulators, manuscripts for peer-reviewed journals, summaries for online platforms, and presentations for conferences. However, it takes a great deal of time and effort to organize all these outputs so that our findings can enter the patient setting. Quarto can change that. It's a tool that lets us efficiently create various polished formats from a single source while meeting diverse submission requirements. This talk will showcase how Quarto can revolutionize our communication, making research more impactful and speeding up the delivery of treatments to our patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>