<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Rishabh Misra</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rishabh-misra.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Sculpting Data for Machine Learning V02</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/sculpting-data-for-machine-learning-v02.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jigyasa Grover</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/sculpting-data-for-machine-learning-v02.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the contemporary world of machine learning algorithms - “data is the new oil”. For the state-of-the-art ML algorithms to work their magic it’s important to lay a strong foundation with access to relevant data. Volumes of crude data are available on the web nowadays, and all we need …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the contemporary world of machine learning algorithms - “data is the new oil”. For the state-of-the-art ML algorithms to work their magic it’s important to lay a strong foundation with access to relevant data. Volumes of crude data are available on the web nowadays, and all we need are the skills to identify and extract meaningful datasets. This talk aims to present the power of the most fundamental aspect of Machine Learning - Dataset Curation, which often does not get its due limelight. It will also walk the audience through the process of constructing good quality datasets as done in formal settings with a simple hands-on Pythonic example. The goal is to institute the importance of data, especially in its worthy format, and the spell it casts on fabricating smart learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category></entry></feed>