<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynote: Domain - Specific Languages to Modern Processors</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/keynote-domain-specific-languages-to-modern-processors-scypy-2016-andreas-klockner.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Klockner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/keynote-domain-specific-languages-to-modern-processors-scypy-2016-andreas-klockner.html</guid><category>ScyPy 2016</category></item><item><title>Bicycles for the Mind: Building High-Performance Tools with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2014/bicycles-for-the-mind-building-high-performance.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andreas Klöckner is an assistant professor in the scientific computing
group within the Department of Computer Science at the University of
Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. He works on high-order numerical methods
for the simulation of wave problems as well as issues in
high-performance scientific computing that relate to bringing these
methods to life on large-scale parallel computers. In support of his
research, Dr. Klöckner has released numerous software packages for
scientific computing in Python, including PyOpenCL, PyCUDA and the PuDB
Python debugger. He obtained his PhD degree at the Division of Applied
Mathematics at Brown University with Jan Hesthaven, working on
large-scale finite element simulations of wave problems in the time
domain. From Brown, Klöckner moved to the Courant Institute of
Mathematical Sciences at New York University as a Courant Instructor,
where he worked on integral equation methods and fast algorithms within
Leslie Greengard's group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Klöckner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-07:pycon-apac-2014/bicycles-for-the-mind-building-high-performance.html</guid></item></channel></rss>