<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tom Johnson</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building navigation for your doc site: 5 best practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/building-navigation-for-your-doc-site-5-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although users typically arrive at doc websites in a confused and
impatient state, not sure of where to find what they're looking for,
good navigation can guide them to the right answer. Good navigation
anticipates users' needs, provides links in commonly viewed places, and
brings the right topic into the foreground amid hundreds of other
topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you build out the navigation for your doc site, follow these 5 design
principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entry point&lt;/strong&gt;. Design the entry point to your system to orient
users and allow them to easily get started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt;. Create a hierarchical outline of the content to help
users both understand and visualize the body of information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modularity&lt;/strong&gt;. Break up content into independent topics that can be
viewed, understood, and updated independent of the whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progressive disclosure&lt;/strong&gt;. Layer the information so that you don't
present everything at once but rather make some content available
only at secondary or tertiary levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wayfinding&lt;/strong&gt;. Provide navigational signposts —
such as breadcrumbs and workflow maps — to help
orient users as to where they are in a larger system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Johnson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/building-navigation-for-your-doc-site-5-best-practices.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Portland 2017</category></item></channel></rss>