<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Howard Poston</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_howard-poston.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Understanding Common Causes of Cryptographic Vulnerabilities</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/understanding-common-causes-of-cryptographic-vulnerabilities.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Howard Poston</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/understanding-common-causes-of-cryptographic-vulnerabilities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cryptography is essential for cybersecurity and data protection, but it is extremely easy to get wrong. Incidents like Zerologon demonstrate how easy it is for a simple tweak to a cryptographic algorithm to break everything. It’s difficult to know what will break a cryptographic algorithm, and the modern …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cryptography is essential for cybersecurity and data protection, but it is extremely easy to get wrong. Incidents like Zerologon demonstrate how easy it is for a simple tweak to a cryptographic algorithm to break everything. It’s difficult to know what will break a cryptographic algorithm, and the modern algorithms we rely on today are considered secure because a lot of people have tried to break them and no one has succeeded yet. That said, there are some fundamental and common mistakes that undermine the security of cryptographic algorithms. This session discusses some of the main ways in which cryptography can go wrong, what happens when these errors occur, and best practices for mitigating the risks of bad cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>