<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Seyed Mohammad Asghari</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_seyed-mohammad-asghari.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Regret Bounds for Decentralized Learning in Cooperative Multi-Agent Dynamical Systems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/regret-bounds-for-decentralized-learning-in-cooperative-multi-agent-dynamical-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Seyed Mohammad Asghari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/regret-bounds-for-decentralized-learning-in-cooperative-multi-agent-dynamical-systems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Regret Bounds for Decentralized Learning in Cooperative Multi-Agent Dynamical Systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seyed Mohammad Asghari (University of Southern California)*; Yi Ouyang (Preferred Networks); Ashutosh Nayyar (University of Southern California)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regret analysis is challenging in Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning (MARL) primarily due to the dynamical environments and the decentralized information among agents. We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Regret Bounds for Decentralized Learning in Cooperative Multi-Agent Dynamical Systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seyed Mohammad Asghari (University of Southern California)*; Yi Ouyang (Preferred Networks); Ashutosh Nayyar (University of Southern California)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regret analysis is challenging in Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning (MARL) primarily due to the dynamical environments and the decentralized information among agents. We attempt to solve this challenge in the context of decentralized learning in multi-agent linear-quadratic (LQ) dynamical systems. We begin with a simple setup consisting of two agents and two dynamically decoupled stochastic linear systems, each system controlled by an agent. The systems are coupled through a quadratic cost function. When both systems' dynamics are unknown and there is no communication among the agents, we show that no learning policy can generate sub-linear in $T$ regret, where $T$ is the time horizon. When only one system's dynamics are unknown and there is one-directional communication from the agent controlling the unknown system to the other agent, we propose a MARL algorithm based on the construction of an auxiliary single-agent LQ problem. The auxiliary single-agent problem in the proposed MARL algorithm serves as an implicit coordination mechanism among the two learning agents. This allows the agents to achieve a regret within $O(sqrt{T})$ of the regret of the auxiliary single-agent problem. Consequently, using existing results for single-agent LQ regret, our algorithm provides a $tilde{O}(sqrt{T})$ regret bound. (Here $tilde{O}(cdot)$ hides constants and logarithmic factors). Our numerical experiments indicate that this bound is matched in practice. From the two-agent problem, we extend our results to multi-agent LQ systems with certain communication patterns which appear in vehicle platoon control.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>