<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_david-liu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>HPC and Python: Intel’s work in enabling the scientific computing community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/hpc-and-python-intels-work-in-enabling-the-scientific-computing-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/hpc-and-python-intels-work-in-enabling-the-scientific-computing-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroSciPy 2019 Bilbao
September 5, Thursday
Mitxelena. Keynote Talk. 9.15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HPC and Python: Intel’s work in enabling the scientific computing community
David Liu&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Addressing multithreading and multiprocessing in transparent and Pythonic ways</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/addressing-multithreading-and-multiprocessing-in-transparent-and-pythonic-ways.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/addressing-multithreading-and-multiprocessing-in-transparent-and-pythonic-ways.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the increase in computing power, harnessing and controlling one’s
code out of the single-threaded realm becomes an ever-increasing
problem, coupled with the desire to stay in the Python layer. With the
recent tools and frameworks that have been published, escaping the GIL
cleanly is much easier than before, allow one’s Python code to
effectively utilize multi-core and many core architectures in the most
Pythonic ways possible. In this talk, learn about how to utilize static
multiprocessing for process pinning, and effectively balancing thread
pools with a monkey-patched import of threading modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to multithreading and multiprocessing in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History of multithreading+multiprocessing in Python, classic
frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems that can occur (oversubscription, nested parallelism issues,
process hopping, pool resource on shared machines)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python accessing bigger hardware over the last few years (28+ cores,
etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When to stay in the GIL, and when to escape it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The advantages and safety of the GIL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-level exiting of the GIL; analysis of when to return to
single-threaded, and when threading is a deceivingly bad idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accountability of frameworks that natively exit the GIL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new multithreading and multiprocessing libraries and techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static multiprocessing module (smp) (and monkey patching of
multiprocessing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thread pool control with command line calls of Python ( python -m tbb
-p 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of using static multiprocessing on a large machine to stop
oversubscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example of pseudo-daemon process on 4-core machine by processor
pinning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thread pool control on a simple NumPy example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary - Best practices for using above methods to control
multithreading+multiprocessing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What needs to be done in the space (frameworks and things that need
to be exposed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems that still exist in the area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Addressing Multithreading and Multiprocessing in Transparent and Pythonic Methods</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/addressing-multithreading-and-multiprocessing-in-transparent-and-pythonic-methods.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-12:scipy-2018/addressing-multithreading-and-multiprocessing-in-transparent-and-pythonic-methods.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the increase in computing power, harnessing and controlling one’s
code out of the single threaded realm becomes an ever-increasing
problem, coupled with the desire to stay in the Python layer. With the
recent tools and frameworks that have been published, escaping the GIL
cleanly is much easier than before, and can allow one’s Python code to
effectively utilize multi-core and many core architectures in the most
Pythonic ways possible. In this talk, learn about how to utilize static
multiprocessing for process pinning, and effectively balancing thread
pools with a monkey-patched import of threading modules.Presenter(s):
Speaker: David Liu, Intel Speaker: Anton Malakhov, Intel Corporation&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Infrastructure design patterns with Python, Buildbot, and Linux Containers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/infrastructure-design-patterns-with-python-buildbot-and-linux-containers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/infrastructure-design-patterns-with-python-buildbot-and-linux-containers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In today’s world of fast-paced development, infrastructure can get
left behind quickly, leading to a potential increase in technical
debt. Buildbot is normally known to be a continuous integration (CI)
framework built in Python, but can be refashioned to solve
infrastructure design patterns that arise in enterprise or production
and deployment situations. Using Python and native Buildbot
components paired with Linux Containers, patterns such as license
management, resource allocation, load balancing, and enterprise
application deployment can be architected quickly with room for
expansion as one’s needs grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to move past the CI mindset and construct infrastructure
needs with Buildbot and popular Linux Containers such as Docker and
ClearContainers. Attendees will learn the best known methods of
configuring Buildbot in non-CI implementations, and how to utilize
the framework components for future needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>