<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Neeraj Pandey</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_neeraj-pandey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Joy of Creating Art with Code.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/the-joy-of-creating-art-with-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/the-joy-of-creating-art-with-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Art is everywhere and it’s beautiful. Unleash the creative artist inside you with the beauty of Generative Art. Learn how algorithms are used to create these aesthetic art forms, how motion and structures emit sounds and what toolkits are required to do so. This talk looks at Python …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Art is everywhere and it’s beautiful. Unleash the creative artist inside you with the beauty of Generative Art. Learn how algorithms are used to create these aesthetic art forms, how motion and structures emit sounds and what toolkits are required to do so. This talk looks at Python as an artistic and visual programming language with the simplicity and beauty of generative art using Processing, PyCairo and webGL. The audience will see an evolution of generative art over the last 50 years, how autonomously these art forms are created using algorithms and how we can stimulate paints and other media. The talk will be showing how to create artworks inspired by geometric and mathematical patterns which also includes randomness with hands-on examples (Two such examples are added here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://imgur.com/a/lycAYnj"&gt;https://imgur.com/a/lycAYnj&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Analytics"></category><category term="JavaScript"></category><category term="Physics"></category><category term="Python 3"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Elegant API Contracts: From Zero to Hero</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2022/building-elegant-api-contracts-from-zero-to-hero.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-02-06:/pycascades-2022/building-elegant-api-contracts-from-zero-to-hero.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how one can write efficient APIs with high-quality API specifications using Open API and RAML specs to create API contracts and achieve a better experience using the API with more reliable unit tests and increased response consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>The Joy of Creating Art with Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/the-joy-of-creating-art-with-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:/pycon-fr-2019/the-joy-of-creating-art-with-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Art is everywhere and it’s beautiful. Unleash the creative artist inside you with the beauty of Generative Art. Learn how algorithms are used to create these aesthetic art forms, how motion and structures emit sounds and what toolkits are required to do so. The talk will take the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Art is everywhere and it’s beautiful. Unleash the creative artist inside you with the beauty of Generative Art. Learn how algorithms are used to create these aesthetic art forms, how motion and structures emit sounds and what toolkits are required to do so. The talk will take the audience to a small history of Generative Art and how autonomously these art forms are created using algorithms with various examples using Processing, Numpy, PyCario and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon FR 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Visual Data Storytelling with Blender and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2024/visual-data-storytelling-with-blender-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-11-03:/pycon-fr-2024/visual-data-storytelling-with-blender-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might have encountered beautiful animations and data storytelling through many educators and experimentalists online and wondered if it’s only done in javascript or could also be done by Python. In this talk, the attendees will learn how to blend the 3D animation power of Blender with the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might have encountered beautiful animations and data storytelling through many educators and experimentalists online and wondered if it’s only done in javascript or could also be done by Python. In this talk, the attendees will learn how to blend the 3D animation power of Blender with the 2D plotting capabilities from Python libraries like matplotlib. On top it, attendees learn how to leverage the latex and Manim library to create beautiful mathematical animations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will demonstrate some practical techniques to create immersive 3D models with Blender and enhance them with detailed 2D plots, providing a comprehensive narrative for data interpretation. By integrating these data-viz tools, devs and data enthusiasts will discover new &amp;amp; impactful ways to leverage Python to present and communicate their data insights from educational and work projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon FR 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Playing games in the browser with WASM</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/playing-games-in-the-browser-with-wasm.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-27:/pycon-korea-2024/playing-games-in-the-browser-with-wasm.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Meets UX: Enhancing User Experience with Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2023/python-meets-ux-enhancing-user-experience-with-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-03:/pycon-taiwan-2023/python-meets-ux-enhancing-user-experience-with-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Taiwan 2023｜Talk 演講｜Day 2, R2 13:05–13:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🪄 說明 Description 🪄
The intersection of UX and Python programming is a powerful combination for building great products and enhancing user experience. Python is a versatile and popular programming language that is widely used for a variety of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Taiwan 2023｜Talk 演講｜Day 2, R2 13:05–13:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🪄 說明 Description 🪄
The intersection of UX and Python programming is a powerful combination for building great products and enhancing user experience. Python is a versatile and popular programming language that is widely used for a variety of tasks, including web development, data analysis, and machine learning. UX, or user experience, is the process of designing products that provide a seamless and intuitive experience for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about this powerful intersection of UX design and Python programming by understanding how Python can be used to enhance the user experience and provide practical examples on how UX designers can automate tasks, gather and analyze data, develop personalized experiences, and continually improve their own skills and processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 講者介紹 About Speaker - Neeraj Pandey 🚀
Neeraj is a polyglot and open-source contributor. Over the years, he has spoken at multiple international Python conferences and has worked on a variety of full-stack software and data science applications, as well as computational arts and quantitative finance projects. He enjoys the challenge of creating new tools and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conf.python.tw/"&gt;https://conf.python.tw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Explainable AI: Demystifying Complex Models with Shapley Values</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2023/explainable-ai-demystifying-complex-models-with-shapley-values.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-02:/pycon-taiwan-2023/explainable-ai-demystifying-complex-models-with-shapley-values.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Taiwan 2023｜Tutorial 專業課程｜Day 1, R3 13:00–14:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🪄 說明 Description 🪄
Explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) refers to AI systems that can clearly and understandably explain their decisions and actions. This is crucial for ensuring that AI systems are transparent, accountable, and trustworthy, and do not make …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Taiwan 2023｜Tutorial 專業課程｜Day 1, R3 13:00–14:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🪄 說明 Description 🪄
Explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) refers to AI systems that can clearly and understandably explain their decisions and actions. This is crucial for ensuring that AI systems are transparent, accountable, and trustworthy, and do not make biased or discriminatory decisions. Python offers various libraries that can be used to improve the interpretability of AI algorithms in a variety of situations, such as enhancing transparency in decision-making systems or facilitating communication between AI experts and non-experts. In this hands-on tutorial, you will learn how to use these tools to improve the interpretability of AI algorithms in Python, and explore key metrics and evaluation methods for measuring the effectiveness of XAI techniques. By the end of this tutorial, you will have a better understanding of how to make your AI systems more transparent and trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 講者介紹 About Speaker - Neeraj Pandey 🚀
Neeraj is a polyglot and open-source contributor. Over the years, he has spoken at multiple international Python conferences and has worked on a variety of full-stack software and data science applications, as well as computational arts and quantitative finance projects. He enjoys the challenge of creating new tools and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conf.python.tw/"&gt;https://conf.python.tw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>The joy of creating art with code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2020/the-joy-of-creating-art-with-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-04-17:/pycon-us-2020/the-joy-of-creating-art-with-code.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon US 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Meets UX: Enhancing User Experience with Code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/python-meets-ux-enhancing-user-experience-with-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/python-meets-ux-enhancing-user-experience-with-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intersection of UX and Python programming is a powerful combination
for building great products and enhancing user experience. Python is a
versatile and popular programming language that is widely used for a
variety of tasks, including web development, data analysis, and machine
learning. UX, or user experience, is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intersection of UX and Python programming is a powerful combination
for building great products and enhancing user experience. Python is a
versatile and popular programming language that is widely used for a
variety of tasks, including web development, data analysis, and machine
learning. UX, or user experience, is the process of designing products
that provide a seamless and intuitive experience for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about this powerful intersection of UX design and Python
programming by understanding how Python can be used to enhance the user
experience and provide practical examples on how UX designers can
automate tasks, gather and analyze data, develop personalized
experiences, and continually improve their own skills and processes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Visual Data Storytelling with Blender and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/visual-data-storytelling-with-blender-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/visual-data-storytelling-with-blender-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might have encountered beautiful animations and data storytelling
through many educators and experimentalists online and wondered if it’s
only done in javascript or could also be done by Python. In this talk,
the attendees will learn how to blend the 3D animation power of Blender
with the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might have encountered beautiful animations and data storytelling
through many educators and experimentalists online and wondered if it’s
only done in javascript or could also be done by Python. In this talk,
the attendees will learn how to blend the 3D animation power of Blender
with the 2D plotting capabilities from Python libraries like matplotlib,
plotly, seaborn, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will demonstrate some practical techniques to create immersive 3D
models with Blender and enhance them with detailed 2D plots, providing a
comprehensive narrative for data interpretation. By integrating these
data-viz tools, devs and data enthusiasts will discover new &amp;amp; impactful
ways to leverage Python to present and communicate their data insights
from educational and work projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>From Desktop to Browser: Crafting Browser-Native Game Engine with Webassembly</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/from-desktop-to-browser-crafting-browser-native-game-engine-with-webassembly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neeraj Pandey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/from-desktop-to-browser-crafting-browser-native-game-engine-with-webassembly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how to turn your Python games into lightning-fast web experiences without compromising speed? In this session, overcome the browser barrier and learn how to create powerful game engines that smoothly connect desktop and web platforms using Pygame, pygbag, and WebAssembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with familiar Pygame foundations …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how to turn your Python games into lightning-fast web experiences without compromising speed? In this session, overcome the browser barrier and learn how to create powerful game engines that smoothly connect desktop and web platforms using Pygame, pygbag, and WebAssembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with familiar Pygame foundations, discover how pygbag transforms Python games into browser-ready experiences. Learn techniques for managing state, particle effects, and physics computations with near-native performance. Through live demonstrations, explore practical strategies for optimizing rendering and maintaining smooth gameplay across different environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the talk, learn how to create WebAssembly-powered games that function flawlessly on any platform without sacrificing user experience, and understand the architectural patterns that enable high-performance browser-based game engines.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>