<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_t-mawushe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Big a little i (practical artificial intelligence in python)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/big-a-little-i-practical-artificial-intelligence.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>T Mawushe</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-05:europython-2012/big-a-little-i-practical-artificial-intelligence.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] T Mawushe - 4 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days it is difficult for software to meet users’ expectations to
behave intelligently. When a program displays a lack of even the most
basic awareness of context it is jarring. At the same time organisations
are seeking to gain a competitive advantage through software that
behaves adaptively based on the information at hand. Solving these
problems is a challenge for today’s developers. There is general
agreement among seasoned developers that having a good understanding of
basic computer science data structures and algorithms is essential. That
said there is one sub-section of algorithms that is underused by most
developers, the algorithms that fall under the general rubric of
Artificial Intelligence. This talk aims to remedy that by providing a
quick refresher course on basic AI algorithms using Python. This talk is
not about building thinking machines, but rather about creating software
that users won’t think is stupid. Basic AI techniques such as Constraint
Propagation and Identification Trees, can really help developers along
the road to smarter software.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>