<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Krishi Sharma</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trust Fall: Three Hidden Gems in MLFlow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/trust-fall-three-hidden-gems-in-mlflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI research is more important now than ever. Trust in AI is critical,
but it’s hard to build trust without metrics and documentation. How can
we make documentation as easy as possible in order to maintain trust in
the results from our research? Is there a way to organize our models so
that we can ensure reproducibility? How can we save ourselves precious
development time by automating parts of the metric tracking process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll give a brief introduction to a popular metric
tracking tool, MLFlow, before going into a deep dive on three lesser
known features that can enhance collaboration, increase transparency and
reduce the time wasted reproducing results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three features that we’ll talk about are autologging, MLFlow system
tags and the MLFlow model registry. We’ll see how using these three
features can save you tons of time that would have otherwise been wasted
writing lines of code, looking for old code or finding the right model
version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you’ll have all the knowledge you need to
successfully use MLFlow to your best advantage. You’ll be able to
automatically log every parameter and metric according to your framework
of choice, link the version of code to the metrics that version produced
for faster reproducibility and have a process that you can reliably use
to write helpful documentation quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Krishi Sharma</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/trust-fall-three-hidden-gems-in-mlflow.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>