<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alejandro-saez-mollejo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Basic Python Packages for Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-madrid-2016/basic-python-packages-for-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Sáez Mollejo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-16:pydata-madrid-2016/basic-python-packages-for-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Madrid 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the talks and workshop tutorials can be found here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyDataMadrid2016/Conference-Info"&gt;https://github.com/PyDataMadrid2016/Conference-Info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aeropython’s guide to the Python Galaxy!
This workshop will be the perfect introduction to the powerful tools and packages that Python can offer to the Data Scientist. We will start with the Jupyter Notebook, and explore the basics of NumPy, matplotlib, SciPy, and many more, through hot topics of today like pollution trends or gravitational waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop is an adaptation of the Aeropython introductory course to Python for engineers, which has been taught about fifteen times at five different universities. We will guide the attendees through the main packages used in science, specifically in data science:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive Widgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NumPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SciPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scikit-Learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SymPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will follow interesting actual themes in order to add flavour, discovering the packages while working on actual data. For example, we will use temperature and pollution data, trying to find underlying patterns, and will try to replicate some of the work made on the Gravitational Waves experiment, which was as well made in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>