<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lindsey-dragun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Accessibility Matters: Creating a Better Web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lindsey Dragun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-23:djangocon-europe-2018/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is an afterthought to many, but to those with issues navigating the web it's very important. We will go over examples of accessibility on the web, short and long term solutions, and talk about why accessibility matters to a variety of users. The audience should leave with the ability to spot some accessibility issues and the knowledge of how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is a huge topic that is often acknowledged as important...by the people who already care about it. This talk is meant to help the entire audience start thinking about accessibility and realize how easy it is to at least put some accessibility into a site (or avoid adding blatantly inaccessible content).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten to fifteen percent of the EU has a disability, according to the EU Labour Force Survey, which is a large potential audience for any site. There are various laws that factor into the amount of web accessibility a country must have, and the consequences a business can face because of that. Accessible web development also tends to lead to better UX and a happier user base. And, another plus: It will save devs time and frustration when they’re working with the code, since good HTML is enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will start with a broad introduction to accessibility, how to break different concerns down into categories for consideration, and touch on some laws around web accessibility. The second part will go through examples of good and bad accessibility and what to look out for, as well as ways to improve accessibility (including &amp;quot;easy wins&amp;quot; that they could implement quickly to drastically improve their sites). The final section will include resources for finding accessibility standards and also browser extensions and the like for people to check on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will be expected to have working knowledge of the internet, webpages, and using webpages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Dragun&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Bad Accessibility Happens – That Doesn’t Have to Be The End</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2018/bad-accessibility-happens-that-doesnt-have-to-be-the-end.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lindsey Dragun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-01-22:pycascades-2018/bad-accessibility-happens-that-doesnt-have-to-be-the-end.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Avoidance is not the answer—bad accessibility will still be there, losing you users and creating bad will. We’ll go through examples of what not to do and how to fix problems. We’ll also talk about compromises that can be made to appease stakeholders and others.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="accessibility"></category></entry><entry><title>Accessibility Matters: Creating a Better Web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2017/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lindsey Dragun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-12-03:north-bay-python-2017/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is a huge topic that is often acknowledged as important...by the people who already care about it. This talk is meant to help the entire audience start thinking about accessibility and realize how easy it is to at least put some accessibility into a site (or avoid adding blatantly inaccessible content).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the U.S. Census Bureau, around 19% of Americans have a disability, which is a large potential audience for any site. Many companies also fall under accessibility laws they might not even be aware cover their products, with lawsuits becoming more prevalent in recent years, and showing a good faith effort to improve your products’ accessibility can help keep your company out of hot water. Accessible web development also tends to lead to better UX and a happier user base. And, another plus: It will save devs time and frustration when they’re working with the code, since good HTML is enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will start with a broad introduction to accessibility, how to break different concerns down into categories for consideration, and touch on the US laws and recent legal outcomes around accessibility. The second part will go through examples of good and bad accessibility and what to look out for, as well as ways to improve accessibility (including &amp;quot;easy wins&amp;quot; that they could implement quickly to drastically improve their sites). The final section will include resources for finding accessibility standards and also browser extensions and the like for people to check on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will be expected to have working knowledge of the internet, webpages, and using webpages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Accessibility Matters: Creating a Better Web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2017/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lindsey Dragun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-14:djangocon-us-2017/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US 2017 - Accessibility Matters: Creating a Better Web by Lindsey Dragun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will go through accessibility concerns on the web through example sites and code with both good and bad accessibility to experience what some users have to struggle with daily. We will cover well-known concerns such as low vision/color blindness and deafness, as well as attention issues and autism, and discuss the limitations and abilities of various alternative input devices that people with motor control issues rely on. Short and long-term fixes will be demonstrated and taught, with the overall goal being that the participants leave knowing how to find and solve accessibility problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Bother With Accessibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only should you want everyone to be able to easily use your site, but having an accessible website comes with a variety of benefits. According to the U.S. Census Bureau, around 19% of Americans have a disability, which is a large potential audience for any site. Many companies also fall under accessibility laws they might not even be aware cover their products, with lawsuits becoming more prevalent in recent years, and showing a good faith effort to improve your products’ accessibility can help keep your company out of hot water. Accessible web development also tends to lead to better UX and a happier user base. And, another plus: It will save devs time and frustration when they’re working with the code, since good HTML is enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who This Talk Is For&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who wishes to learn more about accessibility. While we won’t be going over the absolute basics of accessibility in detail, the examples and resources will be easy to understand for people with very basic knowledge of web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web/"&gt;https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>