<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nicholas Snellgrove</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nicholas-snellgrove.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Using R, Python, and Cloud Infrastructure to Battle Aquatic Invasive Species</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/using-r-python-and-cloud-infrastructure-to-battle-aquatic-invasive-species.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Uli Muellner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/using-r-python-and-cloud-infrastructure-to-battle-aquatic-invasive-species.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invasive species are a huge threat to lake ecosystems in Minnesota. With over 10,000 water bodies across the state, having up-to-date data and decision support is critical. Researchers at the University of Minnesota have created four complex R and Python models to support lake managers, all pulled together …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invasive species are a huge threat to lake ecosystems in Minnesota. With over 10,000 water bodies across the state, having up-to-date data and decision support is critical. Researchers at the University of Minnesota have created four complex R and Python models to support lake managers, all pulled together and presented with the most recent infestation data available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come along with us to see how we connected these models in the AIS Explorer, a decision support application built in Shiny to help prioritize risks and placing watercraft inspectors, using tools like OCPU and cloud toolings like Lambda, EventBridge and AWS S3.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>