<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Laysa Uchoa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Super Search with OpenSearch and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/super-search-with-opensearch-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Super Search with OpenSearch and Python - presented by Laysa Uchoa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenSearch is an open source and free document database with search and aggregation superpowers, based on Elasticsearch. This session covers how to use OpenSearch to perform both simple and advanced searches on semi-structured data such as a product database. Search is pretty useful inside applications, so we'll also discuss how to connect to OpenSearch from existing Python applications, work with data in the database, and perform search and aggregation queries from Python. This talk is recommended for Python developers whose applications are ready to gain some search superpowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laysa Uchoa</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/super-search-with-opensearch-and-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Is it me or Python memory management?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me or Python memory management? by Yuliia Barabash, Laysa Uchoa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered if Python memory management is playing tricks on you? Starting small, everything runs smoothly. But as your application scales, complexity grows, and memory issues rear their head. You ask yourself, &amp;quot;Is it me or Python memory management?&amp;quot;In this talk, we'll show you how Python memory works, provide tools to analyze memory usage and share practical optimization tips. Whether you're a seasoned Python developer or just starting on your Python journey, this talk is designed to provide you with techniques to overcome Python memory management challenges and write more efficient, memory-conscious code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yuliia Barabash</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>Python 3.10: let's pattern match! 🔥</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/python-310-lets-pattern-match.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3.10: let’s pattern match! 🔥 - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.10 is out there and with this comes Pattern Matching. With this
talk, you will be surprised how simple, yet powerful, Pattern Matching
really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk and you, it is a match! 🔥 Python 3.10 is out there now. This
was a two-digit minor version change since the last release, and with
this release new ways of thinking about programming were brought to the
Python language - Pattern Matching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will understand what was there before Python Pattern Matching and how
to use Pattern Matching in different scenarios. We will pattern match
from simple data types to more complex ones, such as dictionaries and
objects. We will also understand how to use guards, and how can build
composable patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you will be surprised how simple, yet powerful,
Pattern Matching really is. This talk and you, it is a match!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Laysa Uchoa&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laysa Uchoa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/python-310-lets-pattern-match.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>apis</category><category>best practice</category><category>development</category></item><item><title>Exploring OpenSearch, Python, and Serverless: Crafting Efficient and Modern Search Applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2023/exploring-opensearch-python-and-serverless-crafting-efficient-and-modern-search-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenSearch, a community-driven, open-source project, offers a robust
alternative for search and analytics needs. When coupled with Python's
flexibility and the efficiency of serverless architecture, it transforms
into a dynamic trio that empowers developers to create efficient and
modern search applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on a journey as we explore the synergy between OpenSearch,
Python, and serverless architecture. In this talk, we'll provide an
overview of OpenSearch and demonstrate how to utilize Python with
serverless architecture to power your search engine. Additionally, we
will delve into best practices and challenges that arise when employing
this combination in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you'll gain a clear understanding of how to
architect, build, and deploy efficient search applications using
OpenSearch, Python, and serverless architecture. Whether you're a
developer aiming to enhance your search capabilities or an architect
exploring modern search solutions, this talk will equip you with the
tools and insights needed to embrace this exciting synergy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laysa Uchoa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-12-16:/pyohio-2023/exploring-opensearch-python-and-serverless-crafting-efficient-and-modern-search-applications.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2023</category></item></channel></rss>