<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ken Jin</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CPython Developer Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/cpython-developer-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - CPython Developer Panel - presented by Łukasz Langa, Pablo Galindo Salgado, Mark Shannon, Steve Dower, Irit Katriel, Batuhan Taskaya &amp;amp; Ken Jin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come meet the folks who make the Python programming language!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A panel discussion of core Python developers will take place on Wednesday at 2pm. Hear what's on their mind, what they're working on and what the future holds for Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Pablo Galindo Salgado, Steve Dower, Batuhan Taskaya, Ken Jin, Irit Katriel and Dr.Mark &amp;quot;&amp;quot;HotPy&amp;quot;&amp;quot; Shannon. Chaired by the esteemed Łukasz &amp;quot;&amp;quot;Any color you like so long as it's black&amp;quot;&amp;quot; Langa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Łukasz Langa</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/cpython-developer-panel.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>How two undergrads from the other side of the planet are speeding up your future code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/how-two-undergrads-from-the-other-side-of-the-planet-are-speeding-up-your-future-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CPython 3.13 is planned to get cool new performance features. One of
them is an experimental runtime bytecode optimizer, which will optimize
bytecode on the fly using compiler optimizations. It aims to do
fancy-sounding things like type propagation, guard elimination, constant
promotion and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s less known - this optimizer is currently being built by a
university undergraduate 😲, with earlier iterations contributed by
another undergrad. We’re also receiving course credit for it! One of us
had no prior experience contributing to CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll split our time 60-40, with some time for the
performance enthusiasts out there, and the remaining time on our
experience contributing to CPython as an (in our opinion)
underrepresented group, and how you can contribute to CPython as a
university student as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be a compiler or CPython expert to attend – this talk
is aimed at everyone who can read and write some Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ken Jin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-19:/pycon-us-2024/how-two-undergrads-from-the-other-side-of-the-planet-are-speeding-up-your-future-code.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>