<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Richard Iannone</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_richard-iannone.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Extending Quarto</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/extending-quarto.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Iannone</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/extending-quarto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Quarto shortcode extensions? Think of them as powerful little programs you can run in your Quarto docs. I won't show you how to build a shortcode extension during this talk but rather I'm going to take you on a trip across this new ecosystem of shortcode extensions …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Quarto shortcode extensions? Think of them as powerful little programs you can run in your Quarto docs. I won't show you how to build a shortcode extension during this talk but rather I'm going to take you on a trip across this new ecosystem of shortcode extensions that people have already written. For example, I'll introduce you to the &lt;cite&gt;fancy-text&lt;/cite&gt; extension for outputting nicely-formatted versions of fancy strings such as LaTeX and BibTeX; you'll learn all about the &lt;cite&gt;fontawesome&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;lordicon&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;academicons&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;material-icons&lt;/cite&gt;, and &lt;cite&gt;bsicons&lt;/cite&gt; shortcode extensions that let you add all sorts of icons. This is only a sampling of the shortcode extensions I will present, there will be many other inspiring examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Adequate Tables? No, We Want Great Tables</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/adequate-tables-no-we-want-great-tables.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Iannone</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/adequate-tables-no-we-want-great-tables.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tables are great, and we’ve been doing a lot on both the R and Python sides to make it possible to generate aesthetically pleasing tables. The gt package for R has been under continuous development for six years, and there are still so many things we can do …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tables are great, and we’ve been doing a lot on both the R and Python sides to make it possible to generate aesthetically pleasing tables. The gt package for R has been under continuous development for six years, and there are still so many things we can do to make it better. Great Tables, our new Python package, brings beautiful tables to Python users and provides an API that’s in tune with that ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we have made great strides and unlocked new table-making possibilities for our users, our ambitions are huge! So, we’d like to show you the state of things on this front and also where we intend to go with our collective table efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Making Beautiful, Publication Quality Tables in Python is Possible in 2024</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/making-beautiful-publication-quality-tables-in-python-is-possible-in-2024.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Chow</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/making-beautiful-publication-quality-tables-in-python-is-possible-in-2024.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tables are undeniably useful for data work. We have many excellent
DataFrame libraries in Python and they give us the flexibility to
manipulate data to our hearts content. But what happens when comes to
presenting tables to others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display of tables can be beautiful. Tables can convey information …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tables are undeniably useful for data work. We have many excellent
DataFrame libraries in Python and they give us the flexibility to
manipulate data to our hearts content. But what happens when comes to
presenting tables to others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display of tables can be beautiful. Tables can convey information
effectively, just as plots do and, sometimes, it’s the better way to
present data. Truly, the time has come to bridge the divide between raw
DataFrame output and wondrously-structured tables suitable for
publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's review the state of ‘display tables’ in 2024. We’ll go over which
table components make for effective displays of information. It’s
surprising but there are many considerations that go into making a
well-crafted table. We’ll take a look at the combinations of Python
packages that fit together to make this important task possible, and
marvel together at the tabular results they can provide.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Great Tables for Everyone</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/great-tables-for-everyone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Iannone</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/great-tables-for-everyone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you find yourself copying your data into Word, just to make a table? If this is you (and this was us) it’s both frustrating and prone to errors. And even though every aspect of a typical analysis can be scripted, it often turns out that the table-making …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you find yourself copying your data into Word, just to make a table? If this is you (and this was us) it’s both frustrating and prone to errors. And even though every aspect of a typical analysis can be scripted, it often turns out that the table-making part is elusive. We made Great Tables to enable complete publishing workflows. This Python package lets you easily generate publication-quality tables with the structure you want, many options for formatting values, and plenty of freedom for styling. Importantly, Great Tables closely integrates with Pandas and Polars DataFrames in order to handle a wide range of analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>