<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lee Kyu-bong</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Challenge of writing a binding for a distributed system algorithm implementation using PyO3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/challenge-of-writing-a-binding-for-a-distributed-system-algorithm-implementation-using-pyo3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will cover technical details related to Python binding, which I have spent the most time thinking about since joining Lablup and which I am currently working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, I will cover technical details related to reference type abstraction to overcome the memory management differences between Rust and Python, as well as technical details related to trait exposure and exception handling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the topic covers technical details, it will be helpful to understand the presentation if you have prior knowledge of Rust or PyO3, but I have prepared it so that you can roughly understand the presentation content even if you do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee Gyu-bong
Lablup DevOps / Developer. A developer interested in various open source activities. Currently, I am challenging and working on various issues related to distributed systems at the company. This presentation will cover technical details related to Python binding, which I have spent the most time thinking about since joining Lablup and which I am currently working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lee Kyu-bong</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/challenge-of-writing-a-binding-for-a-distributed-system-algorithm-implementation-using-pyo3.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>