<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_david-hoese.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using SatPy to Process Earth observing Satellite Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/using-satpy-to-process-earth-observing-satellite-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Hoese</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/using-satpy-to-process-earth-observing-satellite-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is an introduction to SatPy, a python library for easily reading and working with earth-observing satellite data like that of the NOAA-20 VIIRS or GOES-16 ABI instruments. It is aimed at scientific users who would like to simplify some of their satellite data processing tasks. No previous experience with SatPy is needed. During this tutorial we’ll work through common satellite processing tasks using SatPy using Jupyter Notebook examples with real instrument data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>SatPy: A Python Library for Weather Satellite Processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/satpy-a-python-library-for-weather-satellite-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Hoese</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-11:scipy-2018/satpy-a-python-library-for-weather-satellite-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The amount of data sent to earth by meteorological satellites increases
with each new satellite generation. Software used by the scientific
community to interpret the data must be able to handle different file
formats and data types, to resample/interpolate the data, to create RGB
composites, and to write output in many possible formats. To do this
quickly and easily a new python library has been created called SatPy.
This talk will provide a detailed overview of SatPy’s features and how
its simple interfaces can be used as an interactive research tool or in
stable operational processing.Presenter(s): Speaker: David Hoese,
University of Wisconsin - Madison, Space Science and Engineering Center
Speaker: Martin Raspaud, Swedish Meteorological and Hydrological
Institute&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>