<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pam-selle.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Angular 2 and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/angular-2-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pam Selle</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-13:djangocon-us-2016/angular-2-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Angular 2 and You by Pam Selle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AngularJS is one of, if not the, most popular JavaScript framework out there today. But a new day is coming: The dawn of Angular 2! Angular comes with a robust community and standard of practice, but Angular 2 is something even more intriguing: a JavaScript framework based on components (not unlike React!), with an eye towards complying with future web standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll cover the broad strokes of Angular 2, including some of the big game changers: web components and “choose your own language” support, and how it integrates into back-ends like Django to provide some structure to your front-end. You'll learn about Angular 2's approach to the &amp;quot;JavaScript framework&amp;quot; problem, how components create modularity in your application, and a little bit about the JavaScript build toolchain (mysterious to many!) that the JavaScript world is constantly debating over.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>3. Hacking for Humanity with Python: The CuiBono political app</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/3-hacking-for-humanity-with-python-the-cuibono.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jim Snavely</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-11:pycon-us-2012/3-hacking-for-humanity-with-python-the-cuibono.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This poster discusses the development of the CuiBono &amp;quot;political ad truth
detector&amp;quot; app, from concept, to hackathon, to launch. The poster also
talks about Python's prominence at the Philadelphia Random Hacks of
Kindness hackathon (Winter 2011)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>