<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jack Fitzsimons</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jack-fitzsimons.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Eyes off data science: a transparently opaque framework for data processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/eyes-off-data-science-a-transparently-opaque-framework-for-data-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jack Fitzsimons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/eyes-off-data-science-a-transparently-opaque-framework-for-data-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you ever notice that the most important and impactful data sources are inherently sensitive in nature - from healthcare to finance. Even seemingly banal information like your commuting patterns, purchasing habits or insurance reimbursements, can tell a nuanced story of who you are and how you can be influenced …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you ever notice that the most important and impactful data sources are inherently sensitive in nature - from healthcare to finance. Even seemingly banal information like your commuting patterns, purchasing habits or insurance reimbursements, can tell a nuanced story of who you are and how you can be influenced. This causes a headache for the honest data scientist who is interested in big picture analytics, not spy-stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there has been a huge movement over the past 10-15 years to create a new type of tech stack founded on the concept of privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs), which act as brokers of trust between data sources and data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will give an overview of how we have been building (and today launching) a new python framework, which integrates directly with Jupyter via a backend extension, to make using PETs trivial in the day to day functions of a data scientist. We call it Antigranular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect this project to be a long term endeavour and if you are interested in privacy, confidentiality, security and, of course, data science we would encourage you to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry></feed>