<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Trang Le</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_trang-le.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Small Package, Broad Impact: How I Discovered the Ultimate New Hire Hack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/small-package-broad-impact-how-i-discovered-the-ultimate-new-hire-hack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Trang Le</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/small-package-broad-impact-how-i-discovered-the-ultimate-new-hire-hack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Onboarding new hires can be a challenging process, but taking a problem-focused approach can make it more meaningful and rewarding. In this talk, I will share how I discovered the ultimate new hire hack by creating two small packages that gave me the confidence I needed when I started …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Onboarding new hires can be a challenging process, but taking a problem-focused approach can make it more meaningful and rewarding. In this talk, I will share how I discovered the ultimate new hire hack by creating two small packages that gave me the confidence I needed when I started at BMS. Through building these packages, I not only learned R things like using bslib and making font files available for published dashboards, but also gained a deep understanding of my company's internal systems and workflows, and connected with my team via lots of questions. The resulting packages are still heavily used today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me to discover how small packages can have a broad impact and what hiring managers can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>