<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Daniel Woodie</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daniel-woodie.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Developing a Prototyping Competency in a Statistical Science Organization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/developing-a-prototyping-competency-in-a-statistical-science-organization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Woodie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/developing-a-prototyping-competency-in-a-statistical-science-organization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introduction of new tools, methods, and processes can be a struggle within a statistical science organization. Being deliberate and investing in the creation of a prototyping competency can help in accelerating progress. Prototyping allows organizations to quickly experiment with new ideas, reduce the risk of failure, identify potential …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introduction of new tools, methods, and processes can be a struggle within a statistical science organization. Being deliberate and investing in the creation of a prototyping competency can help in accelerating progress. Prototyping allows organizations to quickly experiment with new ideas, reduce the risk of failure, identify potential issues early, and iterate until the desired outcome is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will highlight the key areas we have focused on accelerating, our framework for developing this competency, how we use Shiny, and the lessons we've learned along the way. Developing a prototyping competency is crucial for statistical science organizations that wish to stay competitive and innovative in today's rapidly changing landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>