<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Bianca Rosa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Observability driven development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/observability-driven-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You're all happy developing your application but when it comes the time to send it to production and have the first customers testing, you might realize that whenever a bug is found it is just too hard to understand what is going on in a production environment - you often don't have access to the user data, the user account and struggles to reproduce the error and support your customer properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is too familiar and probably happened to a lot of of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will walk through techniques and things to consider when writing an application that is going to be supported in a production environment with an eye for observability by having searchable, consistent, and rich log messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the problem will be presented to the audience with a use-case scenario where a developer has no way of knowing what happened with a particular customer in a production environment if an API request fails.
Opening the code for this request, we will add together the log messages that would've made it possible for the development to debug this problem properly - and then, talk through strategies to keep in mind during the early development of the code.
We will also walk through log levels and how to use them properly, making sure the log messages are clean and understandable, how to take take advantage of log's extra fields to have metadata about the messages that we are writing, and the best way to make log messages easily searchable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bianca Rosa</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/observability-driven-development.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>Escrevendo um bot do telegram em Python para a comunidade PythOnRio</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyjamas-conf-2019/escrevendo-um-bot-do-telegram-em-python-para-a-comunidade-pythonrio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A ideia desse live stream é unir o útil ao agradável e fazer um bot em conjunto para acionar regras, código de conduta e boas vindas para novos membros no grupo.
Podemos usar algo pronto, mas é mais divertido construirmos algo juntos :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bianca Rosa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:/pyjamas-conf-2019/escrevendo-um-bot-do-telegram-em-python-para-a-comunidade-pythonrio.html</guid><category>Pyjamas Conf 2019</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion: Vozes na Tecnologia: Contando Experiências na Indústria de Tecnologia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-vozes-na-tecnologia-contando-experiencias-na-industria-de-tecnologia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panel Discussion in Portuguese&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Débora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/panel-discussion-vozes-na-tecnologia-contando-experiencias-na-industria-de-tecnologia.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Redes Neurais com Python e Scikit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2017/redes-neurais-com-python-e-scikit.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bianca Rosa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:/python-brasil-2017/redes-neurais-com-python-e-scikit.html</guid><category>Python Brasil 2017</category></item></channel></rss>