<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_marco-montanari.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Django, Django Rest Framework and Angular2: RAD on SaaS platforms</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/django-django-rest-framework-and-angular2-rad-on-saas-platforms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Montanari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-10:europython-2017/django-django-rest-framework-and-angular2-rad-on-saas-platforms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rapid Application Development has been a major topic for the desktop
development world. Yet, desktop development has proven to be at the
end of its timeline and the latest major environment is now the web
in its many forms (from browser to Electron and similars). Django
offers an amazing infrastructure and Django Rest Framework an amazing
middleware to solve most of the problems. The RAD development on
Angular2 is then enabled by a set of libraries developed at Modal
Nodes for both front and backend that ease the development of the
front end tools and front end interactions with both unauthenticated
and authenticated systems via JWT and Djoser. Specifically, we will
see the changes in the metadata that will enable better interactions
and the usage of both the backend elements and the front-end ones in
order to ease development.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>DaNKInDaB - A New Approach to Servers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/dankindab-a-new-approach-to-servers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Montanari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-17:pycon-us-2013/dankindab-a-new-approach-to-servers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of having a web-configurable web/application server with
virtualhosting support using the best Python-based tools to integrate
into the company toolset for the development team has always been
intriguing to me. This tool tries to create a complete webserver
enabling easy deployment of apps on on-premises hardware for both the
lucky ones having a private cloud, and for those who don't.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="poster"></category></entry></feed>