<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Matthew Nicely</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_matthew-nicely.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Harnessing NVIDIA Tensor Cores: An Exploration of CUTLASS &amp; OpenAI Triton</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-harnessing-nvidia-tensor-cores-an-exploration-of-cutlass-openai-triton.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matthew Nicely</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-harnessing-nvidia-tensor-cores-an-exploration-of-cutlass-openai-triton.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover the power of NVIDIA Tensor Cores and accelerate your PyTorch development using two cutting-edge open-source libraries: CUTLASS and OpenAI Triton. This presentation aims to inspire both novice and seasoned PyTorch developers to unlock new efficiencies and capabilities in their work. We delve into the architecture of CUTLASS, revealing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover the power of NVIDIA Tensor Cores and accelerate your PyTorch development using two cutting-edge open-source libraries: CUTLASS and OpenAI Triton. This presentation aims to inspire both novice and seasoned PyTorch developers to unlock new efficiencies and capabilities in their work. We delve into the architecture of CUTLASS, revealing its diverse use cases and value proposition. Simultaneously, we explore Triton's transformative capabilities for NVIDIA Tensor Cores, and the roadmaps for these essential tools. I hope to inspire the audience to engage with these tools for their projects, contributing to a high-performing PyTorch community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2023"></category><category term="Lightning Talk"></category></entry></feed>