<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_parul-sethi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Information Extraction Using Topic Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/information-extraction-using-topic-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Parul Sethi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-09:scipy-2018/information-extraction-using-topic-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Topic Modeling is an information retrieval technique to identify topics
in a large corpus of text documents. This tutorial will guide you
through the process of analyzing your textual data right from
pre-processing raw data - applying topic modeling algorithms -
evaluating manually and automatically - analyzing using visualizations
and its applications in few NLP tasks: Discovering topic correlation
(with dendrograms), Document clustering (demo with Tensorboard),
Document analysis (using word coloring). We will also cover the variants
of topic models like dynamic topic model that learns the evolution of
topics in a corpus collected over different time-stamps, and author
topic model that learns the topic representations of authors in a
corpus.Presenter(s): Speaker: Parul Sethi, University of Delhi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Visualizing Topic Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/visualizing-topic-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T15:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T15:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Parul sethi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/visualizing-topic-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Topic Modelling is a great way to infer topics in a large corpus of text documents but analyzing them could become difficult without any visualization. The purpose of this talk is to introduce the visualizations that aids the process of training topic models and analyze their results for downstream NLP applications. I’ll give a brief introduction to Topic Models before moving to visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll demonstrate the steps to train LDA model in gensim and create the following visualizations using the trained model and how to interpret them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDA Training visualization: Monitoring the LDA model training using Visdom integration in gensim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pyLDAvis: Topic interpretation using the relevance metric effectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic Networks: Discover connections between topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic difference visualization: Determine exact distances between every topic pair along with their intersection/difference of terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dendrogram (with extended heatmap): Topic clustering with a deeper insight into the inter-topic semantic validity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDA Projections: Document clustering using tensorboard based on the topic representation of documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interface for this talk would be Jupyter notebook containing the LDA training and visualisations code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>