<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Intelligent recruitment using NLP and machine learning to identify the most suitable candidates</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/intelligent-recruitment-using-nlp-and-machine-learning-to-identify-the-most-suitable-candidates.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is very common to get 100s of applicants for a role, which is
becoming difficult for recruiters to shortlist the most relevant
candidates. We present here a solution developed at dunnhumby that
leverages Natural Language Processing to assist our recruitment team. By
simply providing a reference resume, our tool helps identifying similar
candidates, helping us focus on the right candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk presents a real-life example of application of machine learning
and natural language processing for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every role we advertise, we get 100s if not 1000s of applicants.
Shortlisting the most relevant candidates becomes therefore very
difficult, and no recruitment team has the capacity and time to go
through all the CV of the candidates who applied for a role. It also
increases the chances to miss the ideal candidate. We present here a
solution developed internally that leverages natural language processing
to shortlist the most relevant candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very often, the hiring manager provides the recruitment team with a
reference CV of the ideal profile he or she is looking for. The way we
have designed the tool is as follows: The text from all the CVs is
extracted and converted into a vector format using Word2Vec. This
generates a vector representation of the candidate’s CV, which are then
compared using cosine-similarities with the vector of the reference CV.
This returns the CV that are the most similar to our reference profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology has proven to give good results, particularly efficient
at shortlisting the most promising candidates. It still does not replace
an actual interview, but it has the potential of greatly reducing the
hiring time and ensuring only the most promising candidates are
interviewed, saving time for both the manager and the candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Victor Robin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-03:pydata-delhi-2019/intelligent-recruitment-using-nlp-and-machine-learning-to-identify-the-most-suitable-candidates.html</guid></item></channel></rss>