<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Your Brain on Python, Literally</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/florida-pycon-2017/your-brain-on-python-literally.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the near future, when you get sick, you’ll be able to get treatment
that’s been personally tailored to your exact situation. This is
possible thanks to the “Body-on-a-Chip”, an emerging field of study in
which human cells with your genetic material are grown into a miniature
system that mimics the function of every major organ in your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These little systems generate a lot of data, and Python is a great way
to gain insight into what these systems are doing and how they’re
responding to a treatment. Data from the “brain” of these systems, a
“brain-on-a-chip” made from real human neurons, is some of the most
challenging and exciting data that there is to analyze. We can gain
insight into how these brain cells are ‘talking’ to each other and how
they’re reorganizing themselves, and how their ability to do these
things changes under different conditions. These insights can help guide
treatment decisions, give understanding into the basic nature of the
brain in general, and open up exciting new opportunities for
technologies that sound like they’re from science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This beginner-friendly talk will walk you through how it’s done, from
getting the raw data to the final analysis, highlighting how everyone’s
favorite language makes the whole endeavor a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Max Jackson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-07:florida-pycon-2017/your-brain-on-python-literally.html</guid></item></channel></rss>