<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Neuroscience Lab</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-barcelona-2017/the-neuroscience-lab.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an excellent fit for scientists; it is readable, has an active scientific community, and, most importantly, is versatile across a wide variety of programming tasks. In this talk, we will celebrate this versatility of Python by sharing the research being done in our neuroscience laboratory, focusing on Python’s involvement in each step of our scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biologists have always built their own hardware to perform unique experiments; today, new data collection and analysis techniques demand that they develop their own software as well. Often, this means that researchers without a formal education in programming must perform a wide variety of programming tasks in order to perform cutting-edge research. As a “real” programming language, Python is an excellent fit for scientists, not only for its oft-celebrated readability, active scientific community, and cross-platform support, but also for its versatility across a wide variety of domains. In this talk, we will celebrate this versatility of Python by sharing the research being done in our neuroscience laboratory, focusing how Python packages, applications, and plugins have become the tools of choice for everything from real-time machine vision and 3D graphics to data analysis and the presentation of scientific results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicholas A. Del Grosso</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-21:pydata-barcelona-2017/the-neuroscience-lab.html</guid></item></channel></rss>