<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lilinoe Harbottle</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lilinoe-harbottle.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>PyLadies Panel: Experiences and Roles within the Tech Community and Open Source</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/pyladies-panel-experiences-and-roles-within-the-tech-community-and-open-source.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tammy Do</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-09:/pycascades-2025/pyladies-panel-experiences-and-roles-within-the-tech-community-and-open-source.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tammy Do, Drishti Jain, Parul Gupta, Lilinoe Harbottle, and Nasim&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Ctrl+Alt+Heal: Python and the Future of MedTech</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/ctrlaltheal-python-and-the-future-of-medtech.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lilinoe Harbottle</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-08:/pycascades-2025/ctrlaltheal-python-and-the-future-of-medtech.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore how Python is transforming medical robotics in this engaging talk. Discover applications in medical imaging and predictive maintenance, focusing on extracting critical insights to enhance robotic performance. Attendees will learn to leverage Python's data science tools to tackle complex healthcare challenges. A basic understanding of Python and its …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore how Python is transforming medical robotics in this engaging talk. Discover applications in medical imaging and predictive maintenance, focusing on extracting critical insights to enhance robotic performance. Attendees will learn to leverage Python's data science tools to tackle complex healthcare challenges. A basic understanding of Python and its libraries will enrich the experience, enabling participants to engage with the content and apply insights to their projects. Ideal for Python developers, data scientists, and healthcare tech enthusiasts—no medical background is required, just a passion for Python and its innovative potential in cutting-edge medical technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2025"></category></entry></feed>