<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jeff-hollan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Deploy Python to the cloud faster with Azure Serverless</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/deploy-python-to-the-cloud-faster-with-azure-serverless.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Hollan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/deploy-python-to-the-cloud-faster-with-azure-serverless.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bringing your Python scripts or apps and running them in the cloud is
easier than ever with serverless computing. In this talk, we’ll show how
you can use Azure Functions to easily deploy and scale your Python
workloads without having to manage any servers or pay for unused compute
resources. We’ll also show how deep integration with Visual Studio Code
offers a great local development experience with full support for
debugging and testing your app, and allows you to seamlessly deploy your
serverless code to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by giving a brief overview of the value of serverless
computing. Next, we'll create a brand new Python app in Visual Studio
Code, and start to add in business logic and ML capabilities. Once we
get the app running debugged locally, we’ll publish it to the cloud as a
serverless function, and demonstrate the serverless scalability.
Finally, we’ll walk you through the tools and capabilities you can
leverage around monitoring and management of your Python Azure
Functions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="APIs"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Microservices"></category><category term="Scaling"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry></feed>