<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lilian</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creating the Next Generation of Billionaires - Part 4</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/creating-the-next-generation-of-billionaires-part-4.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Creating the Next Generation of Billionaires - Part 4 - presented by Lilian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our generation of young people in school (aged 5-18) have noticed the connection between Computer pRogramming, Technology, Bitcoinism Success, Climate Change and Billionaires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mass young people are clamouring to master the skill of Computer pRogramming. It has been dubbed the ‘4th’ R’ (computer pRogramming) along with Reading, wRiting and aRithmetic. So, governments worldwide have launched initiatives to have it taught in schools from Kindergarten to all the way to high school. And now young people are successfully mastering this skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe a case study whereby Computer Programming (Python) was introduced for the first time to a group of young people and how the young people are using it to explore and understand real world problems and data such as those relating to climate change, world population growth and carbon dioxide emissions with Python visualisation libraries such as Matplotlib, Numpy and Pandas. We will talk about the joys and challenges and discoveries made by the young people. We will conclude with suggestions on how to proceed in this area.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilian</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/creating-the-next-generation-of-billionaires-part-4.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>What my 300+ fantastic young students taught me about Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/what-my-300-fantastic-young-students-taught-me-about-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/what-my-300-fantastic-young-students-taught-me-about-python"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/what-my-300-fantastic-young-students-taught-me-about-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer pRogramming, Technology, Bit-coinism Success, Climate Change and Billionaires are all associated with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe how a cohort of  299+ young people (aged 11-14) were introduced to Python Programming, at the same time, for the very first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in this talk, I  would like to share with a great secret in that I have actually learnt more from the young students than they learnt from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about how these young people have opened my eyes, mind  and heart about alternative ways of looking at and appreciating:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The humble IF statement;  the under-rated FOR loop, the dry Return Statement, the functional Maths &amp;amp; Random modules, etc. as if one were an artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will talk about the renewed delight of looking at these things from fresh pairs of eyes and how we can take these new learnings forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilian</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/what-my-300-fantastic-young-students-taught-me-about-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Djangonaut Space: A Mentorship Program For Open Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2025/djangonaut-space-a-mentorship-program-for-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lilian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/C8YYBZ"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/C8YYBZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Djangonaut Space is a mentorship program created to address the problem of sustainability for open source projects. Now into its 4th session, it helps grow the community and bridge the gap between new contributors and long-time maintainers, ensuring the web framework and its eco-system continues to thrive and adapt to changing needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share my experiences and insights about Djangonaut Space as a new contributor and session organizer. Whether you’re new to open source, or a long-time maintainer, or a community leader, a mentorship program can have many benefits for your community. Learn how you can get involved, or how you might borrow ideas to create a successful mentorship program for your community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Apr 27 11:20:00 2025 at Reis River Ranch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilian</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-27:/north-bay-python-2025/djangonaut-space-a-mentorship-program-for-open-source.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2025</category></item></channel></rss>