<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_safia-abdalla.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Sunday Morning keynote</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/sunday-morning-keynote.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Safia Abdalla</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/sunday-morning-keynote.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning something new can often spark new connections in our minds.
Very recently, I started running and focusing on fitness --
and discovered numberous revelations about programming in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll share what just six months of running has shown me
about my six years in the software industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Popping Kernels: An Exploration of Kernel Development for Jupyter Notebooks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/popping-kernels-an-exploration-of-kernel-development-for-jupyter-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Safia Abdalla</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-26:pydata-chicago-2016/popping-kernels-an-exploration-of-kernel-development-for-jupyter-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give individuals with no kernel experience and some Python experience, a brief introduction to the concepts they need to understand in order to develop kernels. This talk will also be useful to individuals who are looking for fun projects that will allow them to strengthen their skills in a particular programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="development"></category><category term="jupyter"></category><category term="jupyter notebook"></category></entry><entry><title>Bringing Research to Real Life</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/bringing-research-to-real-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Safia Abdalla</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/bringing-research-to-real-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is a fascinating field with numerous applications in
data science. New research is always emerging in the field of machine
learning but it can take years for this research to be converted into
usable software libraries. In this talk, I'll be providing a technique
for reading (actually reading) research papers and using the powerful
syntax and data-focused libraries of Python to write up quick and dirty
implementations of techniques written out in research papers. This talk
is relevant to any practical professional who occasionally strays into
the field of academics to discover new techniques that are applicable to
the data problems that they are attempting to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>