<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Felix Wick</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to Setup a new Python Project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/how-to-setup-a-new-python-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new Python project from scratch can be quite hard. How to
structure your files and directories. Where should my packages, modules,
documentation and unit tests go? How do I configure setup.py, Sphinx and
so on? We provide proven answers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever a Python beginner starts with its own project he or she is
confronted with the same technical questions. Questions about a well
thought out directory structure to hold all the files. How setup.py
needs to be configured and even what it is capable of like specifying
entry_points and other goodies. We show from the experience of our
yearslong work with Python how to structure your Python project in terms
of folders, files, modules and packages. How to configure setup.py to
specify your requirements, to use it with nosetests, with Sphinx and so
on. We also elaborate on the usage of Git and Versioneer
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/warner/python-versioneer"&gt;https://github.com/warner/python-versioneer&lt;/a&gt;) to help you version your
package.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felix Wick</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-23:/europython-2014/how-to-setup-a-new-python-project.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2014</category></item><item><title>Exploring the Power of Cyclic Boosting</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/exploring-the-power-of-cyclic-boosting.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have recently open-sourced a pure-Python implementation of Cyclic Boosting, a family of general-purpose, supervised machine learning algorithms. Its predictions are fully explainable on individual sample level, and yet Cyclic Boosting can deliver highly accurate and robust models. For this, it requires little hyperparameter tuning and minimal data pre-processing (including support for missing information and categorical variables of high cardinality), making it an ideal off-the-shelf method for structured, heterogeneous data sets. Furthermore, it is computationally inexpensive and fast, allowing for rapid improvement iterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modeling process, especially the infamous but unavoidable feature engineering, is facilitated by automatic creation of an extensive set of visualizations for data dependencies and training results. In this presentation, we will provide an overview of the inner workings of Cyclic Boosting, along with a few sample use cases, and demonstrate the usage of the new Python library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felix Wick</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/exploring-the-power-of-cyclic-boosting.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item></channel></rss>