<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_axel-goblet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Scheduling machine learning pipelines using Apache Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/scheduling-machine-learning-pipelines-using-apache-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Axel Goblet</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-29:pydata-eindhoven-2019/scheduling-machine-learning-pipelines-using-apache-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scheduling machine learning pipelines in a robust fashion is an
important aspect of many data science projects. Apache Airflow is an
industry standard tool to author, schedule, and monitor complex data
processing workflows. In this workshop, participants will get hands-on
experience with Airflow, and learn how to properly schedule their
machine learning pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past years, the data science teams within organizations matured
in their experimentation capabilities. Making machine learning pipelines
production-ready has become the new main challenge. Apache Airflow is an
industry standard tool for authoring, scheduling, and monitoring
complex, production-grade workflows, with a strong focus on data
processing pipelines. The tool is highly customizable, and integrates
well with most modern working environments and data sources. Airflow
workflows are written in Python, which intersects with the capabilities
of typical data science teams. This workshop is useful for both data
scientists and data engineers who want to schedule machine learning
pipelines in a robust fashion. In the first plenary part, participants
will learn what Airflow is and when it is useful. We will cover the
principles and architecture of Airflow, and show some example workflows.
After that, participants will create their own workflow to schedule a
basic machine learning pipeline, and deploy it. For the more experienced
participants, we offer a bonus assignment; they will leverage Airflow’s
plugin system to further customize their pipeline. The necessary tools
for this workshop will be provided; all you need is a laptop with an
internet browser and basic Python knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>