<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Will barnes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_will-barnes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A Complete fiasco - Dealing with Atomic Data and a Pythonic Solution</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyastro-2018/a-complete-fiasco-dealing-with-atomic-data-and-a-pythonic-solution.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Will Barnes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-30:/pyastro-2018/a-complete-fiasco-dealing-with-atomic-data-and-a-pythonic-solution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atomic data is used ubiquitously throughout the astrophysics and
astronomy community. Whether it is performing radiative transfer
calculations in a protoplanetary disk or interpreting observed spectra
in the solar corona, observers and modelers alike rely heavily on vast
amounts of detailed atomic data. These databases, which contain data
from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atomic data is used ubiquitously throughout the astrophysics and
astronomy community. Whether it is performing radiative transfer
calculations in a protoplanetary disk or interpreting observed spectra
in the solar corona, observers and modelers alike rely heavily on vast
amounts of detailed atomic data. These databases, which contain data
from both laboratory experiments and large simulation codes, are often
difficult to access, have no common format, and require a great deal of
effort (and funding) to assemble. One such example is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chiantidatabase.org/"&gt;CHIANTI
atomic database&lt;/a&gt; which has been maintained continuously since 1995 and
is heavily used by solar physicists. Recently I’ve begun work on a
package called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/wtbarnes/fiasco"&gt;fiasco&lt;/a&gt; (the Italian name for the style of bottle used
to store a Chianti wine) which provides a high-level interface to the
CHIANTI database. In this talk, I’ll discuss the difficulties of working
with this data, the software and techniques used to parse the data, and
the high-level interface. Additionally, and most importantly, I will
discuss the possible use of fiasco as a general interface to any atomic
database and how this might extend the usefulness of the package into
the general astronomy community. My hope is that this last point in
particular will generate much discussion and interest in how to improve
programmatic interfaces to this type of data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyAstro 2018"></category><category term="fiasco"></category></entry><entry><title>ChiantiPy a Python Package for Astrophysical Spectroscopy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/chiantipy-a-python-package-for-astrophysical-spectroscopy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Will Barnes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:/scipy-2017/chiantipy-a-python-package-for-astrophysical-spectroscopy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ChiantiPy is an interface to the CHIANTI atomic database for astrophysical spectroscopy. The highly-cited CHIANTI project, now in its 20th year, is an invaluable resource to the solar physics community. The ChiantiPy project brings the power of the scientific Python stack to the CHIANTI database, allowing solar physicists and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ChiantiPy is an interface to the CHIANTI atomic database for astrophysical spectroscopy. The highly-cited CHIANTI project, now in its 20th year, is an invaluable resource to the solar physics community. The ChiantiPy project brings the power of the scientific Python stack to the CHIANTI database, allowing solar physicists and astronomers to easily make use of this atomic data and calculate commonly used quantities from it such as radiative loss rates and emissivities for particular atomic transitions. In this talk, we will briefly discuss the history of the CHIANTI database and the ChiantiPy project as well as the current state of the project and its place in the solar physics community. We will demonstrate some of the capabilities of the ChiantiPy code and show examples of how ChiantiPy can be used in both modeling and observational studies. Finally, we'll discuss how ChiantiPy helps to bring the power of the CHIANTIC atomic database to the growing set of astronomy-related tools in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2017"></category><category term="ChiantiPy"></category></entry><entry><title>Accelerating the SunPy Data Analysis Ecosystem with Dask</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/accelerating-the-sunpy-data-analysis-ecosystem-with-dask.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Will barnes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/accelerating-the-sunpy-data-analysis-ecosystem-with-dask.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, the SunPy ecosystem, a Python solar data analysis environment, has evolved organically to serve the needs of scientists analyzing solar physics data, mostly on desktop and laptop computers. However, modern solar observatories are producing data volumes in the tens of petabytes, necessitating the need for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, the SunPy ecosystem, a Python solar data analysis environment, has evolved organically to serve the needs of scientists analyzing solar physics data, mostly on desktop and laptop computers. However, modern solar observatories are producing data volumes in the tens of petabytes, necessitating the need for parallelized and out-of-core computation. HelioCloud is a cloud computing environment tailored for heliophysics research and colocated with many terabytes of solar physics data. In this talk, we will show how the SunPy ecosystem, combined with Dask on HelioCloud, can be used to efficiently process high-resolution solar data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks DAY 2 | SciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Pastor Muela</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>