<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sarah Abderemane</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Djangonaut Space, how we organized a mentorship program</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/djangonaut-space-how-we-organized-a-mentorship-program.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting to contribute to a big project might be scary or you just don’t know how to start. So it is not surprising that it is difficult to find new dedicated contributors to a project. This is something that Djangonaut Space organizers want to help with and make people feel that they are part of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that goal in mind, Djangonaut Space launched its first 3-month mentorship program in the Summer of 2023 mentoring 6 members of the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on Djangonaut Space here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://djangonaut.space/"&gt;https://djangonaut.space/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start with why the Django community felt there was a need for a mentorship program. This will include where this idea came from and how other communities might identify a similar need. Then we will go over how Djangonaut Space began. This will include the power of a pilot and what you will need to consider when organizing your own mentorship program.Finally we will see the outcomes of the Djangonaut Space program. This will cover our successes and what didn’t work as we expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can attendees learn:
- How to organize a mentorship program for your own project community
- Things to think about before you start one
- All about Djangonaut Space&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sarah Abderemane</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/djangonaut-space-how-we-organized-a-mentorship-program.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item></channel></rss>