<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - James Walters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What Django Deployment is Really About</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/what-django-deployment-is-really-about.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;People often spend so much time learning how to build apps in Django that when it comes time for deployment, it feels like a whole new world that they don't understand. Deployment recipes might help them get their app online--but then again they might not, if the steps that worked yesterday don't work today. Even if they do get online, they might not understand that deployment process anymore than they did before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of offering another set of steps, I think we can help beginners to make sense of deployment by reducing the entire process to four major areas of concern and equipping them to think through each of these on its own terms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static Files - why do I have to worry about these now? I thought &lt;cite&gt;{% raw %}{% static %}{% endraw %}&lt;/cite&gt; was handling it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database - does my sqlite3 file not work in deployment? How do I use my cloud provider's remote DB?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WSGI Server -  how do I run my app in production? Doesn't manage.py runserver work? I've never heard of WSGI, what is it and why does it matter to my Django project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Server (Apache/nginx/PaaS) - What do I need to understand about web servers like Apache or nginx to get my project online? Do I even need to configure a web server if I go with PaaS?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll also consider:
- Django's deployment checklist
- django-simple-deploy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A link to slides will be posted after the talk at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://james.walters.click/"&gt;http://james.walters.click/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Walters</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-17:/djangocon-us-2023/what-django-deployment-is-really-about.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Web Scraping Crash Course! With Python and Scrapy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2023/web-scraping-crash-course-with-python-and-scrapy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;APIs are a great way to consume publicly accessible data. But what do
you do when there's no API? Enter web scraping: a way you can harvest
data out of the same HTML documents you look at in your web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll talk about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is web scraping?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Scrapy and why should you use it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to scrape data from HTML elements in a web page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code for the example project in the talk will be available!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Walters</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-12-16:/pyohio-2023/web-scraping-crash-course-with-python-and-scrapy.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2023</category></item><item><title>What Django Deployment is Really About</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2024/what-django-deployment-is-really-about.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;People often spend so much time learning how to build apps in Django
that when it comes time for deployment, it feels like a whole new world
that they don’t understand. Deployment recipes might help them get their
app online–but then again they might not, if the steps that worked
yesterday don’t work today. Even if they do get online, they might not
understand that deployment process anymore than they did before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of offering another set of steps, I think we can help beginners
to make sense of deployment by reducing the entire process to four major
areas of concern and equipping them to think through each of these on
its own terms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static Files - why do I have to worry about these now? I thought {%
static %} was handling it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database - does my sqlite3 file not work in deployment? How do I use
my cloud provider’s remote DB?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WSGI Server - how do I run my app in production? Doesn’t manage.py
runserver work? I’ve never heard of WSGI, what is it and why does it
matter to my Django project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Server (Apache/nginx/PaaS) - What do I need to understand about
web servers like Apache or nginx to get my project online? Do I even
need to configure a web server if I go with PaaS?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll also consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django’s deployment checklist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;django-simple-deploy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Walters</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-27:/pyohio-2024/what-django-deployment-is-really-about.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2024</category></item></channel></rss>