<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Day 3 Welcome</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/day-3-welcome.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:scipy-2019/day-3-welcome.html</guid></item><item><title>Day 2 Welcome</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/day-2-welcome.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/day-2-welcome.html</guid></item><item><title>Intermediate Methods for Geospatial Data Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/intermediate-methods-for-geospatial-data-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will provide attendees with tricks, tips, and techniques that are often necessary to work with geographic data in Python. These methods will range from the basics of reading &amp;amp; writing spatial data to the mechanics of combining and summarizing disparate geographic data types and representations. Overall, participants will gain a better understanding of practical methods to bring many different geographic datasets together for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/intermediate-methods-for-geospatial-data-analysis.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/welcome.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:scipy-2019/welcome.html</guid></item><item><title>Spatio-temporal Analysis of Socioeconomic Neighborhoods</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/spatio-temporal-analysis-of-socioeconomic-neighborhoods.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The neighborhood effects literature represents a wide span of the social
sciences broadly concerned with the influence of spatial context on
social processes. From the study of segregation dynamics, the
relationships between the built environment and health outcomes, to the
impact of concentrated poverty on social efficacy, neighborhoods are a
central construct in empirical work. From a dynamic lens, neighborhoods
experience changes not only in their socioeconomic composition, but also
in spatial extent; this latter source of change, however, has been
largely neglected in the extant literature. In this paper, we discuss
the development of novel, spatially explicit approaches to the study of
longitudinal neighborhood dynamics using the scientific Python
ecosystem.Presenter(s): Speaker: Serge Rey, University of California,
Riverside Speaker: Elijah Knaap, University of California Speaker: Su
Han, University of California Speaker: Levi Wolf, University of Bristol&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-12:scipy-2018/spatio-temporal-analysis-of-socioeconomic-neighborhoods.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Geospatial Data Analysis with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/introduction-to-geospatial-data-analysis-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is an introduction to geospatial data analysis in Python,
with a focus on tabular vector data. It is the first part in a series of
two tutorials; this part focuses on introducing the participants to the
different libraries to work with geospatial data and will cover munging
geo-data and exploring relations over space. This includes importing
data in different formats (e.g. shapefile, GeoJSON), visualizing,
combining and tidying them up for analysis, and will use libraries such
as &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;geopandas&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;shapely&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;PySAL&lt;/tt&gt;, or &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rasterio&lt;/tt&gt;.
The second part will built upon this and focus on more more advanced
geographic data science and statistical methods to gain insight from the
data. No previous experience with those geospatial python libraries is
needed, but basic familiarity with geospatial data and concepts
(shapefiles, vector vs raster data) and pandas will be
helpful.Presenter(s): Speaker: Serge Rey, University of California,
Riverside Speaker: Dani Arribas- Bel, University of Liverpool Speaker:
Joris Van den Bossche, Université Paris- Saclay Center for Data Science
Speaker: Levi Wolf, University of Bristol&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-10:scipy-2018/introduction-to-geospatial-data-analysis-with-python.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Geospatial Data and Analysis Stack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/geospatial-data-and-analysis-stack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a growing number of Python packages (fiona, geopandas, pysal,
shapely, etc.) addressing various types of spatial data, as well as the
geoprocessing of that data and its statistical analysis. This session
explore ways to best collaborate between and strengthen these efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/geospatial-data-and-analysis-stack.html</guid></item></channel></rss>