<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tim Hoffmann</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Accelerating your Python code - a systematic overview</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/accelerating-your-python-code-a-systematic-overview.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is slow. We feel the performance limitations when doing computationally intensive work. There are many libraries and methods to accelerate your computations, but which way to go? This talk serves as a navigation guide through the world of speeding up Python. At the end, you should have a high-level understanding of performance aspects and know which way to go when you want to speed up your code next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/accelerating-your-python-code-a-systematic-overview.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Introduction to matplotlib for visualization in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-matplotlib-for-visualization-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial explains the fundamental ideas and concepts of matplotlib. It's suited for complete beginners to get started as well as existing users who want to improve their plotting abilities and learn about best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/introduction-to-matplotlib-for-visualization-in-python.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Enabling the chip technologies of tomorrow – how Python helps us</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/enabling-the-chip-technologies-of-tomorrow-how-python-helps-us.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carl Zeiss SMT GmbH is the leading manufacturer of lithography optics.
Our optics allow chipmakers to produce smaller, faster and more energy
efficient computer chips. As we move to smaller and smaller structures,
the necessary optics grow more and more complex. Customized simulations
and data analytics by highly qualified technical domain experts are
essential. These people are not experienced software developers.
However, with Python and the right support, we can give them powerful
tools to accomplish their task efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pioneering Python in a larger enterprise can be challenging. At present,
we use Python in selected areas of our product development and
production processes. We'd like to share our challenges and solutions
with using Python in a heterogeneous company environment. In particular,
how can we make Python accessible to non-programmers? How do we ensure
consistent development? How do we embed in the non-Python ecosystem of
the company?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:/pycon-de-2018/enabling-the-chip-technologies-of-tomorrow-how-python-helps-us.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2018</category><category>Data Science</category></item><item><title>Break your API gently - or not at all</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2019/break-your-api-gently-or-not-at-all.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tim Hoffmann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyConDE
As hard as we try to write good code, there will always be cases in which we wish we had designed a different function signature, chosen another attribute name, ... But you can't change it anymore because it's public API - or can you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/QXB8DR"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/QXB8DR&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-10:/pycon-de-2019/break-your-api-gently-or-not-at-all.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2019</category></item><item><title>How Python enables future computer chips</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/how-python-enables-future-computer-chips.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the semiconductor division of Carl Zeiss it's our mission to continuously make computer chips faster and more energy efficient. To do so, we go to the very limits of what is possible, both physically and technologically. This is only possible through massive research and development efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we tell the story how Python became a central tool for our R&amp;amp;D activities. This includes technical aspects as well as organization and culture. How do you make sure that hundreds of people work in consistent environments? – How do you get all people on board to work together with Python? – You have lots of domain experts without much software background. How do you prevent them from creating a mess when projects get larger?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Hoffmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/how-python-enables-future-computer-chips.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category></item></channel></rss>