<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Antonis Christofides</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning talks - Tuesday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-tuesday.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Gaevsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-tuesday.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2017</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks 07/30</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/lightning-talks-0730.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talk 3
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonis Christofides</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/lightning-talks-0730.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Why you always had trouble understanding metaclasses</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/why-you-always-had-trouble-understanding-metaclasses.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why you always had trouble understanding metaclasses
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Antonis Christofides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Smart people sometimes like to show off their smarts
by demonstrating their mental juggling abilities. After all,
if you can reliably remember that r is the lower-cased
version of the url with the host and scheme removed,
then you must clearly be very smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difference between a smart programmer and a
professional programmer is that the professional
understands that clarity is king.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Robert C. Martin, &amp;quot;Clean Code&amp;quot;, p.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert C. Martin says it’s hard to mentally translate one name (e.g. “r”) to another, and you can avoid it by using a better name (e.g. “urlPath”). But the problem is not just lost brainpower; it can also be misunderstanding. I’ve seen experienced Python programmers trying to teach Python “metaclasses” by explaining that a metaclass is the class of a class—which it isn’t. Metaclasses have a reputation of being difficult, but they actually become easy once you use the right term for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad terminology can be far more damaging than just confusing people. In April 2021, the European Commission published a proposal for an Artificial Intelligence Act, which they proudly advertise as the “first ever legal framework on AI”. It has provisions such as prohibiting &amp;quot;an AI system that deploys subliminal techniques beyond a person’s consciousness in order to materially distort a person’s behaviour in a manner that causes or is likely to cause that person or another person physical or psychological harm.” What do they mean with &amp;quot;AI system&amp;quot;? Well, more or less... statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this would happen if we didn't use misleading terms such as &amp;quot;artificial intelligence&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do get to metaclasses, the main part of this talk is a tour of bad names. The talk is suitable for all audiences, beginners and advanced alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonis Christofides</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/why-you-always-had-trouble-understanding-metaclasses.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item><item><title>How much time does it take to write tests? A case study</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/how-much-time-does-it-take-to-write-tests-a-case-study.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - How much time does it take to write tests? A case study - presented by Antonis Christofides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 2 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing automated tests takes time. As developers, we are constantly pressed by management to deliver early, which means we are tempted to skip writing some of the tests. Of course, in the long term, the time needed to write tests is paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how much of our time do we spend in order to write tests? Is it half? Is it three-quarters? This can be difficult to measure, particularly if we are using test-driven development, because in that case writing tests is integrated in the process of writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I like test-driven development, I can only practice it when I have a good idea of what code I want to write. But sometimes my idea of how to approach the problem at hand is quite vague and I experiment a lot. In these cases, I write the code first and the tests after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one such case I first finished the functionality I was developing and proclaimed it &amp;quot;&amp;quot;beta&amp;quot;&amp;quot;. I then went on to write the unit tests for it. As a result, I have a clear idea how much time I spent writing documentation and main code, and how much I spent writing tests. In this talk I examine the implications of all this.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonis Christofides</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/how-much-time-does-it-take-to-write-tests-a-case-study.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item></channel></rss>