<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_robert-bradshaw.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Big Data Processing with Apache Beam Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/big-data-processing-with-apache-beam-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Bradshaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:scipy-2017/big-data-processing-with-apache-beam-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two trends for data analysis are the ever increasing size of data sets and the drive for lower-latency results. In this talk, we present Apache Beam--a parallel programming model that allows one to implement batch and streaming data processing jobs that can run on a variety of scalable execution engines like Spark and Dataflow--and its new Python SDK. We discuss some of the interesting challenges in providing a Pythonic API and execution environment for distributed processing, and show how Beam allows the user to write a Python pipeline once that can run in both batch and streaming mode. We walk through a few examples of data processing pipelines in Beam for use cases such as real time data analytics and feature engineering with Tensorflow for machine learning pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>R0 DAY2-K1 Static typing in Python? - Robert Bradshaw (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-k1-static-typing-in-python-robert-bradshaw.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Bradshaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r0-day2-k1-static-typing-in-python-robert-bradshaw.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Robert Bradshaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Bradshaw is a software engineer at Google, working on tools for doing petabyte-scale data processing. He is also active in the open source community, leading the Cython project since it's inception and as a long-time contributor to the open source mathematics software Sage. He received a B.S. in Mathematics and Linguistics from Brigham Young University and a Ph.D. in Mathematics from University of Washington with William Stein studying questions related to the Birch and Swinnerton-Dyer conjecture. Robert currently resides in Seattle, Washington with his wife Camille and their two sets of young twins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/keynote-speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>