<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jessica Greene</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyLadies - Jessica Greene and PyLadies Berlin</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/pyladies-jessica-greene-and-pyladies-berlin.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Greene</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:/pycon-de-2018/pyladies-jessica-greene-and-pyladies-berlin.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2018</category><category>lightning talk</category></item><item><title>Inclusive community leadership</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/inclusive-community-leadership.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inclusive community leadership - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does an inclusive community look like and how can we be inclusive
leaders within it? Community leadership can take many forms, from
organizing events, sharing knowledge, to advocating for other members
and connecting them to opportunities. Communities look to their leaders
to set the tone of the space so it is, therefore, their responsibility
to ensure a continued space that is safe for all its members to thrive.
Leadership should also be sustainable so recognizing and supporting the
growth of new leaders is important. My journey as a community leader
began after attending a PyLadies Berlin meetup in 2018. As a career
changer, my motivation was to immerse myself in a space where I could
learn and meet others in a position similar to my own. Inspired by other
community leaders and conversations with other members, it soon became
my goal to not only nourish my own growth but also that of those around
me however I could. Witnessing the change which we create within the
community has shown me that responsibility also lies with the wider tech
community to support its leaders, who not only add immense value to
their respective communities but reach far beyond them to make the
industry a better place for all. The labor we pour into the community is
essential to fostering inclusive work environments as gender parity (and
other forms of representation) is still severely lacking especially at a
decision-making level at most tech companies. It is this bridge between
community and companies that I have been reflecting on and hope to now
influence. Through the lens of my experience in the PyLadies community
and beyond, sharing both my insights and those gained through
interactions with other members, I will reflect on what it means to be
an inclusive leader and how a community can stay true to these
principles while growing and evolving. This talk aims to inspire folks
to take up leadership roles in their communities while also celebrating
those already putting in the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jessica Greene&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Greene</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/inclusive-community-leadership.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category></item><item><title>Sustainable Code Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/sustainable-code-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sustainable Code Panel - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Jessica Greene, Chris Adams, Uljan Sharka&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Greene</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/sustainable-code-panel.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category></item><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/diversity-inclusion-panel.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Debora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/diversity-inclusion-panel.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Monitoring carbon emissions: making the impact of your python code visible</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/monitoring-carbon-emissions-making-the-impact-of-your-python-code-visible.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If the Internet was a country, it would be the 4th largest polluter”
[1] The power to make impactful change through technology has never been
greater. Doing so starts with understanding the problem space. Our
workshop will guide you through the process of quantifying the emissions
of your Python code and integrating this awareness into your monitoring
strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the basics of observability, an essential part of
operating a deployed service, you’ll learn why it’s important to monitor
your Python code, what makes a good metric, and the common pitfalls to
avoid. We’ll then dive into the practical aspects of exposing and
creating custom metrics, scraping and storing them in Prometheus, a time
series database, and then visualising them in dashboards using Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will also include an overview of climate-conscious tech,
discussing the tech industry’s contribution to the climate crisis and
introducing the principles of green coding. We’ll explore techniques and
libraries for extracting metrics for carbon awareness, because &amp;quot;If you
can't measure it, you can't improve it.&amp;quot; (Peter Drucker) and guide
attendees through a practical session on instrumenting your Python code
for carbon emissions and visualizing this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By attending this workshop, you’ll gain valuable insights and hands-on
experience in making your code more carbon-conscious. You’ll learn about
carbon-aware workloads, strategies for making your services more energy,
and carbon efficient, the importance of cloud provider regions and
transparency, and how to advocate for change. These skills and knowledge
can be integrated into your day-to-day work, making a real difference in
our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us in this journey towards a more sustainable future in tech and a
better planet for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*source: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sustainablewebmanifesto.com/#citation"&gt;https://www.sustainablewebmanifesto.com/#citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Greene</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/monitoring-carbon-emissions-making-the-impact-of-your-python-code-visible.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>