<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Richard Yen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_richard-yen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Explaining EXPLAIN: A dive into PostgreSQL's EXPLAIN plans</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/explaining-explain-a-dive-into-postgresqls-explain-plans.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Yen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-18:/djangocon-us-2022/explaining-explain-a-dive-into-postgresqls-explain-plans.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of people: people who want to use Postgres, and people who want to use Postgres well.  The latter will not be content with a poorly-performing query when they know that better performance can be achieved with some tuning, an index, and/or a query rewrite …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of people: people who want to use Postgres, and people who want to use Postgres well.  The latter will not be content with a poorly-performing query when they know that better performance can be achieved with some tuning, an index, and/or a query rewrite.  For developers and DBAs, this talk discusses what EXPLAIN does, how to interpret its output, what inferences can be extracted from its output, and what can be done to improve query performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Ride Elephants Safely: Working with PostgreSQL when your DBA is not around</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/how-to-ride-elephants-safely-working-with-postgresql-when-your-dba-is-not-around.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Yen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/djangocon-us-2023/how-to-ride-elephants-safely-working-with-postgresql-when-your-dba-is-not-around.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every so often, one may be called upon to perform the tasks of a database administrator, especially in cases where application performance seems to be affected by the database.  This talk will give non-DBAs an insight into how the world's most powerful open-source database works, and the kind of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every so often, one may be called upon to perform the tasks of a database administrator, especially in cases where application performance seems to be affected by the database.  This talk will give non-DBAs an insight into how the world's most powerful open-source database works, and the kind of tools and features that are readily available for people who unexpectedly find themselves in the DBA pilot's seat.  Topics covered will include query tuning, monitoring, indexing, and a basic run-down of some configurables to help you know what options are at your disposal&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2023"></category></entry></feed>