<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Web programming from the beginning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/web-programming-from-the-beginning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s the web all about anyway? How can you make your computer talk to
other computers with Python?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern web frameworks such as Django and Flask are immensely powerful.
However, these useful tools obscure the foundations of network
programming upon which they are based, which can be very helpful to
understand. So instead of building useful applications with these
libraries, let's experiment with sockets!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this tutorial, a Python-flavored history of the web will be presented
and attendees will write or modify a TCP chat client, a static site web
server, an HTTP client, a CGI script, and a WSGI-compliant server and
web application. We will learn what all those things are and how they
fit together, bringing the architecture of modern web apps into better
focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The material will be accessible to participants with no web development
experience, however, they must be able to write and run Python scripts
at the command-line. This tutorial might appeal to someone also
attending an introductory web development tutorial, but it covers
separate, complementary material. Web development experience is not
required but a little exposure would be helpful; for instance,
installing flask and running the minimal application on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flask.pocoo.org/docs/0.11/quickstart/"&gt;quickstart
page&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, prior
exposure to HTML would be useful but is not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Ballinger</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-17:pycon-us-2017/web-programming-from-the-beginning.html</guid></item></channel></rss>