<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ing-wei-tang.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python and SQLs: How I Create Universal SQL CLI Client using PEP 249 standards</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/python-and-sqls-how-i-create-universal-sql-cli-client-using-pep-249-standards.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ing Wei Tang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-22:pycon-taiwan-2019/python-and-sqls-how-i-create-universal-sql-cli-client-using-pep-249-standards.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3, R2 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SQL client is ubiquitous and impossible for developers not to have one in their toolbag. However potentially there is a unforeseen situation that the developers are forbid to use SQL client to access the cloud/on-premise SQL DB. This proposal primarily addresses the issue of such scenario and provides a solution based on the hacker's mindset. In this proposal, the author will show how he tackles this pain point in his workplace, by creating a universal SQL client CLI that allows him to connect to the SQL DB in his DB cluster, hence extends this project to other SQL DB using the API standardization in PEP 249. Apart from integrating all the SQL connectors, the author also implemented standardize hotkey for all the SQL DB, by studying the internal core of the SQL standards, and retrieving SQL metadata using pure SQL queries through the hotkeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ing Wei Tang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ing Wei is the chair for PyCon MY 2019, the co-chair of PyCon MY 2018, and vice president of MyPOP. He has spoken in various PyCons, particularly in PyCon APAC 2018, as well as involving in PyCon communities actively in Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses python a lot in his daily work, especially coding the automation process and flow. During his past time, he likes to experience and perform hacking different things on operating system level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from programming language, he can also speak 5 different types of languages concurrently in one sentence. Please ask for demo if time permits.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Honey, There Is a Python in My Android Phone!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2019/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ing Wei Tang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-20:pycon-taiwan-2019/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R2 10:50–11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple scripting, such as Python, Bash, PHP, Perl are all embedded in modern OS. Since Android is also a linux-based OS, it is also possible to write a script. Unfortunately before SL4A arrives, it is impossible to script on Android phone. SL4A provides rich APIs that allow user to access Android intents such as GPS location, Accelerometer and etc. through scripting. Hence with those APIs, the user can build simple scripts to interact with those APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks demonstrates how android intents can be accessed using python client, hence understanding the interaction between Android and Python API inside SL4A via RPC by dissecting the source code of both Android and Python API inside SL4A. The speaker will then demonstrate how different android intents such as GPS coordinate and gyroscope through a presentation of websocket coded in Python and webapp demo using babylon.js, together with a flask application that allows user to send SMS messages through Rest APIs, using android API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Ing Wei Tang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ing Wei is the chair for PyCon MY 2019, the co-chair of PyCon MY 2018, and vice president of MyPOP. He has spoken in various PyCons, particularly in PyCon APAC 2018, as well as involving in PyCon communities actively in Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses python a lot in his daily work, especially coding the automation process and flow. During his past time, he likes to experience and perform hacking different things on operating system level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from programming language, he can also speak 5 different types of languages concurrently in one sentence. Please ask for demo if time permits.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Honey, there is a Python in my Android Phone!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ing Wei, Tang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/honey-there-is-a-python-in-my-android-phone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple scripting, such as Python, Bash, PHP, Perl are all embedded in
modern operating system. Since Android is also a linux-based operating
system, with some techniques, it is also possible for us to write a
script. Unfortunately before SL4A arrives (Scripting Language 4
Android), it is not possible for us to script on Android phone. SL4A
provides rich APIs that allow user to access Android intents such as GPS
location, Accelerometer, Camera, Battery status, and etc. through
scripting. Hence with the rich APIs, the user can build a very simple
script to interact with those APIs, without building a complex app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks shows how we can interact with android intents and APIs via
RPC using python client embedded inside the android app, through SL4A
app. First the speaker introduces various python related apps available
for android OS. Next the speaker will show the relationship and
interaction between Android API and Python API inside SL4A, and how RPC
is used as communication between two APIs, hence demonstrate how a new
different service/intent can be built based on the provided Android API,
by doing some hacking on Python API inside SL4A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker will begin his talk with introduction on the basic of RPC,
and illustrate the relationship between Android APIs and Python APIs in
SL4A, by comparing both Android and Python code. The speaker will then
demonstrate how different android intents can be accessed on the android
devices, through various demo, such as reading GPS coordinate and x, y,
z position from the accelerometer, together with making a phone call
through python client on android phone. In the end, the speaker will
demonstrate how a flask application that allows user to send SMS
messages through Rest APIs, can be built on top on the android.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>