<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Søren Wengel Mogensen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_soren-wengel-mogensen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Causal screening in dynamical systems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/causal-screening-in-dynamical-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Søren Wengel Mogensen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/causal-screening-in-dynamical-systems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Causal screening in dynamical systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Søren Wengel Mogensen (University of Copenhagen)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many classical algorithms output graphical representations of causal structures by testing conditional independence among a set of random variables. In dynamical systems, local independence can be used analogously as a testable implication of the underlying data-generating process. We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Causal screening in dynamical systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Søren Wengel Mogensen (University of Copenhagen)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many classical algorithms output graphical representations of causal structures by testing conditional independence among a set of random variables. In dynamical systems, local independence can be used analogously as a testable implication of the underlying data-generating process. We suggest some inexpensive methods for causal screening which provide output with a sound causal interpretation under the assumption of ancestral faithfulness. The popular model class of linear Hawkes processes is used to provide an example of a dynamical causal model. We argue that for sparse causal graphs the output will often be close to complete. We give examples of this framework and apply it to a challenging biological system.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>