<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_moises-guimaraes-de-medeiros.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>wolfcrypt: wrapping secrets with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/wolfcrypt-wrapping-secrets-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Moisés Guimarães de Medeiros</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:pycon-cz-2017/wolfcrypt-wrapping-secrets-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ancient art of keeping secrets safe is nowadays one of the
pillars of the internet. e-commerce, online banking, video
conferences and a lot of other things are protected by encryption to
become viable. Becoming fluent in basic cryptographic operations is a
precious tool for any software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wolfcrypt is a Python library that encapsulates wolfSSL’s wolfCrypt
API. wolfCrypt is a lightweight, portable, C-language-based crypto
library targeted at IoT, embedded, and RTOS environments primarily
because of its size, speed, and feature set. It works seamlessly in
desktop, enterprise, and cloud environments as well. It is the crypto
engine behind wolfSSl’s embedded ssl library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will talk about classic and modern cryptography concepts a.k.a.
cryptography 101 and use the wolfcrypt python module to put those
concepts in practice to keep information safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moisés Guimarães is a Brazilian pythonista who lives in João Pessoa,
the capital of the state of Paraíba in Brazil, also the eastmost
place of the Americas. Author of both wolfcrypt and wolfssl modules,
CFFI wrappers for the wolfSSL crypto and SSL/TLS libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He works both as a software engineer at wolfSSL and as a professor at
the Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology of
Paraíba, graduated in Web Development with a specialization degree in
Information Security.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>