<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The anatomy of a #deepfake</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/the-anatomy-of-a-deepfake.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A first-hand exploration of the world of #deepfake and post-truth technologies, looking at the latest developments in art and ML-modelling. Including details of a #deepfake project for a forthcoming BBC programme and revealing some tips and tricks (and pitfalls) involved in bending reality with some Tensorflow and a GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Drass</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-14:pydata-london-2019/the-anatomy-of-a-deepfake.html</guid><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Keynote: What's it Like to be a Bot?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/keynote-whats-it-like-to-be-a-bot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do we mean by intelligence? How do the limitations of language
leave us floundering with regards to discussing our relationship with
‘algorithms’ and emerging machine intelligence? I argue that the
limitations in the discourse surrounding AI are remarkably similar to
the problems found in psychology and philosophy relating to other
minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking the title from the seminal philosphy of mind paper by Thomas
Nagel (What is it like to be a Bat (1974)) this talk looks at the
problems surrounding Artificial Intelligence, illustrated with examples
from my own artistic practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we mean by intelligence? How do the limitations of language
leave us floundering with regards to discussing our relationship with
‘algorithms’ and emerging machine intelligence? I argue that the
limitations in the discourse surrounding AI are remarkably similar to
the problems found in psychology and philosophy relating to other minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has been said about the forthcoming ‘singularity’, but little
attention is being paid to the signals and signs already emerging on
this path. My artworks play in this space, highlighting the potentials
and limitations inherent in existing technologies and questioning our
relationship with the world of bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already live in an algorithmically mediated world, though in many
ways we remain blind to the ramifications. The world of the future will
be teeming with intelligent systems, though they may not conform to our
narrow anthropomorphic perspective on what intelligence is. For us to
prepare for the future, perhaps we need to change the way we think about
thinking, just as the machines are changing theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Drass</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-20:pydata-london-2015/keynote-whats-it-like-to-be-a-bot.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>You give me data, I give you art.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2014/you-give-me-data-i-give-you-art.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data and algorithms are artistic materials just as much as paint and
canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A talk covering my recent work with The Tate's CC dataset, David
Cameron's deleted speeches and the role of the artist in the world of
Big Data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Drass</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-02-22:pydata-london-2014/you-give-me-data-i-give-you-art.html</guid></item></channel></rss>