<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sebastian Buczyński</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Distributed locks with Python and Redis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/distributed-locks-with-python-and-redis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Buczyński - Distributed locks with Python and Redis
[EuroPython 2015]
[22 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional methods of coping with concurrent programming problems are
well-known and described in literature. Many programming languages,
including Python, contain in their standard libraries tools and
primitives such as semaphores and can spawn threads or subprocesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the face of increasing interest in service oriented
architecture and building distributed systems, that span across many
independent server nodes, emerges a need to adapt traditional
solutions, so they can be applied in the new environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will share my experiences gathered during building a
modern contact center - highly concurrent system, which requires
certain resources to be accessed exclusively by several self-contained
components.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:/europython-2015/distributed-locks-with-python-and-redis.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2015</category></item><item><title>Why you don't need design patterns in Python?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/why-you-dont-need-design-patterns-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exactly 23 years have passed since release of one of the biggest IT
classics - &amp;quot;Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented
Software&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contents of the book had considerable influence on dominant
programming languages of those days. However, design patterns were
not glorified by everyone. Voices of rational critic appeared,
pointing out that design patterns are just ways to compensate for
missing languages features by tons of clumsy code. If one implements
design patterns in Python by the book, they will get code that looks
awkward, at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is to present Python's features that either simplifies or
eliminates need for implementing design patterns. Even if you don't
know what design patterns are - don't worry. You still may see some
new interesting Python's features and their usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-11:/europython-2017/why-you-dont-need-design-patterns-in-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2017</category></item><item><title>Refactoring legacy Django app using OOP</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/refactoring-legacy-django-app-using-oop.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refactoring legacy Django app using OOP
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Sebastian Buczyński&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year we can hear rumours about the demise of Object-Oriented Programming. As usual, they are greatly exaggerated. In 2021 OOP still has a lot to offer. The problem is a shortage of good quality materials that would show where it shines and how a Pythonista can leverage it without writing code that looks like Java from the 00s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll show you how you can refactor legacy code in a Django app and tame complex logic living there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value for attendees: see refactoring possible directions and get to know 3 OOP stereotypes
Level of attendees: intermediate &amp;amp; advanced
Expected knowledge: Experience with building web apps, at least superficial knowledge about Django&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is an introduction to 3 out of 8 OOP Stereotypes, i.e. Controller, Interfacer and Information Holder. They'll be introduced using a real-life legacy project refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of this talk, I'll be using code from this repo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Enforcer/django-refactor"&gt;https://github.com/Enforcer/django-refactor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/refactoring-legacy-django-app-using-oop.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item><item><title>BDD - how to make it work?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/bdd-how-to-make-it-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/bdd-how-to-make-it-work"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/bdd-how-to-make-it-work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behaviour-driven development promises evergreen documentation or human-readable executable specification - sounds great. However, adopting it takes much more than simply installing behave or pytest-bdd and writing Gherkin. This talk will show what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/bdd-how-to-make-it-work.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Clean Architecture - Sebastian Buczynski</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2018/clean-architecture-sebastian-buczynski.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczynski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-17:/pycaribbean-2018/clean-architecture-sebastian-buczynski.html</guid><category>PyCaribbean 2018</category></item><item><title>Having fun with pydantic and pattern matching</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/having-fun-with-pydantic-and-pattern-matching.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pattern matching has been with us since Python3.10. Since the
introduction of the match-case statement, we've got a powerful and
elegant tool to control the flow of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is to showcase a real-world scenario of handling different
messages coming from a broker, using match-case and Pydantic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/having-fun-with-pydantic-and-pattern-matching.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Clean architecture in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/clean-architecture-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Believe me or not, but your database is not your application. Neither are ORM models or even your framework. They are not reasons for building yet another project. The real motivation is to satisfy some business needs. Unfortunately, it might get out of sight due to years spent on writing Django- or Rails-like web applications. Their ORMs usually dominates in applications, coupling business logic to the framework and making it impossible to (unit) test it without database access. The fact is you can develop and test features without even thinking about how business objects map into database tables. Software engineering brought several solutions over last few years, and I want to share with you one of them, called Clean Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean Architecture is an approach that puts your customer's concerns in the centre of your software. All other issues, such as persistence are treated as implementation details. This is achieved thanks to a careful layering of the project. There are few interesting outcomes. Firstly, business rules layer knows nothing about a framework or a database. Therefore you can develop and test all business logic without saving results anywhere. Secondly, upgrading or even swapping a framework is less painful. The same is true for every third-party service as they are abstracted away. Thirdly, Clean Architecture makes introducing new team members to the project much simpler since everything has its place. Last, but certainly not least - as time passes and project grows Clean Architecture lets you maintain order remain flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-05:/pygotham-2018/clean-architecture-in-python.html</guid><category>PyGotham 2018</category></item><item><title>How to Improve Tests Thanks to 1 Line of Code?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2021/how-to-improve-tests-thanks-to-1-line-of-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What takes only one line of code and can dramatically improve your
tests? The name! If you write in a more intentional way, you can get a
test that is better designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5 minutes I'll show you a few simple rules of naming tests that you
can start using right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-31:/pyohio-2021/how-to-improve-tests-thanks-to-1-line-of-code.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2021</category></item><item><title>Serverless</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/stx-next-tech-power-summit-2018/serverless.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presentation on Serverless by Sebastian Buczyński, Python Developer &amp;#64; STX Next&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Buczyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-14:/stx-next-tech-power-summit-2018/serverless.html</guid><category>STX Next Tech Power Summit 2018</category></item></channel></rss>