<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Vikram Waradpande</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>You've got trust issues, we've got solutions: Differential Privacy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/youve-got-trust-issues-weve-got-solutions-differential-privacy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we are in an era of big data where large groups of information are
assimilated and analyzed, for insights into human behavior, data privacy
has become a hot topic. Since there is a lot of private information
which once leaked can be misused, all data cannot be released for
research. So, how should privacy be protected in the environment where
data is stored and shared at such an escalating pace? One might think
that simply making personally identifiable fields in the dataset
anonymous might be useful, but this can lead to the entire dataset
becoming useless and not fit for analysis. And research has proven that
by statistically studying both the datasets, private information can
easily be re-extracted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session will start with a brief on the current standards of privacy,
and the possible risks of handling customer data. This will lay the
foundation for introducing Differential Privacy, a cutting-edge
technique of cybersecurity that claims to preserve an individual’s
privacy, by manipulating data in such a way as to not render it useless
for data analysis. Attendees will gain an insight into the concept of
Differential Privacy, how it is employed to minimize the risks
associated with private data, its practical applications in various
domains, and how Python eases the task of employing it in our models
with PyDP. As the talk progresses, a walkthrough of a real-life
practical example, along with a nifty visualization will acquaint the
audience with PyDP, and how differential private results come out to be
in approximation to what unfiltered data would have provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vikram Waradpande</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/youve-got-trust-issues-weve-got-solutions-differential-privacy.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>