<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rants and Ruminations From A Job Applicant After One Hundred! CS Job Interviews in Silicon Valley</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/rants-and-ruminations-from-a-job-applicant-after-one-hundred-cs-job-interviews-in-silicon-valley.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is it like to interview at 1 technology company? Stressful and tiring. What is it like to interview at 100 technology companies total in 4 months? I have done that. In August 2016, I quit a full-time software job to do job searching full-time. I did a job search where I talked to ~100 technology companies in the Bay Area to find the best fit. The hiring process reflects the company culture and its values. Listen to my rants and ruminations from going through various interviewing processes from tiny seed-stage startups to large technology companies in Silicon Valley. Hiring is still broken. Only a few companies do this well. Learn how to reform your own hiring process to be more considerate and thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:djangocon-europe-2017/rants-and-ruminations-from-a-job-applicant-after-one-hundred-cs-job-interviews-in-silicon-valley.html</guid></item><item><title>Rants and Ruminations From A Job Applicant After 💯 CS Job Interviews in Silicon Valley</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/rants-and-ruminations-from-a-job-applicant-after-cs-job-interviews-in-silicon-valley.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is it like to interview at 1 technology company? Stressful and
tiring. What is it like to interview at 100 technology companies? I have
done that. In late August 2016, I quit an uninspiring full-time software
job and talked to 100 employers in the San Francisco Bay Area to find
the best fit. The hiring process reflects the company culture and its
values. Listen to my rants and ruminations of interviewing at tiny
seed-stage startups to large technology companies in Silicon Valley.
Learn how to reform your own hiring process to be more considerate and
thoughtful. Learn how to prepare for interviews efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-19:pycon-us-2017/rants-and-ruminations-from-a-job-applicant-after-cs-job-interviews-in-silicon-valley.html</guid></item><item><title>How to Upgrade to the Newest and Shiniest Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/how-to-upgrade-to-the-newest-and-shiniest-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/24"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/how-to-upgrade-to-the-newest-and-shiniest-django-by-susan-tan/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/how-to-upgrade-to-the-newest-and-shiniest-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Let's read code: the requests library</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/susan-tan-lets-read-code-the-requests-library-pycon-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Susan Tan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re a new engineer at a workplace who has to learn a new unfamiliar codebase. After you acquire a copy of the repo, what is your next step? How do you dissect a new unfamiliar codebase to understand its inner workings? Come see a guided walkthrough of reading the widely used python-requests project, which gets over 18,000 downloads per day and powers many of the world’s REST-based APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-31:pycon-us-2016/susan-tan-lets-read-code-the-requests-library-pycon-2016.html</guid></item><item><title>Python in the Browser: Intro to Brython</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/python-in-the-browser-intro-to-brython.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wished that you can write Python in the browser? Brython
is an experimental Javascript library that enables you to leverage the
elegance of Python on the client side. Novice programmers who are
familiar with Javascript will learn about Brython, how Brython measures
up against Javascript, and why getting client-side Python adopted as a
mainstream tool is really difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-13:pycon-us-2014/python-in-the-browser-intro-to-brython.html</guid></item></channel></rss>