<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_esther-nam.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>One weird trick to becoming a better software developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/one-weird-trick-to-becoming-a-better-software-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Esther Nam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/one-weird-trick-to-becoming-a-better-software-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of us who have worked in software development for longer than a few years probably feel we have an intuitive sense of what a great developer is. Some traits come more easily to mind than others when it comes to identifying a great developer. In this talk we will take a slightly different approach to evaluating software development best practices, and identify one underrated skill common to great software developers: empathy. I hope to demonstrate that cognitive and emotional empathy skills are critical to good software development. We will explore ways to cultivate this trait in order to become better developers, both for our own sakes and for the sake of the teams in which we work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="empathy"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Except When You're Excepting</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/how-to-except-when-youre-excepting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Esther Nam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-15:pycon-us-2013/how-to-except-when-youre-excepting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is an introduction to the practice of exception handling,
aimed at those without a heavy CS background or years of experience, and
who are thus unfamiliar with the technique. Novices to Python will learn
Python-specific techniques that make use of built-in exceptions and the
context manager, as well as unusual but Pythonic ways of managing the
flow control of their program.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Character encoding and Unicode in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/character-encoding-and-unicode-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Esther Nam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-12:pycon-us-2014/character-encoding-and-unicode-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every developer will inevitably feel the pain of character encoding
issues. We will cover the fundamentals every Python developer should
know on character encoding and Unicode. We will teach you how to
identify the types of problems that occur when dealing with character
encoding and outline a set of best practices and useful libraries which
can be used to avoid and fix character encoding issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>