<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Indranil Ghosh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_indranil-ghosh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning Talks 07/29</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/lightning-talks-0729.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cristián Maureira-Fredes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/lightning-talks-0729.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talk 2
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29- Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Introducing Lambda Calculus with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/introducing-lambda-calculus-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/introducing-lambda-calculus-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indranil Ghosh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be focusing on untyped lambda calculus and start by the simple definition of a function, that can be implemented with Python lambda. We will then discuss the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;abstraction&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;application&lt;/strong&gt; in lambda calculus and then move …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indranil Ghosh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be focusing on untyped lambda calculus and start by the simple definition of a function, that can be implemented with Python lambda. We will then discuss the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;abstraction&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;application&lt;/strong&gt; in lambda calculus and then move on to understand what a &lt;strong&gt;substitution&lt;/strong&gt; is and how can these be implemented in Python. We will finally study some combinators which are the basic building blocks of combinatory logic, before ending with encoding datatypes in lambda calculus and implementing the same with Python lambda. Datatypes we will be discussing are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boolean values like TRUE and FALSE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical operators like AND, OR and NOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Church Numerals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Sep  5 14:40:00 2020 at Python 2&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2020"></category><category term="IndranilGhosh"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConAU"></category><category term="PyConline"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Football (soccer) data analysis: A pedagogic introduction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/football-soccer-data-analysis-a-pedagogic-introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/football-soccer-data-analysis-a-pedagogic-introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Indranil Ghosh) Nowadays data is the key to solving challenges in most fields, say astronomy, applied mathematics, health care, or even sports. Data is everywhere and it is super beneficial to leverage these data and build models for making sense out of them and telling stories. The field of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Indranil Ghosh) Nowadays data is the key to solving challenges in most fields, say astronomy, applied mathematics, health care, or even sports. Data is everywhere and it is super beneficial to leverage these data and build models for making sense out of them and telling stories. The field of sports, especially football (soccer), is enriched by data analysis that makes us understand the game better and predict outcomes. Many people want to delve deep into football (soccer) data analysis and get their hands dirty. This talk is to help them do so by pedagogically introducing them to the introductory analytical methodologies to overcome the initial barriers of the field and start working with data analyses and visualizations on football data to deduce interesting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/PJWQZQ/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/PJWQZQ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Sep 12 02:45:00 2021 at Backup Speakers&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="IndranilGhosh"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry><entry><title>An introduction to hands-on football data analysis in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2021/an-introduction-to-hands-on-football-data-analysis-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-02:/pycon-es-2021/an-introduction-to-hands-on-football-data-analysis-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Indranil Ghosh nos presenta "An introduction to hands-on football data analysis in Python".

Resumen:
Many people want to start with football data analysis and this talk (accompanied by jupyter notebooks maintaining a pedagogic flow of Python codes) introduces these concepts hands-on (accessing data, visualization, and analysis) to those interested …&lt;/pre&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Indranil Ghosh nos presenta "An introduction to hands-on football data analysis in Python".

Resumen:
Many people want to start with football data analysis and this talk (accompanied by jupyter notebooks maintaining a pedagogic flow of Python codes) introduces these concepts hands-on (accessing data, visualization, and analysis) to those interested.

 ---
La novena edición de la PyConES se celebra como un evento en línea y totalmente gratuito durante los días 2 y 3 de Octubre de 2021.
Web: https://2021.es.pycon.org
Agenda: https://2021.es.pycon.org/#schedule&lt;/pre&gt;</content><category term="PyCon ES 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Football (soccer) data analysis: A Pedagogic introduction – Indranil Ghosh (PyCon Taiwan 2021)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2021/football-soccer-data-analysis-a-pedagogic-introduction-indranil-ghosh-pycon-taiwan-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-03:/pycon-taiwan-2021/football-soccer-data-analysis-a-pedagogic-introduction-indranil-ghosh-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 10:35-11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays data is the key to solving challenges in most of the fields say astronomy, applied maths, health care, or even sports. Data is everywhere and it is super beneficial to leverage these data to build models for making sense out of these …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2, 10:35-11:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays data is the key to solving challenges in most of the fields say astronomy, applied maths, health care, or even sports. Data is everywhere and it is super beneficial to leverage these data to build models for making sense out of these data and tell stories. The field of sports science, especially football (soccer), is enriched by data analysis that makes us understand the game better and predict outcomes. Many people want to delve deep into football (soccer) data analysis and get their hands dirty. This talk is to help them do so by pedagogically introducing them to the introductory analytical methodologies to overcome the initial barriers of the field and start working with football data analyses and visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the following concepts on football data analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will start my talk addressing how to get open access football event data using the statsbomb API using Python,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I will talk about is drawing a football pitch using the mplsoccer Python module, so that we can start making most of our football data visualizations on this pitch,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will then talk about simple data visualizations like drawing shot maps, pass maps and their corresponding heat maps,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I will teach how to visualize a pass network on this pitch of a particular team during a particular game. We will further advance our knowledge by analyzing this pass network using the NetworkX python module that is usually used in complex network analysis in mathematics. We will learn how to calculate pass degree distributions of each player, find out which player was the most central in that pass network by calculating &amp;quot;centrality&amp;quot; of each player node, and so on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I will teach how to implement computational geometric concepts like Convex Hulls, Voronoi diagrams and Delaunay triangulations using the Python package scipy.spatial and mplsoccer on open access football tracking data so that we can analyze how many passes were available to a player at a particular instance of a game, or how a group of players broke down space on the pitch at a particular instance, etc., and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I will talk about how to analyze Expected Goals (xG) using open data from statsbomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will end my talk guiding the audience to the references I used for starting with football (soccer) data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One use-case for soccer data analysis is, for example, using network analysis to find out the central player from a particular team who has been performing constantly in last few matches. This player can be considered as one of the backbones for that team and are recommended to be deployed in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.
HackMD: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FBkElAGqft"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FBkElAGqft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Indranil Ghosh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a first-year Ph.D. student in applied mathematics from the School of Fundamental Sciences, Massey University. My research is on dynamical systems and robust chaos. I have a master's in Physics from Jadavpur University. I am mostly interested in dynamical systems, computational mathematics, optimization, quantum computing, etc. I am much fascinated with open source software development and write codes mostly in Python and R, and sometimes Fortran. I have developed the R package &amp;quot;QGameTheory&amp;quot;, which is an open-source R tool to work with the basics of quantum computing and game theory simulations. I love presenting my learnings on national/international platforms and have presented in conferences on Python, R, Open source software, etc. Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://indrag49.github.io/"&gt;https://indrag49.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Soccer Pass Network Analysis with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2021/introduction-to-soccer-pass-network-analysis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-31:/pyohio-2021/introduction-to-soccer-pass-network-analysis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk teaches four simple concepts to those who want to start
working on football data analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to access open event data from &lt;em&gt;statsbomb&lt;/em&gt; API,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to draw a soccer pitch using &lt;em&gt;mplsoccer&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to visualize a pass network map for a particular team in a
particular game …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk teaches four simple concepts to those who want to start
working on football data analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to access open event data from &lt;em&gt;statsbomb&lt;/em&gt; API,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to draw a soccer pitch using &lt;em&gt;mplsoccer&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to visualize a pass network map for a particular team in a
particular game, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use the &lt;em&gt;NetworkX&lt;/em&gt; module to analyze the pass network (eg.
finding out-degree distribution of passes, clustering coefficient,
centrality, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2021"></category></entry></feed>