<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tadeh Hakopian</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tadeh-hakopian.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Importance of Visuals in Teaching Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2020/the-importance-of-visuals-in-teaching-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-17:/pybay-2020/the-importance-of-visuals-in-teaching-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2020 Online Edition. It’s the 5th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DESCRIPTION
Python can be taught line by line but not everyone is comfortable with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2020 Online Edition. It’s the 5th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DESCRIPTION
Python can be taught line by line but not everyone is comfortable with purely text and logic based explanation of coding. The current status quo is to teach showing lines of code with inputs and outputs though a lot of visual learners aren’t going to easily grasp that. What if there was a way to communicate the code concepts with images? This talk will show how using geometry and modeling can acclimate novices to coding concepts using visual-spatial examples reinforced by coding concepts applicable anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPEAKER BIO
Tadeh is a developer and designer in Architecture (buildings not computers). He has been a course author, trainer and open source contributor. Over the years he has taught other designers the value of coding and automation and wants to continue to spread that message to as many people as possible with training seminars and talks. He has been a speaker at national conferences about design, tech and Architecture and loves to talk about new possibilities with innovation and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPONSOR ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
The post production of this and other PyBay2020 videos are made possible by our sponsors:
- IBM &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://community.ibm.com/community/user/datascience/home"&gt;https://community.ibm.com/community/user/datascience/home&lt;/a&gt;
- Rookout &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rookout.com/"&gt;https://rookout.com/&lt;/a&gt;
- Anyscale &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anyscale.com"&gt;https://anyscale.com&lt;/a&gt;
- Twilio &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twilio.com/"&gt;https://twilio.com/&lt;/a&gt;
- JetBrains &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.jetbrains.com"&gt;https://www.jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;
- Linode &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://linode.com"&gt;https://linode.com&lt;/a&gt;
- Pearson Informit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.informit.com/"&gt;https://www.informit.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVENT PRODUCER ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
This community conference is produced by organizers of SF Python meetup and volunteers from around the SF Bay Area and beyond. See upcoming events here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sfpythonmeetup.com"&gt;https://sfpythonmeetup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Programming Your Way up a Skyscraper - Python in the Built World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2022/programming-your-way-up-a-skyscraper-python-in-the-built-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-02-06:/pycascades-2022/programming-your-way-up-a-skyscraper-python-in-the-built-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I started working on the latest high rise for San Francisco a challenge stood before me: How am I going to do this without losing my mind? Thankfully Python coding came to the rescue. This talk will showcase all the tools built around Python that can make architecture …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I started working on the latest high rise for San Francisco a challenge stood before me: How am I going to do this without losing my mind? Thankfully Python coding came to the rescue. This talk will showcase all the tools built around Python that can make architecture dreams come true!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Seeing is Believing: Solve Communication Gaps with the Lost Art of Diagrams</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/seeing-is-believing-solve-communication-gaps-with-the-lost-art-of-diagrams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-08:/pycascades-2025/seeing-is-believing-solve-communication-gaps-with-the-lost-art-of-diagrams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about communicating with visuals to make complex ideas simple to understand. Over the years I have produced diagrams, charts, illustrations and other graphics to help people understand sophisticated project concepts. This includes project architecture, standard operating procedures, coding concepts, sprints and roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about communicating with visuals to make complex ideas simple to understand. Over the years I have produced diagrams, charts, illustrations and other graphics to help people understand sophisticated project concepts. This includes project architecture, standard operating procedures, coding concepts, sprints and roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through ways of how to make stylized examples of your project code and workflows in easy to follow examples. By using common software for illustrations along with some simple guidelines you too can make easy to follow visual content for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand how to make your technical documentation into visual graphics with diagram design style guides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See examples of how to take technical documentation and create an intuitive diagram of it to share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come away with an ability to execute a simple (or sophisticated) graphic with essential steps and key requirements&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Programming Your Way up a Skyscraper - Python in the Built World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/programming-your-way-up-a-skyscraper-python-in-the-built-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/programming-your-way-up-a-skyscraper-python-in-the-built-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how Architects leverage Python in building projects to enable more design possibilities than ever before. Python is one of the fastest growing scripting languages in the Building design and construction field increasingly being used by professional in the industry. This talk will lead you through how Architects design …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how Architects leverage Python in building projects to enable more design possibilities than ever before. Python is one of the fastest growing scripting languages in the Building design and construction field increasingly being used by professional in the industry. This talk will lead you through how Architects design, plan, edit and execute scripts with Python using different editing tools. Learn about how designers tackle the challenge of putting a building together with the aid of code including; using Python script to edit geometry, create algorithmic design for buildings, sort data lists, write content to software and much more. With Python you can unleash the potential in your projects so come and see what’s possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>The Lost Art of Diagrams: Making Complex Ideas Easy to See with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/the-lost-art-of-diagrams-making-complex-ideas-easy-to-see-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/the-lost-art-of-diagrams-making-complex-ideas-easy-to-see-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about communicating with visuals to make complex ideas
simple to understand. Over the years I have produced diagrams, charts,
illustrations and other graphics to help people understand sophisticated
project concepts. This includes project architecture, standard operating
procedures, coding concepts, sprints and roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about communicating with visuals to make complex ideas
simple to understand. Over the years I have produced diagrams, charts,
illustrations and other graphics to help people understand sophisticated
project concepts. This includes project architecture, standard operating
procedures, coding concepts, sprints and roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through ways of how to make stylized examples of your
project code and workflows in easy to follow examples. By using common
software for illustrations along with some simple guidelines you too can
make easy to follow visual content for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn methods to visually communicate with your team including with
color, shapes, images, gifs and even memes to help get a point across
Understand how to make your technical documentation into visual graphics
with diagram design style guides See examples of how to take technical
documentation and create an intuitive diagram of it to share Come away
with an ability to execute a simple (or sophisticated) graphic with
essential steps and key requirements&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Seeing is Believing - Using Diagrams to Communicate Complex Ideas with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/seeing-is-believing-using-diagrams-to-communicate-complex-ideas-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/seeing-is-believing-using-diagrams-to-communicate-complex-ideas-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about communicating with visuals to make complex ideas
simple to understand. Over the years I have produced diagrams, charts,
illustrations and other graphics to help people understand sophisticated
project concepts. This includes project architecture, standard operating
procedures, coding concepts, sprints and roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about communicating with visuals to make complex ideas
simple to understand. Over the years I have produced diagrams, charts,
illustrations and other graphics to help people understand sophisticated
project concepts. This includes project architecture, standard operating
procedures, coding concepts, sprints and roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through ways of how to make stylized examples of your
project code and workflows in easy to follow examples. By using common
software for illustrations along with some simple guidelines you too can
make easy to follow visual content for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn methods to visually communicate with your team including with
color, shapes, images, gifs and even memes to help get a point across
Understand how to make your technical documentation into visual graphics
with diagram design style guides See examples of using libraries like
Sphinx, Pydoc, and PlantUML to help make great diagrams Come away with
an ability to execute a simple (or sophisticated) graphic with essential
steps and key requirements&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Python: The Architect's Secret Weapon</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/python-the-architects-secret-weapon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/python-the-architects-secret-weapon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The built environment is undergoing a digital revolution, and Python is at the forefront. This talk will explore how Python, combined with open-source tools like Blender, OpenUSD, and Dynamo, is transforming the way we design, analyze, and construct buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll delve into practical applications, from generating 3D models to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The built environment is undergoing a digital revolution, and Python is at the forefront. This talk will explore how Python, combined with open-source tools like Blender, OpenUSD, and Dynamo, is transforming the way we design, analyze, and construct buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll delve into practical applications, from generating 3D models to performing energy simulations and creating stunning visualizations. You'll learn how to harness the power of Python to address pressing challenges in the construction industry, such as climate change, resource scarcity, and urban development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're interested in how Python can shape the built environment then come and see for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand the role of Python in the Architecture and Construction industry.
Learn how professionals use Python to automate design and analysis tasks.
Explore the potential of open-source tools like Blender, OpenUSD, and Dynamo.
Discover how Python is used to create stunning visualizations and simulations of buildings.
Gain insights into the future of digital design and construction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Computational Thinking for Creatives - Decoding Barriers to Entry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/computational-thinking-for-creatives-decoding-barriers-to-entry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tadeh Hakopian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/computational-thinking-for-creatives-decoding-barriers-to-entry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;1:00 What is computational thinking
2:00 Why understanding computational thinking can help coding problem solving
4:00 How to bridge the gap of learning to code for creatives like designers
8:00 Establishing the thought process of sequential problem solving
16:00 Prepare people to understand how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;1:00 What is computational thinking
2:00 Why understanding computational thinking can help coding problem solving
4:00 How to bridge the gap of learning to code for creatives like designers
8:00 Establishing the thought process of sequential problem solving
16:00 Prepare people to understand how to abstract problems down into steps
24:00 Use visual aides and diagrams to help visual learners understand key concepts of computational thinking
30:00 With patterns people can build the basis for creating algorithms
34:00 Goals of creating training to learn to code while being mindful of different learning styles
36:00 The results including how people were able to get a handle on coding due to computational thinking
40:00 Review Key points and lessons learned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>