<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jesse Seldess</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jesse-seldess.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Bootstrapping Docs at a Startup</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/bootstrapping-docs-at-a-startup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jesse Seldess</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/bootstrapping-docs-at-a-startup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you “bootstrap docs”? In this talk, I will walk through how to
build essential docs for an early stage startup that lays a strong
foundation for continuous improvement and expansion. The story will be
told through my experiences building docs from scratch for CockroachDB
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cockroachlabs.com"&gt;https://www.cockroachlabs …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you “bootstrap docs”? In this talk, I will walk through how to
build essential docs for an early stage startup that lays a strong
foundation for continuous improvement and expansion. The story will be
told through my experiences building docs from scratch for CockroachDB
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cockroachlabs.com"&gt;https://www.cockroachlabs.com&lt;/a&gt;), a next-generation open source database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I joined Cockroach Labs as its first technical writer, CockroachDB
had been in development for nearly two years and had 15 engineers and
60+ open source developers contributing to it. I needed to build a
documentation structure and process that would be lightweight enough for
developers to contribute to and flexible enough to apply to the product
(and team) years down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk the audience through the process of learning a new
product and development team, and allowing that information to guide the
information architecture and tool selection process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics will include: - How do you learn a new product, and why is it
essential to understand its market fit? - How do you learn about your
users - who are they, what are their primary pain points, and what do
they need most from docs? - How do you choose tools and workflows for
building your initial docs architecture? - How do you iterate on,
improve, and expand your docs, and harness contributors to do the same?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Portland 2017"></category></entry></feed>