<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_marco-slaviero.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>House of Salt: Extending and leveraging SaltStack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/house-of-salt-extending-and-leveraging-saltstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Slaviero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:pycon-za-2017/house-of-salt-extending-and-leveraging-saltstack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, sysadmins had cute naming schemes for their boxen,
and it was good. Suddenly, virtualisation! And the cute names
withered as herds of servers were born. Infrastructure automation and
management became a thing. Helper software was released (without
which a nine person company could not hope to manage 400-odd
servers.) And it was good again, until the edges showed. Then we
started to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll discuss the challenges encountered in managing
hundreds of servers delivering a single product on AWS. Relying on
SaltStack for deployment, management and diagnostics, we’ve automated
away painful steps and reduced our attack surface. SaltStack handles
configuration and package management well, but is capable of much more
once you start to customise it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we’ll show examples of custom SaltStack modules, runners,
and event handlers. We’ll describe threats and show how SaltStack helps
us limit their exposure and impact. We’ll catalogue the lessons we’ve
faced in two years of running SaltStack in our production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won't rehash content from previous talks, and novice users will get
to see how the tool can be stretched. If you’re wanting to get more out
of SaltStack than the builtin modules allow for, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>