<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sara Peeters</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sara-peeters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning talks - Wednesday - part 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-2.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="DjangoCon Europe 2017"></category><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>The art of interacting with an autistic software developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/the-art-of-interacting-with-an-autistic-software-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:/djangocon-europe-2017/the-art-of-interacting-with-an-autistic-software-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I tell people I have autism there are roughly two common reactions. Either the mental picture of Rainman gets triggered and they don't believe me at all, or they just shrug and mumble something in the lines of &amp;quot;We all have a bit of that, don't we?&amp;quot; While …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I tell people I have autism there are roughly two common reactions. Either the mental picture of Rainman gets triggered and they don't believe me at all, or they just shrug and mumble something in the lines of &amp;quot;We all have a bit of that, don't we?&amp;quot; While I don't want to judge anyone based on those reactions, I think both perceptions are wrong or at least incomplete, and indeed symptomatic for the lack of deeper understanding of autism in the broader society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless the employment situation of normally gifted people on the autism spectrum has noticeably improved over the last couple of years. Especially in IT related professions, where autistics have even become a specific target group for recruitment. Thanks to those inclusion strategies, as well as improved diagnosis, chances are higher than ever for every one of us to end up working together with someone with a diagnosed autism spectrum disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will have a look behind the scenes of the autism spectrum. We will find out more about the strengths, weaknesses and invisible struggles of those affected. Then we will focus on the working environment of a software developer and propose tips and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon Europe 2017"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Sketchnoting Challenge</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/django-sketchnoting-challenge.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-02:/djangocon-europe-2021/django-sketchnoting-challenge.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sketchnoting is the process of taking visual notes by combining symbolic illustrations and text. In this workshop we will learn the basics of sketchnoting first. And then we will make visual notes about Django concepts! Grab a pencil and some paper, and let's sketch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this workshop we will …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sketchnoting is the process of taking visual notes by combining symbolic illustrations and text. In this workshop we will learn the basics of sketchnoting first. And then we will make visual notes about Django concepts! Grab a pencil and some paper, and let's sketch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this workshop we will learn some easy drawing skills we can use for illustrating tech concepts (or anything else). Sketchnoting, the combination of text and simple, symbolic drawings is a great way to express ideas. Requirements, user stories, notes of meetings, talks, articles or tutorials, all can become much more engaging with a few extra illustrations. Though developers (and people in general) often think they can't draw, there are some easy tricks everyone can learn. In addition, drawing things is a really fun way to spend your time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short intro of what sketchnoting is (5 min), we go over 4 tips for sketching practice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I can't draw this: composition and googling (5 min)
drawing people fast and easy (5 min)
putting text in boxes (5 min)
faces and emotions (5 min)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue with a couple of drawing challenges (10 min), where I will show how to quickly sketch some easy and more difficult concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last 25 minutes will encourage the attendees to illustrate a Django concept on their own, with guidance and support from myself.
This can be the take aways of a Djangocon talk, a concept they recently learned, an illustration to a blogpost or podcast, tips on how to make the most out of an online conference...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop intends to appeal to an audience of all backgrounds and skill levels. On top of that, the content will be appropriate for all ages, so you can draw along with your kids! By the end of this talk, attendees will have some inputs to be creative with pen and paper, and have learned some of the skills that go with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon Europe 2021"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="DjangoConEU"></category><category term="djangoconeu2021"></category></entry></feed>