<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sümer Cip</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Profiling Django &amp; Python apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/profiling-django-python-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to improve what is not measurable! Profiling an application should always be the first step in trying to improve its performance. With this workshop, learn how to identify performance issues in your application and adopt the best profiling practices in your daily development habits. This workshop will use the Blackfire.io tool to help you identify performance leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jérôme Vieilledent</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-03:/djangocon-europe-2021/profiling-django-python-apps.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2021</category><category>Django</category><category>DjangoConEU</category><category>djangoconeu2021</category></item><item><title>Hunting Performance in Django Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/hunting-performance-in-django-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction and Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick introduction of myself followed by an outline of what will be covered and what you will learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why we profile?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical program spends almost all its time in a small subset of its code. Optimizing those hotspots is all that matters. This is what a profiler is for: it leads us straight to the functions where we should spend our effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What types tools are available and how they work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Deterministic Profilers
-Statistical Profilers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be walking over the different use cases, pros/cons for each type. Then I will dig in a bit deeper on how they work under the hood. Understanding the inner workings a bit might be helpful while analysing its output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of information do we get?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll describe what kind of output we get from different profilers. What kind of metrics are available(Wall time, CPU time, sub/cumulative time) and where are those metrics are most useful while hunting for performance problems especially
for Web applications. I will also walk over/explain different kind of visualisations that profilers generate: Flamegraphs, Callgraph, SpeedScope...etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sümer Cip</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-02:/djangocon-europe-2021/hunting-performance-in-django-code.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2021</category><category>Django</category><category>DjangoConEU</category><category>djangoconeu2021</category></item><item><title>Blackfire sponsor workshop: Debugging Performance</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/blackfire-sponsor-workshop-debugging-performance.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Performance is a feature of any application. It should be tested, and cared for like any feature. Using the right tools to understand how code consumes resources, and how to match a given performance budget is key. That discipline can become seamless, from development, to test/staging and production.
This workshop will give tips and tricks to master performance optimization on an example Django application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jérôme Vieilledent</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/blackfire-sponsor-workshop-debugging-performance.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2021</category></item></channel></rss>