<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Understanding and Applying CQRS</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/understanding-and-applying-cqrs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating scalable applications has a number of complex variables and one
of them is to work with scalability and performance in the database
layer. Command Query Responsibility Segregation (CQRS) is a design
pattern that helps produce more performance and resilience in
applications where data access is intense. In this talk, we will
understand when to use and the problems that CQRS solves. We will also
apply CQRS in a Python application using the Nameko framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outline talk is: ○ (4 minutes) - Present a real problem of a web
application, when creating new instances is not a solution, because the
database receives an overwrite of writing and unfeasible to read the
data, collapsing the application. ○ (6 minutes) - Present the CQRS
pattern conceptually and how this design pattern solves this type of
problem using the structure of Command Stack and Query Stack ○ (3
minutes) - Show Nameko as an interesting tool to apply the CQRS. It will
demonstrate the use of HTTP, RPC and the possibility of applying
pub/sub. ○ (6 minutes) - Create (live code) the Command Stack layer
using Nameko on a Postgresql database. ○ (5 minutes) - Create (live
code) the Query Stack layer using Nameko over a MongoDB database. ○ (3
minutes) - Explain common myths and mistakes about CQRS (3 minutes) - Q
&amp;amp; A Session&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vinicius Pacheco</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/understanding-and-applying-cqrs.html</guid></item><item><title>Green threads in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/green-threads-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is for general public with problems to scale. The good
background for this talk is people with minimal knowledge about
threads. After this talk I expect that the audience can be enable to
understand multiprocessing, when use and which tools and methods are
appropriate for each case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding threads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's the first moment on the talk. Here I'll speak about the thread theory and what happen when we use threads on the OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Threads and multiprocess API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'll give simple examples about what python give us to use threads and multiprocessing perhaps with two APIs&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/threading.html"&gt;https://docs.python.org/3/library/threading.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.python.org/3.5/library/multiprocessing.html"&gt;https://docs.python.org/3.5/library/multiprocessing.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding Green threads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here I'll speak about green threads theory and what happen when we use green threads on our OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green thread Patterns and tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here I'll show few examples with keep alive patterns, discuss about a few tools and show gevent and asyncio examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parallelism x asynchronism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'll show the diference between parallelism and asynchronism discussing about the two theories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, when and how&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's is the last talk moment and I'll explain the how complex is work with multiprocess showing cases like queues consume and APIs consume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vinicius Pacheco</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/green-threads-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>APIs and Microservices With Go</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/apis-and-microservices-with-go.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vinicius Pacheco - APIs and Microservices With Go
[EuroPython 2016]
[19 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/apis-and-microservices-with-go"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/apis-and-microservices-with-go&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we show how the Go language helped us get a high
performance in a concise and simple API. Everything will be
exemplified using the backdrop of a real case of Globo.com: API
registrations. We will see how we went from 200 to 19,000 records per
second to the impacts of this rapid growth and the consequences of Go
of use. We also show how our microservices architecture was used in
the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about Go, software architecture and parallelism. How we
went from legacy, complex and slow software to new, speed, resilient
and maintainable software.
I'll start the talk showing the problemas and the challenges that my
team had received. After that, I'll show the tests, tests of
performance and the options that we did considering technologies and
strategies of development. The difficulties and problems also will be
show. Also I talk about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goroutines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilient patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we leave of the Java ecosystem to new free ecosystem with
microservices and how Go help us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vinicius Pacheco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-31:europython-2016/apis-and-microservices-with-go.html</guid></item></channel></rss>