<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Patrick Arminio</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning talks - Wednesday - part 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-1.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Quinn</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-05:/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-wednesday-part-1.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2017</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>GraphQL in Python and Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/graphql-in-python-and-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll talk about GraphQL, a data query language created by Facebook as an alternative to the widely used REST. I’ll list the key differences between the twos and pros and cons of GraphQL over a “traditional” REST API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll tell why GraphQL has been created, what problems does it solve and how to create GraphQL APIs with Python with an additional follow up on how to use it with Django, one of the most popular web framework. If we have enough time I’ll touch on advanced topics like authentication, caching, security and real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeaway: the objective of the talk is to have an introduction on GraphQL, understand why and when to use it and, finally, how to use it Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: the talk is for web developers with some experience building web APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick Arminio&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-25:/djangocon-europe-2018/graphql-in-python-and-django.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2018</category></item><item><title>Domain Driven Design with Django and GraphQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/domain-driven-design-with-django-and-graphql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain driven design is starting getting traction in the Python world, probably also thanks to Architecture Patterns with Python (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cosmicpython.com/"&gt;https://www.cosmicpython.com/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will learn some basics of Domain Driven Design and how to apply the pattern when using Django and GraphQL. We will see different approaches of modelling the domain, and discuss the tradeoffs. We will discuss why this approach makes a lot of sense with GraphQL and finally we will see a complex approach where we leverage the domain driven architecture to have an easy way to abstract how we store and cache our data in order to build a performant GraphQL API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at people with knowledge of web-development. GraphQL knowledge won’t be necessary as I’ll do a quick introduction of that. Experience with Django, Flask or similar framework might be useful but not required.
The audience will learn basic concepts of domain driven design and how to apply them to build a scalable GraphQL API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-02:/djangocon-europe-2021/domain-driven-design-with-django-and-graphql.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2021</category><category>Django</category><category>DjangoConEU</category><category>djangoconeu2021</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Django and GraphQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/introduction-to-django-and-graphql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GraphQL has grown a lot overtime, but it seems to still be a new “thing”
in the Python and Django World. This talk will be an introduction to
GraphQL, explaining why it has been created and how you can use it in
Python and Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short speaker introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small digression on how the “old” web used to be and how it has now
evolved into the modern web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really quick explanation of REST (just to make sure everyone is
familiar with it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some limitations of REST? What can we do about it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to GraphQL, what it is, how’s using it and when has it
been created?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GraphQL: query language syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GraphQL: types and introspection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GraphQL: operation, how to read data,update data and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use Graphql with Python and Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s make a simple API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create mutations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things to consider (security caching and performance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:/djangocon-us-2018/introduction-to-django-and-graphql.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2018</category></item><item><title>Django and Graphql</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/django-and-graphql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The web is constantly evolving, that is even more true with the
frontend world. You don’t have anymore the traditional webapp, in
fact you now have two apps, backend and frontend. But how do they
communicate? Traditionally we have always created REST APIs, but now,
there’s a new player. GraphQL!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-11:/europython-2017/django-and-graphql.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2017</category></item><item><title>GraphQL in Python 🍓</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/graphql-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years GraphQL has gained much traction, but what’s the
state of GraphQL in Python. This talk describes what GraphQL is, why it
has been created and the current state of GraphQL libraries in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a short history of GraphQL, some examples of what makes it
shine and why it can be preferred to REST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also analyse the current state of GraphQL in Python, having a
brief overview of the current libraries and then having an in-depth look
at Strawberry a new library based on dataclasses that makes it easy to
create GraphQl APIs in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/graphql-in-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Django</category><category>RESTful</category><category>Web</category><category>Web General</category><category>Web Servers and MicroFWs</category></item><item><title>GraphQL Subscriptions: Real-time Data with WebSockets* and Strawberry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/graphql-subscriptions-real-time-data-with-websockets-and-strawberry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/graphql-subscriptions-real-time-data-with-websockets-and-strawberry"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/graphql-subscriptions-real-time-data-with-websockets-and-strawberry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring your GraphQL APIs to life with real-time data using Strawberry! 🌟 In this talk, we'll dive into GraphQL Subscriptions and explore how to leverage WebSockets for interactive, real-time updates. Say goodbye to constant polling and hello to efficient, seamless communication!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key insights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding GraphQL Subscriptions and their role in real-time data delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up WebSocket connections and integrating them with your GraphQL server using Strawberry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designing subscription schemas and handling server-side events for seamless updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhancing client-side experiences with real-time data and updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/graphql-subscriptions-real-time-data-with-websockets-and-strawberry.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Strawberry: a dataclasses inspired approach to GraphQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2019/strawberry-a-dataclasses-inspired-approach-to-graphql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Patrick Arminio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, GraphQL has gained much traction, especially in the JavaScript world. Python is getting on board this trend with new interesting libraries. In this talk, we will see how Strawberry makes uses of dataclasses and type hints to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/QABWWM"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/QABWWM&lt;/a&gt;
Follow us on Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-11:/pycon-de-2019/strawberry-a-dataclasses-inspired-approach-to-graphql.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2019</category></item><item><title>Django and GraphQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2017/django-and-graphql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a new alternative to REST API. GraphQL. GraphQL has been created by Facebook in 2012 and since then is being used by big companies like Facebook itself, Github, Shopify and so on. In this talk I'd like to explain why we need an alternative to REST APIs and why GraphQL is that alternative. Also we will see how to use GraphQL with Django and how to use it for non trivial applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-21:/pycon-ireland-2017/django-and-graphql.html</guid><category>PyCon Ireland 2017</category><category>graphql</category></item><item><title>Building GraphQL APIs using Python and Type Hints</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/building-graphql-apis-using-python-and-type-hints.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building GraphQL APIs using Python and Type Hints - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GraphQL is an awesome technology that allows to build type safe APIs. In
this talk we’ll learn how GraphQL works and how we can use Python’s type
hints to create GraphQL APIs. GraphQL is a technology to create web APIs
that has become quite popular in the past years. In this talk we’ll see
in detail what GraphQL is, why it exists and why you should use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll also see how we can implement a GraphQL API using Strawberry and
Python’s type hints. We’ll see why type hints make a lot of sense for
GraphQL and what kind of issue you might encounter writing GraphQL APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the talk you’ll know what GraphQL is, how to implement a
basic GraphQL API using Python and what to look out for when working
with GraphQL in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target audience: python developers with familiarities of web APIs (like
REST). some knowledge of type hints might be useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Patrick Arminio&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/building-graphql-apis-using-python-and-type-hints.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>graphql</category></item><item><title>Django and GraphQL</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/django-and-graphql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The web is constantly evolving, that is even more true with the frontend world. You don’t have anymore the traditional webapp, in fact you now have two apps, backend and frontend. But how do they communicate? Traditionally we have always created REST APIs, but now, there’s a new player. GraphQL!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-28:/pycon-uk-2017/django-and-graphql.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2017</category></item><item><title>Optimizing GraphQL Performance: Tips and Techniques</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2023/optimizing-graphql-performance-tips-and-techniques.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll explore techniques to optimize GraphQL performance for snappy, scalable, and resource-efficient APIs. Attendees will learn about batching queries with DataLoader, managing query complexity and depth, leveraging persisted queries for reduced network overhead, and implementing
caching strategies on both server and client-side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;API performance is crucial for delivering a smooth and responsive user
experience. GraphQL has gained popularity as a flexible and efficient query
language, but without proper optimization, it may underperform or even become a
bottleneck in your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll dive into the essential techniques and best practices to
optimize GraphQL performance, ensuring that your APIs are snappy, scalable, and
resource-efficient. Attendees will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of batching queries and how to implement it using DataLoader or
similar libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of query complexity and depth, and how to set up limits to prevent
resource abuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveraging persisted queries to reduce network overhead and improve caching
capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing caching strategies, both on the server and client-side, to
minimize redundant requests and reduce load times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploring monitoring and observability tools that can help you identify
performance bottlenecks and continuously optimize your GraphQL implementation
for maximum efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-24:/pycon-uk-2023/optimizing-graphql-performance-tips-and-techniques.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2023</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Day 3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are a ~ 5 minutes long, on any topic of interest to other Python people. It doesn't have to be about something that you wrote, it can be something that you learned, or a technique you think other people will be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:23 - Pandy Knight - How to write a test case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05:09 - Shreya Batra - The Effects of Computational THinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;09:36 - Patrick Arminio - The fastest way to fetch the latest python version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11:57 - Ray McLendon - Not all data is created equal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16:24 - Geir Arne Hjelle - Reading PEPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21:30 - Jonathan Helmus - Pip install Python?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;26:07 - Jelle Zijlstra - PEP 688: Typing for the buffer protocol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29:30 - Nick Muoh - Post pandemic meetuup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;33:25 - multiple speakers talking about Regional Python Conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pandy Knight</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-3.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Build a production ready GraphQL API using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/build-a-production-ready-graphql-api-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop will teach you how to create a production ready GraphQL
API using Python and Strawberry. We will be using using Django as our
framework of choice, but most of the concept will be applicable to other
frameworks too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll learn how GraphQL works under the hood, and how we can leverage
type hints to create end to end type safe GraphQL queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll also learn how to authenticate users when using GraphQL and how to
make sure our APIs are performant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we have enough time we'll take a look at doing realtime APIs using
GraphQL subscriptions and how to use GraphQL with frontend frameworks
such as React.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-19:/pycon-us-2023/build-a-production-ready-graphql-api-using-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Django and the new frontend era</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/django-and-the-new-frontend-era.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;React, Ember, Vue - these are just some of the big beasts of the frontend world. How do they fit in a Django world? Is Django still suited for how we are now developing web apps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as Full stack developer so I often jump from Django to frontend frameworks like React and Vue JS. I’d like to share the way we structure Django apps in order to work well with frontend frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-27:/pyconweb-2017/django-and-the-new-frontend-era.html</guid><category>PyConWeb 2017</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>GraphQL in Python and Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyparis-2018/graphql-in-python-and-django.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-14:/pyparis-2018/graphql-in-python-and-django.html</guid><category>PyParis 2018</category></item></channel></rss>