<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_roland-gesthuizen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Smart City: Connecting the dots and digital kids</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/smart-city-connecting-the-dots-and-digital-kids.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roland Gesthuizen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/smart-city-connecting-the-dots-and-digital-kids.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roland Gesthuizen
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/203/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/203/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Schools face a daunting challenge to increase their student
exposure to coding, hands-on technology learning to solve some
real-world problems and teaching STEM principles (Science, Technology,
Engineering and Mathematics) through design, construction and testing.
This personal presentation by a leading teacher illustrate journey to
connect his students to some real-world problems and the challenges
faced along the way. Following on from an earlier
computational-thinking challenge to build and program a moving
vehicle, Roland's current mission is to challenge students to design,
build a smart city consisting of intelligent vehicles and
infrastructure. To do this they need to program a navigation algorithm
to autonomously navigate vehicles through a series of traffic
challenges that test collision avoidance and road safety. They have
been invited to showcase their work at the ITS2016 Word Congress in
Melbourne with a maker-space for delegates to share our hands-on
problem solving and learning with the software and models developed by
the students. Moonshots live in a grey area between audacious
technology and pure science fiction. Our moonshot was to empower
students around the globe to build and control their future.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="education"></category></entry></feed>