<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to become a Data Scientist in 6 months a hacker’s approach to career planning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2016/tetiana-ivanova-how-to-become-a-data-scientist-in-6-months-a-hackers-approach-to-career-planning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData London 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk outlines my journey from complete novice to machine learning practitioner. It started in November 2015 when I left my job as a project manager, and by April 2016 I was hired as a Data Scientist by a startup developing bleeding edge deep learning algorithms for medical imagery processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHORT INTRO
Who I am, my background and short summary of my story. Here I will list the steps I personally took to achieve the goal I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOW DID I DO IT?
Why I chose a “hacky” way to enter this career path. First mover advantage, why getting a degree doesn’t always improve your career prospects. Possibly a rant on the signalling function of formal education and how that is rarely aligned with a relevant practical skill set. Some stats to back it up (best career success predictors). Examples of hacking bureaucracies/social hierarchies from my experience and elsewhere.
List of things not to do and common cognitive pitfalls.
Networking for nerds - how to do it right.
Time management for chronic procrastinators - how to plan a self-guided project. Some notes on psychology of time discounting and need for external reinforcement, with autobiographical examples.
CONCLUSION
You don’t need a PhD or even a masters to do machine learning. On taking calculated risks and especially calculated exits from one’s comfort zone. Some notes on soul searching and how to choose a career that is also a passion. Reading list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack-files.com/T0LFE6T6J-F170V6945-ad054e4f6a"&gt;https://slack-files.com/T0LFE6T6J-F170V6945-ad054e4f6a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tetiana Ivanova</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-11:pydata-london-2016/tetiana-ivanova-how-to-become-a-data-scientist-in-6-months-a-hackers-approach-to-career-planning.html</guid></item></channel></rss>