<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_frederike-jaeger.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data science APIs for everyone created by magic*</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/data-science-apis-for-everyone-created-by-magic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Frederike Jaeger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-15:pycon-uk-2018/data-science-apis-for-everyone-created-by-magic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;*not actually magic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more data than we can handle being produced every day, data science
is the new big thing in tech and taking the world by storm. People like
me (a proud physicist) are doing a big chunk of the data science model
development, often relying on engineers to help them take their model to
the masses. Unfortunately, not every data scientist has an engineer at
hand at all times. So what if they still want to deploy their model
using an API?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help scientists without a strong engineering background do just that,
we created an open source python package called revelio, which lets
users create a basic API with minimal effort. The idea is that you
supply your trained data science model and some sample input, and the
package does everything else for you - including input validation and
creating some documentation. To make things better, you can also monitor
the API requests and predictions. The aim is to make the data science
pipeline easier, especially for data scientists working in small teams
with less support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this talk, I will walk you through creating APIs in Flask,
highlight common patterns in data science and show how revelio makes
implementing these easier. By the end of the talk, you&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;will feel confident prototyping, deploying and monitoring data science
APIs!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>