<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Carlos Cordoba</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_carlos-cordoba.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Spyder debugger: An interactive debugger based on Jupyter technologies</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/the-spyder-debugger-an-interactive-debugger-based-on-jupyter-technologies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Cordoba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/the-spyder-debugger-an-interactive-debugger-based-on-jupyter-technologies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main features of scientific programming is its exploratory nature: starting from some input data, the goal is to analyze it in order to understand what it can tell us about the phenomena that generated it. However, the means to do this are often unclear, and the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main features of scientific programming is its exploratory nature: starting from some input data, the goal is to analyze it in order to understand what it can tell us about the phenomena that generated it. However, the means to do this are often unclear, and the results unforeseen. That is why this type of programming requires tools for rapid, interactive prototyping that allow users to seamlessly switch solutions to tackle the problem at hand. Unfortunately, it is not possible to follow the same approach while debugging, because traditional debuggers are mostly focused on letting users explore the call stack and state of variables, and have limited capabilities to run code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spyder, a community developed, open source IDE written in and for Python, aims to bridge the gap in that area. It blends the debugger with the interpreter to allow data exploration at any point during code execution, not just at the end. For that, Spyder's debugger attempts to offer the same functionality as a full IPython interpreter, so that its users can debug their code in the same way they are used to doing the rest of their scientific programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will cover the debugger features available in Spyder 5, as well as those planned for future versions. Specifically, I will present a live demo to showcase the following features (described in depth in this blog post and the Spyder documentation):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to start the debugger and set breakpoints.
How to better understand the code at a certain frame by writing code snippets in the debugger itself, facilitated by syntax highlighting, code completion, multi-line editing and command history.
How to move up and down in the call stack to explore other frames in the same way.
How to use Spyder's Variable Explorer to browse the contents of objects.
How to generate Matplotlib plots while in the debugger.
How to use IPython magics while debugging to profile code using %timeit, explore the filesystem with %cd and %ls, and open files with %edit.
Thanks to these improvements, Spyder transforms debugging from a task that feels foreign to scientific programming, to be almost second nature. By adding breakpoint calls or setting breakpoints in the debugger, users can easily prototype different solutions for their problems at any point during code execution, and not just at end. This also increases programming speed by allowing to constantly check the correctness of code during development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk, I hope attendees will learn that they don't need resort to print() or other workarounds to debug their code. Instead, they can rely on the robust debugging methods used by professional developers, supported by the interactivity and workflow they're familiar with in IPython/Jupyter.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Towards a Better Documentation System for Scientific Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/towards-a-better-documentation-system-for-scientific-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Cordoba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:/scipy-2015/towards-a-better-documentation-system-for-scientific-python.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="SciPy 2015"></category></entry><entry><title>What's new in Spyder 3.0</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/whats-new-in-spyder-30-scipy-2016-carlos-cordoba.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Cordoba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:/scipy-2016/whats-new-in-spyder-30-scipy-2016-carlos-cordoba.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our aim in this talk is to present the new features available in the next major version of Spyder, the Scientific PYthon DEvelopment EnviRonment. This version (Spyder 3.0) represents almost two years of development and brings important characteristics that we would like to introduce to the SciPy community …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our aim in this talk is to present the new features available in the next major version of Spyder, the Scientific PYthon DEvelopment EnviRonment. This version (Spyder 3.0) represents almost two years of development and brings important characteristics that we would like to introduce to the SciPy community. Among them we can find: the ability to
create and install third-party plugins, improved projects support, syntax highlighting and code completion for all programming languages supported by Pygments, a new file switcher
(similar to the one present in Sublime Text), code folding for the Editor, Emacs keybindings for the entire application, a Numpy array graphical builder, and a fully dark theme for the interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2016"></category><category term="SciPy 2016"></category></entry><entry><title>The Spyder Ecosystem of Plugins</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/the-spyder-ecosystem-of-plugins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Cordoba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:/scipy-2017/the-spyder-ecosystem-of-plugins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we want to introduce to the community a new set of third-party Spyder plugins (developed during the last six months) that extend the program functionality in interesting and novel ways. These plugins are: a &lt;em&gt;Notebook&lt;/em&gt; plugin, that integrates the classic Jupyter notebook in Spyder; a &lt;em&gt;Reports …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we want to introduce to the community a new set of third-party Spyder plugins (developed during the last six months) that extend the program functionality in interesting and novel ways. These plugins are: a &lt;em&gt;Notebook&lt;/em&gt; plugin, that integrates the classic Jupyter notebook in Spyder; a &lt;em&gt;Reports&lt;/em&gt; plugin, that allows users to write documents in markdown, with embedded code snippets and graphics, and export them to HTML and PDF; a &lt;em&gt;Terminal&lt;/em&gt; plugin, that integrates system terminals in Spyder; and a &lt;em&gt;Vim&lt;/em&gt; plugin, that allows using the most common Vim keybindings in Spyder's editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2017"></category><category term="spyder"></category></entry><entry><title>Beyond Jupyter: Other environments to do scientific programming in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-latin-america-2019/beyond-jupyter-other-environments-to-do-scientific-programming-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carlos Córdoba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-10:/scipy-latin-america-2019/beyond-jupyter-other-environments-to-do-scientific-programming-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The easiness with which you can mix code, text, equations and graphics in Jupyter has made it the preferred tool of data scientists, engineers and scientists to do scientific programming in Python. Jupyter certainly excels at data exploration and teaching but lacks many features necessary to create large and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The easiness with which you can mix code, text, equations and graphics in Jupyter has made it the preferred tool of data scientists, engineers and scientists to do scientific programming in Python. Jupyter certainly excels at data exploration and teaching but lacks many features necessary to create large and modular programs, which can be found in other well-known scientific environments such as Matlab. Spyder is an alternative to Jupyter which seeks to provide most of these features in an integrated, easy to use environment that works as a desktop application in all major operating systems (Windows, Linux and macOS). In particular, Spyder comes with a powerful editor that provides code completion, signaling of warnings and errors and the ability to go where a function, class or method is defined. With the next Spyder version, these facilities will be available not only for Python but for several other programming languages as well (e.g. C++ or Julia). After writing your code on the editor, you can execute it in Spyder's integrated IPython console. Spyder supports several types of evaluation modes, according to your needs: you can run the whole file, only portions of the it (called cells) or a single line. This allows for quick iteration and incremental code development: every change can be reevaluated and feedback about its results obtained immediately thanks to the console's presence. To further support this process, Spyder also offers and integrated documentation viewer called 'Help'. After pressing 'Ctrl+I' next to any object used in the editor or the console, the documentation viewer will display its associated help in a beautifully formatted way, which avoids constantly consulting the web to remember how to use that object. After a code execution is completed, Spyder also gives the possibility to explore all objects created by it in a pane called 'Variable Explorer'. There users can inspect and modify the contents of lists, dictionaries, sets, 2D and 3D Numpy arrays, Pandas Dataframes and any other kind of Python object through specialized viewers for each of them. Besides these four main components (Editor, Console, Help and Variable Explorer), Spyder comes with a host of other facilities aimed at increasing productivity and allowing users to easily embark in small to mid-size programming projects. Among them we would like to mention the following: the ability to create projects to quickly switch between different coding efforts, find any text snippet contained in plain text files of a given directory, and explore all files present on that directory. As the current Spyder maintainer, it would be my pleasure to present these and several other components and nifty tricks and features to the SciPy Latin America community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy Latin America 2019"></category></entry></feed>