<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tim Foster</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tim-foster.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Intelligent irrigation management using crop models, optimization and machine learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2021/intelligent-irrigation-management-using-crop-models-optimization-and-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Kelly</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-12:/scipy-2021/intelligent-irrigation-management-using-crop-models-optimization-and-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crop-growth models are powerful tools for supporting optimal planning and management of agricultural water use globally. Here, we present AquaCrop-OSPy, an open source, Python implementation of the crop-water productivity model AquaCrop. The model provides a user friendly, flexible and computationally efficient solution to support agricultural water management, which can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crop-growth models are powerful tools for supporting optimal planning and management of agricultural water use globally. Here, we present AquaCrop-OSPy, an open source, Python implementation of the crop-water productivity model AquaCrop. The model provides a user friendly, flexible and computationally efficient solution to support agricultural water management, which can be readily integrated with other Python modules or code bases and run instantly via a web browser using Google Colab. This Talk demonstrates a number of model applications such as optimizing rule based irrigation strategies, or learning irrigation management strategies from scratch using deep reinforcement learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2021"></category></entry></feed>