<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deep learning techniques for predictive analytics using Python: Theano vs TensorFlow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/deep-learning-techniques-for-predictive-analytics-using-python-theano-vs-tensorflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predictive analytics uses statistical and machine learning techniques to
provide a best assessment of what will happen in the future.
Understanding the future can guide current decisions. This talk will
provide a quick guide on using deep learning approaches in building
predictive models in python. It will give a brief introduction to
predictive models, deep learning, Tensorflow and Thenao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="allaa-hilal-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Allaa Hilal Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allaa R. Hillal has 10+ years’ experience in Data Intelligence, IoT, and
Intelligent systems design. She has a Doctorate degree in Pattern
Analysis and Machine Intelligence from the Electrical and Computer
Engineering at University of Waterloo. Dr. Hilal has been granted
numerous prestigious awards and has also been recognized as one of the
most influential women in the M2M and IoT space by the Connected World
Magazine. She has always been a big supporter of women in Science
Technology and engineering and an active member of women engineering
chapter in the University of Waterloo over the past 9 years now. She is
also the Champion of Women in Technology peer to peer group in Waterloo
and has been working on mentoring young girls and women, of all ages,
throughout the past 3 years. She is also an adjunct assistant professor
at the University of Waterloo in the pattern analysis and Data
Intelligence lab. Currently, she holds the position of Innovation Lead
at Intelligent Mechatronic Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Allaa Hilal</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/deep-learning-techniques-for-predictive-analytics-using-python-theano-vs-tensorflow.html</guid></item></channel></rss>