<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>State of Pylons/TurboGears 2/repoze.bfg</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--state-of-pylons-turbogears-2-repoze-b.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;State of Pylons/TurboGears 2/repoze.bfg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Chris McDonough, Ben Bangert, and Mark Ramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A three-for-one talk by the main developers of three popular Python web
frameworks! We'll (very) briefly cover the state of each of our
individual frameworks and communities, and then we'll describe the
results of our efforts to work together and share code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pylons is a popular, lightweight Python web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TurboGears 2 is a full-stack framework built atop Pylons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;repoze.bfg is a moderately popular, lightweight Python web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main developers and community leaders of these frameworks have been
working together and sharing as much as possible over the course of
roughly the last year. We'll very briefly describe to the audience the
states of our individual efforts, then we'll discuss how we intend to
move forward and share more code and effort in the year to come. The
talk will be more socially- oriented than technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's unusual for open source code and communities to bridge minor
perceived differences in scope and style and to start sharing code and
ideas openly. If you're a user of any of these frameworks, you'll want
to be present for this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Bangert</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--state-of-pylons-turbogears-2-repoze-b.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>pylons</category><category>pyramid</category><category>repoze.bfg</category><category>turbogears</category></item><item><title>Distributed Coordination with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/distributed-coordination-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processes in a cluster can require controlled access to shared
resources, tracking available processes, and sharing state.
Unfortunately most tools in this category are oriented around Java. In
this talk I cover how to use Python to interact with Apache Zookeeper --
a fault-tolerant consistent data-store -- to write coordinated
distributed fault-tolerant applications in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Bangert</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-17:pycon-us-2013/distributed-coordination-with-python.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Dispatch Magic</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/dispatch-magic.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most common tasks in modern web frameworks is to ease the
task of writing bits of code that are then called by the framework.
Handling this task is the first major undertaking of any web framework,
and the part that most web frameworks have in common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do frameworks locate this code? What basic patterns apply to all
frameworks? How does this make me be a better web programmer?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Bangert</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-16:pycon-us-2013/dispatch-magic.html</guid><category>talk</category></item></channel></rss>