<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lovekumar Patel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lovekumar-patel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Empowering Decisions: Advanced Portfolio Analysis and Management through Shiny</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/empowering-decisions-advanced-portfolio-analysis-and-management-through-shiny.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lovekumar Patel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/empowering-decisions-advanced-portfolio-analysis-and-management-through-shiny.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk explores the creation of an advanced portfolio analysis system using Shiny and Plumber API. Focused on delivering real-time insights and interactive tools, the system transforms financial analysis with user-centric design and reusable Shiny modules. The talk will delve into how complex financial data is made dynamic and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk explores the creation of an advanced portfolio analysis system using Shiny and Plumber API. Focused on delivering real-time insights and interactive tools, the system transforms financial analysis with user-centric design and reusable Shiny modules. The talk will delve into how complex financial data is made dynamic and interactive via an internal R package integrating with an ag-grid javascript library to enhance user engagement and decision-making efficiency. A highlight is the Plumber API's dual role: powering the current system and hosting other enterprise applications in other languages (python), demonstrating remarkable cross-platform integration. This system exemplifies the innovative potential of R in financial analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>