<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_uwe-schmitt.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>emzed: a Python based framework for analysis of mass-spectrometry data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/emzed-a-python-based-framework-for-analysis-of-mass-spectrometry-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Uwe Schmitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/emzed-a-python-based-framework-for-analysis-of-mass-spectrometry-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the existing mass spectrometry data analysis tools are desktop
applications designed for specific applications without support for
customization. In addition, many of the commercial solutions offer no or
only limited functionality for exporting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the existing programming libraries in this area are
scattered across different languages, mostly R, Java and Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, data analysis in this area often consists of manual
import/export steps from/to various tools and self-developed scripts
that prevent the reproducibility of results obtained or automated
execution on high-performance infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emzed tries to avoid these problems by integrating existing libraries
and tools from Python, R (and in the near future also Java) into an
easy-to-use API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;To support workflow development and increase confidence in end results&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;emzed also offers tools for interactive visualization of mass
spectrometry related data structures.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation introduces basics and concepts of emzed, some lessons
learned and current development of the next version of emzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about emzed, a Python library to support biologists with
little programming knowledge to implement ad-hoc analyses as well as
workflows for mass-spectrometry data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>