<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michel-voss.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Detection of solar panels based on aerial images of the city of Poznań using deep neural networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/detection-of-solar-panels-based-on-aerial-images-of-the-city-of-poznan-using-deep-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michel Voss</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:pydata-warsaw-2019/detection-of-solar-panels-based-on-aerial-images-of-the-city-of-poznan-using-deep-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the article is to present the results of a study on the
use of deep learning networks to detect solar panels based on aerial
images of Poznan. In addition, the main motivation is to obtain more
detailed information about the use of solar energy in Poland drawing on
big data sources, which until now have not been used for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data was acquired from the Management Board of Geodesy and Municipal
Cadastre GEOPOZ in Poznań and included orthophotomaps for 2016 and the
layer of buildings and plots of lands. We extracted buildings from the
images using R statistical software and the sf package. To detect solar
panels we used the Turi Create library written in Python which
re-implements the YOLO (You Only Look Once) library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The object recognition algorithm was trained on a sample of images that
included annotations (bounding boxes) about the exact location of solar
panels. The results indicate a very high recognition efficiency at the
level of 96-99% on the test sample. Based on this procedure we found
that around 2% of residential buildings in Poznań in 2016 had solar
panels mounted on roofs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we know, this is the first use of deep learning to detect
solar panels in Poland. Currently, similar studies are being carried out
by for instance Statistics Netherlands as part of the DeepSolaris
project. The study exemplifies a trend involving the use of aerial and
satellite images for statistical purposes thanks to advanced machine
learning algorithms and open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>