<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_justin-myles-holmes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python across the USA: This is the Bus.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/python-across-the-usa-this-is-the-bus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justin Myles Holmes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/python-across-the-usa-this-is-the-bus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For 2 years, a family of three has traveled on a converted school bus from conference to conference, building tooling for the road in Python and visiting Python families in every corner of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - 2016-05-30</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-05-30.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ka-Ping Yee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-30:pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-05-30.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Why the Django Community Sucks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2012/why-the-django-community-sucks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justin Myles Holmes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-05:djangocon-us-2012/why-the-django-community-sucks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing in the tradition of self-deprecation that has made DjangoCon
famous, a relative newcomer will outline what the Django community can
learn from the world of social activism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Eric Florenzano ignited a fever following his lightfooted and
lighthearted placement of a mirror in front of the hardest of the
hardcore in the django community with his presentation, “Why Django
Sucks, and How We can Fix It.” Then, a year later, at DjangCon 2011,
Steve Holden grasped the self- critique baton with an even steeper
challenge, making a claim that he described as “the most outrageous
thing you can say” - that the Django documentation sucked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django documentation, already widely considered the best in its
class, has responded to the critique and continues to improve daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also widely viewed as a top strength of Django is its community. While
Django enjoys one of the most thoughtful, patient, and responsive
communities in the world of open source web frameworks, it has a special
opportunity for learning in Washington, D.C., where many of the most
successful and voracious non- profit advocacy organizations call home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will examine some of their tactics and compare them
with those employed by the Django community. Among the topics covered
will be mobilization of new troops, building and listening to diverse
coalitions, and identifying and reaching out to under-represented
populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presenter comes from a decade of experience in non-profit social
justice activism. Having been a Django user for 3.5 years and involved
in the community for 2, will be at only his second DjangoCon.. Freshly
imported, he has the perspective of a passionate newcomer rather a
seasoned veteran.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category></entry></feed>