<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 13:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Mediocre Programmer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/the-mediocre-programmer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mediocre Programmers? What is that? Shouldn't we want to be great
programmers instead? In this talk we'll discuss what it means to be a
mediocre programmer. We'll consider the many pitfalls that may befall
you on your journey, from self-doubt to burnout, and share tips for how
to cope with the challenges of programming and when it might be time to
try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is highlights from a book that I'm writing about the journey
of being a mediocre programmer. Beginners tend to get all of the love,
and advanced programmers get all of the respect and glory. But we don't
have much for helping intermediate programmers. We don't tend to
consider how difficult it can be to work through the exuberance of
beginning programming (where everything is new, fresh, and exciting)
into becoming better programmers. We're just expected to figure things
out on our own. This talk draws on my experiences of being a mediocre
programmer and gives advice and tips on how to become better
programmers. We'll cover how to find a group of traveling companions,
how to focus on learning one thing at a time, and how to deal with the
struggles of our emotions and self doubt. We'll also cover examining our
emotions and understanding when the spark that drew us to programming is
truly burned out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Maloney</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/the-mediocre-programmer.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Debugging with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2017/introduction-to-debugging-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since a moth was discovered in the Mark II computer we've dealt with bugs in software. This talk will show different methods for determining what the code is doing. We'll start with the lowly print statement and introduce advanced forms of logging. We'll also cover several Python debuggers and talk about best practices for debugging and preventing bugs in Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Maloney</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-30:pyohio-2017/introduction-to-debugging-with-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>