<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_christopher-lozinski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Lightning talks on Thursday, July 11</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/lightning-talks-on-thursday-july-11.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Petr Viktorin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/lightning-talks-on-thursday-july-11.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>ZODB: The Graph Database for PythonDevelopers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-pythondevelopers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-pythondevelopers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see the current version of the slides at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf"&gt;https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invite you to first watch the full but slightly earlier version of the
talk at PythonLinks.info/zodb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then read the following summary to see what else is being added to
the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ZODB is a mature graph database written in Python and optimized in
C. Just subclass off of class Persistent Object and Persistent
Container, and your objects, graphs and applications become persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market for Graph Databases has recently exploded, as evidenced by
over $200 Million invested in graph database companies. Most of the
graph databases are written in Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Python developer, you will find much greater productivity
using a graph database written in Python, than one written in statically
bound Java. You cannot add or remove an attribute to an object at
run-time in a statically typed language. Furthermore, the major Java
databases constrain you to one of several persistent data types.
Persistent Python, supported by the ZODB allows you to make any Python
data structure persistent. Publishing JSON, YAML and Pickles are well
supported. GraphQL is conceptually very close to the ZODB schema
approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the ZODB is interesting, but is it risky? The ZODB is mature, rock
solid and well supported. The ZODB is quite heavily used in the Plone
world. Just the government of Brazil has over 100 websites using the
ZODB. That includes the President's office, parliament and many other
governmet offices. Recently the ZODB has been reengineered. It now
supports thousands of write transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major applications of graph databases are fraud detection, social
networks and computer networks. NLP is an interesting application area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk reviews the basic concepts of traversal and views on objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to understand the basics of how objects are stored on
disk. Objects are pickled. There are multiple ways to store those
pickles. When using File Storage, the objects in a transaction are
appended to he end of the database files. When using relstorage, a
record is created with the object id, the version number, and the
pickle. The talk reviews how objects are distributed across multiple
Python processes. With ZEO the pickles are served across the network.
Connections are encrypted. The talk also discusses how to build
real-time (chat and iOT) applications using the MQTT message broker with
the ZODB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance, scalability, and number of objects, are all discussed.
Comparisons are made to traditional relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ZODB Demo makes it very easy to start building your own applications
on top of the ZODB. You can start by customizing the TreeLeaf,
TreeBranch and TreeRoot classes and their templates. You get CRUD for
free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo includes traditional relational CRUD, Create, Read, Update, and
Delete. But it also includes the extended graph CRUD. Rename a Leaf or
Branch. Cut and paste leaves or branches, copy and paste leaves or
branches. View and restore historic versions are demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the real reason to use a graph database is to improve the user
experience. A basic concept in human factors is to limit lists to 7
items. That is why librarians use hierarchy. The Panama Papers
journalists said a graph database was more intuitive. Have you ever
selected your country from a list of 150 countries. Much better to use a
hierarchical list. Have you ever used a Google map with thousands of
pins. Much better to have one page for each city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course the most important reason for using a graph database is
not what the software does, but how it changes how we humans think about
our problems, and how we make decisions. Graph databases enable a
different approach to distributing applications across the network. They
encourage a different approach to managing the git development process.
They enable a different set of decisions to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, readers should have a much better appreciation
for the rich but little known and under appreciated ZODB ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Web"></category></entry><entry><title>The Best Python Videos - PythonLinks.info</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/the-best-python-videos-pythonlinksinfo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/the-best-python-videos-pythonlinksinfo.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="lightning talk"></category></entry><entry><title>ZODB: The Graph database for Python Developers.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ZODB is a mature graph database written in Python and optimized in
C. Just subclass off of class Persistent Object, and Persistent
Container, and your objects, graphs and applications become persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market for Graph Databases has recently exploded, as evidenced by
over $200Million invested in graph database companies. Most of the graph
databases are written in Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Python developer, you will find much greater productivity
using a graph database written in Python, than one written in statically
bound Java. The major Java databases constrain you to one of several
persistent data types. Persistent Python, supported by the ZODB allows
you to make any Python data structure persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new ZODB Demo makes it very easy to start building your own
applications on top of the ZODB. You can start by customizing the
TreeLeaf, TreeBranch and TreeRoot classes and their templates. You get
CRUD for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo includes traditional relational CRUD, Create, Read, Update, and
Delete. But it also includes the extended graph CRUD. Rename a Leaf or
Branch. Cut and paste leaves or branches, copy and paste leaves or
branches. The talk also demonstrates the soon-to-be released view
historic versions and restore a previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;You can watch the talk video here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;PythonLinks.info/zodb&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And see the slides here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf"&gt;https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="ZODB: The Graph database"></category></entry><entry><title>The ZODB Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/the-zodb-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T15:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T15:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/the-zodb-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZODB is an object-oriented database written in Python and optimized in C. It makes it so easy to build trees or graphs of persistent Python objects. Just subclass off of class Persistent, and your applications become persistent. It is heavily used in Pyramid and Plone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the ZODB database, presents important concepts, shows how to build a simple account object, and reviews the tools available.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="zodb"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning talks Thursday</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/lightning-talks-thursday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Viktor Stískala</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:pycon-cz-2017/lightning-talks-thursday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks Thursday&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Python and Poland Directories.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2017/python-and-poland-directories.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-24:pycon-fr-2017/python-and-poland-directories.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PythonLinks is the world's largest Python Directory.  Now that it includes a rapidly growing directory of Python companies organized by Region→Country→City-Company, along with their products, jobs, and links, such as the corporate blog, product reviews, and youtube videos, everyone really likes the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PolandTrade.info is a directory of information about international business with Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>ZODB Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2017/zodb-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-23:pycon-fr-2017/zodb-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZODB is an object-oriented database written in Python and optimized in C.This talk introduces the database, presents important concepts, and reviews the tools available.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2016-07-20</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/lightning-talks-2016-07-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-01:europython-2016/lightning-talks-2016-07-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various speakers - Lightning Talks
[EuroPython 2016]
[20 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks, presented by Harald Massa and Harry Percival&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher Lozinski - blogory.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Naranja &amp;amp; Maria Coetero - Random.random() online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petr Viktorin - PEPs 487 &amp;amp; 520 (*descriptors in 5 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anselm Linsnau - tuxcademy - Great training material - for free!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miroslav Pojman - PyOO - Control Open Office from Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fabio Pliger - Jupyterlab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plethora - Python meets Industry - Data Challenge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adam Castle - Ripe Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Florian Brühen - Crowdfunding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charlie Beeson - Running a Coding Cometition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pavlo  Andriychenko - Jupiter Tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry></feed>