<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_naomi-ceder.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>En verdad es más fácil pedir perdón que permiso</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2019/en-verdad-es-mas-facil-pedir-perdon-que-permiso.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-30:pycon-latam-2019/en-verdad-es-mas-facil-pedir-perdon-que-permiso.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Antipatterns for Inclusion</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-colombia-2018/antipatterns-for-inclusion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-09:pycon-colombia-2018/antipatterns-for-inclusion.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Interview Naomi Ceder</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-colombia-2018/interview-naomi-ceder.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-09:pycon-colombia-2018/interview-naomi-ceder.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Naomi Ceder</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-colombia-2018/naomi-ceder.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-09:pycon-colombia-2018/naomi-ceder.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="introduction"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: What lies ahead?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/keynote-what-lies-ahead.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-09:pylondinium-2018/keynote-what-lies-ahead.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copyright belongs to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Software Foundation Session</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/python-software-foundation-session.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/python-software-foundation-session.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python Software Foundation (PSF) is the organization behind Python
itself. It holds the IP rights, runs PyCon US and tries to help the
Python community world-wide to run events, user groups, workshops or
Python related programming projects by giving out grants. This year,
we’re again having a PSF Members meeting at EuroPython, where the PSF
reports on its activities, new plans and organizational changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting is open to everyone, so if you want to learn more about the
PSF activities, please join in.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Iteration Inside Out - Python's Iteration Protocol</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/iteration-inside-out-pythons-iteration-protocol.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/iteration-inside-out-pythons-iteration-protocol.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using for loops and list comprehensions in Python is basic and quite
common, right? But how does iteration in Python actually work “under the
hood”? The words “iterator” and “iterable” each occur over 500 times in
the Python documentation, but what does an iterator actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; , as
opposed to an iterable? And how do they do it? Learn the details as we
turn the iteration protocol inside out, with live coded demonstrations
along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will start from the way Python iterates of over a sequence, in
comparison with iterating by index, like C. The key point of iterating
over a sequence is that something needs to track which item in the
sequence is next, which is something that Python’s iteration protocol
manages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iterable section will demonstrate creating a simple object that
returns items by index (e.g., a fibonacci series), showing that
&lt;strong&gt;getitem&lt;/strong&gt; is really all you need for an iterable, since an iterator is
created for such objects when iterated upon. BUT, this doesn’t answer
the question of how Python keeps track of which item is next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iterator section answers that question by converting the iterable
just created to an iterator - adding &lt;strong&gt;iter&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;next&lt;/strong&gt; methods and
showing how the iterator saves state and essentially drives the
iteration protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an accurate understanding of iteration protocol will help
developing Pythonistas reason better about both iterating over existing
objects and creating their own iterables and iterators.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What lies ahead? Python’s future strengths and challenges</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/what-lies-ahead-pythons-future-strengths-and-challenges.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-09:pycon-cz-2017/what-lies-ahead-pythons-future-strengths-and-challenges.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does the future hold for Python and for our community? Both have
grown in ways we couldn’t have imagined years ago, but what lies
ahead? We will begin with a look at the history and growth Python and
our community and where we are today. Then we’ll consider some
possible trends and coming challenges as well as the strengths we
have to deal with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Come learn about the Python Software Foundation!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/come-learn-about-the-python-software-foundation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-23T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T15:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-23:pycon-es-2017/come-learn-about-the-python-software-foundation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PSF plays a key role in fostering the Python community around the world. Come find out what the PSF does (and doesn't do), how it works, how the PSF can support your community, and how you can be part of the PSF. We'll describe the membership model and how everyone can be a member, and many people can be voting members. We will also talk about the PSF Grants program, and answer any questions you might have. Everyone is welcome, both non-members and members! PSF stickers will also be available&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python software foundation"></category></entry><entry><title>Come for the language, stay for the community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/come-for-the-language-stay-for-the-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-23T09:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T09:30:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-23:pycon-es-2017/come-for-the-language-stay-for-the-community.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Obstáculos à Inclusão</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2016/keynote-obstaculos-a-inclusao.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-16:python-brasil-2016/keynote-obstaculos-a-inclusao.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote Naomi Ceder - Obstáculos à Inclusão, Por que só diversidade não é suficiente&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Anti-patterns for diversity</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2015/anti-patterns-for-diversity.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-17:pycon-pl-2015/anti-patterns-for-diversity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many years studies have shown that more diverse teams are more creative and flexible and produce better solutions. In addition both the demand for more tech talent and basic fairness also support increased diversity and inclusion. Just as there is no single easy way to write good code there is no single easy way to increase diversity. There are, however, several things that companies and organizations do which actually work against diversity. This talk will explore these anti-patterns for diversity, including uncritical belief in meritocracy, lack of understanding of the realities of marginalization, null processes, misunderstanding of “culture fit”, and an unwillingness to change, as well as some ways that teams, companies, and organizations might work to combat them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Confessions of a True Impostor (A Survival Guide)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2015/keynote-confessions-of-a-true-impostor-a-survival-guide.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-20:pycon-uk-2015/keynote-confessions-of-a-true-impostor-a-survival-guide.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk by: Naomi Ceder&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Antipatterns for Diversity</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/antipatterns-for-diversity.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-02:europython-2015/antipatterns-for-diversity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naomi Ceder - Antipatterns for Diversity
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop doing the same thing but expecting different results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developers we put considerable effort into optimisation. We are
always tinkering, trying to make things better, and striving to remove
antipatterns from our code and our development processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet for some reason we have not been as good at applying this spirit
of optimisation to the problem of increasing diversity, even though
most people these days agree that, like good tests, agile
methodologies, and virtual environments, diversity is a &amp;quot;good thing&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My position is that just as there is no single easy way to write good
code there is no single easy way to increasing diversity. There are,
however, several things that companies and organisations do which
actually work against diversity. This talk will explore these
antipatterns for diversity, including uncritical belief in
meritocracy, lack of understanding of the realities of
marginalisation, null processes, misunderstanding of &amp;quot;culture fit&amp;quot;,
and an unwillingness to change, as well as some ways that teams,
companies, and organisations might work to combat them.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Come for the Language, Stay for the Community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/come-for-the-language-stay-for-the-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/come-for-the-language-stay-for-the-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naomi Ceder - Come for the Language, Stay for the Community
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keynote-stay-for-the-community"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keynote-stay-for-the-community&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Python the language is wonderful, the Python community and the
personal, social, and professional benefits that flow from involvement
in a community like ours are often more compelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about the goals of the Python Software Foundation and how
everyone can take part to help build even better Python communities
locally, regionally, and globally.  I will also discuss some of our
strengths as a community, and also look at some of the challenges we
face going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a powerful and flexible tool that many of us love and use in
many ways. And yet, as wonderful as  the language is, many would say
that the community is even more attractive. This talk will focus on
involvement in the Python community and what that means - in
particular the many personal, social, and professional benefits that
flow from involvement in a community like ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also discuss what the Python Software Foundation does, what its
goals and purpose are, and how everyone in the community can take part
in the PSF to help build even better Python communities. This will
include specific explanations of the membership model and how active
contributors (both in terms of code and community organisation) can
and should become full voting members of the PSF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also touch on our strengths, like our commitment to safe and
inclusive spaces and our devotion to education, and also look at some
of the challenges we face as a community going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PSF Meeting</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/psf-meeting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-01:europython-2016/psf-meeting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naomi Ceder - PSF Meeting
[EuroPython 2016]
[20 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/psf-meeting-2016"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/psf-meeting-2016&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroPython Meeting of the Python Software Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members and non-members are invited to this EuroPython meeting of the
PSF! Please join us for some updates from the PSF board.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Antipatterns for Diversity</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/naomi-ceder-antipatterns-for-diversity-pycon-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-01:pycon-us-2016/naomi-ceder-antipatterns-for-diversity-pycon-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Naomi Ceder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as there is no single easy way to write good code there is no single easy way to increase diversity. There are, however, several things we (yes, even in the Python community) do which actually work against diversity. This talk will explore these anti-patterns for diversity,  as well as some ways that teams, companies, and organizations might work to combat them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Farewell and Welcome Home: Python in Two Genders</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/farewell-and-welcome-home-python-in-two-genders-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/farewell-and-welcome-home-python-in-two-genders-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After half a lifetime I transitioned from male to female while staying
involved in the Python community. This talk discusses that transition
and explores how I found life in Python as a woman different from my
former life as a man and the lessons about diversity I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After half a lifetime &amp;quot;undercover as a man&amp;quot; I transitioned from male to
female while staying involved in the Python community. This talk
discusses that transition and explores how I found life in Python as a
woman different from my former life as a man and the lessons about
diversity I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will include a brief discussion of what being transgender
means, my experiences as I came to terms with it, and the losses and
gains transition entailed. Early on I made the decision to be as open as
possible and to stay engaged in the Python community as I transitioned
and I will discuss why I made that decision and the levels of acceptance
and support I encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transition has been wonderfully successful, but that very transition put
me in a surprisingly different world. Now being part of not one, but at
least 3 groups that are minorities in the Python world gave me a very
different view of a community I thought I knew, and pushed me to being
an activist (or trouble maker) in spite of myself. In addition to the
many positives the Python community has offered me on my journey, I will
discuss the experiences that have made me understand that privilege is
very much alive and well in the Python world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Farewell and Welcome Home: Python in Two Genders</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/farewell-and-welcome-home-python-in-two-genders.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Naomi Ceder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-13:pycon-us-2014/farewell-and-welcome-home-python-in-two-genders.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After half a lifetime &amp;quot;undercover as a man&amp;quot; I transitioned from male to
female while staying involved in the Python community. This talk
discusses that transition and explores how I found life in Python as a
woman different from my former life as a man.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>