<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Charlie Marsh</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ruff: An Extremely Fast Python Linter and Code Formatter, Written in Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/ruff-an-extremely-fast-python-linter-and-code-formatter-written-in-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/astral-sh/ruff"&gt;Ruff&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely fast Python
linter and code formatter, written in Rust. With Ruff, projects can
replace dozens of static analysis tools with a single dependency, all
while executing 10x, 100x, or even 1000x faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, Ruff has grown to millions of downloads per month,
and now powers static analysis for the largest projects in the Python
ecosystem, including NumPy, Pandas, PyTorch, LangChain, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will open with a brief overview of Ruff’s functionality before
diving into its internals, with a focus on performance. In particular,
we’ll look to answer the question: &lt;strong&gt;what does it take to build a
developer tool that’s orders of magnitude faster than the
alternatives?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our exploration will be grounded in specific optimizations and design
decisions that make Ruff fast. Along the way, we’ll also explore the
broader tradeoffs that come with building developer tools for Python, in
Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Ruff is written in Rust, no Rust knowledge is required.
Instead, this talk is aimed at those interested in building performant
developer tools for any domain, in any language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charlie Marsh</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/ruff-an-extremely-fast-python-linter-and-code-formatter-written-in-rust.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Tread Lightly: Leave Shallower Footprints When Building and Testing Your Python Project (Sponsor: Fastly)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/tread-lightly-leave-shallower-footprints-when-building-and-testing-your-python-project-sponsor-fastly.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tread Lightly: Leave Shallower Footprints When Building and Testing Your
Python Project. Presented by Kevin P. Fleming, from Fastly &amp;amp; Charlie
Marsh, creator of Ruff and founder of Astral.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charlie Marsh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/tread-lightly-leave-shallower-footprints-when-building-and-testing-your-python-project-sponsor-fastly.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>