<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Samweli Mwakisambwe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_samweli-mwakisambwe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Open-source Python tools to visualize and analyse geospatial data.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/open-source-python-tools-to-visualize-and-analyse-geospatial-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Samweli Mwakisambwe</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-23:/djangocon-us-2024/open-source-python-tools-to-visualize-and-analyse-geospatial-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will provide an overview of the available Python related geospatial tools that can be used to analyze location data highlighting the possibilities and the potential of this attendees will be able to grasp what tools they can use to access particular location data.
Among the available&amp;nbsp;python …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will provide an overview of the available Python related geospatial tools that can be used to analyze location data highlighting the possibilities and the potential of this attendees will be able to grasp what tools they can use to access particular location data.
Among the available&amp;nbsp;python&amp;nbsp;geospatial tools we will discuss the main and most used in accessing location data types raster and vector, we will have a look at how these base tools can be used to access the types and their benefits.
We will then dive into one of the tools called QGIS and use it as an exemplar of how we can now interact, analyze, and visualize geospatial data in Python. A step-by-step guide on how to import and use QGIS features in Python.
QGIS is a freely downloadable open-source GIS software suite that contains a desktop option, mobile, and web components. QGIS version 3.14 was released with a Temporal Controller an interesting feature that allows immersive and creative visualization of time-based geospatial data.
Then we will see how QGIS can be used inside Django as a package. Showing how to achieve a link between the two tools.
At the end of the talk attendees should expect to have a comprehensive understanding of different Python geospatial tools, whether you are a developer or a professional learning new ways of technology, this talk will equip you with the knowledge on the right geospatial tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Python and PyQgis to make cool maps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/using-python-and-pyqgis-to-make-cool-maps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Samweli Mwakisambwe</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/using-python-and-pyqgis-to-make-cool-maps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;QGIS is a freely downloadable open source GIS software suite that
contains a desktop option, mobile, and web component. QGIS is free to
download and use, it is released with a GPL v3 license which is a non
commercial license allowing users to download and use it without
concerns …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;QGIS is a freely downloadable open source GIS software suite that
contains a desktop option, mobile, and web component. QGIS is free to
download and use, it is released with a GPL v3 license which is a non
commercial license allowing users to download and use it without
concerns compared to other commercial GIS software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QGIS core support in creating different types of maps, thanks to the
recent features updates QGIS version 3.14 was released with a Temporal
Controller feature that is responsible for handling all the temporal
layers inside QGIS. Temporal support was added in the core part of QGIS
hence users can now easily create animation maps from temporal location
datasets inside QGIS without any additional plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QGIS has scripting support using Python language, it also allows
enhancement to its functionality through plugins that are written using
Python language. This usage of the Python language in QGIS (PyQgis) is
achieved by using SIP and PyQt. Through the bindings QGIS has exposed
its core functionality via PyQgis API that can be used to create
standalone python applications that can use QGIS features in making
maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this talk will be to showcase how one could use Python and
QGIS to build map animations from temporal location data using the QGIS
Temporal Controller Python API. The session will also provide a guide on
PyQgis Temporal API, python scripting inside QGIS, how to build
standalone python applications and how to create QGIS python plugins
that can help in making maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is aimed at Python geospatial programmers and anyone looking to
learn how to use open source tools in analyzing location data. Expecting
to raise the participant's awareness and value about the work done and
on the open source tools used in the geospatial field.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry></feed>