<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_carol-willing.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Carol Willing: Keynote</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/carol-willing-keynote.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-05:pydata-la-2019/carol-willing-keynote.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.pydata.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData is an educational program of NumFOCUS, a 501(c)3 non-profit organization in the United States. PyData provides a forum for the international community of users and developers of data analysis tools to share ideas and learn from each other. The global PyData network promotes discussion of best practices, new approaches, and emerging technologies for data management, processing, analytics, and visualization. PyData communities approach data science using many languages, including (but not limited to) Python, Julia, and R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyData conferences aim to be accessible and community-driven, with novice to advanced level presentations. PyData tutorials and talks bring attendees the latest project features along with cutting-edge use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Jupyter: Always Open for Learning and Discovery</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/jupyter-always-open-for-learning-and-discovery.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/jupyter-always-open-for-learning-and-discovery.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Steering Council - Keynote - PyCon 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/python-steering-council-keynote-pycon-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Barry Warsaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-us-2019/python-steering-council-keynote-pycon-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python Steering Council Keynote panel&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category><category term="steering council"></category><category term="panel"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Sharing, by Carol Willing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2018/keynote-sharing-by-carol-willing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-ar-2018/keynote-sharing-by-carol-willing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote presented on Saturday in the PyCon Argentina 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>JupyterLab and JupyterHub - Perfect Together</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/jupyterlab-and-jupyterhub-perfect-together.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/jupyterlab-and-jupyterhub-perfect-together.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Practical Sphinx</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/practical-sphinx.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/practical-sphinx.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each member of your project team uses something different to document
their work -- RestructuredText, Markdown, and Jupyter Notebooks. How do
you combine all of these into useful documentation for your project's users.
Sphinx and friends to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to integrate documentation into your everyday development
workflow, apply best practices, and use modern development tools and
services, like Travis CI and ReadTheDocs, to create engaging and up-to-date
documentation which users and contributors will love.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="documentation"></category><category term="sphinx"></category><category term="readthedocs"></category></entry><entry><title>STEAM Workshops using Jupyter Notebooks, JupyterHub, and Binder</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/steam-workshops-using-jupyter-notebooks-jupyterhub-and-binder.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/steam-workshops-using-jupyter-notebooks-jupyterhub-and-binder.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Middle School and High School students can learn by doing. Jupyter Notebooks and the rich Python ecosystem with libraries on a variety of topics can engage many learners of the sciences and humanities. Interactive content, using Jupyter Widgets and visualization libraries, put the student in charge of manipulating content and extending their learning. Giving students engaging content in familiar subjects encourages them to develop and use computational skills to build upon their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difficulty of teaching workshops is access to computers and the ability to install software on those systems. This talk will demonstrate how a workshop organizer or teacher can deploy JupyterHub easily for a class using the Zero to JupyterHub Guide, Kubernetes, and Cloud Services. Even if students only have access to smartphones, tablets, or shared computers, a workshop can be held using Binder which allows a notebook environment to be served at the click of a button to any modern web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="jupyter notebook"></category><category term="jupyterhub"></category><category term="binder"></category></entry><entry><title>Panel Discussion The Ethics and Politics of Programming</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/panel-discussion-the-ethics-and-politics-of-programming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-28T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T12:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-28:pycon-uk-2017/panel-discussion-the-ethics-and-politics-of-programming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a panel of four experts answering pre-submitted questions from the assembled audience under the guidance of a chairperson. Audience participation will be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fake news on social media, dragnet collection of personal data, being asked to write code for the benefit of your employers but that's not necessarily helpful for your users, using big data to analyse the behaviour of users, government control of the internet, violations of FLOSS licenced code. These subjects and more like them are ripe for discussion in this panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think &amp;quot;Question Time&amp;quot; on BBC1 at 10:30pm on a Thursday and you have a pretty good idea of what it will be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Willing&lt;/strong&gt; (CHAIR)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol Willing is a Python Software Foundation Fellow and former Director, a core developer for CPython and Project Jupyter, and a Research Software Engineer at Cal Poly San Luis Obispo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She's also Geek-In-Residence at Fab Lab San Diego and co-organizes PyLadies San Diego and San Diego Python. Combining a love of nature, the arts, and math with a BSE in Electrical Engineering from Duke and an MS in Management from MIT, she's enjoyed creating and teaching others for over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anwesha Das&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anwesha Das, is an Advocate practicing law for 7 years. She is an active user of FOSS technologies. She is the Organizer of PyLadies Pune. She maintains her blog at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anweshadas.in/"&gt;https://anweshadas.in/&lt;/a&gt;. One of her major goals is to help FOSS developers with the legal aspects of the software industry. She currently also blogs for the Python Software Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irina Bolychevsky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irina is passionate about products and using technology to make things better. She spent many years working on open data at Open Knowledge (as one of the directors and ckan product owner), at web startups, and recently as a data consultant for W3C, Open Data Institute and the UK and Dubai governments. She co-founded redecentralize.org — a project to promote and bring together people working on and interested in decentralised digital technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Miller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the only known biography of David Miller he is, &amp;quot;Human, frequently fascinated. Digital, Health with &amp;#64;ohcuk &amp;amp; friends.&amp;quot; He also happens to have a background in philosophy and an interest in ethical and political matters arising in the digital world. He's a founder of the NHS Hackday and runs Open Healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniele Procida&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniele works for Divio where he helps make Python/Django easier to deploy on the web. He is a member of the Django core team and the Django Software Foundation board, trying to contribute back to open source software and its communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Taming Big Data with Jupyter and Friends</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/taming-big-data-with-jupyter-and-friends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-02:pydata-meetups/taming-big-data-with-jupyter-and-friends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This month, we are excited to host Carol Willing who will be discussing the Jupyter eco-sytem.  Carol develops software, electronics, educational tutorials, and is passionate about outreach.  She is a core developer on the Jupyter Project and is a former director at the Python Software foundation.  She continues to contribute her time to OpenHatch, Systers, PyLadies San Diego, and San Diego Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="jupyter"></category></entry><entry><title>JupyterHub: A "things explainer overview"</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/jupyterhub-a-things-explainer-overview.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-16:pydata-carolinas-2016/jupyterhub-a-things-explainer-overview.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With JupyterHub you can create a multi-user Hub which spawns, manages,
and proxies multiple instances of the single-user Jupyter notebook
(IPython notebook) server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JupyterHub provides single-user notebook servers to many users. For
example, JupyterHub could serve notebooks to a class of students, a
corporate workgroup, or a science research group.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Data, Decision Making, and Being Human</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/keynote-data-decision-making-and-being-human.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/keynote-data-decision-making-and-being-human.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our precious data. We are collecting more than ever before. Today,
we're analyzing large amounts. The results tell a story and imply
truth. In our rush to validate our beliefs, we often experience “Data
Fail”. Want to make a lasting impact on others while building your own
skills? Share your lessons from failure and be a mentor. You may be
surprised by your impact on humanity .&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding Your Groove: Contributing to CPython and Beyond</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/finding-your-groove-contributing-to-cpython-and.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carol Willing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-11:pycon-us-2015/finding-your-groove-contributing-to-cpython-and.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you hear a jumble of jargony noise when reading Python mailing lists?
Do you silently edit your dotfiles and playlists to avoid asking
questions on IRC? Come see how Jazz can help you understand and
contribute to Python. While both seem vast and complex, they build on
simple concepts. By mixing art, knowledge, and improv, you can find your
CPython contribution groove and enjoy cool cats' music.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>