<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tathagata Dasgupta</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tathagata-dasgupta.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A Bug's Life</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/a-bugs-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tathagata Dasgupta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-26:/pyohio-2025/a-bugs-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A beginner friendly talk that goes from the manifestation of a bug in
production, traces it all the way to its inception, and asks what other
than code needs to change to ship faster and NOT break things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We open with the support rotation pager going off as customers …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A beginner friendly talk that goes from the manifestation of a bug in
production, traces it all the way to its inception, and asks what other
than code needs to change to ship faster and NOT break things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We open with the support rotation pager going off as customers of a low
latency realtime system report an outage. With every second of downtime
resulting in revenue loss, it is all hands on deck for the site
reliability team, Dev team, data team, product owners are peeling down
the stack. We will see the to the commit messages in polyglot systems
that caused the failure, the bug getting squashed, hotfix getting
shipped and crisis is averted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut to the blameless postmortem - the real life challenges of issue
resolution that is more than changing lines in code, debugging
workflows, monitoring gaps, testing limitations, navigating change
management processes, team dynamics. for each of these pillars we will
see what allowed the teams to shift left, and shorten a bug's lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;What does the audience get out of it:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Modern software deployments are complex and dynamic ecosystems, an
ideal breeding ground for bugs. In a way, the lifecycle of a bug,
reveals the truth about the software development lifecycle of a
product.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk takes learnings from multiple real life outages and tries to
condense it as a shift-left journey by Continuous Questioning how can
we catch bugs in lower environments.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2025"></category></entry></feed>