<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Marlene Mhangami</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/diversity-inclusion-in-the-python-community-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel - presented by Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Naomi Ceder, Nabanita Roy &amp;amp; Iqbal Abdullah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come meet some of the folks working on Diversity and Inclusion in the global Python Community!
Join the live panel discussion to hear about the challenges and the work they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Marlene Mhangami, Nabanita Roy, Iqbal Abdullah, Tereza Iofciu. Chaired by Naomi Ceder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tereza Iofciu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/diversity-inclusion-in-the-python-community-panel.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Elephants, ibises and a more Pythonic way to work with databases</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/elephants-ibises-and-a-more-pythonic-way-to-work-with-databases.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Elephants, ibises and a more Pythonic way to work with databases - presented by Marlene Mhangami&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was working on setting up a relational database to explore records from DataSF’s Civic Art Collection. Whenever I attend a tech conference I try to spend a day or two in the city to check out its cultural scene, so this seemed like useful information! I decided to use MySQL as my database engine. Coming from a Pandas background I was surprised by how unproductive and restricted I felt writing raw SQL queries. I also spent a significant amount of time resolving errors in queries that worked with one flavor of SQL but failed with MySQL. Throughout the process, I kept thinking to myself if only there was a more Pythonic way!!! A few weeks later I was introduced to Ibis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in Zimbabwe and the first thing that pops into my mind when I think of the word ibis is a safari. One of my favorite things to do when I'm not working is to go on a game drive. Whenever I've been adventuring on safari I usually see ibises perched on top of an elephant. The contrast between the creatures is stark! The African Sacred Ibis is a small, elegant creature that's named after the ancient Egyptian god Thoth. While as many of us know, an elephant is a very big and complex animal. This image serves as a great metaphor for the Python package and how it interacts with big database engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ibis allows you to write intuitive Python code and have that code be translated into SQL. Whether you’re wanting to interact with SQL databases or wanting to use distributed DBMSs, Ibis lets you do this in Python. You can think of the python code as the less complex elegant layer sitting on top of any big data engine of your choice. At the moment, Ibis supports quite a few backends including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional DBMSs: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite Analytical DBMSs: OmniSciDB, ClickHouse, Datafusion Distributed DBMSs: Impala, PySpark, BigQuery In memory analytics: pandas and Dask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything you can write in an SQL select statement you can write in Ibis. You can carry out joins, filters, and other operations on your data in a familiar, Pandas-like syntax. In this talk, we'll go through several examples of these and compare what the SQL code would look like versus writing to the database with Ibis. Overall, using Ibis simplifies your workflows, makes you more productive, and keeps your code readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/elephants-ibises-and-a-more-pythonic-way-to-work-with-databases.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Worldwide Python Communities: Learn From Organizers in Zimbabwe, Indonesia, and South Korea</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2021/worldwide-python-communities-learn-from-organizers-in-zimbabwe-indonesia-and-south-korea.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;COVID has changed the landscape of in-person events, resulting in cancelled meetups, conferences, and workshops all over the world. Despite the cancellations, the Python community has continued to meet, grow, and learn together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join this interactive session to learn from community organizers based in three counties: Zimbabwe, Indonesia, and South Korea to hear about how COVID has impacted their communities, and what they’ve done to continue to foster a local Python community in spite of quarantines and cancellations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.com/pycascades-2021/talk/SYDH97/"&gt;https://pretalx.com/pycascades-2021/talk/SYDH97/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After three amazing in-person conferences, this time we're moving PyCascades online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCascades is a regional PyCon in the Pacific Northwest, celebrating the west coast Python developer and user community. Our organizing team includes members of the Vancouver, Seattle, and Portland Python user groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos are released as CC BY-NC-SA 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pycascades #pycon #python #conference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Feb 20 13:55:00 2021 at Interactive Track&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dan Mouris</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-02-20:/pycascades-2021/worldwide-python-communities-learn-from-organizers-in-zimbabwe-indonesia-and-south-korea.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2021</category><category>#pycascades#pycon#python#conference</category><category>pycascades</category><category>pycascades2021</category></item><item><title>Meet &amp; Greet with PSF D&amp;I workgroup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2022/meet-greet-with-psf-di-workgroup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Débora Azevedo, Sayantika Banik, Georgi Ker) Python has become one of the most popular programming languages in the world, meaning that along with this growth the Python community has continued to expand, in every continent around the globe. While this growth has been exciting, it has also brought new challenges and opportunities to improve our global community. Through this panel, we would like to address those challenges and understand our community better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tereza Iofciu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-02-06:/pycascades-2022/meet-greet-with-psf-di-workgroup.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2022</category></item><item><title>A Beginners Guide to GPUs for Pythonistas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/a-beginners-guide-to-gpus-for-pythonistas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Marlene Mhangami) In this talk, I will be discussing Python and GPUs! I will give a brief history of Python and parallel computing, take a look at Python’s ‘infamous’ GIL, and share how and why Pythonistas can get started with using GPUs to do more work faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/8EKEQS/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/8EKEQS/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 15:00:00 2021 at Science, Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/a-beginners-guide-to-gpus-for-pythonistas.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2021</category><category>MarleneMhangami</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2021</category></item><item><title>ZimboPy: Empowering Zimbabwean Girls As Change Makers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZimboPy is an organic, on-the-ground effort by a local non-profit
organization and Python developers in the Harare software development
community to advance the cause of women in technology in Zimbabwe. The
program operates in community centers, universities, high schools and
tech hubs to make programming accessible to girls regardless of their
socio-economic status. Upon initially joining a ZimboPy club, many of
the girls would have never used a computer before, let alone code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Zimbabwe, only 17% of computer science undergraduate majors are
women, and in the developing world, women make up less than 20% of the
information and technology workforce. ZimboPy exists to empower
Zimbabwean girls with the skills and confidence necessary to not only
enter the local tech industry, but to lead it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to learning to code, ZimboPy club members also join a global
network of women in technology that are working to tackle social
challenges through human-centered design and computer science. ZimboPy’s
mentorship program invites experienced women developers, mainly from the
United States and Europe, to help Zimbabwean girls address local
problems which can be solved with technology, such as clean water and
e-commerce solutions for small shops in towns and villages. Mentors will
travel to Zimbabwe and work with girls as they develop a plan for their
applications and pair-program with them, answering questions and
providing feedback along the way. To ensure that the girls are
successful, mentors will continue to work with their groups even after
leaving the country through weekly video conferences and email feedback.
Overall, ZimboPy looks forward to changing Zimbabwe’s future through
creativity, collaboration and the power of Python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:/pycon-italia-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2017</category><category>internationalization</category><category>School</category><category>Learning</category><category>problem solving</category></item><item><title>Diversity Panel: experience and discussion from all over the world</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion table about Diversity in all its hues with organizers and
experts from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:/pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2017</category><category>diversity</category><category>panel</category></item><item><title>Marlene Mhangami - The Growth of the Python Community in Africa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-nigeria-2017/marlene-mhangami-the-growth-of-the-python-community-in-africa.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-15:/pycon-nigeria-2017/marlene-mhangami-the-growth-of-the-python-community-in-africa.html</guid><category>PyCon Nigeria 2017</category></item><item><title>Leadership and Identity in the Pan African Python movement</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/leadership-and-identity-in-the-pan-african-python-movement.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will be discussing three lessons about leadership that I learned during my time chairing Pycon Africa 2019. I will also be sharing how personal and group identity played a consistent and significant role throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-14:/pycon-uk-2019/leadership-and-identity-in-the-pan-african-python-movement.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2019</category></item><item><title>Leadership and Identity in the Pan-African Python movement</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2020/leadership-and-identity-in-the-pan-african-python-movement.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-04-17:/pycon-us-2020/leadership-and-identity-in-the-pan-african-python-movement.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2020</category></item><item><title>Diversity and Inclusion Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/diversity-and-inclusion-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity and Inclusion Panel&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Débora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/diversity-and-inclusion-panel.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Friday Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/friday-lightning-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friday Lightning Talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bruce Merry: &amp;quot;asyncio: it's all about the cancellation&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simba Nyatsanga: &amp;quot;Keep you friends close and caches closer&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter van Onselen: &amp;quot;And now for something completely different&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simon Cross: &amp;quot;Python Software Society of South Africa&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whitney Tennant: &amp;quot;Why I kept flying to Cape Town for sammiches&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew French: &amp;quot;Grid computing on a budget (Or: Reinventing celery)&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marlene Mhangami: &amp;quot;The PSF and Python in Africa&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pi Delport</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:/pycon-za-2017/friday-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>PyCon ZA 2017</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>ZimboPy: Empowering Zimbabwean Girls As Change Makers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZimboPy is an organic, on-the-ground effort by a local non-profit
organization and Python developers in the Harare software development
community to advance the cause of women in technology in Zimbabwe. The
program operates in community centers, universities, high schools and
tech hubs to make programming accessible to girls regardless of their
socio-economic status. Upon initially joining a ZimboPy club, many of
the girls would have never used a computer before, let alone code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Zimbabwe, only 17% of computer science undergraduate majors are
women, and in the developing world, women make up less than 20% of the
information and technology workforce. ZimboPy exists to empower
Zimbabwean girls with the skills and confidence necessary to not only
enter the local tech industry, but to lead it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to learning to code, ZimboPy club members also join a global
network of women in technology that are working to tackle social
challenges through human-centered design and computer science.The Python
community has been a central part of our work. For our mentorship week
that was held in April we had python programmers from USA, Italy,
Australia and of course Zimbabwe join us in person and virtually. Our
talk will outline what we've achieved so far and how anyone who's part
of the Python community can get involved. We invite developers from
around the world to help Zimbabwean girls address local problems which
can be solved with technology, such as clean water and e-commerce
solutions for small shops in towns and villages. Mentors can travel to
Zimbabwe and work with girls as they develop a plan for their
applications and pair-program with them, answering questions and
providing feedback along the way. Overall, ZimboPy looks forward to
changing Zimbabwe's future through creativity, collaboration and the
power of Python programming&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-05:/pycon-za-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</guid><category>PyCon ZA 2017</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Transcendence: The Power of Representation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-transcendence-the-power-of-representation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover representation in tech. It will have some code examples in it that show diversity statistics at some big tech companies and look at how these can affect women currently in the industry and women looking to join. I will share my own experiences being a woman in the Python community and how representation has helped and hurt in my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-transcendence-the-power-of-representation.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item></channel></rss>