<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Dan Snow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dan-snow.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Open Source Property Assessment: Tidymodels to Allocate $16B in Property Taxes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/open-source-property-assessment-tidymodels-to-allocate-16b-in-property-taxes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicole Jardine</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/open-source-property-assessment-tidymodels-to-allocate-16b-in-property-taxes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How the Cook County Assessor's Office uses R and tidymodels for its residential property valuation models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cook County Assessor's Office (CCAO) determines the current market value of properties for the purpose of property taxation. Since 2020, the CCAO has used R, tidymodels, and LightGBM to build predictive models …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How the Cook County Assessor's Office uses R and tidymodels for its residential property valuation models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cook County Assessor's Office (CCAO) determines the current market value of properties for the purpose of property taxation. Since 2020, the CCAO has used R, tidymodels, and LightGBM to build predictive models that value Cook County's 1.5 million residential properties, which are collectively worth over $400B. These predictive models are open-source, easily replicable, and have significantly improved valuation accuracy and equity over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join CCAO Chief Data Officer Nicole Jardine and Director of Data Science Dan Snow as they walk through the CCAO's modeling process, shares lessons learned, and offer a sneak peek at changes planned for the 2024 reassessment of Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ccao-data"&gt;https://github.com/ccao-data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>