<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - lil anonymous</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creating the Next Generations of Billionaires - Part 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/creating-the-next-generations-of-billionaires-part-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teaching the Next Generation of Computer Trillionaires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our generation of young people in school (aged 5-18) have noticed the connection between Computer pRogramming, Technology, Success and Billionaires. On mass they are clamouring to master the skill of Computer pRogramming. It  has been dubbed the ‘4th’ R’ (computer pRogramming) along with Reading, wRiting and aRithmetic. So, governments worldwide have launched initiatives to have it taught in schools from Kindergarten to all the way to high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do we best teach and motivate the next generation in acquiring this skill?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe a successful working model for the teaching of Computer pRogamming. We have been building upon this model for a couple of years now.  Last year at EuroPython 2019 in Basel, we spoke about this subject and this year we would like to share more findings with the Python community about what we are learning about the teaching of Computer Programming to children and young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will describe a case study whereby computer programming (Python) was introduced to a group of 110 young people from the ages of 11 to 18, in a U.K secondary school. The talk will include descriptions of the various teaching methodologies &amp;amp; the outcomes; &amp;amp; the challenges involved. The talk will conclude with helpful suggestions, on how to proceed in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">lil anonymous</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/creating-the-next-generations-of-billionaires-part-2.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Education</category><category>General</category><category>Python 3</category><category>Science</category><category>Teaching</category></item><item><title>Taking Part in the Greatest Experiment in History</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/taking-part-in-the-greatest-experiment-in-history.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lockdown Online Education for Children with Python Programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few weeks, one of the largest and most exciting experiments in the history of mankind has taken place, with over  900 million children in over 190 countries being the recipients of online (virtual) education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in one corner of the globe in a high school in the UK,  Python Programming lessons in an entirely online medium were delivered for the 1st time as opposed to the then normal face-to-face mode of delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will see in this poster how the teaching of Python Programming in this online fashion was both delivered and received, for a group of children aged 11-14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss how great efforts were made to ensure that the online sessions were fit-for-purpose, educational and at the same time exciting and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss how we discovered the pleasant surprises and advantages of teaching on an online forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will look at some of the  Python Programs, such as currency converters, modelling graphs using libraries, random password generaters, etc. produced by the children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, it was a surprisingly pleasant experience for all concerned (i.e educators, students, parents, etc.) and we believe going forward the education system should also seriously  incorporate this medium of online learning, not just for adults but also for children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">lil anonymous</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/taking-part-in-the-greatest-experiment-in-history.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Education</category></item></channel></rss>