<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nicolas Hug</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nicolas-hug.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Collaborative filtering for recommendation systems in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyparis-2017/collaborative-filtering-for-recommendation-systems-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Hug</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-12:/pyparis-2017/collaborative-filtering-for-recommendation-systems-in-python.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will present the topic of recommendation systems. We
will focus on two popular approaches: neighborhood-based methods and
matrix- factorization based techniques. We will also present Surprise,
an open source Python package for easily building and analyzing
recommendation algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyParis 2017"></category></entry><entry><title>Accelerating Explorations in Vision and Multimodal AI Using Pytorch Libraries</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2023/accelerating-explorations-in-vision-and-multimodal-ai-using-pytorch-libraries.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Hug</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/pytorch-conference-2023/accelerating-explorations-in-vision-and-multimodal-ai-using-pytorch-libraries.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyTorch Libraries provide building blocks (data processing transforms, modeling components, loss functions, etc.) on top of PyTorch as well as examples and tutorials on how to use these building blocks for training SoTA Models. In this talk, we’ll provide insights into ongoing work to accelerate exploration in multimodal …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyTorch Libraries provide building blocks (data processing transforms, modeling components, loss functions, etc.) on top of PyTorch as well as examples and tutorials on how to use these building blocks for training SoTA Models. In this talk, we’ll provide insights into ongoing work to accelerate exploration in multimodal understanding and generative AI using TorchMultimodal. We'll also present TorchVision's new transforms API, with added support for image detection, segmentation, and video tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Implementing and Using Iterable Datasets: What Could Go Wrong?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/implementing-and-using-iterable-datasets-what-could-go-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Hug</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/implementing-and-using-iterable-datasets-what-could-go-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyTorch supports two kinds of datasets: Iterable datasets and indexable &amp;quot;map-style&amp;quot; datasets. Iterable datasets can be more flexible and potentially faster than their indexable cousins. They are also much harder to use correctly, and can easily lead to silently wrong results. This talk is a quick and fun intro …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyTorch supports two kinds of datasets: Iterable datasets and indexable &amp;quot;map-style&amp;quot; datasets. Iterable datasets can be more flexible and potentially faster than their indexable cousins. They are also much harder to use correctly, and can easily lead to silently wrong results. This talk is a quick and fun intro to some of the traps that Iterable datasets lay out for you, with some tips to help you avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category><category term="Lightning Talk"></category></entry><entry><title>TorchCodec: The Media Decoding Library for PyTorch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-day-2025/torchcodec-the-media-decoding-library-for-pytorch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Hug</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-07:/pytorch-day-2025/torchcodec-the-media-decoding-library-for-pytorch.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyTorch Day 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Fast Gradient Boosting Decision Trees with PyGBM and Numba</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/fast-gradient-boosting-decision-trees-with-pygbm-and-numba.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolas Hug</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/scipy-2019/fast-gradient-boosting-decision-trees-with-pygbm-and-numba.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a high predictive power and a low tendency to overfit, Gradient Boosting Decision Trees (GBDT) are very popular, and they are often used in winning solutions to machine learning competitions, as well as industry applications. After presenting Gradient Boosting as a special kind of gradient descent, we will …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a high predictive power and a low tendency to overfit, Gradient Boosting Decision Trees (GBDT) are very popular, and they are often used in winning solutions to machine learning competitions, as well as industry applications. After presenting Gradient Boosting as a special kind of gradient descent, we will describe various tricks and techniques that can speed up a GBDT implementation by multiple orders of magnitude. We will also present PyGBM, a fast pure-Python implementation of GBDTs inspired by LightGBM, that leverages Numba's JIT compilation. We will also provide feedback about our extensive use of Numba.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2019"></category></entry></feed>