<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ginga: an open-source astronomical image viewer and toolkit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/ginga-an-open-source-astronomical-image-viewer-a-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ginga is a new astronomical image viewer written in python. It uses and
inter-operates with several key scientific python packages: numpy,
pyfits, and scipy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authors: Jeschke, Eric, Subaru Telescope, National Astronomical
Observatory of Japan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: Astronomy and Astrophysics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ginga is a new astronomical image viewer written in python. It uses and
inter-operates with several key scientific python packages: numpy,
pyfits, and scipy. A key differentiator for this image viewer, compared
to older-generation FITS viewers, is that all the key components are
written as python classes, allowing for the first time a powerful FITS
image display widget to be directly embedded in, and tightly coupled
with, python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We call Ginga a toolkit for programming FITS viewers because it includes
a choice of base classes for programming custom viewers for two
different modern widget sets: Gtk and Qt, available on the three common
desktop platforms. In addition, a reference viewer is included with the
source code based on a plugin architecture in which the viewer can be
extended with plugins scripted in python. The code is released under a
BSD license similar to other major python packages and is available on
github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ginga has been introduced only recently as a tool to the astronomical
community, but since SciPy has a developer focus this talk concentrates
on programming with the Ginga toolkit. We cover two cases: using the
bare image widget to build custom viewers and writing plugins for the
existing full-featured Ginga viewer. The talk may be of interest to
anyone developing code in python needing to display scientific image
(CCD or CMOS) data and astronomers interested in python-based quick look
and analysis tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Jeschke</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-01:scipy-2013/ginga-an-open-source-astronomical-image-viewer-a-0.html</guid><category>astronomy</category><category>astrophysics</category><category>ginga</category></item><item><title>Enhancements to Ginga: an Astronomical Image Viewer and Toolkit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/enhancements-to-ginga-an-astronomical-image-view.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We describe recent developments in the Ginga package, a open-source
astronomical image viewer and toolkit written in python and hosted on
Github. The package was introduced to the scientific python community at
SciPy 2013 and has received a number of enhancements since then based on
user feedback. The talk includes an image mosaicing demo of a wide-field
camera exposure with 116 4Kx2K CCDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ginga is an open-source astronomical image viewer and toolkit written in
python and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ejeschke/ginga"&gt;hosted on Github&lt;/a&gt;. It
uses and inter-operates with several key scientific python packages:
numpy, scipy, astropy and matplotlib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk/poster we describe and illustrate recent enhancements to
the package since the introductory talk at SciPy 2013, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modular/pluggable interfaces for world coordinate systems, image file
I/O and star and image catalogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for rendering into matplotlib figures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for image mosaicing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for image overlays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;customizable user-interface bindings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self contained Mac OS X packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the talk we will demonstrate the mosaicing plugin that is being
used with several instruments at Subaru Telescope in Hawaii, including
the new Hyper Suprime-Cam wide-field camera with 116 separate 4Kx2K
CCDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk/poster may be of interest to anyone developing code in python
needing to display scientific image (CCD or CMOS) data and astronomers
interested in python-based quick look and analysis tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Jeschke</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/enhancements-to-ginga-an-astronomical-image-view.html</guid><category>astronomy</category></item></channel></rss>