<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Public Python for the greater good</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/public-python-for-the-greater-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code4sa.org/"&gt;Code For South Africa&lt;/a&gt; use technology to
facilitate promoting informed decision making for positive social
change. This can mean generally being aware of what's going on, as well
as deep critical research and analysis. We run the civic tech movement
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codebridge.org.za"&gt;{code}bridge&lt;/a&gt; where people come and hack
together or on their lonesome on civic tech projects. A quick summary
will be given of some outputs of this community in Cape Town and
Ethekwini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll summarise some work we've done using mostly common python tools
for the good of South African society. In particular I'll show how I've
scraped and mirrored a government website on a tight budget at
{code}bridge for better access to public information and seen usage pick
up right after the local elections. We'll also show how a little bit of
tech can empower citizens to hold government to account, and participate
in the governing and development of our infrastructure. How presumably
boring government notices really come to life when made accessible and
personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at anyone keen on making a big impact with a little
bit of tech, and interested in improving lives. There are many low
hanging fruit out there where lives can be improved with technology
facilitating the necessary groundwork. I'd like to show you how easy it
is to make an impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a heavily revised version of a talk given at DebConf 2016 with
several new projects matured or launched since.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">JD Bothma</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/public-python-for-the-greater-good.html</guid></item><item><title>Making man-made medicine price data more useful</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/making-man-made-medicine-price-data-more-useful.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A walk-through of how we practically clean and use a public dataset
that is changing people's lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mpr.gov.za/"&gt;Medicine Price Registry&lt;/a&gt; is a spreadsheet
published one or more times per year, with the latest prices and active
ingredients for medicines registered for sale in South Africa. Like most
data, it's dirty and has limited usability in its original form. We take
you through some of the practical steps we take to clean the data and
make it easier to analyse and use. This allows us, for example, to
analyse how price competition from generics lower medicine prices, or
not!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is intended as a simple real-world example of how we work around
the issues with a dataset using a few common tools. This could be done
with any platform, but jupyter notebooks, sqlalchemy, alembic migrations
and the brevity of python is a nice combination for the iteration needed
to work with this data and adapt as we get to know it. We start with a
GUI tool called OpenRefine but it pretty quickly becomes necessary to
write just a bit of code to move quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of material out there on specific tools. I'd like to show
the reality of dirty datasets, and the workarounds and approaches we use
to get value from it nonetheless. One such example is using charts and
ordering to group related data and visually identify interesting events.
I encourage people to ask questions and offer suggestions. The effort
put into this project has been limited by time constraints but any
improvements can have real world impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in trying something like this yourself, you're
invited to chat with me about civic technology, perhaps join our civic
tech community, and help figure out how it can be most effective. You
may also be interested in the CodeBridge Community Evening Thursday 5
October at 18:30.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">JD Bothma</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-05:pycon-za-2017/making-man-made-medicine-price-data-more-useful.html</guid></item></channel></rss>