<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python Powered Restful API Basics with Web2py</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2016/python-powered-restful-api-basics-with-web2py.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web2py's rapid prototyping capabilities can be leveraged to bootstrap quickly through initial prototypes into full production environments. RESTful API construction can be a powerful developer tool to modularizing applications for maintenance and optimization. Basics of RESTful API design and implementation will be covered with a case study tutorial. Concepts will be expanded upon to leverage built in web2py functionality for rapid prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Graves</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-07:depy-2016/python-powered-restful-api-basics-with-web2py.html</guid></item><item><title>Maximum Viable Integrity with web2py</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/maximum-viable-integrity-with-web2py.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating an enterprise grade application to meet static business
specifications is an easy task for a developer using web2py. Keeping up
with ever changing needs of a business, while maintaining core
application logic can be more difficult. At Suits + Tables, we have
found this process facilitated using a combination of Unit Testing,
Behavior Driven Development, and Continuous Integration. Best practices
for maintaining Maximum Viable Integrity during iteration and deployment
of web2py applications will be discussed in the context of Suits +
Tables and other case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Graves</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/maximum-viable-integrity-with-web2py.html</guid></item></channel></rss>