<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How I Learned to Code with My Dad</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2018/how-i-learned-to-code-with-my-dad.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m nine years old, and I want to be a video game developer. I learned
about coding by watching my dad and asking questions. To me coding is
like a “sport” and I think lots of kids would like to code if they had a
chance to learn and build things. I’d like to tell you how I got
started, and show some of the projects I’ve built. Then you can have
ideas on how to help other kids get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Preston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-29:pyohio-2018/how-i-learned-to-code-with-my-dad.html</guid></item><item><title>Useful Python Libraries for Network Engineers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2018/useful-python-libraries-for-network-engineers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has quickly become THE language for network automation and
programmability due to it’s combined simplicity and power. If you are a
network engineer looking to get started with automation and Python, it
can be tough to now where to start. This session proposes the modules
and libraries every engineer should have in their tool bag.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hank Preston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-29:pyohio-2018/useful-python-libraries-for-network-engineers.html</guid></item><item><title>Build a Chat Bot with Chuck Norris, Python and Docker (Tutorial)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2017/build-a-chat-bot-with-chuck-norris-python-and-docker-tutorial.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session we build a Chuck Norris joke-telling Chat Bot! We'll write our bot using Python and package it up as a Docker image. You'll learn about Webhooks and their importance in cloud applications, Micro-Services and the Cisco Spark Collaboration Cloud. This session is designed to be fun and hands on, so make sure to bring your laptop, sense of humor and great questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hank Preston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-30:pyohio-2017/build-a-chat-bot-with-chuck-norris-python-and-docker-tutorial.html</guid></item></channel></rss>