<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Kim Tae-wan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scalable Backtesting with Python, From I O to Scalability</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/scalable-backtesting-with-python-from-i-o-to-scalability.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing how to quickly and efficiently simulate stock price information in the Python ecosystem. Backtesting is a necessary process to verify the validity of a strategy, but it can take a considerable amount of time as the time-frequency of the data becomes more precise and the complexity of the strategy increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that efficient and accurate backtesting is not only a tool to speed up the computation time, but also to quickly operate a better strategy and enhance profitability. In this session,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving the IO speed of daily OHLC ~ tick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison of the computation time of pandas vectorization compared to for loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backtesting package structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed backtesting using Ray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizing trading strategies using Ray Cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Tae-wan
I am majoring in Computer Science at SUNY Korea SBU, and I like analysis in chaotic environments such as pattern exploration of market data. I am interested in data engineering and optimization, and I would like to contribute to quickly responding to the complexity of the financial market and creating robust alpha through this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kim Tae-wan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/scalable-backtesting-with-python-from-i-o-to-scalability.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>