<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Transfer Learning in Natural Language Processing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/transfer-learning-in-natural-language-processing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transfer learning refers to the methods that leverage a trained model in
one domain to achieve better results on tasks in a related domain i.e.
we transfer the knowledge gained in one domain to a new domain. This
talk is centered on recent developments in deep learning to facilitate
transfer learning in NLP. We will discuss the transformer architecture
and its extensions like GPT and BERT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classic supervised machine learning paradigm is based on learning in
isolation a single predictive model for a task using a single dataset.
This approach requires a large number of training examples and performs
best for well-defined and narrow tasks. Transfer learning refers to the
methods that leverage a trained model in one domain to achieve better
results on tasks in a related domain. The model thus trained also show
better generalization properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer vision has seen great success of transfer learning, model
trained on the Imagenet data have been 'fine-tuned' to achieve
State-of-thee-art in many other problems. In last two years, NLP has
also witnessed the emergence of several transfer learning methods and
architectures, which significantly improved upon the state-of-the-art on
a wide range of NLP tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will present an overview of modern transfer learning methods in NLP,
how models are pre-trained, what information the representations they
learn capture, and review examples and case studies on how these models
can be integrated and adapted in downstream NLP tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Janu Verma</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-03:pydata-delhi-2019/transfer-learning-in-natural-language-processing.html</guid></item></channel></rss>