<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Angela Parker</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What do you want to be known for?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/what-do-you-want-to-be-known-for.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you want to be known for? - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel professionally unsatisfied, struggle to make decisions, or
have a burning desire to leave behind an epic legacy – this session is
for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this fun + interactive session you’ll discover your Top 2 Personal
Values that are the secret to creating impact through your work. You
work hard. You are great at your job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hard work is not what creates FULFILLMENT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel professionally unsatisfied, struggle to make decisions, want
to feel more creative, or desire to leave behind an epic legacy – this
session is for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this fun + interactive session you’ll discover the secret to creating
impact through your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you get clear about what you value – finding your purpose, choosing
a direction, and making important career decisions becomes easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session you’ll discover: - Your top two personal values - How to
quickly make career decisions that feel right - How to use creativity to
get clarity - Who you are now by modernizing your value system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join certified coach, master workshop facilitator, community creator,
and international entrepreneur Angela Parker for this unique session
that will help you get clear and inspire you to take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Angela is American she lives half the year in Trentino Italy
and is a big supporter of the Python Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official Bio: Angela Parker is an international entrepreneur, CPCC
Certified Coach, ICF Coach Member, and AJ&amp;amp;Smart Master Workshop
Facilitator who teaches deep-feeling leaders &amp;amp; entrepreneurs how to use
creativity, values, self-compassion, and radical self-care – to create
deeply fulfilling work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angela designs and facilitates impactful in-person and on-line
workshops, masterminds, and experiences for leaders and teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angela founded the largest and longest running outdoor fitness program
in Santa Monica CA. After her exit in 2018 she began coaching and
offering workshop facilitation. She’s known for her empathy, intuition,
directness, humor, and ability to thread the most impactful details into
all her sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angela and her work has been featured on CBS, The LA Times, ESPN, MTV,
ABC, The Hallmark Channel, Carson Magazine, and Self Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Covid possible, Angela splits her time between the Italian Alps,
Los Angeles, Chicago, and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Angela Parker&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Angela Parker</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/what-do-you-want-to-be-known-for.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>communication</category><category>community</category><category>education</category><category>scaling</category><category>teaching</category></item></channel></rss>