<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tamir-lousky.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>From plotting to chart porn - Creating slick charts with Matplotlib</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2017/from-plotting-to-chart-porn-creating-slick-charts-with-matplotlib.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tamir Lousky</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-12:pycon-israel-2017/from-plotting-to-chart-porn-creating-slick-charts-with-matplotlib.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is gaining speed as a leading data science programming language, alongside R. An essential part of data science is data visualization, something easily achieved with popular plotting library Matplotlib. While matplotlib is powerful and versatile, R has one advantage with respect to plotting: ggplot2, which easily generates beautiful charts out of the box. In this talk we will demonstrate how to painlessly generate eye candy charts with Matplotlib, using styles, color maps, full chart customization and clever subplotting with figures and axis objects. We'll also briefly discuss basic and advanced interactivity for Jupyter notebooks and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Generating, automating and processing 3D graphics with Blender's python API</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2016/generating-automating-and-processing-3d-graphics-with-blenders-python-api.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tamir Lousky</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-10:pycon-israel-2016/generating-automating-and-processing-3d-graphics-with-blenders-python-api.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is often used as a scripting language within graphics software. One of these is the open source 3D animation program Blender, which has a powerful python API that can be extended with any python library. At Invertex, we use this tool to automatically analyze 3D scans and generate custom products, in some cases ready for 3D printing. This talk will provide a short overview of Blender and its python API, and demonstrate how to use it with a few short examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/tamir-lousky.pdf"&gt;http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/tamir-lousky.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>