<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Machine Learning to play chess</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2017/using-machine-learning-to-play-chess.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, chess engines contain many lines of code handcrafted under the guidance of grandmasters. Are you interested in being knee deep in chess theory just to crank out a half decent engine? No? This talk is for you. Why not create an engine that learns to improve itself?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aubhro Sengupta</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-29:pyohio-2017/using-machine-learning-to-play-chess.html</guid></item><item><title>Abstractions and building up: A case study with chess_py, an open source chess platform</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/abstractions-and-building-up-a-case-study-with-chess_py-an-open-source-chess-platform.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programming can seem difficult because of the enormous level of abstraction involved. Objects are being dealt with that have very little to do with the real world. They are hard to grasp, touch, and feel. Chess on the other hand is a very concrete and physical game. Objects such as the board, pieces, and even logic such as the basic rules of the game are much easier to understand. How the pieces in chess interact, their capabilities, and their placement on the board can be similar to the way objects interact in python. Using chess_py, an open source platform for chess written by me in python, we can delve into the different classes and data structures to understand how they work and gain a deeper understanding of the language of python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aubhro Sengupta</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/abstractions-and-building-up-a-case-study-with-chess_py-an-open-source-chess-platform.html</guid></item></channel></rss>