<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rethinking the Python Web Framework</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/rethinking-the-python-web-framework.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you could rethink the Python web framework? What would it be like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I had the opportunity to do this. The result is a web framework called Morepath. It doesn't look wildly different on the outside. I'm going to demonstrate a few ways in which it is different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a user of a web framework, I want to show you use cases you may not even realize you have.&amp;nbsp;If you're a developer of a web framework, I want to offer you ideas you may not have considered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martijn Faassen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-28:pyconweb-2017/rethinking-the-python-web-framework.html</guid><category>keynote</category><category>morepath</category></item><item><title>Morepath: a Python Web Framework with Super Powers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/morepath-a-python-web-framework-with-super-power.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://morepath.readthedocs.org"&gt;Morepath&lt;/a&gt; is a server web framework
written with modern, rich client web development in mind. Why another
new Python web framework in 2014?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it can be done better: Morepath understands how to construct
hyperlinks from models. Writing a generic view in Morepath is like
writing any other view. With Morepath, you can reuse, extend and
override apps as easily as you can construct them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you don't end up using Morepath, you will learn something about
how the nature of web frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://morepath.readthedocs.org"&gt;Morepath&lt;/a&gt; is a new server web
framework written with modern, rich client web development in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk I will be discussing some core features of Morepath that
make it different:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its different take on routing and linking. Morepath has support to
help you construct hyperlinks to models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its view system: plain views, generic views, view composition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morepath's approach to application construction allows application
extension and overriding, and composition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will attempt to convince people to try Morepath. For those
unable or unwilling to try, I will communicate some design principles
behind Morepath which can be of help to any web developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martijn Faassen</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/morepath-a-python-web-framework-with-super-power.html</guid></item><item><title>Spinning a Web Framework</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/spinning-a-web-framework.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the years I've been exposed to a lot of ideas in web frameworks.
Reflecting on these ideas is valuable when you build a new one, but also
when you simply use an existing web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss the slow genesis of Morepath, a micro
web-framework with super powers that I've created, and discuss some of
the ideas behind it, things I've learned, and also share some thoughts
about the creative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideas behind Morepath are not revolutionary, but hopefully still
make you think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Martijn Faassen</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-16:pycon-de-2013/spinning-a-web-framework.html</guid></item></channel></rss>