<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_emma-gordon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Introduction to Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/introduction-to-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emma Gordon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-18:pycon-uk-2018/introduction-to-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, you keep hearing about neural networks. Perhaps you've even gone to
a talk or two, but are still wondering exactly how a neural network
works, what you'd use one for and how to get started. This talk has you
covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll illustrate the basic concepts by walking through implementing a
neural network from scratch in Python, and then move on to the powerful
real world libraries you'd use in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session is aimed at programmers of all experience levels who are
newcomers to the subject of neural networks. If you're already using
them as part of your work, there will likely be nothing new for you
here.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Writing Code? Pfft... Evolve it Instead!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/keynote-writing-code-pfft-evolve-it-instead.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emma Gordon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-23:djangocon-europe-2018/keynote-writing-code-pfft-evolve-it-instead.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re heading into a future of delivery drones, driverless cars and 3D-printed “hoverboards” …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With machines now able to perform many tasks better than humans, some people are going to be out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not software developers, right?! Could a computer generate the code you currently write for a living?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll take a look at how technology is changing the work that people do, and think about the implications of that for our society. We'll then take a look at one of the many biologically inspired approaches to AI - Genetic Algorithms, and how they can be used to generate code given a description of the function that that code should perform, rather than having a software developer write it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler - you’re probably not out of a job, yet…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emma Gordon&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Bee</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/python-bee.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emma Gordon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:europython-2017/python-bee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thought up in 2009 by a group of MIT students who entered the Python
bee into a competition for “bad ideas”, a Python bee is like a
spelling bee for programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of spelling words, participants are given functions to write
and must spell them out loud - one character at a time, without
looking at the code that they're writing! Players must spell valid
Python and every character counts, including symbols and whitespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the twist for the second round (credit for this one goes to
dropboxblogs):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're now allowed to look at the code, but... you must now team up
with other programmers, entering alternate characters without being
allowed to communicate via any other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for everyone to be able to have a go, we'll split up into
small groups to play - for those that want to be competitive, we'll
use a scoring system so that we can still declare an overall
champion. You're very welcome to come along just to have fun though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - a fun hour of slightly ridiculous programming games :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Writing code? Pfft... Evolve it instead!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/writing-code-pfft-evolve-it-instead.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emma Gordon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/writing-code-pfft-evolve-it-instead.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're heading into a future of delivery drones, driverless cars and
3D-printed &amp;quot;hoverboards&amp;quot; ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With machines now able to perform many tasks better than humans, some
people are going to be out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not software developers, right?! Could a computer generate the
code you currently write for a living?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll take a look at one of the many biologically
inspired approaches to AI - Genetic Algorithms, and how they can be
used to generate code given a description of the function that that
code should perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler - you're probably not out of a job, yet...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>