<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Reiko Okamoto</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_reiko-okamoto.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>What an Early 2000s Reality Show Taught Me about File Management</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/what-an-early-2000s-reality-show-taught-me-about-file-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Reiko Okamoto</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/what-an-early-2000s-reality-show-taught-me-about-file-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clutter, whether it's physical or digital, destroys our ability to focus; home organization ideas can be extended to create an workspace where analysts feel inspired to work with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas from home organization shows are surprisingly applicable to file management. Using a room divider to establish dedicated zones for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clutter, whether it's physical or digital, destroys our ability to focus; home organization ideas can be extended to create an workspace where analysts feel inspired to work with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas from home organization shows are surprisingly applicable to file management. Using a room divider to establish dedicated zones for different activities in a studio apartment is analogous to creating self-contained projects in RStudio. Likewise, swapping mismatched hangers with matching ones to tidy a closet resembles the adoption of a file naming convention to make a directory easier to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will share good practices in file management through the lens of home organization. We all know that clutter, whether it is in our physical space or on our machine, destroys our ability to focus. These practices will help R users of all levels create a serene, relaxing environment where they feel inspired to work with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://reikookamoto.github.io/"&gt;https://reikookamoto.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/reikookamoto/posit-conf-2023-neat"&gt;https://github.com/reikookamoto/posit-conf-2023-neat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>