<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Organizing Conferences For Learners: How we did it in Namibia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/organizing-conferences-for-learners-how-we-did-it-in-namibia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk you will hear about the importance of organizing conferences for school learners, how you can go about organizing one, what you need to do and what you need to avoid as you prepare the conference, how to engage with school teachers as a software developer, what the results of such conferences could bring out in our children and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poor quality of the software developers in our community is increasing. On top of other factors, most of our learners are introduced or exposed to computing only in university. This has caused the quality of our software developers to drop. We wanted to change that by introducing programming clubs in high schools and then we decided that why not run a conference for them. That's how this idea came up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Upani&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Upani</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-24:djangocon-europe-2018/organizing-conferences-for-learners-how-we-did-it-in-namibia.html</guid></item><item><title>Organizing conferences for learners: How we made it work in Namibia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/organizing-conferences-for-learners-how-we-made-it-work-in-namibia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will focus on why it is important to have conferences for learners (especially in developing countries), compare how different it is to organizing a conference for adults, do’s and don’ts of organizing such a conference, how to organize one and possible outcomes of such conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Upani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/organizing-conferences-for-learners-how-we-made-it-work-in-namibia.html</guid></item><item><title>High School Pythonistas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/high-school-pythonistas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jessica Upani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything from a lack of teachers to dysfunctional computer labs has led to a loss of interest in Junior Computer studies learners registering for the subject in their senior grades. These has led to yet a bigger problem which is what I want to address in my talk. PYNAM is short for Python Namibia. It is a Python programming society. We established PYNAM during the Feb 2015 PyCon Namibia conference. We primarily aim at bringing the Python Community in Namibia together and to promote Python to the young children through our school outreach programs. This year we are hosting a first ever programming day where the learners get to showcase their software and also raise money to help fix the computer lab at the school. My talk will report about the programs that the learners will create, the whole experience of developing the systems and organizing the event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Upani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:pycon-uk-2016/high-school-pythonistas.html</guid></item><item><title>Ensure Python Development: Practical strides that we can take to ensure Python skills development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/ensure-python-development-practical-strides-that-we-can-take-to-ensure-python-skills-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several countries such as Zimbabwe, Nigeria to name a few that
have just started having python events in their countries and I would
like to share what steps we are taking to ensure that we are not just
organizing these events but we are also taking necessary steps to ensure
that in the future we are actually really developing the skills of the
new developers in our nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will serve as motivation and it will give a sense of direction for
these developing countries. In the end we are hoping to motivate more
countries to follow our steps. We need to show each other support and
share our actions, this will serve that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk does not need any expertise. It will benefit both new
organizers as well as experienced organizers who have not taken some of
these steps already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Upani</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/ensure-python-development-practical-strides-that-we-can-take-to-ensure-python-skills-development.html</guid></item></channel></rss>