<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_elisa-jasinska.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python for Networking Devices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2016/python-for-networking-devices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elisa Jasinska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-15:pycon-pl-2016/python-for-networking-devices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Internet is a series of tubes and at the end of those tubes are:
networking devices! To form the Internet as we know it, each provider
network has to be managed, maintained and interconnected. Traditional
Network Engineering is moving more and more towards automated device and
service management, a task often performed in Python due to the
availability of many useful libraries. This talk will walk you though
common tasks in Network Engineering and introduce a number of Python
libraries that are helpful in accessing and managing networking
equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Automating Network Equipment with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/automating-network-equipment-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elisa Jasinska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-12:pycon-sk-2017/automating-network-equipment-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cisco, Juniper, Arista... plenty of network equipment vendors support some form of automated access tho their devices these days. Many of those access libraries are written in Python and made it the goto language for network engineers. From abstracting Netconf or SSH, configuring devices or retrieving structured data - depending on the vendor support, the available libraries provide plenty of functionality to take traditional network engineering to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will walk you though what functionality a typical network library provides and will present examples on how to manage and configure your network infrastructure in an automated fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>