<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ville-saavuori.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Pythonic JavaScript for Web Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/pythonic-javascript-for-web-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ville Säävuori</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/pythonic-javascript-for-web-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having a basic knowledge of JavaScript is obligatory for every Web
developer in todays world. Most of us are familiar with the pain of
having to write some simple hide/show logic and ajax queries with
jQuery on a page that is mostly rendered server-side. Nowadays,
however, there are lots of great JavaScript frameworks and build
tools that not only make these things very easy to do The Right Way,
but also make the whole process quite painless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent past year in a small startup writing only front-end code and
evaluating different tools and best practises. Bringing these tools
to old Django projects has been eye-opening. There are practically no
documentation or code examples on how to integrate these things to
Python backend projects, so it’s very hard to get started from
scratch. In this talk we’ll go trough some of the tools, examples on
how to get started, and also some coding guidelines on how to make
JavaScript look and feel more sane and Pythonic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current state of JavaScript frameworks is notoriously bad; there
are more of them than blog engines written with Django. We’ll focus
on Vue.js (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vuejs.org"&gt;https://vuejs.org&lt;/a&gt;) which is a lightweight, very easy to
get started and yet powerful tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll also take a look at new end-to-end browser test tools and
modern build tools that enable us to take full advantage of the huge
NPM package universe (Cheeseshop for JS)  and write modern
ES2015/ES2016 JavaScript that has more powerful and cleaner syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks (day 3)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2010/djangoconeu-lightingtalksthirdday663flv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jan Lehnardt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-05-26:djangocon-europe-2010/djangoconeu-lightingtalksthirdday663flv.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry></feed>