<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Andrea Longo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andrea-longo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Do you know a runbook from a flip book? How sysadmins use documentation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/do-you-know-a-runbook-from-a-flip-book-how-sysadmins-use-documentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Longo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/do-you-know-a-runbook-from-a-flip-book-how-sysadmins-use-documentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come along on a tour of common types of documentation system
administrators use to get their jobs done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an enterprise software developer, system administrators are my
customers and colleagues. In this session, learn not just what gets
used, but also what internal and informal sources to look for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come along on a tour of common types of documentation system
administrators use to get their jobs done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an enterprise software developer, system administrators are my
customers and colleagues. In this session, learn not just what gets
used, but also what internal and informal sources to look for to create
better docs. I'll share what I've learned sysadmins want from the
written information they rely on daily. I'll also talk about what ops
teams write for themselves that can add important details to your
documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll go beyond glossy presentation slides of instructor-led training to
delve into what's meaningful for day-to-day tasks. For example,
integration and migration: to accomplish this smoothly, sysadmins need
references and examples to install, configure, and customize new tools
to work with existing systems. Tutorials can show how, real-world
configuration examples show what, and cookbooks provide ready-made
examples to customize as needed. Deployment checklists ensure the
rollout goes smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergencies can happen at any hour — which is why
runbooks can be so valuable. With step-by-step details so staff can
respond without making mistakes. A junior engineer can resolve an issue
without calling a developer for help. Manifests, dependency lists, and
logs become necessary adjuncts to documentation, providing critical data
for root cause analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about these sources, not just how others use them, but where you
can find valuable detail to enhance the documents you write for
operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Portland 2017"></category></entry></feed>