<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alexis-lucattini.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Remote DNA Sequencing and Analysis; Nanopore sequencing, FPGA boards and a fortunate Epiphany</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/remote-dna-sequencing-and-analysis-nanopore-sequencing-fpga-boards-and-a-fortunate-epiphany.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexis Lucattini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-04:pycon-au-2017/remote-dna-sequencing-and-analysis-nanopore-sequencing-fpga-boards-and-a-fortunate-epiphany.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a MinION?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxford Nanopore's MinION is a 91g portable sequencing device, which has been a huge talking point in the sequencing community since entering the market in 2014. First thought of as having potential, it's now recognised as a valuable asset of any genomic laboratory.
The MinION can deliver long-read yields as great as its competitor PacBio. This is due to its yield per flowcell increasing 10-fold in the past 18 months, which has created much delight to the community albeit some problems for researchers (and ONT themselves) when it comes to data handling and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The raw output from a MinION is an electrical signal over-time which must be put through a computationally-intensive RNN to infer the nucleotides of a given DNA strand -  this process is known as basecalling. If one were to do this on a normal laptop, it would take over a week to complete all the reads from a 48-hour run, which hinders the real-time component of the MinION technology. In order to keep the basecall processing at the same rate as the throughput, the MinION output needs to be transferred to a high powered server, which hinders on the MinION's portability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to overcome this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running reads simultaneously through this basecalling processing is a must when it comes to real-time Nanopore sequencing, which is why we combine ONT with another start-up project, Adapteva's Parallela board, a credit card sized micro-server with an in-built FPGA board, ideal for parallel processing. We explore the compatability of the Parallela and the MinION, with the aim of performing both sequencing and analysis in a remote environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>