<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Monika Bláhová</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_monika-blahova.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Czech Drought Monitoring system</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/czech-drought-monitoring-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Monika Bláhová</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/czech-drought-monitoring-system.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Czech Drought Monitoring system – a journey from manual work to global drought monitoring and machine learning, powered by Python - presented by Monika Bláhová&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to encourage beginner developers not to underestimate the skills and benefits they can bring to various non-IT …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Czech Drought Monitoring system – a journey from manual work to global drought monitoring and machine learning, powered by Python - presented by Monika Bláhová&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to encourage beginner developers not to underestimate the skills and benefits they can bring to various non-IT environments. I joined a team focused on drought research at the Czech Academy of Science in 2016 with a fresh degree in Geoinformatics and minimal experience with coding. Thanks to this very little initial knowledge, we were able to build a robust system providing drought monitoring and forecast for Czechia and also the whole of central Europe. We were able to fight through text files, user inputs, and geodata of all sorts and say goodbye to manual processing thanks to Python and its geospatial and data processing libraries. On the technical side, the presentation should introduce some of the handy geospatial and data processing tools to get your hands on any task, from producing colorful maps to analyzing time trends in satellite imagery. It should also be a guide on identifying needs and building the most necessary data manipulation processes from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>