<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ayan Mukhopadhyay</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ayan-mukhopadhyay.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Robust Spatial-Temporal Incident Prediction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/robust-spatial-temporal-incident-prediction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ayan Mukhopadhyay</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/robust-spatial-temporal-incident-prediction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robust Spatial-Temporal Incident Prediction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayan Mukhopadhyay (Stanford University)*; Kai Wang (Harvard University); Andrew Perrault (Harvard University); Mykel Kochenderfer (Stanford University); Milind Tambe (Harvard University); Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatio-temporal incident prediction is a central issue in law enforcement, with applications in fighting crimes like poaching, human …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robust Spatial-Temporal Incident Prediction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayan Mukhopadhyay (Stanford University)*; Kai Wang (Harvard University); Andrew Perrault (Harvard University); Mykel Kochenderfer (Stanford University); Milind Tambe (Harvard University); Yevgeniy Vorobeychik (Washington University in St. Louis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatio-temporal incident prediction is a central issue in law enforcement, with applications in fighting crimes like poaching, human trafficking, illegal fishing, burglaries and smuggling. However, state of the art approaches fail to account for  evasion in response to predictive models, a common form of which is spatial shift in incident occurrence. We present a general approach for incident forecasting that is robust to spatial shifts. We propose two techniques for solving the resulting robust optimization problem: first, a constraint generation method guaranteed to yield an optimal solution, and second, a more scalable gradient-based approach. We then apply these techniques to both discrete-time and continuous-time robust incident forecasting. We evaluate our algorithms on two different real-world datasets, demonstrating that our approach is significantly more robust than conventional methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>