<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Will Vincent</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Panel Discussion: The State of Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/panel-discussion-the-state-of-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us for a panel on the State of Django: the state of the Django codebase and also the state of the Django community as represented by organizations like the Django Software Foundation, Django Girls, the Python Software Foundation and DEFNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderated by Dawn Wages, our panelists will discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how we can continue to grow the Django community and create a welcoming space for beginners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the priorities for the continued development and maturation of Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ways to improve Django events and bring them to new regions worldwide, especially in the COVID landscapee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;success stories from Django communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concrete steps toward better and more effective diversity and inclusion efforts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how Django fits into the larger Python ecosystem, especially as other fields like data science continue to grow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and much more. It’s been a long time since we gathered leaders of the Django community on one stage to have an open-ended discussion about Django’s present and future, and we hope you’ll join us for this special event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Panelists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Carlton Gibson](/presenters/carlton-gibson/), Django Fellow and co-host of the Django Chat podcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Andrew Godwin](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://aeracode.org/"&gt;https://aeracode.org/&lt;/a&gt;), longtime Django core contributor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Jeff Triplett](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webology.dev/"&gt;https://webology.dev/&lt;/a&gt;), DEFNA President and PSF board member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Will Vincent](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wsvincent.com/"&gt;https://wsvincent.com/&lt;/a&gt;), DSF Treasurer and co-host of the Django Chat podcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Rachell Calhoun](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.rachellcalhoun.com/"&gt;https://www.rachellcalhoun.com/&lt;/a&gt;), DjangoGirls Trustee, DjangoGirls Grand Rapids (Michigan), PyLadies Grand Rapids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Mariusz Felisiak](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/MariuszFelisiak"&gt;https://twitter.com/MariuszFelisiak&lt;/a&gt;), Django Fellow and core team member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Godwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-19:/djangocon-us-2022/panel-discussion-the-state-of-django.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>The Django Jigsaw Puzzle: Aligning All the Pieces</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/the-django-jigsaw-puzzle-aligning-all-the-pieces.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning Django often feels like trying to solve an immense jigsaw puzzle with the pieces all turned upside down. It's hard to align all the pieces when you don't know how they should fit together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is based on over a decade of using and teaching Django professionally. I will cover all the major puzzle pieces of Django: how they work independently and together. I don’t expect anyone to have mastery over all these pieces--I certainly don’t--but knowing the overall picture of Django and what the pieces are will provide a roadmap for learning and improving your Django abilities no matter your current level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will Vincent</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-17:/djangocon-us-2022/the-django-jigsaw-puzzle-aligning-all-the-pieces.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>Django User Model: Past, Present, and Future</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/django-user-model-past-present-and-future.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django's default User model is now 20 years old and, in the words of former Django Fellow Carlton Gibson, a &amp;quot;leaky battery.&amp;quot; This talk examines the historical basis for User and past efforts to update or replace it. It evaluates current best practices, including custom user models and third-party packages, that support modern user authentication patterns. And it looks forward to future updates to User that support Django's goal of advancing the state of the art in web development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will Vincent</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-25:/djangocon-us-2024/django-user-model-past-present-and-future.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>