<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_douglas-finch.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Air Quality &amp; Python: Developing Online Analysis Tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/air-quality-python-developing-online-analysis-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Douglas Finch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/air-quality-python-developing-online-analysis-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Poor surface air quality has a range of implications for human health
and the economy. Without concerted mitigation efforts, trends in
urbanisation and aspirations for progressive economic growth will result
in poorer levels of air quality. Analysing and interpreting the incoming
data streams from heterogeneous air quality measurement stations is
critical for tackling the problem and for developing early warning
systems. I am using Python to develop a set of online analysis tools
(ukatmos.org) to enable the public to quickly and easily plot air
quality data in many ways, effectively freeing up information that is
already publicly available but in awkward formats and often involves
development of code. We anticipate these tools will also support data
science classes at school, and can speed up scientific research by
minimizing effort in repeating analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover how the tools integrate numerous Python libraries
(e.g. Pandas and NumPy), the Django web framework, the Plot.ly tools for
creating interactive graphs, and SQL to address the large data volumes.
Developing these Python tools in an adaptive and scalable way allows it
to grow as more data become available, e.g. satellite observations.
Adaptability also includes evolving user requirements. This project will
also be developed into a Python library allowing the user to easily use
the online analysis tools from an offline Python environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>