<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michael-trythall.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Under the Hood of Modern CSS Frameworks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/under-the-hood-of-modern-css-frameworks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Trythall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-18:djangocon-us-2016/under-the-hood-of-modern-css-frameworks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Together we’ll look at the code behind Bootstrap, Foundation, Semantic UI, and other CSS frameworks. We’ll identify common patterns and architectural decisions that make these systems so easy to use. Some of the things we’ll discover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it takes to set up a good type system.
How style and structure are separated to make theming easier.
Best practices for stubbing out grid systems.
How configuration works.
How to make everything feel cohesive.
What it takes to test a framework so you can potentially test your own.
So much more!
If you’re looking to improve your skills with one of these frameworks or potentially roll your own mini-Bootstrap, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Customizing the Django Admin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--customizing-the-django-admin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Trythall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-08:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--customizing-the-django-admin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to build great admin user interfaces while still leveraging the
power of the Django's batteries-included admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django admin interface is a great tool for rapidly viewing and
generating content, but its default one size fits all approach may not
be the best for the users of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is broken into two parts. First, we will discuss user
experience and what users have come to expect from an admin tool. In the
second half, we'll show you how to bend Django's admin to meet those
expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="admin"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2010"></category></entry><entry><title>CSS Processors</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/css-processors.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Trythall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-01:djangocon-us-2013/css-processors.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CSS Preprocessors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 12:15 p.m.--1 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preprocessors like Sass and LESS bring basic programming functionality
to CSS allowing for resilient, configurable front-ends. Learn more about
these tools, how to use them, how to integrate them into your workflow,
and how to extend them by opening their hoods. Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk covers core concepts and syntax, then moves into best
practices and pitfalls. This talk demonstrates the programming
capabilities baked into preprocessors with real world scenarios and
working code samples. The audience will gain the knowledge necessary to
begin using these tools and learn where to look to stay up-to-date.
Introduction Capabilities Real World Usage Advanced Usage, a Glance
Under the Hood Wrap Up/QA&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>