<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_josh-simmons.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How we designed an inclusivity-first conference on a shoestring budget and short timeline</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/how-we-designed-an-inclusivity-first-conference-on-a-shoestring-budget-and-short-timeline.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Neugebauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/how-we-designed-an-inclusivity-first-conference-on-a-shoestring-budget-and-short-timeline.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Christopher Neugebauer, Josh Simmons, Sam Kitajima-Kimbrel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New conferences rarely have resources to run the sort of outreach and inclusion programs that big conferences have. It’s hard to guess how much money you’ll have to spend, how many attendees you’ll have, and what your new community will look like. With so many things to worry about, it’s no surprise that most events don’t prioritise outreach until they’ve got a few years under their belt, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t have to be this way, and it can even be easier to build a new event around outreach and inclusion than it is to build it in later on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk shares the story of North Bay Python’s inaugural conference, which we planned in under 6 months, ran on a $40,000 budget, and built a welcoming community to make it real. We made inclusivity a founding principle and did so without compromising our speaker lineup while still attracting great sponsorship and hosted an event that almost every attendee wants to return to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’re going to share with you how we built a conference, from the ground up, to be as inclusive as we could make it. We’ll touch on early organisation, marketing, and on-the ground logistics. Throughout the talk, you’ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we designed a budget that let us prioritise outreach and inclusion activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we built the community that we wanted before the conference even started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we ran an event that proved that we meant everything we said&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You too can host a new conference with a great lineup on a shoestring budget and short timeline, and you can do it while being inclusive, welcoming, and putting attendee safety first. Find out how you can have your cake, eat it, and still have lots to share with your new community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Saturday PM Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/saturday-pm-lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Ansell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/saturday-pm-lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks Saturday, August 05 2017 04 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Ansell - Python on FPGAs 1:15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicky Ringland and Jim Mussared - National Computer Science School 6:28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinton McKinnon - The Amazing StarLAB 11:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josh Simmons - Open Source in Education 13:32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Weipa - Systematic Problem Solving 18:34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Leslie - PEP-628 The world's oldest bug 23:50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Moore - OMNICODE 29:08&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Lonsdale - FASTQE 33:22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tisham Dhar - Energy Monitor 37:29&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhydwyn McGuire - R 42:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josh Driver - Faster PostgreSQL Text Search 44:26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fraser Tweedale - On naming things 49:49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Leonard - High Risk Demo Episode 2 55:28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ned Letcher - PyEnv 59:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke Deller - Garbage Collection Live demo 1:04:25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Learn by Doing: Getting Students into FOSS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/learn-by-doing-getting-students-into-foss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Simmons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-04:pycon-au-2017/learn-by-doing-getting-students-into-foss.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting students involved with free and open source projects is a great way to provide them with real world development experience while contributing to the common good, but making that first contribution is difficult even for students already confident in their skills. This is where the Google Open Source team’s student programs, Google Summer of Code and Google Code-in, come into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been partnering with open source projects for 12 years to provide students with structure, mentorship, and real world experience. Through participation in these programs, students learn how to work on existing codebases, communicate across timezones, run test suites, use version control systems, and ultimately end up making contributions that are nearly professional quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session I’ll share more information about these programs and other opportunities for students to learn by doing in open source.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Source and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/vancouver-python-developers/open-source-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Simmons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-04:vancouver-python-developers/open-source-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source is nothing if not communities, yet so much about our communities are left to chance. Professional community managers are helping, but change, especially cultural change, must be bottom up as much as it is top down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll look at open source web tech communities and see who gets what right so we can all learn from them. We’ll finish by exploring what every community member can do to shape and improve the communities to which they belong.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python in the NHL Front Office</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/vancouver-python-developers/python-in-the-nhl-front-office.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Simmons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-04:vancouver-python-developers/python-in-the-nhl-front-office.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advancements in statistical analysis have recently emerged in professional hockey as a way for teams to improve their performance, player development, and decision making. Working at the forefront of this analytics revolution, from the blogosphere to the National Hockey League, Josh will discuss the ways he uses Python to process data and solve problems to guide decision makers in all facets of front office activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Source and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/open-source-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Simmons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/open-source-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Josh Simmons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Open source is nothing if not community, yet so much about our communities are left to chance. These days maintainers and community managers are taking a more proactive role in setting the tone, building communities that are more productive and inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But culture change must come from the bottom up as much as the top down. In this talk I highlight salient problems and share solutions that everyone can pursue to shape the communities to which they belong.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Fail Early, Fail Often, Fail Well</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/fail-early-fail-often-fail-well.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Simmons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/fail-early-fail-often-fail-well.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josh Simmons
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/34/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/34/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
It happens. Things go south and it’s not even clear how. Your client and you can’t see eye to eye, or your enthusiastic new business partner has dropped off the radar. The project you’ve invested weeks, months, or years into may never see the light of day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failure comes in many forms and the increasing complexity of our projects and the world they operate in doesn’t help. Despite our best efforts, learning the hard way is often the only way. Perhaps this is why modern startup culture has rallied around the mantra: “Fail fast. Fail early. Fail often.” But I spent the better part of my career failing in freelance, agency, and startups, and the experience leads me to believe the common refrain to be lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like gymnasts who train to fall properly, I believe we must learn to fail well. In this talk, I draw from my experience learning the hard way, flagging the ten easiest and most insidious mistakes one can make. Because failure is inevitable, I will also be sharing a framework for recovery that includes managing yourself, your relationships, and your reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will leave with a better sense of what NOT to do, an idea of how to cope with failure, and the knowledge that failure is inevitable and that’s OK.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why would a new developer choose Django?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/why-would-a-new-developer-choose-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Simmons</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/why-would-a-new-developer-choose-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josh Simmons
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/36/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/36/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
What makes new developers choose Django over Rails or WordPress? As a web developer and community organizer, Josh has learned a lot about the differences between the frameworks and why people make the choices they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll compare Django with other ecosystems to see where it excels and where it lags. You'll leave with a better sense of the web ecosystem as a whole and why people are choosing things that &lt;em&gt;aren't&lt;/em&gt; Django. Critically, attendees will leave with specific ideas about how to attract more new developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>