<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_martin-beroiz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Transient detection and image analysis pipeline for TOROS project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/transient-detection-and-image-analysis-pipeline-f.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Martin Beroiz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/transient-detection-and-image-analysis-pipeline-f.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TOROS project will be an astronomical survey of the southern hemisphere
in search of optical transients counterparts for aLIGO. This project
will make extended use of Machine learning techniques to identify
interesting transient candidates to aLIGO alerts. It also uses OpenCV
library for image aligning and some of the subsequent processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In preparation for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://toros.phys.utb.edu/TOROS/Welcome.html%20&amp;quot;TOROS%20project&amp;quot;"&gt;TOROS
project&lt;/a&gt;
designed to survey the southern hemisphere sky in search for transients,
we develop a pipeline for image analysis and processing based on Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code makes extended use of the open source image processing library
OpenCV to align the images astrometrically and makes use of other
astronomical specific routines like the Astropy package to deal with
FITS files. The design will involve integration with SciDB,
Astrometry.net, parallelization and other pythonic astronomical tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This automated optical transients discovery tool will be tested with
real (CSTAR and TORITOS telescopes) and simulated data samples as the
input for a machine learning classification tool of light-curves based
on AstroML and Scikit-Learn libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is version controlled using git and we will handle future
collaboration among scientist from different countries using the open
source project manager Trac. It will be available as an open source
project in popular web repositories like github or bitbucket.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>