<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nataraj Dasgupta</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nataraj-dasgupta.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Predicting the economic impact of COVID 19 using real time images from space</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2021/predicting-the-economic-impact-of-covid-19-using-real-time-images-from-space.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nataraj Dasgupta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-12:/scipy-2021/predicting-the-economic-impact-of-covid-19-using-real-time-images-from-space.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this Talk, we will discuss the process of analysing terabytes of GeoTIFF images of surface lights on Earth from space at scale using Multiprocessing, geospatial, image-processing and raster libraries on high-performance AWS instances. Second, we will discuss how the data can then be used with Machine Learning libraries …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this Talk, we will discuss the process of analysing terabytes of GeoTIFF images of surface lights on Earth from space at scale using Multiprocessing, geospatial, image-processing and raster libraries on high-performance AWS instances. Second, we will discuss how the data can then be used with Machine Learning libraries to predict GDP and other economic metrics, especially during supply-demand shocks like COVID-19. In a recent analysis, using this approach, we accurately predicted the GDP impact in India during COVID-19 with a 99.5% accuracy, much ahead of official announcements, compared to 67% accuracy of estimates from leading investment banks. Overall, the Talk covers 4 disciplines: 1) computer science - TB-scale parallel processing using Python/Linux, 2) stats/ml - geospatial statistics &amp;amp; econometrics, 3) engineering - high-performance cloud computing and 4) finance - economics of supply-demand shocks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2021"></category></entry></feed>