<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cartopy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/cartopy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cartopy is a Python package which builds on Proj.4 to define coordinate
reference systems for the transformation and visualisation of geospatial
data. It has a simple matplotlib interface for publication quality
visualisation. This talk will outline some of cartopy's functionality
and demonstrate some practical applications within the realm of
scientific presentation of geospatial data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The practice of representing geospatial data upon a flat surface is
known as cartography, and the topological implications of projecting
fundamentally 3D data onto a 2 dimensional surface has been the
challenge of map-makers since time immemorial. Geospatial visualisation
software is often implemented without consideration for the 3rd
dimension and this commonly results in problems around the dateline or
at the poles. For small areas these problems are often not apparent and
mostly surmountable, but at a global scale, such as when visualising
output from GCMs (General circulation models), the underlying
representation must be addressed head-on in order to visualise the data
&amp;quot;impact free&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cartopy is a Python package which builds on top of Proj.4 to define
coordinate reference systems for the transformation and visualisation of
geospatial data. As well as the fundamental transformations there is
also a matplotlib interface allowing easy generation of maps with the
same publication quiality expected of matplotlib. Cartopy employs
several techniques to handle geospatial data correctly, including true
spherical interpolation for raster data, and Shapely geometry
interpolate-and-cut transformations for geospatial vector data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will outline some of the capabilities of cartopy, and continue
onto its practical application within the realm of scientific
presentation of geospatial data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Richard Hattersley</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/cartopy.html</guid></item></channel></rss>