<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Adam Zíka</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Representation is King: The Journey to Quality Dialog Embeddings</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/representation-is-king-the-journey-to-quality-dialog-embeddings.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2A on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representation is King: The Journey to Quality Dialog Embeddings by Adam Zíka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/representation-is-king-the-journey-to-quality-dialog-embeddings"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/representation-is-king-the-journey-to-quality-dialog-embeddings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In natural language processing, embeddings are crucial for understanding textual data. In this talk, we’ll explore sentence embeddings and their application in dialog systems. We'll focus on a use case involving the classification of dialogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll demonstrate the necessity of sentence transformers for this problem, specifically utilizing one of the top-performing small-sized sentence transformers. We will show how to fine-tune this model with both labeled and unlabeled dialog data, using the SentenceTransformers Python framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is practical, packed with easy-to-follow examples, and aimed at building intuition around this topic. While some basic knowledge of Transformers would be beneficial, it is not required. Newcomers are also welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Zíka</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/representation-is-king-the-journey-to-quality-dialog-embeddings.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>