<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ramón Huidobro</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Una serie de relatos de mentoring</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/una-serie-de-relatos-de-mentoring.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Espero poder motivar a los participantes a probar mentorear.
El esquema que propongo:
- Clarificar la diferencia entre enseñar y mentorear
- Ser mentor Voluntario (Ejemplos propios: programando con menores, Rails Girls Summer of Code, talleres)
- Buenas prácticas de mentor
- En el lugar del trabajo (Integracion, entrenaje)
- Concluciones, lectura adicional
Aportes:
- La responsabilidad de dejar una buena impresión
- Estimular buenos hábitos
- Apoyar al mentee
- Aprender juntos y admitir cuando uno no sabe algo
- Ser una persona buena para escuchar
- Como y donde poder empezar a mentorear
- Comunidades de práctica
- Demostrar el proceso de solución de problemas
- Compartir la alegría de compartir el conocimiento
Llevo 8 años de experiencia trabajando con menores programando, participando en talleres introduciéndole a la gente la programación.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ramón Huidobro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-23:/djangocon-us-2021/una-serie-de-relatos-de-mentoring.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>There's More to Open Source than Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/theres-more-to-open-source-than-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source software has always been about more than just code. While the technical contributions of developers are critical to the success of an open source project, there are countless other ways that people can contribute to the community. From documentation and translation to community management and design, non-code contributions are essential to building a healthy and sustainable open source ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the many different ways that people can contribute to open source beyond writing code. We'll discuss the importance of diverse perspectives and skill sets in creating a thriving open source community, and provide examples of successful projects that have leveraged non-code contributions to achieve their goals. We'll also offer practical tips and advice for those interested in getting involved in open source but who may not have coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, attendees will have a deeper understanding of the many ways that they can contribute to open source, and how their unique skills and talents can help to build a stronger and more inclusive community. They will leave with a renewed sense of excitement and motivation to get involved in open source, regardless of their technical background.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ramón Huidobro</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-17:/djangocon-us-2023/theres-more-to-open-source-than-code.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>New dev, old codebase: A series of mentorship stories</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/new-dev-old-codebase-a-series-of-mentorship-stories.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My aim with this talk is to inspire folks to try a hand at mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll cover the example of peers having attended a Rails Girls workshop and then a few months later being a mentor at one. Mentorship is relative, and loads of initiatives are structured this way! That being said, I believe the intended audience can be relative newcomers to programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outline is as follows:
* Clarifications: Mentorship vs training vs teaching
* Volunteering mentorship (Personal examples: Teaching children, Rails Girls Summer of Code, workshops)
* Mentorship best practices
* At the workplace (Onboarding a junior developer to a recent codebase)
* Conclusions, further reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeaways/topics covered include:
* Responsibility in leaving an impression on a newer programmer
* Encouraging good habits
* Being supportive
* Learning alongside mentees
* Admitting when you don’t know the answer or the solution to something
* Letting mentees voice their ideas
* Starting out as a mentor (finding places to mentor)
* Communities of practise
* Showing mentees your problem-solving process
* Sharing the joy of sharing knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ramon Huidobro</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-24:/python-web-conf-2022/new-dev-old-codebase-a-series-of-mentorship-stories.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>