<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynotes: Growing Community That Makes a Difference</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2016/keynotes-growing-community-that-makes-a-difference.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/ola-and-ola.pdf"&gt;http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/ola-and-ola.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ola Sendecka</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-08:pycon-israel-2016/keynotes-growing-community-that-makes-a-difference.html</guid></item><item><title>Stress Testing Your Code of Conduct...</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/stress-testing-your-code-of-conduct.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stress Testing Your Code of Conduct in Production by Ola Sendecka  &amp;amp; Baptiste Mispelon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django and Python communities have made codes of conducts a standard feature for many years now. But what exactly is a code of conduct? How does it work in practice? Why do we need them? What you should report? What are the consequences of having one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (Ola &amp;amp; Baptiste) have been working as CoC points of contacts at many conferences for the past few years: EuroPython 2014, DjangoCon Europe (2015 and 2016), and Django Under the Hood (2014, 2015). This has given us a unique insight into the inner workings and practical implications of codes of conducts and we want to share it with the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will start with a brief history of codes of conducts. From then, we'll go over some of the challenges and pitfalls of implementing a CoC in our communities or events. After that, we'll show how CoC work in practice and answer some common questions about them. We will then briefly talk about how lessons learnt from CoC world can be applied successfully in your daily job to grow supportive and strong teams. Finally, we'll finish off by showing the new standardized CoC processes that we've been working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this talk, we want to continue the process we've started of bringing CoC to the front of the stage, making them more transparent and less taboo. We believe that CoC are an essential part of any community and we'd like to share our vision for how we think ours should work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ola Sendecka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-13:djangocon-us-2016/stress-testing-your-code-of-conduct.html</guid></item><item><title>Keynote: It's Dangerous To Go Alone, Take This: The Power of a Community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/keynote-its-dangerous-to-go-alone-take-this-the-power-of-a-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ola Sitarska/Ola Sendecka - Keynote: It's Dangerous To Go Alone, Take This: The Power of a Community
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this keynote, Ola and Ola will take you on a fantastic journey to
the magical world of little Liz, who is totally enchanted by
technology. The story of Liz will show that with a little bit of
magic, curiosity, courage and hard work, you can defeat all the
obstacles standing in your way. You'll discover with her that making
big and scary things is easier when you're not doing them alone.
Because sometimes, one magical spell, the helpful hand of a friend or
this shiny sparkle is all it takes to make a dent in one's universe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ola Sitarska</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:europython-2015/keynote-its-dangerous-to-go-alone-take-this-the-power-of-a-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Into the rabbit hole</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/ola-sendecka-into-the-rabbit-hole-at-djangocon.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ola Sendecka</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:djangocon-europe-2015/ola-sendecka-into-the-rabbit-hole-at-djangocon.html</guid></item></channel></rss>