<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Alvaro Duran</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alvaro-duran.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Working in Units: How to Decouple the Database and Domain Layers in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/working-in-units-how-to-decouple-the-database-and-domain-layers-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alvaro Duran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/working-in-units-how-to-decouple-the-database-and-domain-layers-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — North Hall on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/working-in-units-how-to-decouple-the-database-and-domain-layers-in-python"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/working-in-units-how-to-decouple-the-database-and-domain-layers-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A crucial element of architecting a software application for scale is the collaboration of domain experts and developers. For that to happen, the application must separate the domain layer— where elements that represent the real world reside …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — North Hall on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/working-in-units-how-to-decouple-the-database-and-domain-layers-in-python"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/working-in-units-how-to-decouple-the-database-and-domain-layers-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A crucial element of architecting a software application for scale is the collaboration of domain experts and developers. For that to happen, the application must separate the domain layer— where elements that represent the real world reside—from the infrastructure layer—where these elements are translated into precise software processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the Fintech team at Kiwi.com, we are rearchitecting a critical service to accept more payment providers. As part of this refactor, we are adopting the Unit of Work pattern to disentangle domain entities from the database processes that represent them. This way, domain experts can share their knowledge with developers more easily, and developers can find opportunities for optimization without the involvement of domain experts in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will gain a solid understanding of how to implement the UoW pattern in their Python applications, how it fits into the broader context of DDD, and how to prepare their code for future growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Enterprise Python: Software That Lives Long And Prosper</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/enterprise-python-software-that-lives-long-and-prosper.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alvaro Duran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/enterprise-python-software-that-lives-long-and-prosper.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise Python: Software That Lives Long And Prosper by Alvaro Duran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/enterprise-python-software-that-lives-long-and-prosper"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/enterprise-python-software-that-lives-long-and-prosper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, as software continues to “eat the world”, applications increasingly grow in complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowhere else is this phenomenon more prevalent than in big organizations, which …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise Python: Software That Lives Long And Prosper by Alvaro Duran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/enterprise-python-software-that-lives-long-and-prosper"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/enterprise-python-software-that-lives-long-and-prosper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, as software continues to “eat the world”, applications increasingly grow in complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowhere else is this phenomenon more prevalent than in big organizations, which over time have hired more people to develop and maintain more features. There, it is no longer possible to have a complete mental model of what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise software, when unchecked, bloats and becomes brittle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, engineers build software to  keep complexity at bay, not to create it. When writing code, the goal is to make processes less labor intensive and more reliable. Yet, enterprise software has become a black hole for man-hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python disrupted Java to become the de facto programming language for enterprises precisely because it tackled this problem in a way that Java, or any other programming language, could not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is that so? This talk will dive deep into this exact question. What does Python offer that radically changed how software gets built in organizations, both big and small?. And why is it that newer languages that have come along, such as Go and Rust, haven’t been able to put a dent on its dominions, and have been forced to recede into niche use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for engineers who want to understand and leverage Python to its maximum maintainability potential. They intuitively understand that Python is a great tool for that, but are unsure as to how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a NoGIL Load Balancer in 30 minutes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/building-a-nogil-load-balancer-in-30-minutes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alvaro Duran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/building-a-nogil-load-balancer-in-30-minutes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Load balancers are widespread nowadays because most software systems are web-centric and service oriented. However, they’re extremely complex to build, because they must be very performant and use sophisticated algorithms to route traffic. Until recently, you couldn’t use Python to build one, because even though it would …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Load balancers are widespread nowadays because most software systems are web-centric and service oriented. However, they’re extremely complex to build, because they must be very performant and use sophisticated algorithms to route traffic. Until recently, you couldn’t use Python to build one, because even though it would make the code simpler, the GIL prevented multiple threads from executing Python at the same time. Now that you can, what are the practical implications in your day to day work? In this talk, we’re going to live code a load balancer in Python. This will help us understand the pros and cons of using modules such as asyncio, threading and concurrent.futures, and what changes when we remove the GIL from the way. Whether you’re building systems that demand concurrency (such as AI models or DevOps pipelines), or you’re just curious about how tools like gUnicorn or Starlette work under the hood, you’ll come away with practical insights on how to start off the NoGIL era on the right foot.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>