<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Eva Nanyonga</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Only reliable Data: Protecting Database Integrity</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/only-reliable-data-protecting-database-integrity.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Database transactions are incredibly important for the reliability of financial operations. The reliability and accuracy of these tarnsactions hinge upon robust database integrity measures. This presentation will explore key concepts essential to maintaining database integrity within financial ledger environments using the Django Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will gain insights into the following aspects:
1. Transaction Atomicity: Understanding how atomic database transactions are performed in Django to ensure data consistency.
2. Concurrency Control: Using the Django ORM to manage concurrent transactions to safeguard data against corruption.
3. Durability through Logging: Performing transaction logging to ensuring help teams recover from failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will address real-world challenges and considerations in implementing and maintaining database integrity using the Django framework. Practical examples and case studies will be shared to illustrate the application of database integrity with the help of the Django ORM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the attendee is a database administrator or a developer, this session will provide valuable insights into the foundational principles and strategies for upholding database integrity in critical financial environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eva Nanyonga</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-24:/djangocon-us-2024/only-reliable-data-protecting-database-integrity.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>