<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Elena Romashkova</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_elena-romashkova.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Climate Model Evaluation Workflow Built on Jupyter Notebooks | SciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/climate-model-evaluation-workflow-built-on-jupyter-notebooks-scipy-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elena Romashkova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/climate-model-evaluation-workflow-built-on-jupyter-notebooks-scipy-2023.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project introduces an extensible workflow used to evaluate climate model output using collections of Jupyter notebooks. The workflow supports parametrizing and batch-executing notebooks using Papermill, in conjunction with developing notebooks interactively. Additional features include integration with Dask and caching intermediate data products generated by notebooks. The final product …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project introduces an extensible workflow used to evaluate climate model output using collections of Jupyter notebooks. The workflow supports parametrizing and batch-executing notebooks using Papermill, in conjunction with developing notebooks interactively. Additional features include integration with Dask and caching intermediate data products generated by notebooks. The final product of the workflow can automatically be built into a Jupyter book for easy presentation and shareability. While it was initially developed for climate modeling, the flexible and extensible nature of this framework makes it adaptable to any kind of data analysis work, and the presentation will highlight this capability.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>