<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jeff Wagner</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jeff-wagner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Open FF: next generation force fields with open data, open software, and open science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/open-ff-next-generation-force-fields-with-open-data-open-software-and-open-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Wagner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/open-ff-next-generation-force-fields-with-open-data-open-software-and-open-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Open Force Field (OpenFF) initiative was formed to build a new generation of force fields for molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using modern data-driven techniques. Openness is one of our fundamental founding principles, and everything we produce is released openly and accessibly so that the community can validate, modify …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Open Force Field (OpenFF) initiative was formed to build a new generation of force fields for molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using modern data-driven techniques. Openness is one of our fundamental founding principles, and everything we produce is released openly and accessibly so that the community can validate, modify, or extend our work. Here we introduce some flagship packages in our ecosystem and the advances they have enabled in force field science and MD workflows. These include fitting custom functional forms, exploring the addition of off-site charges, and using neural networks to assign charges to protein-ligand systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>