<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ekhtiar-syed.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) and Visualization Techniques for Image Segmentation Challenges</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/exploratory-data-analysis-eda-and-visualization-techniques-for-image-segmentation-challenges.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ekhtiar Syed</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-30:pydata-eindhoven-2019/exploratory-data-analysis-eda-and-visualization-techniques-for-image-segmentation-challenges.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We tend to skip the step of exploring and analysing the data while
working with images. In this talk, we will look at EDA and visualisation
techniques for image segmentation tasks by reviewing three different
competition I have participated recently on Kaggle. I will also
summarise with a guideline for EDA and visualisation for image
segmentation challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer vision, image segmentation is the process of assigning
labels to every pixel of an image. An example use case of this could be
identifying some kind of defect from an image where every pixel is
labeled ok or not ok. Data for image segmentation typically comes in two
parts: the image data and mask to label the class and area of interest.
In practice, we label each pixel by building a deep learning model to
automatically produce the mask as an output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For traditional datasets, like text data, understanding the data by
doing an exploratory data analysis (EDA) is almost a mandatory step
before doing any modelling. However, for image segmentation tasks, this
step often goes missing. This is partly because as the input data is
literally images, there is less opportunity to be creative. Of course we
can print out a few images, and the masks; but this will not give us the
whole story. As we often skip EDA and jump right to modelling without
understanding the content of the data, we less aware about different
training strategies for building our model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have participated in three image segmentation competitions
on Kaggle, which were were very interesting on their own. For example,
one of the competition challenge was to identify and label pneumothorax,
a type of lung inflammation, from chest x rays of the patient. For all
three competitions I created notebooks to perform exploratory data
analysis (EDA) before creating a model. The analysis from these
notebooks brought a lot of useful insights to the Kaggle community, and
helped them come up with better strategies to train the model they have
built. All three notebooks went on to receive a gold medal on Kaggle and
link to these notebooks are attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I want to walk the audience through the process of doing
exploratory data analysis and visualisation for image segmentation tasks
by reviewing the three kernels linked below. These kernels uses everyday
python libraries like Pandas, Open-CV, Matplotlib, Plotly, and MLxtend.
After walking through the examples from the kernel below, I will
summarise with a guideline, which others working with image segmentation
tasks can use as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaggle.com/ekhtiar/finding-pneumo-part-1-eda-and-unet"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/ekhtiar/finding-pneumo-part-1-eda-and-unet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaggle.com/ekhtiar/defect-area-segments-eda-with-plotly-fp-mining"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/ekhtiar/defect-area-segments-eda-with-plotly-fp-mining&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaggle.com/ekhtiar/eda-find-me-in-the-clouds"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/ekhtiar/eda-find-me-in-the-clouds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>