<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Driving simulation and data analysis of magnetic nanostructures through Jupyter Notebook</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/driving-simulation-and-data-analysis-of-magnetic-nanostructures-through-jupyter-notebook.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present ongoing work from a project that makes a particular computer
simulation (implemented in C++ and Tk/Tcl) accessible through a Python
interface, and through the Jupyter Notebook. The talk describes the
motivation and current status of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more detail, the computer simulation in question is the Object
Oriented Micromagnetic Modelling Framework
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://math.nist.gov/oommf/"&gt;OOMMF&lt;/a&gt;) which is likely the most
widely used micromagnetic simulation package. It can be driven through a
graphical (Tk) user interface or through a configuration file that
defines a simulation run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we first show a Python interface to OOMMF that allows the
driving of OOMMF simulations from a Python program or interpreter
prompt. This way we embed a widely used scientific code from 1990s in a
general purpose programming language
[&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.1063/1.4977225"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] and enable the full use of
the ecosystem of scientific libraries available for Python. For example,
design optimisation, specialised post-processing, and the creation of
figures can all be carried out using a single script; making the work
more easily reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, we integrate the Python interface to OOMMF into a Jupyter
notebook, so that all existing benefits of using Jupyter are inherited
for the use in computational micromagnetics, which is the reason we
named our code Jupyter- OOMMF (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://joommf.github.io/"&gt;JOOMMF&lt;/a&gt;). A
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tryjoommf.soton.ac.uk/"&gt;JupyterHub installation&lt;/a&gt; of the tool
reduces barriers in uptake, and all the code is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/joommf"&gt;on
github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss the benefits of driving computer simulation and data analysis
through Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is a part of the Jupyter-OOMMF (JOOMMF) activity in the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opendreamkit.org/"&gt;OpenDreamKit&lt;/a&gt; project and we acknowledge
financial support from Horizon 2020 European Research Infrastructures
project (676541). The work is also supported by the EPSRC CDT in Next
Generation Computational Modelling EP/L015382/1, and the EPSRC grants
EP/M022668/1 and EP/N032128/1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional context: micromagnetic modelling is a key research method
in academia and industry to support development of high-capacity
magnetic storage devices that are cheap, fast, and reliable, and to
enable research into future alternative storage and processing
technologies such as spintronics. The OOMMF modelling package has been
used in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://math.nist.gov/oommf/oommf_cites.html"&gt;over 2500
publications&lt;/a&gt; since
1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Beg, M., Pepper, R. A., and Fangohr, H. User interfaces for
computational science: A domain specific language for OOMMF embedded in
Python. AIP Advances 7, 056025 (2017), &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.1063/1.4977225"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1063/1.4977225&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hans Fangohr</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/driving-simulation-and-data-analysis-of-magnetic-nanostructures-through-jupyter-notebook.html</guid><category>Data Science</category><category>Jupyter</category><category>Programming</category><category>Python</category><category>Science</category></item></channel></rss>