<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Gabriel Kuettel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_gabriel-kuettel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Real-World Problems Blockchain Actually Solves (and How to Code Them in Python) (Sponsor: Algorand)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/real-world-problems-blockchain-actually-solves-and-how-to-code-them-in-python-sponsor-algorand.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriel Kuettel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-15:/pycon-us-2025/real-world-problems-blockchain-actually-solves-and-how-to-code-them-in-python-sponsor-algorand.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll zero in on real-world problems blockchain genuinely solves. We'll cut through the jargon and focus on when blockchain makes sense and when it doesn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything we build will use Python, using libraries and patterns you already know, plus a few lightweight tools to interact with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll zero in on real-world problems blockchain genuinely solves. We'll cut through the jargon and focus on when blockchain makes sense and when it doesn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything we build will use Python, using libraries and patterns you already know, plus a few lightweight tools to interact with the Algorand blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll work through hands-on examples: coding trust into peer-to-peer payment systems for underbanked regions, building fractional ownership for previously illiquid assets, and creating self-sovereign digital identity systems that empower users with ownership of their credentials. These aren't hypotheticals—companies are running these solutions in production today, and we'll break down how they do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect a session that meets you where you are: practical, approachable, and 100% Python. By the end, you'll see where blockchain fits into your toolkit—not as a magic bullet, but as a practical option for specific, thorny problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>