<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The story of a 52 year-old database</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/the-story-of-a-52-year-old-database.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A historical look at the Cambridge Structural Database – The World’s Repository of Organic Chemical Structures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Abstract:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Some notable points looking back along the timeline of database
technology:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1995 - The first version of MySQL released.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1987 - SQL became a standard of the International Organization for
Standardization (ISO).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1986 - SQL became a standard of the American National Standards
Institute (ANSI).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1983 - Andreas Reuter and Theo Härder coined the acronym ACID.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1974 - The first prototype version of the INGRES relational DBMS
released.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1971 - The first microprocessor launched - the Intel 4004.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1970 - The relational model of data was proposed by E.F. Codd.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1967 - Introduction of the DEC PDP-10 computer.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- 1965 - Compilation of the Cambridge Structural Database (CSD) began.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cambridge Structural Database (CSD) was initiated as response to an
“information explosion” with aims including “the compilation of a
numerical database relating to organocarbon crystal structures”. Five
decades later, this database is still curated and widely distributed
within the scientific community. The CSD is probably the oldest
numerical database actively maintained and used today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1966, the database filled one volume of a printed book. In 1991, the
database used 196Mbytes. Today, a SQLite version of the database uses
6.4Gbytes. Along the way, the CCDC has driven many computational and
scientific advances. E.g., the first practical 3D chemical search system
was developed by the CCDC. Learn about past innovations and technical
foundations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all very interesting, but what does that have to do with Python?
The CSD Python API is a mechanism for accessing the data - alongside a
wide range of molecular modelling and cheminformatic algorithms. This
API is gaining rapid adoption in both academic and industrial chemistry
communities. Learn how we can better serve our users thanks to Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stewart Adcock</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-17:pycon-uk-2018/the-story-of-a-52-year-old-database.html</guid></item></channel></rss>