<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_krystian-zielinski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>TrashAsistant: A kivy App, which uses Deep Neural Networks, for helping trash segregation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/trashasistant-a-kivy-app-which-uses-deep-neural-networks-for-helping-trash-segregation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olgun AYDIN</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-12:pydata-warsaw-2019/trashasistant-a-kivy-app-which-uses-deep-neural-networks-for-helping-trash-segregation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have developed a mobile application using kivy framework. It uses
Deep Neural Networks to help segregating trashes. Thanks to this app,
before throwing trash to specific bin, you will know which trash bin you
should throw to. Only thing you will do is just taking a photo of the
trash via the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Municipality in Gdansk started to be really strict about segregating
trash last year. They are checking segregating performance of
residential buildings and providing opportunity to pay less tax to those
people who live in the buildings which have better segregation
performance. Also, they are fining companies which don't follow the
segregation instructions. Even though, instructions are well defined
still sometimes people are confused to decide which trash bin they
should use. For example, empty carton of milk seems like it should go to
the bin for paper, but actually it should go to the bin for plastic and
metals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have realized that having a mobile app which will guide people about
this purpose would be very helpful. We have developed deep neural
networks(DNN) using transfer learning. DNNs have been trained by using
keras Python library. After having good performed model, kivy app has
been developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this speech, we would like to talk about transfer learning, Python
keras library, kivy framework, obstacles we had and future plans about
additional features to the application.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>