<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tim Rogers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>"You never get a second chance to make a first impression": writing great "getting started" documentation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-prague-2017/you-never-get-a-second-chance-to-make-a-first-impression-writing-great-getting-started-documentation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the old saying goes, “you never get a second chance to make a first
impression”. When you first meet someone new (not least at a conference
for documentarians!), those first few moments set the tone. In exactly
the same way, the experience your user has when they first “meet” your
product and get to grips with it will set the tone for your entire
relationship with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As documentarians, we so often focus on building detailed and exhaustive
“reference” documentation, but in doing that, we forget to provide the
right kind of “getting started” experience for a user brand new to our
product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At GoCardless, we spent the first years of the life of our platform
focused on building high-quality reference documentation. But in Summer
2016, we kicked off a big piece of work on a new set of resources: a
“getting started” guide for our API, getting the user from
nought-to-sixty on our developer platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the right first impression, we had to turn things on their head
and think from the reader’s perspective. From this perspective, what
we’ll write and build looks very different to our “reference”
documentation, seeking not only to teach the user how to use our
product, but also to explain the fundamental concepts behind it and to
bring the user to the all-important “aha!” moment where they see the
value in what we’re offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll go through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the fundamental differences between “reference” and “getting started”
documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lessons we learnt on the way as we experimented and spent
extensive time with end users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what we built&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the results — from our users’ perspective, and in terms of how we
build demand within the company for further “getting started” content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Rogers</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-11:/write-the-docs-prague-2017/you-never-get-a-second-chance-to-make-a-first-impression-writing-great-getting-started-documentation.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Prague 2017</category></item></channel></rss>