<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Colby Ford</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_colby-ford.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Succeed in the Life Sciences with R/Python and the Cloud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/succeed-in-the-life-sciences-with-rpython-and-the-cloud.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Colby Ford</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/succeed-in-the-life-sciences-with-rpython-and-the-cloud.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk covers best practices and lessons learned surrounding the use of R and Python by technical teams in the cloud, focusing on Posit Workbench, Azure ML, and Databricks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the life sciences, whether it's pharma, biotech, research, or another type of organization, we are unique in that we …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk covers best practices and lessons learned surrounding the use of R and Python by technical teams in the cloud, focusing on Posit Workbench, Azure ML, and Databricks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the life sciences, whether it's pharma, biotech, research, or another type of organization, we are unique in that we blend scientific knowledge with technical skills to extract insights from large, complex datasets. In the cloud, we can architect solutions to help us scale, automate, and collaborate. Interestingly, the use of R and Python by bioinformatics, genomics, biostatistics, and data science teams can be challenging in a cloud-first world where all the data is somewhere other than your laptop (like a data lake).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will share best practices and lessons learned surrounding the use of R and Python by technical teams in the cloud. We'll focus on the use of Posit Workbench and RStudio on various cloud services such as Azure ML and Databricks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuple, The Cloud Genomics Company: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tuple.xyz"&gt;https://tuple.xyz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>