<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jonas Kübler</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jonas-kubler.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Kernel Conditional Moment Test via Maximum Moment Restriction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/kernel-conditional-moment-test-via-maximum-moment-restriction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Krikamol Muandet</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/kernel-conditional-moment-test-via-maximum-moment-restriction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Kernel Conditional Moment Test via Maximum Moment Restriction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krikamol Muandet (Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems)*; Wittawat Jitkrittum (Google); Jonas Kübler (MPI for Intelligent Systems, Tübingen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a new family of specification tests called kernel conditional moment (KCM) tests. Our tests are built on a novel representation of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Kernel Conditional Moment Test via Maximum Moment Restriction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krikamol Muandet (Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems)*; Wittawat Jitkrittum (Google); Jonas Kübler (MPI for Intelligent Systems, Tübingen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a new family of specification tests called kernel conditional moment (KCM) tests. Our tests are built on a novel representation of conditional moment restrictions in a reproducing kernel Hilbert space (RKHS) called conditional moment embedding (CMME). After transforming the conditional moment restrictions into a continuum of unconditional counterparts, the test statistic is defined as the maximum moment restriction (MMR) within the unit ball of the RKHS. We show that the MMR not only fully characterizes the original conditional moment restrictions, leading to consistency in both hypothesis testing and parameter estimation, but also has an analytic expression that is easy to compute as well as closed-form asymptotic distributions. Our empirical studies show that the KCM test has a promising finite-sample performance compared to existing tests.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>