<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jingge Zhu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jingge-zhu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Semi-Supervised Learning: the Case When Unlabeled Data is Equally Useful</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/semi-supervised-learning-the-case-when-unlabeled-data-is-equally-useful.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jingge Zhu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/semi-supervised-learning-the-case-when-unlabeled-data-is-equally-useful.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Semi-Supervised Learning: the Case When Unlabeled Data is Equally UsefulㅇㅇJingge Zhu (University of Melbourne)ㅇㅇSemi-supervised learning algorithms attempt to take advantage of relatively inexpensive unlabeled data to improve learning performance. In this work, we consider statistical models where the data distributions can be characterized by continuous parameters. We show …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Semi-Supervised Learning: the Case When Unlabeled Data is Equally UsefulㅇㅇJingge Zhu (University of Melbourne)ㅇㅇSemi-supervised learning algorithms attempt to take advantage of relatively inexpensive unlabeled data to improve learning performance. In this work, we consider statistical models where the data distributions can be characterized by continuous parameters. We show that under certain conditions on the distribution, unlabeled data is equally useful as labeled date in terms of learning rate. Specifically, let $n, m$ be the number of labeled and unlabeled data, respectively. It is shown that the learning rate of semi-supervised learning scales as  and scales as  whereas the learning rate of supervised learning scales as $O(1/n)$.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>