<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_peter-farrell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>BayPiggies July 2016 Talk at LinkedIn by Peter Farrell: Hacking Math Class with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/baypiggies-july-2016-talk-at-linkedin-by-peter-farrell-hacking-math-class-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Farrell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-21:bay-piggies/baypiggies-july-2016-talk-at-linkedin-by-peter-farrell-hacking-math-class-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Math instruction is stuck in the 19th Century and it's in dire need of modernization. Computer programming in Python has the potential to make math class more relevant, meaningful and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming can not only achieve the goals we've always had for math students - to be able to think computationally and build algebraic and geometric tools to solve problems - but it can be used to explore math topics beyond the reach of traditional methods. Using Python, students can create fractals, cellular automata and 3D models to help them learn math or science topics. And it looks cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://baypiggies.net"&gt;http://baypiggies.net&lt;/a&gt; for upcoming talks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Learning Math and Science Using Python (December 2013)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/learning-math-and-science-using-python-december-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Farrell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-12-19:bay-piggies/learning-math-and-science-using-python-december-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Peter Farrell
Topic: Learning Math and Science Using Python
Date: Dec-19-2013
Location: LinkedIn, Mtn. View&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
In 1980 Seymour Papert's Mindstorms suggested that everything meaningful in math education could be done using a computer. Mathematics teaching has yet to take full advantage of modern technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python should be in the toolbox of every student right from the beginning of algebra, not only because it makes arithmetic trivial but because it can facilitate deeper exploration of topics ranging from algebra to calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation we'll see how Python can be used to clarify difficult topics high school students are faced with in math and science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike outdated skills like factoring polynomials, working with functions is more valuable than ever thanks to computers and Python in particular because (forgive my oversimplification) in Python &amp;quot;everything is a function.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High school math and physics courses also demand a knowledge of vectors, so more teachers should take advantage of the 3-D possibilities of Visual Python to model situations using vectors. It will be shown how physical situations otherwise involving disheartening differential equations can be modeled and easily solved in VPython. Furthermore, conjectures which were previously difficult to prove in physics can be easily created and visually proven by high school students with a little Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker:
Peter Farrell has been a high school math teacher and tutor on the East Coast and the West Coast and even on the Equator. He's currently a STEM Instructor at four Summit Charter High Schools in the Bay Area through Learningtech.org&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>