<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sarah Kaiser</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sarah-kaiser.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Development Environment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/eternal-sunshine-of-the-spotless-development-environment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Kaiser</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-18:/pycascades-2023/eternal-sunshine-of-the-spotless-development-environment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;But it worked on machine&amp;quot; is one the most frustrating lines to hear when collaborating on a project. Creating and configuring reproducible environments is a major part of modern software development and had led to the popularity of tools like Docker to specify where and how code runs. Setting …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;But it worked on machine&amp;quot; is one the most frustrating lines to hear when collaborating on a project. Creating and configuring reproducible environments is a major part of modern software development and had led to the popularity of tools like Docker to specify where and how code runs. Setting up Docker and Development Containers in VS Code make it easy to configure not only the where the code runs, but also the developer workspace. Setting up these tools can reduce effort for maintainers, bootstrap contributors, and make running events like workshops or sprints easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will cover why setting up container infrastructure like Docker can be useful for your project, and how you can extend that with Dev Containers to configure a full development experience in VS Code. We will also take a look at two common OSS project scenarios and how workflows for using Docker, Dev Containers and Codespaces make things easier. No container experience required, and some knowledge of VS Code helpful, but not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>I declare an environment! - Reproducibility with and without Docker</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2024/i-declare-an-environment-reproducibility-with-and-without-docker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Kaiser</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-04-06:/pycascades-2024/i-declare-an-environment-reproducibility-with-and-without-docker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A software project being called &amp;quot;reproducible&amp;quot; can mean a lot of things, but usually includes a description of how and where the code in your project can be run. Often this means including Python virtual environment, a Conda environment, or even a Docker container to help others replicate your …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A software project being called &amp;quot;reproducible&amp;quot; can mean a lot of things, but usually includes a description of how and where the code in your project can be run. Often this means including Python virtual environment, a Conda environment, or even a Docker container to help others replicate your work. In this talk I will introduce some of the most common ways the scientific Python community approaches reproducibility, and what are the advantages and disadvantages of the approaches. I will also share a new way that you can make not only your Python code but your development machine reproducible without Docker containers with a tool called Nix. I will also show an example of using a Nix defined operating system (NixOS) with Docker containers to run my home lab.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Eternal sunshine of the spotless development environment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/eternal-sunshine-of-the-spotless-development-environment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Kaiser</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/eternal-sunshine-of-the-spotless-development-environment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It says the package is not installed?” is a common refrain when working
on software projects, especially in Python. Creating and configuring
reproducible environments is a major part of modern software development
and has led to the popularity of tools like Docker to specify where and
how code runs …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It says the package is not installed?” is a common refrain when working
on software projects, especially in Python. Creating and configuring
reproducible environments is a major part of modern software development
and has led to the popularity of tools like Docker to specify where and
how code runs. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://containers.dev/"&gt;Development (Dev) Container&lt;/a&gt;
are an open specification that extends Docker images to make it easy to
configure not only the where the code runs, but also the developer
workspace in your preferred editors or toolchains like VS Code, PyCharm,
or DevPod. Setting up Dev Containers for your projects can reduce
maintainer overhead of OSS projects, bootstrap contributors, and make
running events like workshops or sprints go more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will briefly cover why setting up container
infrastructure can be useful for isolating your project environments and
dig into how you can extend that with Dev Containers to configure a
complete development experience using VS Code. We will look at two
common OSS project situations, onboarding and workshops, to see how
workflows for using Dev Containers and other supporting tools make
things easier. No container experience required, brief familiarity with
VS Code is helpful, but not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>