<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Charles Blackmon-Luca</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_charles-blackmon-luca.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Accelerating ETL/SQL Workloads with RAPIDS-Dask + Dask-SQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/accelerating-etlsql-workloads-with-rapids-dask-dask-sql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Charles Blackmon-Luca</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/accelerating-etlsql-workloads-with-rapids-dask-dask-sql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NVIDIA® RAPIDS suite of open-source software libraries enable end-to-end data science pipelines to run entirely on GPUs, offering massive parallelism, high memory bandwidth and high speed interconnect through user-friendly PyData APIs. Coupled with Dask, a Python library for distributed computing, RAPIDS libraries can achieve even higher performance by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NVIDIA® RAPIDS suite of open-source software libraries enable end-to-end data science pipelines to run entirely on GPUs, offering massive parallelism, high memory bandwidth and high speed interconnect through user-friendly PyData APIs. Coupled with Dask, a Python library for distributed computing, RAPIDS libraries can achieve even higher performance by scaling out across multiple GPUs and machines. And now, with the introduction of Dask-SQL, SQL users can take full advantage of this software stack to accelerate their data science workloads. This talk will present an overview of RAPIDS-Dask and introduce Dask-SQL, a developing SQL interface for the RAPIDS-Dask ecosystem which can leverage both CPU and GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>