<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_skipper-seabold.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>What's the Science in Data Science?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2018/whats-the-science-in-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Skipper Seabold</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-23:pydata-la-2018/whats-the-science-in-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gold standard for validating any scientific assumption is to run an
experiment. Data science isn’t any different. Unfortunately, it’s not
always possible to design the perfect experiment. In this talk, we’ll
take a realistic look at measurement using tools from the social
sciences to conduct quasi-experiments with observational data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Python for Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/introduction-to-python-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Skipper Seabold</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/introduction-to-python-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial introduces users to Python for data science. From data cleaning to model building, we will work through a series of short examples together using some real-world health inspection data. Attendees will have their hands on the keyboard, using the Python standard library and pandas to clean data and scikit-learn to build some models.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Dask for Parallel Computing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/using-dask-for-parallel-computing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Skipper Seabold</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-26:pydata-chicago-2016/using-dask-for-parallel-computing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dask is a relatively new library for parallel computing in Python. It builds around familiar data structures to users of the PyData stack and enables them to scale up their work on one or many machines. This tutorial will introduce users to the core concepts of dask by working through some example problems. The tutorial will be distributed via Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="dask"></category><category term="parallel"></category><category term="parallel computing"></category></entry><entry><title>statsmodels</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/statsmodels.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Skipper Seabold</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-17:scipy-2012/statsmodels.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will give users an overview of the capabilities of
statsmodels, including how to conduct exploratory data analysis, fit
statistical models, and check that the modeling assumptions are met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of Python in data analysis and statistics is growing rapidly. It
is not uncommon now for researchers to conduct data cleaning steps in
Python and then move to some other software to estimate statistical
models. Statsmodels, however, is a Python module that attempts to bridge
this gap and allow users to estimate statistical models, perform
statistical tests, and conduct data exploration in Python. Researchers
across fields such as economics and the social sciences to finance and
engineering may find that statsmodels meets their needs for statistical
computing and data analysis in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All examples in this tutorial will use real data. Attendees are expected
to have some familiarity with statistical methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this knowledge attendees will be ready to jump in and use Python
for applied statistical analysis and will have an idea how they can
extend statsmodels for their own needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="advanced"></category></entry><entry><title>Classification using Pandas and Scikit-Learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/classification-using-pandas-and-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Skipper Seabold</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/classification-using-pandas-and-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will be a tutorial-style talk demonstrating how to use pandas and
scikit-learn to do classification tasks. We will do some data munging
and visualization using pandas and matplotlib. Then we will introduce
some of the different classifiers in scikit-learn and show how to
include them into a classification pipeline to produce the best
predictive model. Interactive IPython/Jupyter notebooks will be
provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>