<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Drishti Jain</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Illuminate Data with Visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/illuminate-data-with-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will walk through the concept of Data mining and visualization right from the basics. A free and open source tool for data visualization -Orange from a beginner to an advance level will also be covered. We will also cover the concepts of data mining and data warehousing to gain a deeper insight into the concept and help understand the process form the core level.
Data mining refers to an autonomous process of discovery of previously unknown patterns which are valid, potentially useful or novel from large database.Orange is Open source machine learning, data visualization and data mining toolkit.
Orange features an interactive data visualization platform. The platform provides a wide variety of data analysis and visualization by statistical distributions, scatter plots, box plots, decision trees, heat maps, linear projections to name a few. By carefully selecting attributes in the dataset we can drill down multidimensional data to 2D. It helps in fast prototyping of data analysis workflow.
The talk will also cover the recent and diverse existing use cases of Orange like:
1. Analysis of hyperspectra images from the Ryugu asteroid
2. Language support for 50 languages
3. bioinformatics, and many more.
By the end of the talk attendees would have a clear knowledge of
- What Orange is
- How they can use it in work or side projects
- Be able to use it as a separate tool or embed it as a library in their existing Python projects
And use all functionalities of Orange of data mining and visualization to the fullest!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Drishti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-22:/djangocon-us-2021/illuminate-data-with-visualization.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>Django's Data Science Makeover: Integrating D3.js and Bokeh for Data Visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/djangos-data-science-makeover-integrating-d3js-and-bokeh-for-data-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is a versatile web framework that can be used for building a wide range of applications, from blogs to e-commerce platforms. In recent years, there has been a growing demand for web-based data visualization, which requires integrating data visualization libraries with web frameworks like Django. This talk will demonstrate how to use D3.js and Bokeh, two popular data visualization libraries, with Django to create dynamic and interactive visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start by discussing the basics of Django and data visualization with D3.js and Bokeh. We will then dive into the specifics of integrating these libraries with Django. You will learn how to leverage Django's powerful database and ORM to feed data to your visualizations, and how to customize your visualizations with CSS and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also cover some advanced topics, such as real-time data streaming with Django Channels and integrating machine learning models with your visualizations. By the end of this talk, you will have a solid understanding of how to integrate D3.js and Bokeh with Django for your data science projects. You will leave with the skills needed to create stunning and interactive visualizations that can be embedded in your Django web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Drishti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-18:/djangocon-us-2023/djangos-data-science-makeover-integrating-d3js-and-bokeh-for-data-visualization.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Pythonic Play: Crafting Interactive Worlds with Python in Game Development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2024/pythonic-play-crafting-interactive-worlds-with-python-in-game-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Embark on a thrilling journey into the realm of game development where the elegance of Python meets the excitement of interactive experiences! In this talk, I will unravel the captivating world of Python game development, exploring the tools, techniques, and creative possibilities that make Python a formidable language for crafting immersive games.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Drishti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-04-06:/pycascades-2024/pythonic-play-crafting-interactive-worlds-with-python-in-game-development.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2024</category></item><item><title>PyLadies Panel: Experiences and Roles within the Tech Community and Open Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/pyladies-panel-experiences-and-roles-within-the-tech-community-and-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tammy Do, Drishti Jain, Parul Gupta, Lilinoe Harbottle, and Nasim&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tammy Do</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-09:/pycascades-2025/pyladies-panel-experiences-and-roles-within-the-tech-community-and-open-source.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2025</category></item><item><title>Python for Planet Earth: Climate Modeling and Sustainability in Action</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/python-for-planet-earth-climate-modeling-and-sustainability-in-action.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover how Python is shaping the future of our planet in this engaging talk. I’ll explore how Python is used to model climate change, monitor environmental shifts, and drive sustainability projects. See how this powerful language is enabling scientists and developers to turn data into actionable insights, helping to tackle some of the most pressing challenges facing our world today. Whether you’re a coder or a climate enthusiast, this session will show you how Python can make a real difference for the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Drishti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-09:/pycascades-2025/python-for-planet-earth-climate-modeling-and-sustainability-in-action.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2025</category></item><item><title>When life gives you Orange, make data speak volumes! - Drishti Jain</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2019/when-life-gives-you-orange-make-data-speak-volumes-drishti-jain.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Drishti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-06-15:/pycon-thailand-2019/when-life-gives-you-orange-make-data-speak-volumes-drishti-jain.html</guid><category>PyCon Thailand 2019</category></item></channel></rss>