<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_allison-bolen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-28T13:45:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>What's the Buzz with Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/whats-the-buzz-with-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-28T13:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T13:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allison Bolen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/whats-the-buzz-with-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Honeybee colonies throughout North America have declined precipitously
due to parasites, pesticides, and poor nutrition over the past two
decades. Monitoring hive health autonomously assists beekeeper efforts.
We developed a model which automatically detects events in bee hive
weight data assisting data collection efforts improving data quality for
future machine learning models to be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pesticides, parasites, and poor nutrition, has led to the decline of
honeybee colonies throughout North America. A number of methods have
been proposed to combat the problem, with one here at Grand Valley State
University (GVSU) focusing on collecting hive weight data identifying
potential issues through data analytics. Currently, “citizen scientist”
beekeepers participate by collecting weight data from their hives
through the Bee Informed Partnership (BIP). Using Python3, Bokeh, SciKit
learn and Pandas we were able to produce a model using linear regression
that could predict patterns in weight data. Our short term goal for the
project was to create a model that could predict events and windows of
time where events could have occured to improve the data quality and
user engagement. The ultimate long term goal of this project is to
predict what kind of event occurred such as adding food to the hive,
harvesting honey, swarming events, and even parasite infestation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>