<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Paul Roeland</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_paul-roeland.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>MacGyvering your docs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2015/macgyvering-your-docs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Roeland</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-31:/write-the-docs-europe-2015/macgyvering-your-docs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So, your project needs better docs. For that, you'd need lots of
people. Professionalism. A well-thought out plan. All the tools. And a
whopping budget in both time and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you're sitting there, with just a few paperclips, seven moldy
Mentos mints, a strip of Duct tape, a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So, your project needs better docs. For that, you'd need lots of
people. Professionalism. A well-thought out plan. All the tools. And a
whopping budget in both time and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you're sitting there, with just a few paperclips, seven moldy
Mentos mints, a strip of Duct tape, a pencil and some nail polish
remover...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, hang on! There's also the combined experiences of generations of
people fighting seemingly insurmountable odds. From environmental
activists to LGBTQ people taking to the streets, we can draw on a rich
history of inspired individuals taking whatever is at hand, mixed with
some clever zaniness to quite fabulous effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what if we apply an activist mindset and some DIY hacking into our
process? What lessons can we learn from a world where TOC means Theory
Of Change, where working on a shoestring budget is the norm and where
empowering people to go beyond what they think they can do is considered
mission- critical?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear: the aim here is not to knock professionalism in docs, quite
the contrary! Yet, faced with a lack of resources, 'bend the rules and
get going' sure beats lethargy. Not to mention being fun...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(And before you think I'll be bringing back the dreaded mullet: the next
MacGyver will be a woman, according to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thenextmacgyver.com"&gt;http://thenextmacgyver.com&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Europe 2015"></category></entry></feed>