<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Anna Haensch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_anna-haensch.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Day 3 Lightning Talks | SciPy 2022</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/day-3-lightning-talks-scipy-2022.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lalitha Krishnamoorthy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/day-3-lightning-talks-scipy-2022.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Python for Global Applications: Law and Diplomacy Students</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/python-for-global-applications-law-and-diplomacy-students.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Karin Knudson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/python-for-global-applications-law-and-diplomacy-students.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students in fields like international affairs are increasingly seeking to gain proficiency in data science skills with Python. Such students have the potential to connect data science to its societal context in a sophisticated way. For educators working with such students to support this potential, it is essential to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students in fields like international affairs are increasingly seeking to gain proficiency in data science skills with Python. Such students have the potential to connect data science to its societal context in a sophisticated way. For educators working with such students to support this potential, it is essential to 1) welcome newcomers and center student perspectives and 2) consistently and authentically connect technical content with societal context. We present a framework for teaching Python based introductory data science skills in a highly contextualized and domain flexible environment, based on our experience teaching introductory data science to law and diplomacy students.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Small Town Police Accountability A Data Science Toolkit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/small-town-police-accountability-a-data-science-toolkit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Haensch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/small-town-police-accountability-a-data-science-toolkit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will share a Python library to obtain and analyze policing data, that was developed in conjunction with community activists, data scientists, social scientists and the Small Town Police Accountability (SToPA) Research Lab. We will showcase components of the SToPA library which use Python tools such …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will share a Python library to obtain and analyze policing data, that was developed in conjunction with community activists, data scientists, social scientists and the Small Town Police Accountability (SToPA) Research Lab. We will showcase components of the SToPA library which use Python tools such as web drivers, optical character recognition, geospatial mapping, machine learning and statistical sampling to better understand the policing landscape. The goal of this work is to present an easily replicable framework for analyzing police and community interactions with accessible on-ramps for activists, developers and researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>