<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Arcas - Using Python to access open research literature</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2017/arcas-using-python-to-access-open-research-literature.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Literature collection is a crucial process in all studies. It allows for the
comparison in the historical context of the research as well as how the
research is different or original from what others have done. Not several
years ago, assembling sources was not an easy task. A major part of the
problem was overcome with the creation of various scholarly databases and
collections that live on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of programming is that it allows repeated tasks such as harvesting
the web for data to be automatised; that is how the web scraping or web data
extraction was created. Similarly, enabling an automatised process to scrape
through the scholarly databases would greatly benefit researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has inspired the development of an open source library called Arcas
which allows for web scraping of academic articles using open access APIs.
APIs such PLOS, IEEE, arXiv etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proposal for EuroScipy 2017 is to introduce the library Arcas and how
scraping online APIs was implemented in a sustainable and reproducible manner
using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to test the abilities of the library a data set was collected on
a specific topic. I am also proposing to give a very brief analysis on this
data set using both supervised and unsupervised machine learning
algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nikoleta Evdokia Glynatsi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-31:euroscipy-2017/arcas-using-python-to-access-open-research-literature.html</guid><category>arcas</category></item><item><title>Prisoners, Cooperation and Spatial Structure</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/prisoners-cooperation-and-spatial-structure.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nikoleta Evdokia Glynatsi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be a brief introduction to Game Theory: the Prisoner's Dilemma, the tournaments that have been carried out since 1980 and the Axelrod library. Moreover, it will focus on my summer research which is on Spatial tournaments for the Iterated Prisoners Dilemma. It will mention some key points as to why spatial structure was chosen for further research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My contribution to the Axelrod library will be shown and how the results where analyzed and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nikoleta Evdokia Glynatsi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:pycon-uk-2016/prisoners-cooperation-and-spatial-structure.html</guid></item></channel></rss>