<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Chris Ward</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A documentation crash course for developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/a-documentation-crash-course-for-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many times have you come across an awesome looking library or tool that you're keen to work with in your own project but can't even begin to understand how to use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers are great at creating amazing and cutting-edge code, but not always so good and explaining themselves, and I want to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I want to draw upon my experience in writing tutorials and technical documentation to help you write clear, concise and usable documentation for your own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why write documentation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explaining your point and motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating context and meaning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing clear copy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating meaningful examples and tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation systems and formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making documentation part of build processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing Docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versioning of Docs and maintaining consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Ward</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-12:/pycon-sk-2017/a-documentation-crash-course-for-developers.html</guid><category>PyCon SK 2017</category></item><item><title>Documenting your Story - Crafting a good presentation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2015/documenting-your-story-crafting-a-good-presentation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst not a part of the core documentation of projects, presentations
and delivering them to the public are an essential part of spreading the
word about what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need to be as equally consistent with your messaging and style
guides, get to a key point effectively and also allow the presenter to
inject some personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially hard with technical projects where the 'story' is
either hard to explain or can't just end up sounding like a sales pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I will explore and explain my experiences as an
advocate for several open source projects, audience reactions to those
presentations and how I have iterated my presentations in sync with
changes to product and branding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Ward</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-31:/write-the-docs-europe-2015/documenting-your-story-crafting-a-good-presentation.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Europe 2015</category></item><item><title>Beyond Software - Learning from Other Technical Writers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2016/beyond-software-learning-from-other-technical-writers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of my technical writing work for software projects I have been
creating a board game. A board game also requires mechanics to function
and players to clearly understand how these mechanics work to use and
appreciate fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my research for writing game manuals I looked at manuals for
furniture, electronics, and cars to see how they explain to users how to
setup and use their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I will look at how the technical writing skills of
different industries can learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game Manuals and tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assembly instructions (e.g. those wonderful Ikea inserts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Manuals for electronics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as part of looking at these case studies, the presentation will
cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iconography vs Text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The limitations of updating print manuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing language and cultural colloquialisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying what needs to be said and what doesn't&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And by the end of the presentation I hope that everyone will have learnt
a lot from each other and realize that we're all trying to achieve the
same thing(s).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Ward</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:/write-the-docs-europe-2016/beyond-software-learning-from-other-technical-writers.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Europe 2016</category></item><item><title>Documentation beyond words</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-prague-2017/documentation-beyond-words.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I will explore other ways to communicate concepts
beyond words to show that documentation needn't just be about technical
writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the presentation I will briefly cover theories and
principles behind forms of communication and what documentarians can
learn from them. Topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portraying meaning in images: Iconography, maps, manuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-verbal conversation: Body language, ways of speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fidelity: Sketch notes, simplicity, style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During each of these topics I will present in the style of the topic, so
expect something a little different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second practical part of the presentation I will take elements of
the theory and applying them practically. I will start by looking at
screenshots and diagrams. When and how to use them, what they should
show, and how to manage them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I'll cover taking screenshots to the next level with animated gifs
and screen recordings that show clear user flows and expected results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally in this part of the presentation I will cover interactive
documentation, and the options for allowing readers to directly
manipulate and experiment with documentation and directly see inputs and
outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, our work typically appears on one of the most dynamic
platforms (the web) that has ever existed, let's all do more with it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Ward</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-11:/write-the-docs-prague-2017/documentation-beyond-words.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Prague 2017</category></item></channel></rss>