<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Joel Lord</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MongoDB and Python, a Perfect Match</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/mongodb-and-python-a-perfect-match.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MongoDB and Python, a Perfect Match - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any modern web application needs a database. Why hassle with an old
database when you can easily use modern technology? MongoDB works
perfectly well with Python. Learn how in this talk. Is your application
looking for a database to hang out with? Search no more! MongoDB and
Python are a perfect match. By leveraging the native Python driver,
accessing a MongoDB database is easier than ever. In this presentation,
the attendees will learn what a document database is and how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Joel Lord&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joel Lord</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/mongodb-and-python-a-perfect-match.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>apis</category><category>databases</category><category>mongodb</category></item><item><title>I Don't Care About Security (And Neither Should You)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/i-dont-care-about-security-and-neither-should-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember when setting up a login page was easy? It seems like nowadays
it can take weeks to start a project -- creating a signup form, a login
form, a password recovery screen, and all the validation in between. And
you haven't even started on security considerations yet. During this
presentation, the attendees will be introduced to OpenID Connect and
OAuth. They will also learn how to leverage these technologies to create
more secure applications. Most importantly, they will learn how to
delegate authorization and authentication so they can focus on their
real work and forget about all that security stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides this talk Joel is planning a workshop on building a passwordless
authentication server.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joel Lord</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-23:/pycon-sk-2019/i-dont-care-about-security-and-neither-should-you.html</guid><category>PyCon SK 2019</category></item></channel></rss>