<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>List me your virtues</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2018/list-me-your-virtues.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data structures are the building blocks of mostly each piece of code that we can write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, CPython developers have come up with ingenious solutions to make the lists efficient in the standard library and release us from the tedious work of allocating and releasing memory on the bare metal. But, aren't you curious about how they work in a dynamic language like Python?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we are going to dig deep and learn about how lists work in Python. We will learn about topics such as, the complexity that involves appending new data efficiently, how lists can store different data types, what algorithm is used to sort lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bonus track, we will briefly talk about how third-party packages like NumPy can be an excellent replacement, in some cases, of our beloved lists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maite Giménez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-07:pycon-es-2018/list-me-your-virtues.html</guid></item><item><title>List me your virtues</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/list-me-your-virtues.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's the first data structure that comes to your mind? Lists of course! But, Do we know how those lovely lists work? Is there any difference between a list and an array? What algorithm order Python's list? So many questions for a tiny data structure so widely used. Let's learn together about it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright belongs to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maite Giménez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-10:pylondinium-2018/list-me-your-virtues.html</guid></item><item><title>Deep Learning models in Python without gibberish</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/deep-learning-models-in-python-without-gibberish.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Las dos tecnologías más disruptivas actualmente en AI son el Deep Learning y el Reinforcement Learning. ¿Podemos hacernos ricos aplicando estas tecnologías al mundo de las finanzas? En esta charla daremos algunas claves sobre cómo usar Tensorflow para crear redes neuronales que aprenden a invertir en los mercados, y una introducción al Deep Q Learning, un algoritmo de aprendizaje con refuerzo que aprende el “juego” de la Bolsa como cualquier otro robot sometido a ciclos de acción + recompensa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maite Giménez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-23:pycon-es-2017/deep-learning-models-in-python-without-gibberish.html</guid><category>tensorflow</category></item></channel></rss>