<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sharon-steed.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to talk to humans: a different approach to soft skills</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/how-to-talk-to-humans-a-different-approach-to-soft.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sharon Steed</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-21:djangocon-us-2015/how-to-talk-to-humans-a-different-approach-to-soft.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to talk to humans: a different approach to soft skills by Sharon
Steed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers are trained to communicate to things with a goal in mind.
When you're talking to something like, say a computer, you type in your
code and it responds by giving you back what you want. Nine times out of
ten, it works perfectly. Why, then, is it so difficult to do this same
thing when talking to a client about a project, updating a superior on
your progress, or pitching an investor your million-dollar idea? Because
talking to people requires a special set of skills - namely, empathy and
a little bit of storytelling. In an industry filled with brilliant
minds, great ideas and mass disruption, so few of the best and brightest
know how to tell their compelling story. The takeaways from this
workshop will be learning how to value the listener and use
vulnerability to improve your social connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will take you through the difficulty of broken communication -
I, myself, stutter and have great difficulty in saying the simplest
things - to discovering how to reframe your perceived weaknesses. None
of us are perfect, but sometimes those things that we feel are our weak
points are the exact things that we can use to our advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HH6e/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HH6e/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>