<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Word! Automating a Hip-hop word of the day blog</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/word-automating-a-hip-hop-word-of-the-day-blog.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been surprised by sophisticated vocabulary used by some
hip-hop artists? With standard data science tools, I search a large
corpus of hip-hop lyrics in order to extract rhyming couplets that
include uncommon and interesting words. Using curated output from this
code, I demonstrate how to automate the creation of short text-based
posts for a hip-hop themed &amp;quot;Word of the Day&amp;quot; blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="christopher-ing-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Christopher Ing Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris is a PhD student at University of Toronto studying computational
biochemistry. He has degrees in computational physics and physics from
University of Waterloo. He has converted countless graduate students to
Python in the wake of his scientific career, not to mention, he's a
minor celebrity on Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Ing</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/word-automating-a-hip-hop-word-of-the-day-blog.html</guid></item><item><title>Hacking structural biology with Python and pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2015/hacking-structural-biology-with-python-and-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Canada 2015: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2015.pycon.ca/en/schedule/16/"&gt;https://2015.pycon.ca/en/schedule/16/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk Description
The dynamic motions of biomolecules like DNA, RNA, and proteins are integral to our understanding of drugs, disease, and human health. By performing large-scale supercomputer simulations, one can model the motion of proteins in ways impractical or impossible using traditional lab bench experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While data science approaches are ubiquitous in the field of genomics, commonly dealing with massive genetic sequence and expression datasets, the application of &amp;quot;&amp;quot;big data&amp;quot;&amp;quot; methodology is infrequently used in the field of structural biology due to the high computational expense of running simulations. However, advances in high-performance computing are resulting in increased dataset sizes and data analysis is emerging as the primary bottleneck to scientific discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I present the use of Python and Pandas to accelerate analysis of time series data extracted from molecular dynamics trajectories. The application of this approach is directed at the study of the voltage-gated sodium channel, a protein found in human neurons that is responsible for propagating nerve impulses. Using a Jupyter notebook, I perform exploratory analysis on a large dataset of trajectories and arrive at a mechanistic model for the function of this protein. This model may then be used to quantify how genetic diseases and drugs might alter the function of the protein in subsequent research.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Ing</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-11-07:pycon-ca-2015/hacking-structural-biology-with-python-and-pandas.html</guid></item></channel></rss>