<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Project Jupyter</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/project-jupyter.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An overview of Project Jupyter.
​
Abstract
Jupyter is an open source, language agnostic, interactive computing platform used in scientific computing and data science that provides multiple tools tailored for different workflows, from traditional terminal-style control to the popular web-based Notebook. The Jupyter Notebook is a web application that allows users to create and share documents that contain live code, equations, visualizations and explanatory text. Jupyter is the evolution of the original ideas in the IPython interactive shell, as we generalized them into a language agnostic protocol that has now been implemented in over 50 separate languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One project within the Jupyter ecosystem, JupyterHub, is a multi-user environment for Jupyter Notebooks that runs off a central server and that can be used to serve Notebooks to classes of students, corporate workgroups, or scientific research groups. JupyterHub is the backbone for UC Berkeley’s new Undergraduate Data Science Education Program, an ambitious program that aims to provide every freshman with core knowledge and skills in data science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will discuss and demonstrate the many development activities underway at Project Jupyter, including IPython 5.0, JupyterHub, and JupyterLab, and how these tools are used in data science, industry, scientific research, and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;
Jamie Whitacre is the technical project manager for Project Jupyter, an open-source scientific computing and data science ecosystem used extensively in academia and industry. Project Jupyter operates out of the Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) at UC Berkeley. Matthias Bussonnier is a postdoctoral researcher at BIDS and a core developer for Jupyter and IPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/jamie-whitacre-project-jupyter"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/jamie-whitacre-project-jupyter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jamie Whitacre</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-20:pybay-2016/project-jupyter.html</guid></item><item><title>JupyterLab</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/jupyterlab.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk provides an early view of JupyterLab, an evolution of the Jupyter Notebook that provides a modular and extensible user interface within the context of a powerful workspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Jupyter provides building blocks for interactive and exploratory computing. These building blocks make science and data science reproducible across over 40 programming language (Python, Julia, R, etc.). Central to the project is the Jupyter Notebook, a web-based interactive computing platform that allows users to author data- and code-driven narratives - computational narratives - that combine live code, equations, narrative text, visualizations, interactive dashboards and other media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental idea of JupyterLab is to offer a user interface that supports interactive workflows that include, but go far beyond, Jupyter Notebooks. In JupyterLab, users can arrange multiple notebooks, text editors, terminals, output areas, etc. on a single page with multiple panels, tabs, splitters, and collapsible sidebars with a file browser, command palette and integrated help system. The codebase and UI of JupyterLab is based on a flexible plugin system that makes it easy to extend with new components.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jamie Whitacre</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/jupyterlab.html</guid></item></channel></rss>