<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>I Make Fashion Tech and Human Organs for My Mental Health</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/i-make-fashion-tech-and-human-organs-for-my-mental-health.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am an engineer of all sorts. I tinker with electronics, fashion, programming and stem cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share my knowledge and experiences in both wearable
fashion technology (what it is, what we can do with it, why its
relevant) that i have created with various programming languages
including python as a creative hobby outlet, and in tissue engineering
with stem cells which is my profession. The aim of my talk is really to
make people aware that you can have multiple interests and it is highly
encouraged for a fulfilling lifestyle and improved mental health. In
adults, having work that you're passionate about can easily engulf your
whole life easily ignoring other needs in life. It is so easy to go on
without realising that if work was taken away from you, you haven't got
anything else. There is a fear of trying something new due to not
enjoying it or not being good at it. In teenagers and children, they are
often blindsided by stereotypes. Young girls that I have spoken to feel
there is a pressure to give up fashion and beauty in pursuing a STEM
career or education. I set myself in this instance as a role model to
show that people generally are multidirectional and cross-disciplinary
interest is easy to get into, unique, beneficial and sought after.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rachel Rui Wong</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-16:pycon-uk-2018/i-make-fashion-tech-and-human-organs-for-my-mental-health.html</guid></item></channel></rss>