<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ítalo Epifânio</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Going beyond with Jupyter Notebooks: Write your first package using literate programming</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/going-beyond-with-jupyter-notebooks-write-your-first-package-using-literate-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literate_programming"&gt;Literate
programming&lt;/a&gt; is a
programming paradigm that incorporates explanations in natural language
(such as Spanish) embedded with the traditional code. Literate
programming allows developers to tell a story with their codes,
improving the understanding of the project, focusing on documentation,
and making it easier to onboard developers. Although being a very
well-regarded concept discussed by respected researchers like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donald_Knuth"&gt;Donald
Knuth&lt;/a&gt;, literate
programming tools like Jupyter notebooks are considered inefficient for
serious software development. This perception has limited Jupyter
notebooks to simple python scripts and educational materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nbdev.fast.ai/"&gt;Nbdev&lt;/a&gt; library has proven that literate
programming is useful in developing big and serious projects, like
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/fastai/fastai"&gt;FastAi&lt;/a&gt;. This tutorial will show
attendees how to get the benefits of literate programming while also
following software development best practices. We'll get hands-on
experience in writing and publishing a Python Package while using
Jupyter Notebooks. In addition to publishing the package, we'll also
learn how to deploy the docs, run simple tests and run these tests on
CI/CD, making sure that our package will only get published if the tests
pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this tutorial uses Jupyter Notebooks and Nbdev the student
doesn't need previous knowledge of these tools. A simple computer with
Python and pip installed is all we'll use. Students should have some
minimal Python knowledge and Git experience (Simple commands like push,
pull, add and commit). A GitHub account will also be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ítalo Epifânio</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-19:/pycon-us-2023/going-beyond-with-jupyter-notebooks-write-your-first-package-using-literate-programming.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>