<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sheena O'Connell</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sheena-oconnell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Building a dev-focused learner management system with Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/building-a-dev-focused-learner-management-system-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sheena O'Connell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-17:/djangocon-us-2022/building-a-dev-focused-learner-management-system-with-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover:
- our mission
- how we ran as an on-premises training provider
- the utter chaos of our transition to remote (there were about 250 sim cards registered on our MD's name. Lol)
- how we prioritised what we built
- how we ended up choosing Django
- high level view …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover:
- our mission
- how we ran as an on-premises training provider
- the utter chaos of our transition to remote (there were about 250 sim cards registered on our MD's name. Lol)
- how we prioritised what we built
- how we ended up choosing Django
- high level view of how we train different kinds of coders
- where we are heading&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote - Power to the People who Teach the People</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/keynote-power-to-the-people-who-teach-the-people.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sheena O'Connell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-23:/djangocon-us-2024/keynote-power-to-the-people-who-teach-the-people.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing I absolutely love about the Python community is the fact that there are so many people with teacher's hearts. Teaching is an amazing thing, you can change a person's life just by spending some time with them, having conversations, showing them stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's normal for people with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing I absolutely love about the Python community is the fact that there are so many people with teacher's hearts. Teaching is an amazing thing, you can change a person's life just by spending some time with them, having conversations, showing them stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's normal for people with software development skills to take on teaching roles - this might be through formal or informal workplace mentorship, community involvement, through being hired to teach or any number of other situations. Teaching and sharing knowledge is often a part of the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software development and teaching are two distinct skill sets. There is a science to teaching and learning - there is a robust body of knowledge, there are techniques, mindsets and patterns that make teaching effective. And, on the flip side, there are mistakes, anti-patterns and myths that are very much worth avoiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's perfectly normal for software developers to take on teaching roles and responsibilities, but it's exceedingly rare for software developers to receive any training in how to teach well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been working in alternative education for&amp;nbsp;quite some time, I've learned a lot of lessons along the way. In this talk, I'll share some of the most impactful lessons I've learned.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning to code in the age of AI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/learning-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sheena O'Connell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/learning-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to code in the age of AI by Sheena O'Connell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/learning-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/learning-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the industry, programmers of all levels are embracing AI and LLMs. But: it's still worthwhile to learn the foundations of coding. And there's a risk …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to code in the age of AI by Sheena O'Connell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/learning-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/learning-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the industry, programmers of all levels are embracing AI and LLMs. But: it's still worthwhile to learn the foundations of coding. And there's a risk: some learners are using AIs as footguns and limiting their own growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing your web app with Playwright</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2024/testing-your-web-app-with-playwright.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sheena O'Connell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-04-07:/pycascades-2024/testing-your-web-app-with-playwright.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, if you wanted a truly modern web frontend experience for your Python web app you would have limited options in how to pull it off. A lot of people would reach for heavy frontend tools and frameworks such as React, Vue or one of their …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, if you wanted a truly modern web frontend experience for your Python web app you would have limited options in how to pull it off. A lot of people would reach for heavy frontend tools and frameworks such as React, Vue or one of their many, many competitors. And those tools generally have their recommendations around testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are shifting a bit - tools like HTMX and AlpineJS are taking Python Web dev by storm and simplifying the creation of modern frontends. A Python web app can now take on the full responsibility of producing a modern frontend. So it would be good to test them in Python as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Playwright comes in. It promises to enable reliable end-to-end testing for modern web apps. And it has Python bindings. &lt;em&gt;swoon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll give you a little tour of Playwright and how to use it in your app. I'll demo some workflows, patterns, tips, and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - Sunday</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/lightning-talks-sunday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Illirik Smirnov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-18:/pycon-us-2025/lightning-talks-sunday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collection of lightning talks made by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:15 - Illirik Smirnov - Phone numbers and you: tips, tricks, and footguns
5:15 - Evan Kohilas - What have they done! Why is &lt;cite&gt;re.sub&lt;/cite&gt; changing from Python 3.13?
9:55 - Adam Silkey - &amp;quot;Solving&amp;quot; Python Packaging on Windows, once and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collection of lightning talks made by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:15 - Illirik Smirnov - Phone numbers and you: tips, tricks, and footguns
5:15 - Evan Kohilas - What have they done! Why is &lt;cite&gt;re.sub&lt;/cite&gt; changing from Python 3.13?
9:55 - Adam Silkey - &amp;quot;Solving&amp;quot; Python Packaging on Windows, once and for all
12:00 - Jonathan Daniel - Using &lt;cite&gt;uv pip&lt;/cite&gt; to accelerarte Docker
17:00 - Takanori Suzuki - Put the Cat Emoji in your documents!
22:30 - Jing Cao - What I learned going on strike with the NYTimes Tech Guild
28:00 - Michael McCaffrey - Overcoming ADHD and anxiety to achieve long-term goals
32:50 - Joongi Kim - My 10 years with PyCon KR
38:10 - Dave Peck - A whirlwind tour of t-strings!
43:45 - Sheena O'Connell - Python in Africa
48:00 - Conference Announcements&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>