<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Plénière n°1 / Keynote #1: The 750,000-Line Long Pull Request: Crafting a more Resilient Open Source Community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/pleniere-ndeg1-keynote-1-the-750000-line-long-pull-request-crafting-a-more-resilient-open-source-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, a community of developers and economists are developing
OpenFisca, an open source framework in Python that turns law into
software so it can be used by administrations, economists and
activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the community around OpenFisca grew, we needed to adapt to new
expertises, new expectations, and new work habits. The arrival of a
very large PR tested of the work we had put in to create a resilient
community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will describe how we worked to create a dynamic
community that can deal with uncertainty (new contributors, very large
PRs, …) and grow to reach new heights in the hope it can inspire
others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna-Livia Gomart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:pycon-fr-2019/pleniere-ndeg1-keynote-1-the-750000-line-long-pull-request-crafting-a-more-resilient-open-source-community.html</guid></item><item><title>The 750,000-line long pull request: crafting a more resilient open source community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2019/the-750000-line-long-pull-request-crafting-a-more-resilient-open-source-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As open source communities grow, they need to adapt to new dynamics: Different types of expertise between contributors, different expectations, etc. The arrival of a very large PR on the OpenFisca project became the test of the work we had put in to create a more resilient community.
Since 2011, a community of developers and economists are developing OpenFisca, an open source framework in Python that turns law into software so it can be used by administrations, economists and activists.
The contributors are split between tech experts and domain experts, each bringing interesting skills, mindsets and issues. However, a full time tech team became the full time core team, shifting the balance of the community. Having a full time team working on the project was a plus, but it gave tech experts a central role that put a lot of strain on domain experts’ contributions.
In this talk, I will describe how we worked to create a dynamic community that can deal with uncertainty (new contributors, very large PRs, …) and grow to reach new heights in the hope it can inspire other communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna-Livia Gomart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-20:djangocon-europe-2019/the-750000-line-long-pull-request-crafting-a-more-resilient-open-source-community.html</guid></item><item><title>It's not a bug, it's a bias</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/its-not-a-bug-its-a-bias.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Product makers have a biased view of the world, and this translates to biased algorithms.
How can we take this into account, and create a fairer world though fairer algorithms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though Apple's Siri came out with a built-in response to where to hide a body, it was incapable of pointing a user to an abortion clinic.
How did an Artificial Assistant get iffy about abortion?
And how can I stop my own biases from seeping into the products and services I create?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I explore our preconceptions about the nature of algorithms, and how users and makers influence them to model the world according to their perspective.
I conclude the talk by proposing a change of mindset for product designers, to be more aware of our capacity to let our biases infuse our services, and to put in place tools to create more inclusive experiences for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna-Livia Gomart&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna-Livia Gomart</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-23:djangocon-europe-2018/its-not-a-bug-its-a-bias.html</guid></item></channel></rss>