<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kevin-van-wilder.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Keynote: Your Product is more than the Application!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2014/keynote-your-product-is-more-than-the-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Van Wilder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-14:djangocon-europe-2014/keynote-your-product-is-more-than-the-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All too often we see developers and system operators fail to
communicate. Both teams seems to have different requirements: developers
want new features and releases whilst operators want stable systems. But
the fact of the matter is that both teams have the same goals. When both
teams are brought together from the get-go, you notice the goals become
visible again and the requirements align.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Devops movement in IT is a critical mass of developers and IT
operations aligning their ideas. It is a collection of best practices,
tooling and a philophy that emphasizes on collaboration and automation.
But the most important best practice a developer and IT operator
requires is the art of clear and concise communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll finally remove the confusion of what Devops really is
and explain the best practices and toolsets. The talk revolves around
the CALMS acronym:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture: people and process first, if you dont have the correct
culture, all attempts will be fruitless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation: remove the human error from the equation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean: learn to adapt to situations, think outside the box and
identify processes that are a waste of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measurements: If you can't measure, you can't identify and improve.
Performance metrics, process metrics and even people metrics!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing: This is the loopback in the CALMS cycle. Share your ideas
and solutions with the community. Learn from the advise of other
people and improve your own processes along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your product is more than the application, it is also the monitoring,
the infrastructure, the constant improvement, the sharing of knowledge
and the people developing it!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>