<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Don Kirkby</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_don-kirkby.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Tightening Your Feedback Loop with Live Coding</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/tightening-your-feedback-loop-with-live-coding.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Don Kirkby</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-18:/pycascades-2023/tightening-your-feedback-loop-with-live-coding.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes Python easy to work with is that you don't need a compile step before you can check that your code works. What if you could skip the save and run steps, too? Live coding lets you constantly run your code, as you edit …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes Python easy to work with is that you don't need a compile step before you can check that your code works. What if you could skip the save and run steps, too? Live coding lets you constantly run your code, as you edit it, and shows you what's happening inside. It's also great for visual tools like Matplotlib and Pillow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be demonstrating my Live Coding in Python project that includes plugins for PyCharm, Emacs, and SublimeText, as well as live tutorials that use Pyodide to let the reader experiment with code samples right in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Live Coding in Python v2.16</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/vancouver-python-developers/live-coding-in-python-v216.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Don Kirkby</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-20:/vancouver-python-developers/live-coding-in-python-v216.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demonstrates an Eclipse plugin that runs your Python code while you type it, including a new feature: live unit tests. Also shows Emacs package and new PyCharm plugin, as well as the old features of turtle graphics and live coding display.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Vancouver Python Developers"></category><category term="live coding"></category><category term="tools"></category></entry></feed>