<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Milecia McGregor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Reproducible Experiments to Create Better Machine Learning Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/using-reproducible-experiments-to-create-better-machine-learning-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you start exploring multiple model architectures with different hyperparameter values, you need a way to quickly iterate. There are a lot of ways to handle this, but all of them require time and you might not be able to go back to a particular point to resume or restart training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how you can use the open-source tool, DVC, to compare training metrics using two methods for tuning hyperparameters: grid search and random search. You’ll learn how you can save and track the changes in your data, code, and metrics without adding a lot of commits to your Git history. This approach will scale with your data and projects and make sure that your team can reproduce results easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Milecia McGregor</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/using-reproducible-experiments-to-create-better-machine-learning-models.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>