<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - David Melamed</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deep dive into threat detection in the cloud with Spark and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2016/deep-dive-into-threat-detection-in-the-cloud-with-spark-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is all over the place. In the cyber space, it's one of the biggest buzzwords of 2015 and most prominent tools used to detect anomalies, in particular when involved in User Behavior Analysis. This talk is a journey inside the cyber security techniques put in place at CloudLock to detect anomalies using Python. We will start our journey by looking at the data collection and processing implemented mostly inside celery tasks in order to produce a clean and enriched feed of billions of events daily. We will then present our use of Apache Spark MLLib with python and how we leverage AWS Lambda and EMR in our flexible infrastructure. Finally, we will show an example of data visualization around our threat map. We will also discuss the pros and cons of using Python with Apache Spark when dealing with scale as well as Docker as a way to encapsulate some parts of the data pipeline and to serve the models to the application. Come learn how to build an efficient ETL at scale using Python all the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: Deep dive into threat detection in the cloud with Spark and Python by David Melamed&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Melamed</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-21:/pycon-israel-2016/deep-dive-into-threat-detection-in-the-cloud-with-spark-and-python.html</guid><category>PyCon Israel 2016</category></item><item><title>Minimum Viable Security for Python Applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2022/minimum-viable-security-for-python-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python remains a very popular programming and scripting language in the DevOps ecosystem for building CI/CD pipelines. In the same way we think about how we design and build our Python applications, we need to design, build and automate security into our applications from the ground floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: David Melamed
Currently CTO and Co-Founder of Jit, the Continuous Security platform for Developers. David has a PhD in Bioinformatics and for the past 20 years has been a full-stack developer, CTO &amp;amp; technical evangelist, mostly in the cloud, and specifically in cloud security, working for leading organizations such as MyHeritage, CloudLock (acquired by Cisco) and leading the ‘advanced development team’ for the CTO of Cisco’s cloud security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Melamed</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-21:/pytexas-2022/minimum-viable-security-for-python-applications.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2022</category></item></channel></rss>