<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_elyse-maria-glina.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Human as a Second Language: Succeeding with the Natural Language Toolkit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2012/human-as-a-second-language-succeeding-with-the-n.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Elyse Maria Glina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-08-21:pycon-au-2012/human-as-a-second-language-succeeding-with-the-n.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK) suite offers powerful tools for
natural language processing and analysis. Like many other code
libraries, it enables programmers to achieve results when working with
data they may not be an expert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK) suite offers powerful tools for
natural language processing and analysis. Like many other code
libraries, it enables programmers to achieve results when working with
data they may not be an expert in the handling of - in this case, human
language. The NLTK is particularly valuable as human language skills are
in general something programmers can get along without, and therefore
they are likely to be ill- equipped with the tools to most effectively
work with language data. However, while NLTK provides programmers with a
way to work with all the relevant parts of language without needing to
rely on their own grammar skills, there are many concepts in the field
of natural language processing that require basic comprehension of
natural language operation, which may make knowing where to start
working with the NLTK difficult for the average programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will demonstrate some of the NLTK's powerful and
impressive features, while covering the concepts that will enable any
programmer to work cool tricks on natural language. The application of
the NLTK to a very basic artificial intelligence will be shown.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="nltk"></category></entry></feed>