<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>R1-D1-06 Millions way to avoid overfitting when building a portfolio - Chia-Yi Yen (PyCon APAC 2015)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2015/r1-d1-06-millions-way-to-avoid-overfitting-when-a.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:  Chia-Yi Yen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You never know how to build a successful portfolio that always gives you significant return, but you definitely should know what would make you build a model that is doomed to be a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overfitting is the most common one. In the brief talk, I would like to share some experience how to avoid overfitting. At least in some ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples would be shown in Python toolkit like ipython, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, and seaborn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chia-Yi Yen, you can call her &amp;quot;Yen&amp;quot; just like the Japanese dollar yen, is a financial engineer in a local hedge fund. She has been responsible for multi-factor model construction, data infrastructure, data Extract-Transform-Load solution, and other numeric analysis projects. She is active in many open-source communities like Python and R, and she is also the organizer of Taiwan R-Ladies community, which is a female meetup of everything about data in the world of R language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;組織/公司 Risksoft Technology Ltd., Quantitative Strategies Department
頭銜 Financial Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/91"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org/2015apac/zh/program/91&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chia-Yi Yen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-24:pycon-apac-2015/r1-d1-06-millions-way-to-avoid-overfitting-when-a.html</guid></item></channel></rss>