<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_shir-meir-lador.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Fraud detection challenges and data skepticism using LIME</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/fraud-detection-challenges-and-data-skepticism-using-lime.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shir Meir Lador</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-01-05:pydata-meetups/fraud-detection-challenges-and-data-skepticism-using-lime.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shir presents the story of developing a machine learning model which automatically approves factoring deals, the challenges in the model training, evaluation and interpretation including a mysterious problem in the model creation and the details of its final solution. In addition she discusses data leakage, overfitting and a cutting-edge framework for model explanations (LIME).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>5 Simple Steps to Create Meaningful Features from Clickstream Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2017/5-simple-steps-to-create-meaningful-features-from-clickstream-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Shir Meir Lador</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-12:pycon-israel-2017/5-simple-steps-to-create-meaningful-features-from-clickstream-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predicting client financial behaviour is usually done by financial data sources - such as client financial history, bank and credit statements, etc. In this talk we will review a different type of data source for risk assessment - features engineered from clickstream data gathered by Mixpanel. We will discuss what kind of features can be generated from clickstream data and how to generate these features using Pandas, what is the benefit of these unconventional features, what are the different correlations of the features with user financial behaviour and how can you apply clickstream data analysis to your problems in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>