<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Semona Igama</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_semona-igama.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Impress your enterprise customers with OpenID Connect login</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2024/impress-your-enterprise-customers-with-openid-connect-login.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Semona Igama</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-21:/pybay-2024/impress-your-enterprise-customers-with-openid-connect-login.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you sell a Python SaaS app, customers' first question will be, &amp;quot;How do I log in?&amp;quot;. Are you committing the security faux pas of rolling your own authentication? Does your app only support password login? If you've integrated identity standards, do you understand how they work and how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you sell a Python SaaS app, customers' first question will be, &amp;quot;How do I log in?&amp;quot;. Are you committing the security faux pas of rolling your own authentication? Does your app only support password login? If you've integrated identity standards, do you understand how they work and how you can benefit from their full set of features? In this talk, you'll learn the principles of how to use OpenID Connect (OIDC) to secure a Django app for the first time or refresh your knowledge. OIDC allows enterprise customers' users to sign in with their corporate identity providers and facilitates social login with Google or Twitter. Show your customers how you're prioritizing their authentication needs by following secure open standards.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Safeguard your precious API endpoints built on FastAPI using OAuth 2.0</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/safeguard-your-precious-api-endpoints-built-on-fastapi-using-oauth-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Semona Igama</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/safeguard-your-precious-api-endpoints-built-on-fastapi-using-oauth-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Audience Level: Beginners, Pythonistas who build on FastAPI who are not security experts but still need to deploy secure APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is implementing authorization to your API endpoints an afterthought? Who should have access to your API endpoints? This talk covers using OAuth 2.0 to secure API endpoints (including …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Audience Level: Beginners, Pythonistas who build on FastAPI who are not security experts but still need to deploy secure APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is implementing authorization to your API endpoints an afterthought? Who should have access to your API endpoints? This talk covers using OAuth 2.0 to secure API endpoints (including ML endpoints) built on FastAPI following industry-recognized best practices. Come on a journey with me from taking your API endpoints to being not just functional but also secure. When you follow secure identity standards, you’ll be equipped with a deeper understanding of the critical need for authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>