<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_cornelia-van-der-walt.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Insight into Customer Segmentation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2018/insight-into-customer-segmentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cornelia van der Walt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-12:pycon-za-2018/insight-into-customer-segmentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In retail, understanding your customer is all, and when you do not have
a brick and mortar storefront to attract new shoppers, it is even more
important to get insight into the array of visitors who frequent your
site. You need an idea of who they are, what they want and how to
attract them. This is a universal truth of all businesses and the
lessons learned here could be easily applied to other industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter data science and the ability to segment your customers. What is
customer segmentation? What types of segmentation are there? What models
could you use? How do you do it? What is it good for? Having done it a
few times, first for Superbalist, then for the Spree customers during
the Superbalist/Spree merger, I might have a few tricks and tips to
share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will look at a high-level overview of clustering, then
deep-dive into the code a bit before coming up at the end with a few use
cases and conclusions. I'll discuss a few potential model algorithms we
investigated, but focus mostly on the K-Means clustering model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have some data science experience it would be helpful, but the
talk should provide interesting information for everyone. The talk aims
to leave you with a solid idea of how to build a customer segmentation
model of your own. Come discover the joys of classification models with
me!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>