<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Sam Faktorovich</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Interviewing and hiring technical writers: the Siberian way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/interviewing-and-hiring-technical-writers-the-siberian-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My name is Sam and I am the head of technical documentation department
at Zodiac Interactive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Zodiac we create low-level software (we call it 'middleware') that
runs inside cable TV set-top boxes. Most cable companies in North
America use our products; most probably, your set-top box runs at least
some code written by Zodiac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zodiac has R&amp;amp;D departments all over the world; my office is located in
Novosibirsk, Russia – right in the center of Siberia (so yes, there is a
big probability that your set-top box runs some code that was written in
the midst of Siberian taiga)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation department at our R&amp;amp;D center concentrates only on
architectural documentation: our docs explain the design and
architectural decisions of our software components to other teams and
R&amp;amp;D centers all over the world . We don't document user interface, write
client knowledge bases, or do UI copy. Our technical writers must be
tech-savvy enough to understand the architectural peculiarities of
complex multithreaded applications, must be able to read code in C++
and, above all, must have perfect written English – Zodiac is an
American company, and we write all our docs in English, not Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last 5 years our R&amp;amp;D center went from not having any
documentarians at all to a team of 4 excellent and capable technical
writers. We were able to set up effective processes of integrating
documentation in overall development activities and find out good
metrics for quality of architectural docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation processes and documentation quality are frequent topics at
Write the Docs, so I want to talk about more generic things:
interviewing, assessing and hiring technical writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk will tackle the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How hard is it to find a &amp;quot;highly technical&amp;quot; technical writer?
(remember that our documentarians must read and understand C++ code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to switch your non-documentarian team members to
writing documentation full-time? Do developers make good technical
writers? What about QA engineers? (our answer was no: it's better to
hire new documentarians than to evolve existing team members into
technical writers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which one is easier: hiring a technically capable person and teaching
them to write well, or hiring a person with good writing skills but
no technical knowledge whatsoever and then training them on technical
stuff? (we went with the second option)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessing the candidates: what is the perfect pre-interview
assignment test and is it OK if the typical candidate spends 10-14
days to complete it? Should your candidates write something that
resembles your working docs, or some generic texts on complex topics
are enough? (for example, we ask our candidates to explain SSL
certificates to their math-savvy, but not-cryptographically-inclined
uncle: private/public keys, digital signatures, chains of trust and
so on)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviewing candidates for a technical writer position: are
interviews necessary at all? Can a good interview outweigh a bad
assignment test? Can a bad interview spoil the impression after a
good assignment test? What things should be asked during an
interview?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sam Faktorovich</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/interviewing-and-hiring-technical-writers-the-siberian-way.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Portland 2017</category></item></channel></rss>