<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brad-frank.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Jupyter Notebooks for Radio Astronomy Research</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/jupyter-notebooks-for-radio-astronomy-research.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brad Frank</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-05:pycon-za-2017/jupyter-notebooks-for-radio-astronomy-research.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Inter-University Institute for Data Intensive Astronomy (IDIA,
www.idia.ac.za), we are focusing on several important use-cases
related to the delivery of science data products from large radio
telescopes, such as MeerKAT. The requirements for the hardcore
processing and analysis of raw radio data has to be counter-balanced
with our essential need to collaborate on our science projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have thus adopted the Jupyter Hub/Notebooks as the principle means of
running radio astronomy workflows, pipelines and calibration scripts. We
have found this to be an enormously useful and powerful medium to
prototype technical recipes, and to share lessons learned. This allows
us to shorten the amount of time taken to develop a complex astronomical
workflow, and shifts the focus on the data and the processes involved in
a single, comprehensive framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usage of Jupyter Notebooks is become quite popular in radio
astronomy, and marks a distinct paradigm shift in the way that
astronomers all over the world are collaborating on large science
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I will focus on our usage of Jupyter Hub/Notebooks within an
astronomical context, and some highlights related to the development of
our astronomical computing software stack in python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>