<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Radio astronomical TRAnsient detection Pipeline (TRAP)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2014/the-radio-astronomical-transient-detection-pipeli.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LOFAR, the Low Frequency Array, is an innovative new radio telescope in
the Netherlands, which will continuously monitor the radio sky. The
study of transient sources is one of the key science projects of LOFAR.
Under this remit come all time-variable astronomical radio sources,
including pulsars, gamma-ray bursts, X-ray binaries, radio supernovae,
flare stars, and even exo-planets. With its continuous monitoring of a
large area of sky, it is hoped that LOFAR will detect many new transient
events, and provide alerts to the international community for follow-up
observations at other wavelengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To detect and analyse transient sources we’ve created a software
pipeline named TRAP. The TRAP is almost completely written in Python. In
short the TRAP consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storing to database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Association in time and frequency (in database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualising results (webinterface)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the datarates in the pipeline are high, key in the design of our
pipeline is that we move most calculations to the database. This implies
complex and math heavy queries. To assist in managing these queries we
use SQLAlchemy. TRAP can be used on various database backends like
PostgreSQL, but also the less known MonetDB. MonetDB is a column store
database which is believed to outperform traditional SQL databases on
huge datasets. To interact with MonetDB we developed a Python API,
SQLALchemy dialect and Django backend. For visualisation of the results
we’ve created an interactive browser based web interface based on
Django, bootstrap and highcharts. For parallising the image processing
we use Celery. In my talk i’ll explain why we use these frameworks and
dive in the internals of our pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target audience is people that are interested in how to build a
scientific processing pipline using off the shelf libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gijs Molenaar</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-22:euroscipy-2014/the-radio-astronomical-transient-detection-pipeli.html</guid></item></channel></rss>