<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sattar Vakili</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sattar-vakili.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Amortized variance reduction for doubly stochastic objective</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/amortized-variance-reduction-for-doubly-stochastic-objective.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ayman Boustati</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/amortized-variance-reduction-for-doubly-stochastic-objective.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Amortized variance reduction for doubly stochastic objective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayman Boustati (University of Warwick)*; Sattar Vakili (Prowler.io); James Hensman (PROWLER.io); ST John (PROWLER.io)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximate inference in complex probabilistic models such as deep Gaussian processes requires the optimisation of doubly stochastic objective functions. These objectives incorporate randomness both from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Amortized variance reduction for doubly stochastic objective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayman Boustati (University of Warwick)*; Sattar Vakili (Prowler.io); James Hensman (PROWLER.io); ST John (PROWLER.io)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximate inference in complex probabilistic models such as deep Gaussian processes requires the optimisation of doubly stochastic objective functions. These objectives incorporate randomness both from mini-batch subsampling of the data and from Monte Carlo estimation of expectations. If the gradient variance is high, the stochastic optimisation problem becomes difficult with a slow rate of convergence. Control variates can be used to reduce the variance, but past approaches do not take into account how mini-batch stochasticity affects sampling stochasticity, resulting in sub-optimal variance reduction. We propose a new approach in which we use a recognition network to cheaply approximate the optimal control variate for each mini-batch, with no additional model gradient computations. We illustrate the properties of this proposal and test its performance on logistic regression and deep Gaussian processes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>