<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_taylor-oshan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>pySI A Python Framework for Spatial Interaction Modelling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/pysi-a-python-framework-for-spatial-interaction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Taylor Oshan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/pysi-a-python-framework-for-spatial-interaction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spatial Interaction Modelling is a method for calibrating parameters for
components within a system of flows, such as migration or trade, and
then using those parameters to estimate new flows. Despite their
popularity, a unified Python framework to employ them does not exist. In
response, pySI was created as a coherent tool for calibrating models and
simulating flows for a variety of models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Functions from libraries such as scipy.optimize, scipy.spatial,
statsmodels, and numdifftools comprise the core of the pySI.calibrate
routines, which are automatically constructed depending upon the
specified model inputs. As a result, the user can focus on identifying
different flow systems and understanding the associated spatial
processes, rather than the algorithmic divergences which emerge between
different models. After calibration is completed, the estimated
parameters and their diagnostic statistics can be reported in a uniform
fashion. Using functions within pySI.simulate, the parameter estimates
can act as inputs in order to predict new flows. More recently developed
models, which do not require input parameters, are also made available,
allowing comparisons amongst results from differing conceptual
formulations. Finally, results may be visualized with plots and networks
via matplotlib, igraph, and networkx. Overall, the pySI framework will
increase the accessibility of spatial interaction modelling while also
serving as a tool which can help new users understand the associated
methodological intricacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this presentation, the concept of spatial interaction and a few
key modelling terms will first be introduced, along with several example
applications. Next, two traditional techniques for calibrating spatial
interaction models, Poisson generalized linear regression and direct
maximum likelihood estimation will be contrasted. It will then be
demonstrated how this new framework will allow users to execute either
form of calibration using identical input variables, which are based
upon a pandas DataFrame specification, without any significant
mathematical or statistical training. Results from two different
conceptual models will be compared to illustrate how pySI can be used to
explore different methods and models of spatial interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>