<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nic Crane</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nic-crane.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Mixing R, Python, and Quarto: Crafting the Perfect Open Source Cocktail</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/mixing-r-python-and-quarto-crafting-the-perfect-open-source-cocktail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alenka Frim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/mixing-r-python-and-quarto-crafting-the-perfect-open-source-cocktail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collaborating effectively on a cross-language open-source project like Apache Arrow has a lot in common with data science teams, where the most productivity is seen when people are given the right tools to enable them to contribute to the programming language they are most familiar with. In this talk …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collaborating effectively on a cross-language open-source project like Apache Arrow has a lot in common with data science teams, where the most productivity is seen when people are given the right tools to enable them to contribute to the programming language they are most familiar with. In this talk, we share a project we created to combine information from different sources to simplify project maintenance and monitor important metrics for tracking project sustainability, using Quarto dashboards with both R and Python components. We'll share the lessons we learned collaborating on this project - what was easy, where things got tougher, and concrete principles we discovered were key to effective cross-language collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>