<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Suzuki</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_suzuki.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Introduction to Structural Pattern Matching Takanori</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/introduction-to-structural-pattern-matching-takanori.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Suzuki</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/introduction-to-structural-pattern-matching-takanori.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Structural Pattern Matching is a new feature in Python 3.10. I think it's a big feature added to Python after a long time. In this talk, I will show you the basic usage of the feature with various sample code. Let's try to understand how to use Pattern …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Structural Pattern Matching is a new feature in Python 3.10. I think it's a big feature added to Python after a long time. In this talk, I will show you the basic usage of the feature with various sample code. Let's try to understand how to use Pattern Matching and start using it in 3.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce the motivation behind Strucral Pattern Matching from PEP.
Then I will explain the syntax and basic usage of Structural Pattern Matching.
Next I will show how to use the various patterns with sample code.
The patterns introduced are Literal, Capture, Wildcard, OR, Value, Group, Class, Sequence, Mapping, AS and Guards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takanori Suzuki
Takanori is a Chairperson of PyCon JP Association (www.pycon.jp). He is also a director of BeProud Inc.(www.beproud.jp), and his title is &amp;quot;Python Climber&amp;quot;. Takanori held PyCon JP 2014 to 2016 as the chairperson. Currently he teaches Python to beginners as a lecturer at Python Boot Camp(pycamp.pycon.jp) all over Japan. In addition, he published several Python books. Tananori plays trumpet, climbs boulder, loves Lego, ferrets and beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry></feed>