<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kevin-keenoy.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Transforming the government’s Digital Marketplace from portal to platform</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/transforming-the-governments-digital-marketplace-from-portal-to-platform.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Keenoy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-16:pycon-uk-2016/transforming-the-governments-digital-marketplace-from-portal-to-platform.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presentation by: Kevin Keenoy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public sector can use the Digital Marketplace (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.digitalmarketplace.service.gov.uk/"&gt;https://www.digitalmarketplace.service.gov.uk/&lt;/a&gt;) to find people and technology for digital projects. Over £1,000,000,000 has been spent on cloud services by government through the G-Cloud framework since it launched in 2012, over half of that spend being with SMEs rather than big systems integrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2014 the Digital Marketplace was a single Grails application (written in Groovy, running on the JVM) that provided a simple searchable catalogue of cloud services. Applications from suppliers to provide their services were handled externally by two separate systems run by the Crown Commercial Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then we have rebuilt the Digital Marketplace from scratch in Python as a RESTful system of Flask applications and expanded its functionality to supplant these external systems. It is now on its way to becoming a general-purpose platform for handling suppliers’ applications to sell their services to government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain how the the architecture of the system has evolved over a series of iterations of supplier application processes, and also delve deeper into how we drive both the frontend applications and data validation from a separate “content repository” of YAML files that can be maintained by content designers rather than developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>