<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Intermediate Methods for Geospatial Data Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/intermediate-methods-for-geospatial-data-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will provide attendees with tricks, tips, and techniques that are often necessary to work with geographic data in Python. These methods will range from the basics of reading &amp;amp; writing spatial data to the mechanics of combining and summarizing disparate geographic data types and representations. Overall, participants will gain a better understanding of practical methods to bring many different geographic datasets together for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/intermediate-methods-for-geospatial-data-analysis.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Geospatial Data Analysis with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/introduction-to-geospatial-data-analysis-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is an introduction to geospatial data analysis in Python,
with a focus on tabular vector data. It is the first part in a series of
two tutorials; this part focuses on introducing the participants to the
different libraries to work with geospatial data and will cover munging
geo-data and exploring relations over space. This includes importing
data in different formats (e.g. shapefile, GeoJSON), visualizing,
combining and tidying them up for analysis, and will use libraries such
as &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;geopandas&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;shapely&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;PySAL&lt;/tt&gt;, or &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rasterio&lt;/tt&gt;.
The second part will built upon this and focus on more more advanced
geographic data science and statistical methods to gain insight from the
data. No previous experience with those geospatial python libraries is
needed, but basic familiarity with geospatial data and concepts
(shapefiles, vector vs raster data) and pandas will be
helpful.Presenter(s): Speaker: Serge Rey, University of California,
Riverside Speaker: Dani Arribas- Bel, University of Liverpool Speaker:
Joris Van den Bossche, Université Paris- Saclay Center for Data Science
Speaker: Levi Wolf, University of Bristol&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Serge Rey</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-10:scipy-2018/introduction-to-geospatial-data-analysis-with-python.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item></channel></rss>