<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_adam-hughes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Domain Analysis of Mosaic Proteins in Purple Sea Urchin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/domain-analysis-of-mosaic-proteins-in-purple-sea.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Hughes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/domain-analysis-of-mosaic-proteins-in-purple-sea.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Purple sea urchins (Strongylocentrotus purpuratus or Sp) are
invertebrates that share more than 7,000 genes with humans, more than
other common model invertebrate organisms like fruit flies and worms. In
addition, the innate immune system of sea urchins demonstrates
unprecedented complexity. These factors make the sea urchin a very
interesting organism for investigations of immunology. Of particular
interest are the set of proteins in SP that contain C-type lectin
(CLECT) domains, a functional region in the protein which recognizes
sugars. Proteins containing CLECTs may be particularly important to
immune system robustness because of sugars that are present on
pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary goals of this research project are first to identify all the
CLECT-containing proteins in the Sp genome, and then to predict their
function based on similarity to characterized proteins in other species
(protein homology or similarity). The latter goal is particularly
challenging and requires new and creative analysis methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an informational viewpoint, proteins are represented by a unique
sequence of letters, each letter corresponding to an amino acid. For
example G-A-V indicates the sequence glycine, alanine and valine.
Commonality between proteins is usually measured by sequence alignments;
that is, by directly comparing the sequence of letters between two
proteins. Algorithms and tools for these alignments are among the most
standardized and available tools in bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sequence similarity between homologous proteins can degrade over long
evolutionary timescales. This is in part because some mutations at the
sequence level can occur without compromising a protein's overall
function. This is akin to the evolution of a language, e.g modern
English and middle English, which initially appear to be separate
languages due to spelling differences. Because domains are regions of a
protein which can function semi- independently, they are less prone to
accommodate mutations. By comparing proteins based on the ordering of
their domains, or their &amp;quot;domain architecture&amp;quot;, it becomes possible to
identify homology, or similarities in domain order, separated by
extensive evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alignment tools based on domain architecture are promising, but are
still in their infancy. Consequently, very few researchers utilize both
sequence and domain alignment methodologies corroboratively. Using
Python scripts in tandem with various web tools and databases, we have
identified the top alignment candidates for the CLECT-containing Sp
proteins using both methods. With the help of the Enthought Tool Suite,
we have created a simple visualization tool that allows users to examine
the sequence alignments side-by-side with two types of domain
alignments. The information provided by these three results together is
much more informative with respect to predicting protein function than
any single method alone. Finally, we have developed a systematic set of
heuristic rules to allow users to make objective comparisons among the
three sets of results. The results can later be parsed using Python
scripts to make quantitative and qualitative assessments of the dataset.
We believe that these new comparison and visualization techniques will
apply in general to computational proteomics.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Bioinformatics Mini-Symposia"></category></entry></feed>