<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sergey-maidanov.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Accelerate data analytics and Python performance with Intel® software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/accelerate-data-analytics-and-python-performance-with-intelr-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sergey Maidanov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-25:pydata-seattle-2015/accelerate-data-analytics-and-python-performance-with-intelr-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Talk- Intel
This talk presents an overview of some of the tools, technologies and programs being developed and offered by Intel® for the Data community and Python Developers. We'll highlight the new Intel® Data Analytics Acceleration Library (Intel® DAAL), a prototype Python profiler, a Python Distribution for scientific computing &amp;amp; data analysis, Intel® MKL, Intel® IPP and the free software tools program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk presents an overview of some of the tools, technologies and programs being developed and offered by Intel® for the Data community and Python Developers. The Intel® Data Analytics Acceleration Library (Intel® DAAL) is a C++ and Java software solution for data analytics. The library provides a set of optimized building blocks that can be used in all stages of the data analytics workflow. A prototype Python profiler will be featured, with details on the highlights and advantages of this tool. Another project in the works is a Python Distribution for scientific computing and data analysis, that leverages the power of Intel® Math Kernel library (Intel® MKL) to deliver faster performance. A quick spotlight on the latest features and additions to the Intel ® Performance Libraries – Intel® MKL and Intel® Integrated Performance Primitives (Intel® IPP). And finally, a fresh look at the Intel free tools software program, to discover some of the free offerings for academic researchers, educators, students and open source contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>