<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hongjoo-lee.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Deep Learning your Broadband Network @HOME</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/deep-learning-your-broadband-network-home.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hongjoo Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:europython-2017/deep-learning-your-broadband-network-home.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of us have broadband internet services at home. Sometimes it
does not work well, and we visit speed test page and check internet
speed for ourselves or call cable company to report the service
failure. As a Python programmer, have you ever tried to automate the
internet speed test on a regular basis? Have you ever thought about
logging the data and analyzing the time series ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will go through the whole process of data mining and
knowledge discovery. Firstly we write a script to run speed test
periodically and log the metric. Then we parse the log data and
convert them into a time series and visualize the data for a certain
period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we conduct some data analysis; finding trends, forecasting, and
detecting anomalous data. There will be several statistic or deep
learning techniques used for the analysis; ARIMA (Autoregressive
Integrated Moving Average), LSTM (Long Short Term Memory).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to provide basic idea how to run speed test and collect
metrics by automated script in Python. Also, I will provide high
level concept of the methodologies for analyzing time series data.
Also, I would like to motivate Python people to try this at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session is designed to be accessible to everyone, including
anyone with no expertise in mathematics, computer science.
Understandings of basic concepts of machine learning and some Python
tools bringing such concepts into practice might be helpful, but not
necessary for the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>