<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jiamou Liu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jiamou-liu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Selling Data at an Auction under Privacy Constraints</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/selling-data-at-an-auction-under-privacy-constraints.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mengxiao Zhang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/selling-data-at-an-auction-under-privacy-constraints.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selling Data at an Auction under Privacy Constraintsㅇ
ㅇMengxiao Zhang (The University of Auckland)*; Fernando Beltran (The University of Auckland); Jiamou Liu (University of Auckland)ㅇㅇPrivate data query combines mechanism design with privacy protection to produce aggregated statistics from privately-owned data records. The problem arises in a data marketplace …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selling Data at an Auction under Privacy Constraintsㅇ
ㅇMengxiao Zhang (The University of Auckland)*; Fernando Beltran (The University of Auckland); Jiamou Liu (University of Auckland)ㅇㅇPrivate data query combines mechanism design with privacy protection to produce aggregated statistics from privately-owned data records. The problem arises in a data marketplace where data owners have personalised privacy requirements and private data valuations. We focus on the case when the data owners are single-minded, i.e., they are willing to release their data only if the data broker guarantees to meet their announced privacy requirements. For a data broker who wants to purchase data from such data owners, we propose the SingleMindedQuery (SMQ) mechanism, which uses a reverse auction to select data owners and determine compensations. SMQ satisfies interim incentive compatibility, individual rationality, and budget feasibility. Moreover, it uses purchased privacy expectation maximisation as a principle to produce accurate outputs for commonly-used queries such as counting, median and linear predictor. The effectiveness of our method is empirically validated by a series of experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>