<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 16:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Refactor Yourself</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/refactor-yourself.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you sometimes feel like a pile of legacy code? Do you dread
refactoring yourself into a &amp;quot;new hotness,” due to the insurmountable
amount of work it may take? Do you want to break free, but are unsure of
where to start? Look no further, as this session will embark on a
journey to refactor you, one red- green test at a time, starting with
the highest priority issues first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have been there (or witnessed it in someone else): glassy-eyed,
glaring into many open screens, fingers rushing through multiple lines
of code, energy drink of some sort by your side, and possibly snacks
that were dug out of the pantry (which should have been disposed of long
ago). You are now propelled into a sleepless night — and hopefully,
victory by the time the sun comes up. As you sit there trying to solve
yet another complex problem, you become keenly aware of the fuzzy
sensation in your brain, the fatigue in your body, the somewhat weird
noises in your stomach, and your general lack of capacity to process
what it is you came here to do. In this talk, we will walk through
concepts of sleep hygiene, eating habits, digestive concerns, body
aches, strains, and pains, mood concerns, and how they all affect your
ability to function. We will discuss how to examine your recent
behavior, prioritize any symptoms, what to tackle first, and how to
persevere in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Esther B. Gotfryd</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/refactor-yourself.html</guid></item></channel></rss>