<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Patrick van den Berg</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_patrick-van-den-berg.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Automating the Dutch National Flu Surveillance for Pandemic Preparedness</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/automating-the-dutch-national-flu-surveillance-for-pandemic-preparedness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Patrick van den Berg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/automating-the-dutch-national-flu-surveillance-for-pandemic-preparedness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next pandemic may be caused by a flu strain, and with thousands of patients with the flu in Dutch hospitals annually it is important to have accurate and current data. The National Institute for Public Health and the Environment of the Netherlands (RIVM) collects and processes flu data …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next pandemic may be caused by a flu strain, and with thousands of patients with the flu in Dutch hospitals annually it is important to have accurate and current data. The National Institute for Public Health and the Environment of the Netherlands (RIVM) collects and processes flu data to achieve pandemic preparedness. However, the flu reporting process used to be very laborious, stealing precious time from epidemiologists. In our journey of automating this data pipeline we learned that collaboration was the most important factor in getting to a working system. This talk will be at the cross-section of data science and epidemiology and will provide you with a valuable opportunity to learn from our experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>