<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_matthieu-amiguet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python for realtime audio processing in a live music context</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/python-for-realtime-audio-processing-in-a-live-music-context.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matthieu Amiguet</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/python-for-realtime-audio-processing-in-a-live-music-context.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Les Chemins de Traverse we explore ways of &amp;quot;augmenting&amp;quot; acoustical
musical instruments with new sonic possibilities offered by computers.
For doing so, we need ultra-low latency real-time audio processing
programs. Pretty much the typical situation where python should &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be
used, right? Wrong. As it happens, that's exactly what we've been doing
for the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on Olivier Belanger's wonderful pyo module and (ab)using
python's flexibility, we developed custom software to allow us to
express our musical ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to hear how it sounds, you should go to Europython's social
event that will feature a gig based on python-augmented (!) instruments.
And if you want to know how we came to use python in this context and
how we do it, you should come to this talk!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Augmented Reality"></category><category term="DIY"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="Use Case"></category></entry><entry><title>Matthieu Amiguet – Charming Snake: Python for Live Music – SPS16</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/swiss-python-summit-2016/matthieu-amiguet-charming-snake-python-for-live-music-sps16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matthieu Amiguet</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-05:swiss-python-summit-2016/matthieu-amiguet-charming-snake-python-for-live-music-sps16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;At Les Chemins de Traverse we explore ways of &amp;quot;augmenting&amp;quot; acoustical musical instruments with new possibilities offered by computers. For doing so, we need ultra-low latency real-time audio processing programs. Pretty much the typical situation where python should &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be used, right? Wrong. We've recently included python (with a strong use of Olivier Bélanger's wonderful pyo module) in our set of tools for realizing the musical ideas we have in mind. This talk will expose why we came to consider python as a very interesting option for our realtime audio systems and how we use it on stage, with code and sound samples.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk recorded at the Swiss Python Summit on February 5th, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licensed as Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>