<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sarah Hersh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sarah-hersh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Start with the tasks, not the endpoints</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2017/start-with-the-tasks-not-the-endpoints.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Hersh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-15:/write-the-docs-portland-2017/start-with-the-tasks-not-the-endpoints.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last spring, as I approached reworking the information architecture of
the NPR One Developer Center, I started by interviewing several of our
partner developers to find out what pain points they encountered when
developing on our platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmingly, the responses included complaints about confusing site
navigation and frustration around …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last spring, as I approached reworking the information architecture of
the NPR One Developer Center, I started by interviewing several of our
partner developers to find out what pain points they encountered when
developing on our platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmingly, the responses included complaints about confusing site
navigation and frustration around having to search multiple pages to
string together the necessary information to implement features. After
considering this feedback, we redesigned the documentation site to focus
on information needed to complete a desired task, and while we still
provide endpoint reference documentation, my focus now is to start from
thinking about what a developer is trying to accomplish, rather than
what data an endpoint is capable of providing. Essentially, the focus of
the docs shifted away from what the API can do, towards what “I”, as the
developer, can do with this API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a task-oriented approach allowed us to reorganize and revise our
content in a way that has significantly shortened our onboarding process
for partner developers, shortening the app verification process and
time-to- market, and most importantly allows us to better collaborate
with our partners to develop exciting new experiences for NPR listeners.
For those who work on documenting hypermedia APIs, this can be a
particularly useful approach, since these services tend to have fewer
specific endpoints, and the documentation needs to focus much more on
how the client can successfully navigate links to accomplish the desired
task. In this 30-minute talk, I' ll discuss how you can successfully
integrate this approach to your workflow when considering everything
from overall information architecture, to deciding which content assets
to prioritize, to refining the tone used throughout your developer
communications.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Portland 2017"></category></entry></feed>