<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_min-khant-zaw.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Writing a good frontend test cases using RobotFramework</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/writing-a-good-frontend-test-cases-using-robotframework.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Min Khant Zaw</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/writing-a-good-frontend-test-cases-using-robotframework.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is a short talk about how a simple Gherkin-styled Python based Robotframework could be used to write test cases. It covers the brief installation using python envwrapper - an environment isolation package and simply showing 2 python scripts which is usable with Robotframework and 1~2 Robotframework's keyword-based testing. It will also cover some important inbuilt functions in Robotframeworks such as sending out keystrokes to the System and using some other libraries to help and make front-end testing a much more awesome experience. Another part of the talk would be describing a single keyword base and some yaml scripts to make the test-cases more reusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name's Min Khant Zaw. I am Computer Science student who is enthusiastic about mostly near-to-the-metal stuff. I mostly code in C++, Java and Python but I use C++ the most because I like playing around with Algorithms.  I am also the President of the IT Society in my campus and had organized over 10 events for the Computer Science students. I mostly spent my time listening to British Synth Pop and spitting out all the crappy codes I can come up with in Sublime Text.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>