<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sqlkit: empowering database access</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlkit-empowering-database-access.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Alessandro Dentella - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's very easy to access databases with Python, and there are many ORMs
allowing a high level of abstraction. Still, it's a long road from there
to interactive handling of data, even for very simple tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sqlkit tries to act as a bridge, offering some mega-widgets that allow
you to build GUI applications or directly access data using the
'sqledit' application, shipped with sqlkit; sqlkit is built with PyGTK
and SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation covers some of the most powerful features of sqlkit,
and shows how easy it is to build small programs for personal use, as
well as rich and complex applications. It primarily focuses on two
points: how easy it is to create data forms (eventually with one2many or
many2many, thanks to a original definition of layouts), and the template
system based on OpenOffice which allows easy report creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation shows how sqlkit can be used both as application
development framework and as a tool to help us while developing other
applications (e.g.: Django, OpenERP,… ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deliver a gradual presentation, we'll use the configuration system of
sqledit, starting from a minimal configuration (a single URL) we'll add
elements to that until we'll have a full application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Dentella</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/sqlkit-empowering-database-access.html</guid><category>database</category><category>forms</category><category>framework</category><category>gui</category><category>openoffice</category><category>python,</category></item><item><title>Sqlkit: database ad accesso immediato</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlkit-database-ad-accesso-immediato.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Alessandro Dentella - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Italiana
Big Mac&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;È molto facile accedere ad un database con Python e ci sono molti ORM
che permettono un alto livello di astrazione. Da qui c'é ancora una
lunga strada per arrivare a manipolare interattivamente i dati anche per
semplici compiti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sqlkit cerca di coprire questa distanza fornendo alcuni mega-widgets che
permettono di costruire ogni applicazione GUI o accedere direttamente ai
dati con l'applicazione 'sqledit', che viene distribuita con sqlkit.
Sqlkit è costruita con PyGTK e SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa presentazione esplora alcune fra le più potenti caratteristiche
di sqlkit e mostra quanto sia semplice costruire piccoli programmini ad
uso personale o applicazioni ricche ed articolate. Si focalizza
principalmente su due punti: quanto sia facile creare maschere per
editare dati (anche relazioni on2many o many2many, grazie al modo
originale di definire i layout) e al sistema di template basato su
OpenOffice che rende incredibilmente semplice creare report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa presentazione vuole mostrare come sqlkit può essere usato sia
come framework di sviluppo di applicazioni, sia come strumento che ci
aiuta mentre sviluppiamo altre applicazioni (es.: Django, OpenERP,… ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per rendere la presentazione più graduale, sfrutteremo il sistema di
configurazione di sqledit Partendo da una configurazione minima -un URL-
aggiungeremo elementi fino ad ottenere una vera applicazione.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Dentella</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/sqlkit-database-ad-accesso-immediato.html</guid><category>ci</category><category>database</category><category>framework</category><category>gui</category><category>openoffice</category><category>orm</category></item></channel></rss>