<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_paul-nation.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>QuTiP: An open-source Python framework for the dynamics of open quantum systems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/qutip-an-open-source-python-framework-for-the-dy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Nation</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/qutip-an-open-source-python-framework-for-the-dy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present QuTiP, an object-oriented open-source framework for solving
the dynamics of open quantum systems. The QuTiP framework is written in
a combination of Python and Cython, and using SciPy, NumPy and
matplotlib to provide an environment for computational quantum mechanics
that is easy and efficient to use. Arbitrary quantum systems, including
time-dependent systems, may be built up from operators and states
defined by a quantum object class, and then passed on to a choice of
unitary and dissipative evolution solvers. We give an overview of the
basic structure for the framework and the techniques used in its
implementation. We also present a few selected examples from
contemporary research on quantum mechanics that illustrate the strengths
of the framework, and the types of calculation that can be performed.
The framework described here is particularly well suited to the fields
of quantum optics, superconducting circuit devices, nanomechanics, and
trapped ions, while also being ideal as an educational tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qutip.googlecode.com"&gt;http://qutip.googlecode.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hpc"></category></entry></feed>