<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Shir Meir Lador</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The secret sauce of data science management</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/the-secret-sauce-of-data-science-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Shir Meir Lador&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Machine Learning &amp;amp; Stats
The question - “how to become a successful data scientist?” is often discussed in conferences like these. Today I would like to address a second level question. How to make the success scale? How to build a DS team in which the whole is greater than the sum of its parts?
The question - “how to become a successful data scientist?” is often discussed in conferences like these. Today I would like to address a second level question. How to make the success scale? How to build a DS team in which the whole is greater than the sum of its parts?
In this talk, I will share lessons learned during my 4 years as data science team &amp;amp; group leader on how to build a DS team that prospers while addressing the unique challenges of leading such a team.
We will discuss how to create the setting for a DS to grow and research while driving winning results for the organization. I will share our AI playbook that enables us to select the right projects to maximize our value and to collaborate with our partners most effectively to bring them to production. In addition we will discuss the importance of communication with upper management and how to do it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/LWUWAU"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/LWUWAU&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shir Meir Lador</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-11:/pycon-de-2022/the-secret-sauce-of-data-science-management.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2022</category><category>PyCon</category><category>PyConDE</category><category>pyconde2022</category><category>pydata</category><category>PyDataBerlin</category><category>pydataberlin2022</category></item><item><title>5 Simple Steps to Create Meaningful Features from Clickstream Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2017/5-simple-steps-to-create-meaningful-features-from-clickstream-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predicting client financial behaviour is usually done by financial data sources - such as client financial history, bank and credit statements, etc. In this talk we will review a different type of data source for risk assessment - features engineered from clickstream data gathered by Mixpanel. We will discuss what kind of features can be generated from clickstream data and how to generate these features using Pandas, what is the benefit of these unconventional features, what are the different correlations of the features with user financial behaviour and how can you apply clickstream data analysis to your problems in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shir Meir Lador</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-12:/pycon-israel-2017/5-simple-steps-to-create-meaningful-features-from-clickstream-data.html</guid><category>PyCon Israel 2017</category></item><item><title>Fraud detection challenges and data skepticism using LIME</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/fraud-detection-challenges-and-data-skepticism-using-lime.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shir presents the story of developing a machine learning model which automatically approves factoring deals, the challenges in the model training, evaluation and interpretation including a mysterious problem in the model creation and the details of its final solution. In addition she discusses data leakage, overfitting and a cutting-edge framework for model explanations (LIME).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shir Meir Lador</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-01-05:/pydata-meetups/fraud-detection-challenges-and-data-skepticism-using-lime.html</guid><category>PyData Meetups</category></item></channel></rss>