<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mike Mead</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mike-mead.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Be the CEO of Your Career</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/be-the-ceo-of-your-career.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Mead</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-22:/python-web-conf-2022/be-the-ceo-of-your-career.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does career success mean to you?  How will you achieve it?  In this session, whether you want to climb the corporate ladder or find greater fulfillment in your current role, you’ll learn creative methods to help you achieve your ultimate career success.  We’ll discuss these three …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does career success mean to you?  How will you achieve it?  In this session, whether you want to climb the corporate ladder or find greater fulfillment in your current role, you’ll learn creative methods to help you achieve your ultimate career success.  We’ll discuss these three questions:
* What do you want?  Defining success in your terms
* How do you win? Mastering the “career behaviors” that matter most
* Why does it matter? Creating your legacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>