<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Atieno Ouma</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_atieno-ouma.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>SIGN-TO-TEXT:Unleashing the Power of Google AI for real time ASL transcription</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2023/sign-to-textunleashing-the-power-of-google-ai-for-real-time-asl-transcription.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Atieno Ouma</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-24:/pycon-uk-2023/sign-to-textunleashing-the-power-of-google-ai-for-real-time-asl-transcription.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will delve into how leveraging Google's cutting-edge tools and frameworks, combined with Python, can revolutionize the way we bridge the communication gap between sign language users and the wider world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication barriers between the deaf and hard-of-hearing community and the wider world have created significant …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will delve into how leveraging Google's cutting-edge tools and frameworks, combined with Python, can revolutionize the way we bridge the communication gap between sign language users and the wider world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication barriers between the deaf and hard-of-hearing community and the wider world have created significant challenges in effective interaction.However the good news is cutting-edge AI technologies can revolutionize the way we transcribe American Sign Language (ASL) and enable inclusive communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the power of Python libraries and Google's AI tools, including the Google Cloud Vision API for hand and finger tracking, TensorFlow for deep learning models, and AutoML for data scarcity challenges, I will demonstrate Sign_To_Text, a revolutionary system that transforms how sign language users connect with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Witness live demonstrations as I seamlessly integrate Google AI technologies to translate fingerspelled letters in real time into textual representations, empowering individuals and fostering inclusive communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon UK 2023"></category></entry></feed>