<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>My Journey With Code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/my-journey-with-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anna’s keynote will dive into her journey with coding, what got her
interested in programming and why she chose Python despite the language
not being popular in her region. She will also talk about her journey
learning to code in Python and how her involvement in the Python
community as a beginner has helped her grow and develop her coding
skills. She will share what mentorship means to her and how positive
mentorship can impact the lives of many beginner coders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/my-journey-with-code.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Building a Python community in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-nigeria-2018/building-a-python-community-in-zimbabwe.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-13:pycon-nigeria-2018/building-a-python-community-in-zimbabwe.html</guid></item><item><title>Diversity Panel: experience and discussion from all over the world</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion table about Diversity in all its hues with organizers and
experts from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</guid><category>diversity</category><category>panel</category></item><item><title>Python in Africa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</guid><category>conferences</category><category>business</category><category>startup</category><category>beginner</category><category>community</category><category>women</category><category>teamwork</category><category>OpenSource</category><category>social</category><category>pyladies</category><category>education</category><category>Learning environment</category><category>user-groups</category></item><item><title>All about community panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion about the efforts to have open, and sustainable communities (in economic, physical and emotional sense) and how this reflects on individuals&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Russell Keith-Magee</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</guid></item><item><title>Setting up a Python Community in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/setting-up-a-python-community-in-zimbabwe.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organizing Python events with the aim of setting up a Python community in a collapsed economy, without an open source software development house is not an easy task. In this talk, we share the journey we have traveled trying to set up a community that defies the existing norms/culture in the IT sector in Zimbabwe. We share the experiences and the challenges we faced in setting up a Python community in Zimbabwe as well as the sacrifices we have had to make to ensure PyCon Zimbabwe would take place. In our talk, we also elaborate why the lack of know-how and information can hinder the growth of a community. We also share our successes and the milestones we have managed to reach in establishing our community. We also share on the importance of support from established communities and the impact it has on an emerging community. The aim of our talk is to share the challenges faced by developers in developing countries and convince participants on how they can contribute to OSS communities in developing countries and why they should. By the end of this talk, participants should understand why understanding the context is so important in promoting the growth of communities outside their own region. In the end, we hope to convince the audience why we felt travelling a road trip of more than 33hrs was worth the while. We will conclude by sharing with the audience what we feel should be the future of open source in Zimbabwe and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/setting-up-a-python-community-in-zimbabwe.html</guid></item><item><title>Open Source Software Initiatives in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/open-source-software-initiatives-in-zimbabwe.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zimbabwean companies and individuals have been consumers of open source
software for over a decade now. Nevertheless, developers in Zimbabwe
have done little in terms of developing an active and vibrant open
source community until 2015 which saw the establishment of PyZim. This
is because affiliation to professional bodies is not heavily emphasized
in most industries, especially the ICT industry. The economic challenges
facing the country for the past two decades have also made affiliation
to such organisations a luxury as the country has over 90% unemployment
rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this background, it is no surprise that setting up a vibrant
Python user group has been fraught with many challenges. In my talk, I
intent to share the journey we have traveled in setting up PyZim. I will
also share our experiences organising Django Girls workshops and PyCon
Zimbabwe 2016. I will also share with the audience the challenges faced,
opportunities arising, benefits accrued and important lessons learnt
through the experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-07:pycon-za-2016/open-source-software-initiatives-in-zimbabwe.html</guid></item></channel></rss>