<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_patrick-marsh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Utilizing Python in a Real-Time, Quasi-Operational Meteorological Environment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/utilizing-python-in-a-real-time-quasi-operationa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Patrick Marsh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/utilizing-python-in-a-real-time-quasi-operationa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's (NOAA) Hazardous
Weather Testbed (HWT) is a facility jointly managed by NOAA's National
Severe Storms Laboratory (NSSL), NOAA National Weather Service's (NWS)
the Storm Prediction Center (SPC), and the NOAA NWS Oklahoma City/Norman
Weather Forecast Office (OUN) within the National Weather Center
building on the University of Oklahoma South Research Campus. The HWT is
designed to accelerate the transition of promising new meteorological
insights and technologies into advances in forecasting and warning for
hazardous weather events throughout the United States. The HWT
facilities include a combined forecast and research area situated
between the operations rooms of the SPC and OUN, and a nearby
development laboratory. The facilities support enhanced collaboration
between research scientists and operational weather forecasters on
specific topics that are of mutual interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cornerstone of the HWT is the yearly Experimental Forecast Program
(EFP) and Experimental Warning Program (EWP) which take place every
spring. In each of those programs, forecasters, researchers, and
developers come together to participate in a real-time operational
forecasting or warning environment with the purpose of testing and
evaluating cutting-edge tools and methods for forecasting and warning.
In the EFP program, between 5 and 10 TB of meteorological data are
processed for evaluation over the course of a 5 week period. These data
come in a variety of sources, a variety of formats, each requiring a
different set of processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss how the data flow and data creation processes of
the EFP are accomplished in a real-time setting through the use of
Python. The utilization of Python ranges from simple shell scripting, to
speeding up algorithm development (and runtimes) with Numpy and Cython,
to creating new, open source data-visualization platforms, such as the
Skew-T and Hodograph Analysis and Research Program in Python, or
SHARPpy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Meteorology Mini-Symposia"></category></entry></feed>