<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Patrick Smyth</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Notebooks for All: Accessibility &amp; Jupyter Notebooks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/notebooks-for-all-accessibility-jupyter-notebooks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This poster summarizes the &amp;quot;Astronomy Notebooks For All&amp;quot; project undertaken in 2022-2023 by Space Telescope Science Institute. We are researching how Jupyter Notebooks can be made more accessible through paid usability testing sessions with disabled developers, scientists, and students. Our focus is on the compatibility of Jupyter Notebooks with assistive technologies such as screen readers, magnification, and braille readers. Additionally, we are developing potential solutions for the problems we find that may be incorporated upstream into the wider Jupyter project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This poster will examine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility issues with Jupyter Notebooks and how these problems frequently keep disabled people out of careers in data and bench sciences.
Our user-centered method of tackling this difficult problem by cycling between paid usability feedback sessions with impacted users and implementation of accessibility enhancements. We repeat this until we create a benchmark notebook built with a more accessible structure to contribute back to the community.
Stories of how Jupyter accessibility impacts community members, including case studies of people with disabilities deterred from pursuing careers in STEM by inaccessible tools.
Specific problems we have uncovered so far and solutions we have tried for those problems. Solutions will focus on both individual authors and the wider codebase.
Our team from a variety of organizations (Space Telescope Science Institute, Iota School, Quansight) with a diverse array of skills used in the project.
How members of the Jupyter community can contribute to further work towards accessibility and inclusion in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Smyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/notebooks-for-all-accessibility-jupyter-notebooks.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Cheese Must Stand: Defending the Python Library Ecosystem in 2025</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/cheese-must-stand-defending-the-python-library-ecosystem-in-2025.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supply chain attacks on Python package infrastructure increased in frequency and sophistication in 2024. As PyPI comes under threat, how can we continue to secure our beloved cheese shop through 2025?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 600k packages in PyPI power sensitive infrastructure in almost every critical industry, and it's no surprise that the Python library ecosystem is a target. In 2024 alone, the Ultralytics token compromise and the NP6 combined typosquatting and DLL sideloading attack show the sophistication of these supply chain attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this talk (12 minutes), we'll look back at these 2024 attacks and also consider examples such as the &amp;quot;revival hijack&amp;quot; attack vector and the 2022 dependency confusion attack on PyTorch. In the second portion (12 minutes), we'll dig into some critical developments in this area that have helped to mitigate recent attacks, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provenance transparency logs using Sigstore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progressive supply chain security levels with SLSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software Bills of Materials (sbomS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artifact scanners such as Grype and Trivy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also briefly discuss specific insights from developing Chainguard’s Guarded Ecosystems for Python, an ambitious alternative package index that rebuilds included packages from scratch. The final takeaway: while mitigations exist for these threats, they're not equally distributed, and we'll point out low hanging fruit for securing projects and infrastructure (3 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be an accessible introduction to an intermediate topic (software supply chain security). Expect some cheesy puns and memes as we deal with this muenster problem—all in excellent taste, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick recently received best speaker at SwampUP 2024. Srishti and Patrick recently teamed up for PyTorch 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Smyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-18:/pycon-us-2025/cheese-must-stand-defending-the-python-library-ecosystem-in-2025.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item><item><title>Beyond Zero: Eliminating Vulnerabilities in PyTorch Container Images</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/beyond-zero-eliminating-vulnerabilities-in-pytorch-container-images.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Container images are increasingly the future of production applications at scale, providing reproducibility, robustness, and transparency. As PyTorch images get deployed to production, however, security becomes a major concern. PyTorch has a large attack surface, and building secure PyTorch images can be a challenge. Currently, the official PyTorch runtime container image has 30 CVEs (known vulnerabilities) rated critical and 256 CVE rated high. Improving this situation could secure many deployments that incorporate PyTorch for cloud-based inference or training. In this fast-paced session, we'll take a deep dive on the official PyTorch image from a vulnerability mitigation perspective, looking hard at included packages, executables, and active CVE. We'll identify low-hanging fruit for increasing security, including stripping bloat and building fresh. We'll also talk about the next level of security practiced in Chainguard's PyTorch image builds, such as including SBOMs and going distroless. Finally, we'll consider emerging tools and approaches for analyzing AI artifacts such as models and how these systems can benefit PyTorch in production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Smyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/beyond-zero-eliminating-vulnerabilities-in-pytorch-container-images.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category><category>Lightning Talk</category></item></channel></rss>