<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Satellite data is for everyone: insights into modern remote sensing research with open data and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/satellite-data-is-for-everyone-insights-into-modern-remote-sensing-research-with-open-data-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The largest earth observation programme Copernicus
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://copernicus.eu"&gt;http://copernicus.eu&lt;/a&gt;) makes it possible to perform terrestrial
observations providing data for all kinds of purposes. One important
objective is to monitor the land-use and land-cover changes with the
Sentinel-2 satellite mission. These satellites measure the sun
reflectance on the earth surface with multispectral cameras (13 channels
between 440 nm to 2190 nm). Machine learning techniques like
convolutional neural networks (CNN) are able to learn the link between
the satellite image (spectrum) and the ground truth (land use class). In
this talk, we give an overview about the state-of-the-art land-use
classification with CNNs based on an open dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EuroSAT benchmark dataset (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://madm.dfki.de/downloads"&gt;http://madm.dfki.de/downloads&lt;/a&gt;) is freely
provided by German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI).
It consists of 27.000 image patches for ten different land use/cover
classes, e.g. industrial and residential areas, different crop and
vegetation types and forests. All samples have 64 by 64 pixel dimension
and include either only the RGB images or all 13 bands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use different out-of-box CNNs for the Keras deep learning
library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://keras.io/"&gt;https://keras.io/&lt;/a&gt;). All networks are either included in Keras
itself or are available from Github repositories. We will show the
process of transfer learning for the RGB datasets. Furthermore, the
minimal changes required to apply commonly used CNNs to multispectral
data are demonstrated. Thus, the interested audience will be able to
perform their own classification of remote sensing data within a very
short time. Results of different network structures are visually
compared. Especially the differences of transfer learning and learning
from scratch are demonstrated. This also includes the amount of
necessary training epochs, progress of training and validation error and
visual comparison of the results of the trained networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we give a quick overview about the current research topics
including recurrent neural networks for spatio-temporal land-use
classification and further applications of multi- and hyperspectral
data, e.g. for the estimation of water parameters and soil
characteristics. Additionally, we provide links to the code and dataset
used in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felix M. Riese</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/satellite-data-is-for-everyone-insights-into-modern-remote-sensing-research-with-open-data-and-python.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Computer Vision</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Science</category></item></channel></rss>