<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Liz Roten</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_liz-roten.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The 'I' in Team: Peer-to-Peer Best Practices for Growing Data Science Teams</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/the-i-in-team-peer-to-peer-best-practices-for-growing-data-science-teams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Liz Roten</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/the-i-in-team-peer-to-peer-best-practices-for-growing-data-science-teams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;R users don't always come in sets. Often, you may be the only user on in the cubicle-block. But, one miraculous day, your manager finally fills the void and you welcome more folks on your team. Suddenly, the little R system you created to suit your needs, like a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;R users don't always come in sets. Often, you may be the only user on in the cubicle-block. But, one miraculous day, your manager finally fills the void and you welcome more folks on your team. Suddenly, the little R system you created to suit your needs, like a custom package, code styling, and file organization, isn't just for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to suddenly overhaul that one package you wrote two years ago? It probably won't work when your colleagues try to update it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your new teammates are data.table fans, but you prefer the tidyverse. Do you need to refactor? Are style choices, like indentation important when collaborating, or are you just being persnickety?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how to bring new teammates on board and blend your respective styles without pulling your hair out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry></feed>