<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Machine Learning for Inventory Management</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-for-inventory-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Material forecast is the process of deciding which items to stock in the
inventory, how much, and when. Aim of the forecast is to increase parts
availability with the less possible impact on inventory, having enough
stock in the warehouse to ensure the business keeps moving but not
enough stock to drain its limited cash reserves. This decision process
is being profoundly revised in its foundational concepts, thanks to new
classification methodologies enabled by Machine Learning. We integrated
domain knowledge and ML to create a new classification and level setting
process, leveraging on 6 years of data and new statistical indicators
for demand patter. These new features are used to run the machine
learning algorithm that classify Make To Stock / Make To Order items in
a single flow approach. The validation phase is reduced at each
iteration as ML model can be re-trained to incorporate past validations,
increasing efficiency and performances. Level setting problem is
addressed benchmarking ML methods (Reinforcement Learning), Montecarlo
simulations and traditional statistical methodologies. Regarding RL and
Montecarlo we established punishments for letting an particular
inventory item run out of stock and we also punish the model for stock
too higher value for too long. For rewards, we primarily focus on
ordering items within a safe window before the demand. First application
of this new methodology brings a 20% reduction of inventory, without
impact on sales, and a workload reduction of about 70%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1554"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1554&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laura De Stefanis</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-for-inventory-management.html</guid><category>logistics</category><category>clustering</category><category>statistics</category><category>Python</category><category>Big-Data</category><category>gestionali</category><category>django</category><category>supplychain</category><category>sql</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category></item></channel></rss>