<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daniel-lindeman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-27T10:30:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>“Who’d I Lend That Book To?” Hard Questions Answered with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/whod-i-lend-that-book-to-hard-questions-answered-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-27T10:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T10:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lindeman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-27:pyohio-2019/whod-i-lend-that-book-to-hard-questions-answered-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love reading books, but I love lending them out even more! In order to
keep track of my personal library, a daunting task indeed, I’ve employed
Python, a Raspberry Pi, and an RFID reader. Take a tour through what
it’s like working with hardware, Python, and putting it all together
into a useful web application. This is a beginner friendly talk, so
don’t worry if you’ve never worked with hardware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) is here to stay, but getting started can
seem intimidating. Inspired by the magical checkout process at my local
library, I began the journey of building my own IoT book lending
application. Along the way, I discovered that Python was consistently
able to make the impossible seem approachable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start with a base installation of Raspbian on a Raspberry Pi and
find that Python is already there waiting to help. Then we’ll hook up an
RFID reader to our Pi, and see that even though it has wires and pins,
it’s nothing to be scared of. With the RFID reader and the fantastic
MFRC522-python library, we’re able to read and write data to RFID
stickers, neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could stop here, but we’ve got Python, so let’s hook it up to a Flask
app and end at a complete book lending application. I hope attendees
will gain an appreciation for the technology all around them, their
local library, and how powerful Python is. I hope to demystify working
with hardware and dispel some perceived barriers to entry for IoT
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python in Serverless Architectures</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2018/python-in-serverless-architectures.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lindeman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-29:pyohio-2018/python-in-serverless-architectures.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serverless architectures are all the rage right now, but why? The cost
savings? The developer story? Because it's shiny and new? In this talk I
will start with a basic Flask App and show the process of migrating to a
serverless architecture on AWS using the Serverless framework. Along the
way, we'll also highlight some of the tradeoffs developers make when
choosing a serverless architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>