<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Becca Krouse</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_becca-krouse.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>{slushy}: A Bridge to the Future</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/slushy-a-bridge-to-the-future.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Becca Krouse</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/slushy-a-bridge-to-the-future.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scaling the use of R can present complications for environment management, especially in regulated industries with a focus on traceability. One solution is controlled (aka &amp;quot;frozen&amp;quot;) environments, which are carefully curated and tested by tech teams. However, the speed of R development means the environments quickly become outdated and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scaling the use of R can present complications for environment management, especially in regulated industries with a focus on traceability. One solution is controlled (aka &amp;quot;frozen&amp;quot;) environments, which are carefully curated and tested by tech teams. However, the speed of R development means the environments quickly become outdated and users are unable to benefit from the latest advances. Enter {slushy}: a team-friendly tool powered by {renv} and Posit Package Manager. Users can quickly mimic a controlled environment, with the easy ability to time travel between snapshot dates. Attendees will learn how {slushy} bolstered our R adoption efforts, and how this strategy enables tech teams and users to work in parallel towards a common future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Stitch by Stitch: The Art of Engaging New Users</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/stitch-by-stitch-the-art-of-engaging-new-users.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Becca Krouse</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/stitch-by-stitch-the-art-of-engaging-new-users.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the world of crochet, the Woobles kit simplifies yarn, hooks, and stitches for beginners, alleviating decision fatigue and fostering early success. This model unexpectedly extends to the domain of R. Newcomers, especially in industries less familiar with open-source, may find mastering new tools daunting. We grappled with this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the world of crochet, the Woobles kit simplifies yarn, hooks, and stitches for beginners, alleviating decision fatigue and fostering early success. This model unexpectedly extends to the domain of R. Newcomers, especially in industries less familiar with open-source, may find mastering new tools daunting. We grappled with this while developing {tfrmt}, a table-making package for pharma. This talk will draw parallels with crochet to explore strategies for engaging and retaining new users. Attendees will grasp the role of a starter kit for easing the learning curve and the value of nurturing experts with transferable skills. They'll glean insights to support their own audiences, whether in creating an R package or crafting a cuddly unicorn.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>