<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Stefan Krawczyk</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stefan-krawczyk.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Why you should be using structured logs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/why-you-should-be-using-structured-logs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Krawczyk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-16:/pybay-2019/why-you-should-be-using-structured-logs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
At Stitch Fix most application logs are output in a structured JSON format for simpler debugging and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
At Stitch Fix most application logs are output in a structured JSON format for simpler debugging and downstream consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll cover in more detail why structured logs are useful and provide leverage, caveats to using them, and how simple it is to get one going with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
At Stitch Fix most application logs are output in a structured JSON format for simpler debugging and downstream consumption. For example, data scientists can add a field to their application log and it will automatically turn up as a parsed field in Elasticsearch for easy dashboarding and querying via Kibana, or be easily found and queried in Presto. In this talk we’ll cover in more detail why structured logs are useful and provide leverage, caveats to using them, and how simple it is to get one going with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Stefan loves the stimulus of working at the intersection of design, engineering, and data. He grew up in New Zealand, speaks Polish, and spent formative years at Stanford, LinkedIn, Nextdoor &amp;amp; Idibon. Outside of work Stefan likes to 🏊, 🌮, 🍺, and ✈.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks DAY 3 | SciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Axel Donath</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>