<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Abhishek Sanwaliya</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_abhishek-sanwaliya.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Network Embeddings based Recommendation Model with multi-factor consideration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/network-embeddings-based-recommendation-model-with-multi-factor-consideration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abhishek Sanwaliya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/network-embeddings-based-recommendation-model-with-multi-factor-consideration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - A Network Embeddings based Recommendation Model with multi-factor consideration - presented by ABHISHEK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method consists of three main steps: First, network embedding formulation performed on each user specific behavior network; Then, embeddings weight distribution estimated through intermediate layers of network with final …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - A Network Embeddings based Recommendation Model with multi-factor consideration - presented by ABHISHEK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method consists of three main steps: First, network embedding formulation performed on each user specific behavior network; Then, embeddings weight distribution estimated through intermediate layers of network with final layer for target (item purchased as labels); Finally, both factors: (a) Learned weights from implicit data (cross-domain) and (b) explicit factors from domain data used by multi-factorization method for recommendations.
The proposed method transfers knowledge across implicit and explicit factors and associated dimensions. The suggested approach tested real-world data with evidence of outperforming existing algorithms with significant lift in recommendation accuracy. Empirical experimentation outcomes illustrate the potential of both factors for making effective recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>