<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_i-kang-ding.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-03T16:15:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Lessons learned from building a community of Python users among thousands of analysts</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/lessons-learned-from-building-a-community-of-python-users-among-thousands-of-analysts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T16:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T16:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>I-Kang Ding</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/lessons-learned-from-building-a-community-of-python-users-among-thousands-of-analysts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting a few years ago, Capital One has committed to go all-in on
public cloud and open source software for many of our core business
operations, processes, and machine learning models. To support this
transformation, we embarked on a multi-year journey to build a Python
community with critical mass of users, and scale adoption of Python in
our business analyst and data analyst workforces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has been envisioned since its early days as a programming
language which can be used to &amp;quot;create better, easier to use tools for
program development and analysis&amp;quot;, as well as &amp;quot;build a user community
around all of the above, encouraging feedback and self-help&amp;quot;. [1] In our
experience scaling Python adoption amongst analyst communities within a
Fortune 500 company, we have found the aforementioned visions true to
form - not only is Python a great first programming language for our
analysts to learn, it also comes with &amp;quot;batteries included&amp;quot; and contains
many of the data-related tools and libraries which allows our analysts
to get productive very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will highlight our multi-pronged approaches to overcome
organizational inertia to build a community of Python users, provide
Python and OSS training, and encourage Python adoption (with mixed
success). We'll share what (we think) best practices are out there, and
lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference: [1] Computer Programming for Everybody
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/doc/essays/cp4e.html"&gt;http://www.python.org/doc/essays/cp4e.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry></feed>