<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AI: Differentiating Hype and Real Value</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/ai-differentiating-hype-and-real-value.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prof. Dr. Michael Feindt&lt;/strong&gt; is the brain behind Blue Yonder GmbH . His NeuroBayes algorithm was developed during his many years of scientific research at CERN. Michael is also a professor at the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Germany, and a lecturer at the Data Science Academy.
Artificial Intelligence: Differentiating Hype and Real Value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from the evolution of biological and artificial life and intelligence examples of already existing superhuman performance of &amp;quot;narrow“ AI are presented. The history of artificial neural networks nicely shows how wrong human experts can be. Conditions for and principles of predictive and prescriptive analytics, two important working horses of AI, are presented. It is explained why superhuman performance is especially possible in mass decisions under uncertainty. Their value is proven with examples from largely improved and automated public scientific research as well as decision making in enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A personal view about the role of python and some selected topics that will gain much more attention like causality extraction from historic data and discrimination-free algorithms are given, before concluding on how we should face the challenges but especially the chances of AI to create a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof. Dr. Michael Feindt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/ai-differentiating-hype-and-real-value.html</guid><category>Keynote</category></item></channel></rss>