<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jack-bennett.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-28T13:45:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>I Lost 25 Pounds Thanks to Python: Personal Data Analytics Using Pandas and Numpy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/i-lost-25-pounds-thanks-to-python-personal-data-analytics-using-pandas-and-numpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-28T13:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T13:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jack Bennett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/i-lost-25-pounds-thanks-to-python-personal-data-analytics-using-pandas-and-numpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python provides a great set of built-in tools and third-party libraries
for data analysis. Modern personal devices like smart watches or phones
generate streams of data about body metrics, location, movement, and
more. I describe Python-based methods for extracting and analyzing data
from personal smart devices. I applied these methods to track and change
habits and behaviors to lose 25 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your smartwatch and smartphone provide reams of data about your body,
movement, behavior, health, and more. Python is an ideal language to use
for analyzing, transforming, and displaying this data. Furthermore,
numerous third-party packages such as NumPy, SciPy, pandas, and
matplotlib make this process easier, faster, more fun, and more
insightful than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, you can use these tools to get tangible results in your
life: for example, during the first few months of 2019, I used a set of
Python scripts operating on a combination of personal data sources to
modify my habits and behaviors to lose 25 pounds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we analyze several streams of data from Apple Watch and
iPhone to explore what we can learn from them, individually and in
combination. Data categories that we explore include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heart rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body weight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use simple but powerful techniques from signal processing, including
moving averages and filtering, to extract insight from the data.
Additionally, we investigate correlations between the different data
streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting this methodology in place is fun, informative, and personally
rewarding. In particular, you can use it for habit tracking, to increase
self- knowledge and motivate useful habit change.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>