<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Dr. Kari L. Jordan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inclusive pedagogy to support computational teaching</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/inclusive-pedagogy-to-support-computational-teaching.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How we teach, rather than what we teach, often has the most impact on
who participates and on learning outcomes. This presentation covers
trends in computational teaching, and focuses on how these trends relate
to diversity, inclusion, equity, and access to computational training.
Through the lens of The Carpentries, an organization dedicated to
teaching foundational coding and data science skills worldwide, we
present best practices and opportunities for improvement in
computational teaching pedagogy. Evidence-based teaching practices,
“train-the-trainer” programs, and mentoring are three strategies we
outline that support inclusive pedagogy in computational teaching. We
describe and discuss effective teaching practices that promote inclusive
pedagogy in computational teaching, including formative assessment,
collaborative note taking, a strong commitment to a Code of Conduct, and
creating a welcoming environment for learners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tracy Teal</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-02:/pycon-us-2019/inclusive-pedagogy-to-support-computational-teaching.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2019</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Keynote Speaker - Dr. Kari L. Jordan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/keynote-speaker-dr-kari-l-jordan.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Kari L. Jordan, is a leading figure in data science education, serving as the Executive Director for The Carpentries, a globally recognized nonprofit organization. Upon completing Bachelor's and Master’s degrees in Mechanical Engineering from Michigan Technological University, she pursued a Ph.D. in Engineering Education at The Ohio State University, specializing in interventions to enhance belonging for people of color in STEM. Dr. Jordan's visionary leadership has propelled The Carpentries' mission worldwide, fostering exponential growth and impact across academia, industry, and government sectors. A sought-after speaker and advocate for diversity and inclusion, she champions accessible data literacy and bridges the digital skills gap through strategic initiatives and international collaboration. Dr. Jordan's dedication to empowering individuals and fostering inclusive learning environments has earned her widespread recognition and respect, shaping the future of data literacy for societal betterment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Kari L. Jordan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-18:/pycon-us-2025/keynote-speaker-dr-kari-l-jordan.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item></channel></rss>