<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Jang Hye-sik</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Our Python's childhood</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/our-pythons-childhood.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the role of English in programming languages? Python! — It has become a given since some time ago.
However, even though Perl is known, Python has been in obscurity for over 10 years, and has been overtaken by the rising Ruby, becoming like an old language, and eventually becoming a universal language..! What happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 2 code that seems to come from the primitive era, where () is not used after print.. Did Python 2 have a refreshing childhood? As the 20th century passed, when people called it Python, Python, Python, and Pythong (!) in Korean at almost the same rate, how was it possible for the notation “Python,” which is also against the Korean notation rules for foreign words, to be adopted as the standard notation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this segment, we will talk about the development process of Python 2, the period of rapid growth of Python, and the story of how the Python community established itself in Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jang Hye-sik
I have been a Python committer for several years since 2001, 22 years ago. I like creating groups, so I have been running a domestic Python user group for several years. Currently, I am working as an assistant professor at the Department of Life Sciences at Seoul National University, and my main work is to explore the mysteries of life by analyzing information inside cells with Python. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://qbio.io/"&gt;https://qbio.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jang Hye-sik</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/our-pythons-childhood.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>