<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sev Leonard</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sev-leonard.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Can you please pass the data? IoT communication with MicroPython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2018/can-you-please-pass-the-data-iot-communication-with-micropython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sev Leonard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-01-23:/pycascades-2018/can-you-please-pass-the-data-iot-communication-with-micropython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come learn a bit about Micropython, a specialized version of Python for micro controllers, and how you can use it to pass messages among IoT devices. Using the concepts and code presented this talk will include a live demo of a connected temperature sensor (somewhat like the NEST). Beginner …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come learn a bit about Micropython, a specialized version of Python for micro controllers, and how you can use it to pass messages among IoT devices. Using the concepts and code presented this talk will include a live demo of a connected temperature sensor (somewhat like the NEST). Beginner friendly!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2018"></category><category term="iot"></category><category term="micropython"></category></entry><entry><title>Only You Can Prevent Data Fires</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2025/only-you-can-prevent-data-fires.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sev Leonard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-02-08:/pycascades-2025/only-you-can-prevent-data-fires.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many Pythonistas find themselves engaged in the work of tending and defending data, ensuring high quality data is available for products and analytics users. Much like defending a home against wildfires, there are proactive steps you can take to shield your data from disaster. In this talk you’ll …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many Pythonistas find themselves engaged in the work of tending and defending data, ensuring high quality data is available for products and analytics users. Much like defending a home against wildfires, there are proactive steps you can take to shield your data from disaster. In this talk you’ll see a comprehensive approach to data quality, implementing checks at various parts of the data lifecycle. You'll also learn a bit about wildfire preparedness along the way. If you’ve experienced the chaotic nature of real-world data and are looking for a way to quench the flames this session is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - 2016-06-01</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-06-01.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hayley Denbraver</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-01:/pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-06-01.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon US 2016"></category><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>The Fellowship of the Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/sev-leonard-the-fellowship-of-the-data-pycon-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sev Leonard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-30:/pycon-us-2016/sev-leonard-the-fellowship-of-the-data-pycon-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sev Leonard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is an excellent tool for gathering, organizing, and storing data. This tutorial will cover efficient &amp;amp; scalable methods for performing these activities as part of an automated data pipeline, enabling attendees to build the One Data Pipeline To Rule Them All.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sev Leonard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is an excellent tool for gathering, organizing, and storing data. This tutorial will cover efficient &amp;amp; scalable methods for performing these activities as part of an automated data pipeline, enabling attendees to build the One Data Pipeline To Rule Them All.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2016"></category></entry><entry><title>IoT Lab with Micropython and Friends</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/iot-lab-with-micropython-and-friends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sev Leonard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-18:/pycon-us-2017/iot-lab-with-micropython-and-friends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come learn about the Internet of Things and Micropython in this hands-on
hardware tutorial, no soldering or hardware experience required! We will
be building a wifi-enabled temperature sensor as a vehicle for learning
IoT concepts including data capture, building security into data
transmission, and messaging between IoT clients and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come learn about the Internet of Things and Micropython in this hands-on
hardware tutorial, no soldering or hardware experience required! We will
be building a wifi-enabled temperature sensor as a vehicle for learning
IoT concepts including data capture, building security into data
transmission, and messaging between IoT clients and servers. Attendees
will have an opportunity to take their sensors out into the conference
venue to take measurements, reconvening to discuss analysis and
visualization of IoT data. All the hardware needed will be provided, and
attendees will be able to program the devices via a locally-hosted web
interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will be a great introduction for folks interested in
Internet of Things, Micropython, or hardware hacking. You do not need
prior experience in any of these topics to attend. We will be using the
ESP8266 micro controller and the MQTT protocol for messaging. Attendees
should download the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mosquitto.org/download/"&gt;mosquitto MQTT
broker&lt;/a&gt; in addition to collateral
that will be sent out to attendees ahead of the tutorial. We will be
using the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.micropython.org/en/latest/esp8266/esp8266/tutorial/repl.html"&gt;WebREPL
interface&lt;/a&gt;
for programming the ESP8266. If you are wondering what the heck all of
this means do not despair! These topics will be covered in the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2017"></category></entry><entry><title>Schemas: The Key To Data Happiness</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/schemas-the-key-to-data-happiness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sev Leonard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/schemas-the-key-to-data-happiness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shape shifting data got you down? If you’re a Pythonista who works with data you’ve probably had at least one headache due to unexpected changes in data. In this talk you’ll see how to create, maintain, and leverage schemas to generate test and training data, improve …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shape shifting data got you down? If you’re a Pythonista who works with data you’ve probably had at least one headache due to unexpected changes in data. In this talk you’ll see how to create, maintain, and leverage schemas to generate test and training data, improve data pipeline reliability, generate code, and some other neat tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Micropython for Mews</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/micropython-for-mews.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sev Leonard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:/pydx-2016/micropython-for-mews.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Sev Leonard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never miss a photo from your favorite internet cat again. Learn how to make a small wifi-connected badge using micropython and some snazzy electronics. No experience required! This talk will chronicle the experience of a first time micropythonista setting up the ESP8266 wifi …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Sev Leonard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never miss a photo from your favorite internet cat again. Learn how to make a small wifi-connected badge using micropython and some snazzy electronics. No experience required! This talk will chronicle the experience of a first time micropythonista setting up the ESP8266 wifi module with an LCD display using the Arduino IDE. Attendees will learn how to get setup to program microcontrollers with micropython, how to connect to wifi to get the latest cat pics, and how to display kittens on an LCD.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyDX 2016"></category><category term="micropython"></category><category term="ESP8266"></category></entry></feed>