<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Abhinand C</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_abhinand-c.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Time Made Easy: Simplify Date and Time Handling with Python's Pendulum</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abhinand C</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2B on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pendulum is a Python package for working with dates, times, and timezones. It offers a simple and intuitive API for common date/time operations and provides advanced functionality for dealing with more complex scenarios. Some of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Terrace 2B on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/time-made-easy-simplify-date-and-time-handling-with-pythons-pendulum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pendulum is a Python package for working with dates, times, and timezones. It offers a simple and intuitive API for common date/time operations and provides advanced functionality for dealing with more complex scenarios. Some of the interesting points of Pendulum include support for leap years, time zones, and daylight saving time, as well as a fluent API for creating and modifying dates and times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Pendulum is its support for time zones. The library comes with a comprehensive list of time zones, and it can automatically adjust dates and times to the local time zone of a given location. Additionally, Pendulum can handle time zone conversions with ease, making it easy to work with date/time data across different time zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pendulum also provides a powerful API for creating and modifying dates and times. With its fluent interface, developers can create and manipulate dates and times using a natural, human-readable syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Event-Driven Python service using FastStream and AsyncAPI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/building-event-driven-python-service-using-faststream-and-asyncapi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abhinand C</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/building-event-driven-python-service-using-faststream-and-asyncapi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building Event-Driven Python service using FastStream and AsyncAPI by Abhinand C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/building-event-driven-python-service-using-faststream-and-asyncapi"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/building-event-driven-python-service-using-faststream-and-asyncapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we dive into the world of Event Driven Architecture and Message Streaming, using Python and FastStream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll learn to integrate FastStream, a python …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building Event-Driven Python service using FastStream and AsyncAPI by Abhinand C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/building-event-driven-python-service-using-faststream-and-asyncapi"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/building-event-driven-python-service-using-faststream-and-asyncapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we dive into the world of Event Driven Architecture and Message Streaming, using Python and FastStream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll learn to integrate FastStream, a python framework, into your projects and leverage AsyncAPI to define contracts for asynchronous communication and event streaming. Through practical examples and insights, you'll discover the art of building scalable, responsive Python applications that thrive in real-time environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#### About AsyncAPI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AsyncAPI is an open standard/specification and growing set of open-source tools to help developers define, build, and maintain asynchronous APIs and Event-Driven Architectures. It describes message-driven APIs in a machine-readable format, and is protocol-agnostic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#### About FastStream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FastStream is a powerful and easy-to-use Python framework for building asynchronous services interacting with event streams such as Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS and Redis. FastStream simplifies the process of writing producers and consumers for message queues, handling all the parsing, networking and documentation generation automatically. FastStream provides unified API across multiple brokers, built-in Pydantic validations, automatic AsyncAPI documentation, FastAPI like Dependency Injection System, built-in support for test and extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry></feed>