<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building a RESTful real-time analytics system with Pyramid</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/building-a-restful-real-time-analytics-system-with-pyramid.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrii Chaichenko - Building a RESTful real-time analytics system with Pyramid
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CeleraOne tries to bring its vision to Big Data by developing a unique
platform for real-time Big Data processing. The platform is capable of
personalizing multi-channel user flows, right-in time targeting and
analytics while seamlessly scaling to billions of page impression. It
is currently tailored to the needs of content providers, but of course
not limited to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The platform’s architecture is based on four main layers:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proxy/Distribution -- OpenResty/LUA for dynamic request forwarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RESTful API -- several Python applications written using Pyramid web framework running under uWSGI server, which serve as an integration point for third party systems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics -- Python API for Big Data querying and distributed workers performing heavy data collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-memory Engine -- CeleraOne’s NoSql database which provides both data storage and fast business logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk I would like to give insights on how we use Python in the
architecture, which tools and technologies were chosen, and share
experiences deploying and running the system in production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrii Chaichenko</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-08:europython-2015/building-a-restful-real-time-analytics-system-with-pyramid.html</guid></item></channel></rss>