<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Sound of Silence: Online Misogyny and How we Model It</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2019/the-sound-of-silence-online-misogyny-and-how-we-model-it.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Teresa Ingram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyData
Female-identifying people are being attacked and silenced online. Social media platforms act as neutral bodies and law enforcement can’t stop the abuse. When you can’t trust that your safety will be protected online, what can you do? We say, Opt Out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/JUQMXE"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/JUQMXE&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Teresa Ingram</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-11:pydata-berlin-2019/the-sound-of-silence-online-misogyny-and-how-we-model-it.html</guid></item><item><title>Opt Out of Online Sexism – Open Source Activism</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/opt-out-of-online-sexism-open-source-activism.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Although people of all genders can experience violence and abuse
online, the abuse experienced by women is often sexist or misogynistic
in nature, and online threats of violence against women are often
sexualized and include specific references to women’s bodies. &amp;quot; -
Amnesty International. This abuse pushes women offline, affecting their
social well-being, representation and economic potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss how we plan to help resolve this with our
browser extension, Opt Out. I will discuss the online global tragedy
that is online sexual harassment, our idea and where we’re at with
current implementation. I will also talk about what it’s like to build
an open source activism project, one which aims to be lead by the
community it’s trying to protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover current research and results from our own engagement with
the community, where the idea came from and challenges we have faced and
plan to face in the future. I will also dive into the intricate world of
natural language processing (NLP) for online harassment and talk about
balancing state-of-the-art data science with web development in an open
source community, one being managed by someone relatively new to tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Teresa Ingram</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/opt-out-of-online-sexism-open-source-activism.html</guid><category>Communication</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Open-Source</category><category>TDD</category><category>Web</category></item></channel></rss>