<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alejandro-saucedo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>A practical guide towards algorithmic bias and explainability in machine learning.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-algorithmic-bias-and-explainability-in-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:pydata-london-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-algorithmic-bias-and-explainability-in-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Undesired bias in machine learning has become a worrying topic due to the numerous high profile incidents. In this talk we demystify machine learning bias through a hands-on example. We'll be tasked to automate the loan approval process for a company, and introduce key tools and techniques from latest research that allow us to assess and mitigate undesired bias in our machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The state of Machine Learning Operations in 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-state-of-machine-learning-operations-in-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/the-state-of-machine-learning-operations-in-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of the key challenges and trends in
the productization of machine learning systems, including concepts such
as reproducibility, explainability and orchestration. The talk will also
provide a high level overview of several key open source tools and
frameworks available to tackle these issues, which have been identifyed
putting together the Awesome Machine Learning Operations list
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/EthicalML/awesome-machine-learning-operations"&gt;https://github.com/EthicalML/awesome-machine-learning-operations&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The key concepts that will be covered are:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Reproducibility&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Explainability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Orchestration of models&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reproducibility piece will cover key motivations as well as
practical requirements for model versioning, together with tools that
allow data scientists to achieve version control of model+config+data to
ensure full model lineage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explainability piece will contain a high level overview of why this
has become an important topic in machine learning, including the high
profile incidents that tech companies have experienced where undesired
biases have slipped into data. This will also include a high level
overview of some of the tools available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the orchestration piece will cover some of the fundamental
challenges with large scale serving of models, together with some of the
key tools that are available to ensure this challenge can be tackled.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Deep Learning"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>A practical guide towards explainability and bias evaluation in ML</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-belarus-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-explainability-and-bias-evaluation-in-ml.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-16:pycon-belarus-2019/a-practical-guide-towards-explainability-and-bias-evaluation-in-ml.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning Pipelines with Python &amp; Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-23:pycon-hk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning and data pipelines in Python. I will
cover practical presentation that will build from the basics of Airflow,
and show how it is possible to build scalable and distributed machine
learning data pipelines using a distributed architecture with a
producer- consumer backend using Celery. I will provide insights on some
of the key learnings I have obtained throughout my career building
machine learning systems, as well as caveats and best practices
deploying scalable data pipelines systems in production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning: Building scalable distributed machine learning pipelines with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-building-scalable-distributed-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/industrial-machine-learning-building-scalable-distributed-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk would provide useful and practical understanding on how to
build industry-ready machine learning models in python through
distributed, horizontally-scalable architectures. I will include why and
when these architectures are required, best practices, caveats,
technologies to use them, and a practical implementation using celery +
rabbitmq.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="celery"></category><category term="rabbitmq"></category></entry><entry><title>Industrial Machine Learning Pipelines with Python &amp; Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/industrial-machine-learning-pipelines-with-python-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide key insights on the learnings I have obtained
throughout my career building &amp;amp; deploying machine learning systems in
critical environments across several sectors. I will provide a deep dive
on how to build scalable and distributed machine learning data pipelines
using Airflow with a Celery backend. I will also compare Airflow with
other technologies available out there and how it differentiates, such
as Luigi, Chronos, Pinball, etc. If you attend the talk, you will obtain
an understanding on the solid fundamentals of Airflow, together with its
caveats and walk-arounds for more complex use-cases. As we proceed with
the examples, I will cover the challenges that you will run into when
scaling Machine Learning systems, and how Airflow can be used to address
these using a manager-worker-queue architecture for distributed
processing with Celery. By the end of this talk you will have the
knowledge required to build your own industry-ready machine learning
pipelines to process data at scale, and I will provide further reading
resources so people are able to implement the knowledge obtained almost
right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Industrial Data Pipelines with Python and Airflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2018/industrial-data-pipelines-with-python-and-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-22:pycon-russia-2018/industrial-data-pipelines-with-python-and-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alejandro Saucedo&lt;/strong&gt; , Eigen Technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.ru/2018/en/program/content/Alejandro/"&gt;**Industrial Data Pipelines with Python and
Airflow**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a practical deep dive on how to build
industry-ready machine learning / data pipelines using Airflow. This
will consist of a practical presentation that will build from the basics
of Airflow, and show how it is possible to build scalable and
distributed machine learning data pipelines using a distributed
architecture with a Celery backend. I will provide insights on some of
the key learnings I've obtained throughout my career building &amp;amp;
deploying machine learning systems in critical environments across
several sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Industrial ML - Overview of the technologies available to build scalable machine learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2018/industrial-ml-overview-of-the-technologies-available-to-build-scalable-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-08:pydata-berlin-2018/industrial-ml-overview-of-the-technologies-available-to-build-scalable-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide useful and practical understanding on how to
build industry-ready machine learning pipelines in python through
distributed, horizontally-scalable architectures. This talk will also go
into detail on the motivations for such architectures, the technologies
required, best practices, caveats and practical use-cases in industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>