<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_robert-layton.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Learning TensorFlow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/learning-tensorflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Layton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/learning-tensorflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robert Layton
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/126/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/126/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
The recently released TensorFlow library has caused great waves in machine learning circles, with its powerful syntax that allows for distributed computation, improved efficiency, and modularisation. The framework allows you to build graph-based models, such as those used in machine learning and artificial intelligence, and have those models run on a distributed computing systems, including GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover what TensorFlow is, why/when you should use it, and cover the basics surrounding Variables, Placeholders, and Custom Functions. Importantly, there are several use cases &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; focused on data analytics - TensorFlow is more than just a machine learning library!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="datascience"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry><entry><title>scikit-learn, machine learning and cybercrime attribution</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2013/scikit-learn-machine-learning-and-cybercrime-att.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Layton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-06:pycon-au-2013/scikit-learn-machine-learning-and-cybercrime-att.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scikit-learn library is a rapidly growing open source toolkit for
machine learning in python. It allows for practitioners and researchers
to apply machine learning in a variety of applications and is used by
companies worldwide. Developed by programmers from around the world, the
project has a large (and increasing) number of machine learning
algorithms, a very useful set of utility functions and has also spawned
a set of detailed tutorials. Written in python with the aid of numpy,
scipy and cython, this library is featured, fast and extensible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce scikit-learn, giving an overview of the
library, its features and how to use it for a number of different
applications. Next talk about some of the tutorials that are actively
being developed for learning machine learning and scikit-learn and also
how to contribute. Through this, I'll introduce some key machine
learning concepts and how you can apply them to a variety of tasks. The
focus will be on practical uses, rather than theoretical advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To end the presentation, I'll briefly overview the research I perform at
the Internet Commerce Security Laboratory (University of Ballarat) in
cybercrime attribution, where I work with our industry partners to
disrupt cybercrime. While it can be very difficult to do direct network
based attribution, indirect methods through criminal profiling may
assist in stopping crimes such as phishing or online fraud. I'll walk
through some of our results in identifying the size and scope of the
operations behind some of these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Predicting sports winners using data analytics with pandas and scikit-learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/predicting-sports-winners-using-data-analytics-wi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Layton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/predicting-sports-winners-using-data-analytics-wi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pandas and scikit-learn packages combine together to produce a
powerful toolkit for data analytics. In this talk, we will be using them
together to analyse the outcome of NBA games, trying to predict the
winner of a match. There is plenty of data out there to allow us to
create good predictions – the key is getting it in the right format and
building the right model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will go through importing data from the net, cleaning it
up, creating new features, and building a predictive model. We then
evaluate how well we did, using recent NBA data. The model we use will
be a decision tree ensemble called a random forest.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>