<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Erin 'August' Allard</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_erin-august-allard.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Make Your Engineering Team A Fabulous Place for Programmers with ADHD and Autism</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2023/make-your-engineering-team-a-fabulous-place-for-programmers-with-adhd-and-autism.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erin 'August' Allard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-30:/north-bay-python-2023/make-your-engineering-team-a-fabulous-place-for-programmers-with-adhd-and-autism.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In StackOverflow's 2022 annual survey of 16,000 developers worldwide, 10.6% of respondents reported being affected by concentration or memory challenges, such as having Attention Deficit Hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), and 4.3% of respondents self-identified as having an Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD). These results indicate that on a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In StackOverflow's 2022 annual survey of 16,000 developers worldwide, 10.6% of respondents reported being affected by concentration or memory challenges, such as having Attention Deficit Hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), and 4.3% of respondents self-identified as having an Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD). These results indicate that on a team of 20 engineers, up to 3 people on the team may have what are called &amp;quot;neurodivergent&amp;quot; brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the symptoms of ADHD and ASD? What are the so-called neurodivergent &amp;quot;superpowers&amp;quot; you may have seen on social media? How can we create work environments that foster ease and success for neurodivergent software engineers? Join this session to find out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="North Bay Python 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>13 fun facts about Python's return statement for savvy programmers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2024/13-fun-facts-about-pythons-return-statement-for-savvy-programmers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erin 'August' Allard</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-21:/pybay-2024/13-fun-facts-about-pythons-return-statement-for-savvy-programmers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python’s return statement is one of the first keywords introduced to new learners of the language. We’re taught that it “tells Python the function is done” and often not much else about it! What happens if you forget to include a return at the end of a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python’s return statement is one of the first keywords introduced to new learners of the language. We’re taught that it “tells Python the function is done” and often not much else about it! What happens if you forget to include a return at the end of a function? What if you try to use one outside of a function? Can a function return another function? Come learn about all of the cool things you can achieve in your programs through a better understanding of return statements!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2024"></category></entry></feed>