<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ayush-singh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Deep Learning the Bayesian way : Moving towards safer AI !</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2018/deep-learning-the-bayesian-way-moving-towards-safer-ai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ayush Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-fr-2018/deep-learning-the-bayesian-way-moving-towards-safer-ai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the advancements in the domain of Deep learning, it has found
application in various real-life problems such as self-driving cars and
healthcare diagnosis. But with great powers comes greater
responsibility, so the question arises, “Is our AI safe ?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The critical part of any machine learning system is understanding what
it does not know. Unfortunately, today’s deep learning algorithms are
usually unable to understand their uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an introduction to the resurging filed of
Bayesian Deep Learning. I would be discussing various theoretical
aspects and the current state-of-the-art in this domain. I would be
taking you through the code for constructing Bayesian deep nets and
visualizing their uncertainty in their results using libraries like
PyMC3, Pytorch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prerequisites for this talk familiarity with basic probability,
Intermediary python, and passion to learn something new :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to approach a ML Problem with Python ?: YouTube Like Count Prediction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-hk-2017/how-to-approach-a-ml-problem-with-python-youtube-like-count-prediction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ayush Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-hk-2017/how-to-approach-a-ml-problem-with-python-youtube-like-count-prediction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever thought of &amp;quot;How to approach a Machine Learning Problem ?&amp;quot;. This talk will guide you through pipeline for approaching a Machine Learning problem (Supervised) by taking up a real world problem which will make it easy for the audience to relate with. The task would be “Predicting like counts for a given YouTube video” and I would be taking you through the very first step of Data Collection to Model Evaluation, discussing various essential steps like Data analysis, Feature engineering, feature selection and many more along the way. Every step would be accompanied by some code snippets in Python using various scientific and ML libraries like Sklearn, Numpy etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>