<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lalleh Rafeei</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lalleh-rafeei.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Instrumentation Nightmares: A review of some of our toughest cases</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/instrumentation-nightmares-a-review-of-some-of-our-toughest-cases.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hannah Stepanek</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/instrumentation-nightmares-a-review-of-some-of-our-toughest-cases.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how companies like New Relic, Data Dog, and Sentry
instrument your code? In this talk we will briefly review how to hook
into the Python import system in order to instrument code. We'll present
some useful design patterns and tricks of the trade. Then, we'll launch
straight …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how companies like New Relic, Data Dog, and Sentry
instrument your code? In this talk we will briefly review how to hook
into the Python import system in order to instrument code. We'll present
some useful design patterns and tricks of the trade. Then, we'll launch
straight into real world examples and challenging instrumentation we've
done over the years. Take a deep dive with us into some of the most
popular Python libraries in use today and learn how they work
underneath. We'll talk about proxies, wrapt, async, Python's web server
specifications, and more! You will walk away from this talk with an
understanding of how instrumentation works under the hood and how to
make your own code instrumentation friendly. You'll also learn about
various design patterns; some that are gotos for instrumentation and
some that make instrumentation nightmarishly difficult. We hope you will
join us on this instrumentation journey and come away with an
understanding of how it all works to make developer's lives easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry></feed>