<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Min Jean Cho</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_min-jean-cho.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Intel GPU in Upstream PyTorch: Expanding GPU Choices and Enhancing Backend Flexibility</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/intel-gpu-in-upstream-pytorch-expanding-gpu-choices-and-enhancing-backend-flexibility.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eikan Wang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/intel-gpu-in-upstream-pytorch-expanding-gpu-choices-and-enhancing-backend-flexibility.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel GPU in Upstream PyTorch: Expanding GPU Choices and Enhancing Backend Flexibility - Eikan Wang &amp;amp; Min Jean Cho, Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration of Intel GPU support into PyTorch marks a pivotal enhancement for PyTorch device and runtime. We generalized the PyTorch device and runtime to accommodate streaming devices. The generalization not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel GPU in Upstream PyTorch: Expanding GPU Choices and Enhancing Backend Flexibility - Eikan Wang &amp;amp; Min Jean Cho, Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration of Intel GPU support into PyTorch marks a pivotal enhancement for PyTorch device and runtime. We generalized the PyTorch device and runtime to accommodate streaming devices. The generalization not only facilitates the deployment of PyTorch on ubiquitous hardware but also makes the integration of different HW backends easier. In addition, PyTorch with Intel GPU supports various Intel GPUs from the data center to the client. It enriches and democratizes PyTorch HW ecosystem. Particularly in AIPC scenarios where Intel's integrated and discrete GPUs are prevalent, Pytorch with Intel GPU can deliver promising performance and improved OOB experience in the AIPC domain that can extend PyTorch's applicability significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>