<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alexander-shvets.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PyWat. Do you know Python well enough?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2017/pywat-do-you-know-python-well-enough.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Shvets</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-16:pycon-russia-2017/pywat-do-you-know-python-well-enough.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python developers don’t trust to other programming languages because Python is undoubtedly the coolest language in the world! It is great pleasure to make fun of JavaScript or Ruby for their non-obviousness and magic. But is Python behavior always so obvious? Will it let you down at the crucial moment? Let's see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In interactive mode, we'll play with you in the PyWat quiz and, of course, deep dive into Python for the correct answers. Disclaimer: The sarcasm in this talk does not represent anyone's actual opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Секреты здорового питания: полезные рецепты с Celery</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2015/sekrety-zdorovogo-pitaniia-poleznye-retsepty-s-celery.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Shvets</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-19:pycon-russia-2015/sekrety-zdorovogo-pitaniia-poleznye-retsepty-s-celery.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Секретный состав сельдерея или неформальное введение в архитектуру Celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Подбираем ингредиенты на пробу. Как правильно логировать и отлаживать очередей&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Заботимся о долгом послевкусии. Как обеспечить стабильную работу очередей без простоя и потери задач&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Готовимся к кулинарному состязанию. Как избежать гонок при выполнении задач&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Несколько профессиональных рецептов шеф-повара по настройке Celery для больших проектов&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>