<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mike McCaffrey</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lights! Python! Action!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/lights-python-action.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intended to be an entertaining overview of challenges faced and lessons
learned working on my first big maker project. Using code snippets,
pictures and short demos, I will discuss problems overcome while
developing new features and integrating new devices into my humble
animated sign, which includes lights along with rhythmic and melodic
components. I promise not to dance; no one wants to see that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intended audience is anyone interested in maker projects. I will
also be touching on introductory-level topics in type hinting; the
standard library modules abc, dataclasses, signal, and threading; and
the 3rd-party modules aiohttp, gpiozero, and requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;Note on Photosensitivity:&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Based on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.epilepsy.com/stories/shedding-light-photosensitivity-one-epilepsys-most-complex-conditions"&gt;this epilepsy.com
article&lt;/a&gt;,
this presentation should be safe for any photosensitive audience
member. I will include this information in a slide at the beginning of
the presentation, and give anyone in the audience the chance to leave
or ask questions before proceeding.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sign project uses standard 60 watt incandescent bulbs, which are
not capable of producing a strobe effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For further safety, during the presentation, bulbs will not cycle on
and off more than 3 times per second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, the room’s lighting will not be darkened more than
usual for a standard presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mike McCaffrey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-26:/pyohio-2025/lights-python-action.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2025</category></item></channel></rss>