<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Demetri Pananos</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_demetri-pananos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Making sense of marginal effects</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/making-sense-of-marginal-effects.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Demetri Pananos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/making-sense-of-marginal-effects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The marginaleffects package for R and Python offers a single point of entry to easily interpret over 100 types of models using a simple and consistent interface. Marginaleffects has become an indispensable tool for moving away from tables of regression coefficients and towards easily interpretable estimates. In addition to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The marginaleffects package for R and Python offers a single point of entry to easily interpret over 100 types of models using a simple and consistent interface. Marginaleffects has become an indispensable tool for moving away from tables of regression coefficients and towards easily interpretable estimates. In addition to making regression models more interpretable, marginaleffects offers flexible plotting tools, efficient implementations, validated results against Stata, and a thoroughly documented website abundant with examples and vignettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for data scientists and data analysts who analyze data with regression models. We’ll cover how to estimate and visualize a variety of effect summaries with marginaleffects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>