<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyConAU 2010: Genropy - a framework for creating complex applications deployed on the web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--genropy---a-framework-for-creating-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy - A framework for creating complex applications deployed on the
web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jeff B Edwards (Goodsoftware)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.genropy.org/"&gt;Genropy&lt;/a&gt; is the python implementation of
Genro, and is an application framework quite different from the standard
(django, cherrypy, turbogears), for building powerful database
applications deployed from the browser. Many differences and advantages
between this framework and traditional python application frameworks are
explained. Genropy is a suitable for creating complex 'applications' as
opposed to 'sites'. The differentiation is that an application is
something an operator uses all day, has trained users, that have to
'squeeze' all the power from it available. Conversely, a 'site' is
basically public and not necessarily powerful as a user spends a
relatively small amount of time on it. Genropy is the framework for
creation applications. It is used for attendee registration and sales in
pycon italy, the larger national conference in Europe (Florence, Italy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will demonstrate how to create a simple application (3
tables) and demonstrate the ease and power of using python for the model
view and controller on the client. It demonstrates how one api- being
the genro Bag - is used to create the model, to map the sql to objects,
to create the GUI and communicate all data. So all of it can be done in
python instead of having to use many different technologies and
languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Edwards from Goodsoftware is strategic partner of Sofwell who is
the author of Genropy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeff B Edwards</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--genropy---a-framework-for-creating-.html</guid><category>databases</category><category>gui</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau2010</category><category>web</category></item></channel></rss>