<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ben-keating.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Small Shop / Big Solutions: Django and Long-Term Thinking</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/small-shop-big-solutions-django-and-long-term.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Keating</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-03:djangocon-us-2013/small-shop-big-solutions-django-and-long-term.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SMALL SHOP / BIG SOLUTIONS: DJANGO AND LONG-TERM THINKING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday 4 p.m.--4:45 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Novice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DESCRIPTION In a small non-profit with a 10,000 year business plan, how
does todays technology play a role? how does it hold up against entropy
and evolve over long-periods of time? Django has done very well for us
and I'd like to share some of my stories and lessons. A small shop can
build big solutions that last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT This talk will focus on how Django has helped a small
non-profit keep up with the big guys and 3rd party solutions over the
long-term. I'll share with you how I stumbled upon it, dove in and
pitched it to the rest of the company. How we (and you, through IRC
#django!) took our three major sites, all running on different
technoloiges, and migrated them to Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much else out there that we use, of course and I learned
some valuable lessons from Django on how to pick out the great ones.
We'll get to discuss and share workflow productivity tips. Being a
non-profit that takes no sides, I have the special oppourtunity to share
inside stories and lessons that may be of use to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In smaller shops, full-stack positions are common and thats what I am. I
think a lot of us are. It's hard to do so but with the help of tools
such as Django we're able to pick up incredible pace and build awesome
things together.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>