<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Justine Wezenaar</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_justine-wezenaar.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How we used vectorization for 1000x Python speedups (no C or Spark needed!)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/how-we-used-vectorization-for-1000x-python-speedups-no-c-or-spark-needed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Hollenbeck</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/how-we-used-vectorization-for-1000x-python-speedups-no-c-or-spark-needed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we used vectorization for 1000x Python speedups (no C or Spark needed!) by Jonathan Hollenbeck, Justine Wezenaar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-we-used-vectorization-for-1000x-python-speedups-no-c-or-spark-needed"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-we-used-vectorization-for-1000x-python-speedups-no-c-or-spark-needed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to make all your code faster? With matrices, library knowledge, and a sprinkle of creativity, you can consistently …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we used vectorization for 1000x Python speedups (no C or Spark needed!) by Jonathan Hollenbeck, Justine Wezenaar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-we-used-vectorization-for-1000x-python-speedups-no-c-or-spark-needed"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-we-used-vectorization-for-1000x-python-speedups-no-c-or-spark-needed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to make all your code faster? With matrices, library knowledge, and a sprinkle of creativity, you can consistently speed up multivariate Python functions by 1000x!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modal optimization requires simple axioms - arithmetic, checking a case, calling the right sklearn function, and so on. When that’s not sufficient, three core tricks - converting conditional logic to set theory, stacking vectors into a matrix, and shaping data to match library expectations - cover the vast majority of real world cases (90% of the ~400 functions we vectorized).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Bloomberg, ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) Scores require complex computations on large data sets. Time-series computations are fundamental for Governance - one UDF infers board support for a policy from prior cyclical votes and other time offset inputs. By rewriting the pandas backfill as a series of reductions on a 4-tensor, we reduced the runtime from 45 minutes to 10 milliseconds! Analogously, due to real world complexity, finance UDFs can end up with 100+ if/else branches in one function. With a mix of De Morgan’s laws and sparse matrix representations, we simplified the cases and achieved 1000x+ speedups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll conclude with a quick overview of cutting-edge tools, and hope you’ll leave with a concrete strategy for vectorizing financial models!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry></feed>