<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Andres Pineda</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning Talks (PyCascades 2023)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/lightning-talks-pycascades-2023.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jim De la Hunt
Lightning Talk: Global domain names and email addresses, or, email me at जिम&amp;#64;डाटामेल.भारत . Alerting people that non-ASCII domain names are in use and spreading. Our code should be able to handle them. Python tools and online resources to get domain names and email right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Wes Lord
Lightning Talk: The surprising alternative to git rebase (it's git reset)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sam Edwardes
Lightning Talk: How to do &amp;quot;everything&amp;quot; with Pydantic. I want walk the audience through using Pydantic to do a few really cool things including: (1) parsing JSON into python objects, (2) validating data, (3) refactoring your code, (4) talking to a SQL database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tony Fast
Lightning Talk: Important digital accessibility language, standards, and tools for designing inclusive technology . Attendees will learn community and industry standards for auditing and understanding web content accessibility guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Mariatta Wijaya
Lightning Talk: PyCon US 2023: the 20 years celebration special. I will tell attendees about info about PyCon US 2023: registration, schedule, venue, etc. While this year's travel grant application has closed, it's still worth knowing that it exists and I will share how attendees can stay updated on PyCon US news so they can apply for next year's travel grants. I'll also share how attending PyCon has impacted my personal growth and career and opens up opportunities, and I would love for more people to have the same experience by attending PyCon US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Robin Reynolds-Haertle
Lightning Talk: Yellowstone Codera - Python programming puzzles with a Yellowstone theme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Santiago Soler
Lightning Talk: During this lightning talk I'll present Pooch, an open-source Python library for downloading and catching data files from the web. It provides easy ways to download data files from different protocols, cache it locally, check their integrity through checksums, and more. It also provides tools for downloading collections of files, useful for managing sample datasets for scientific and data-processing Python packages. Currently Pooch is being used by well-known libraries like SciPy, scikit-learn, Xarray and scikit-image, amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Andres Pineda
Lightning Talk: Invite to Pycon Latam&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jim De la Hunt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-19:/pycascades-2023/lightning-talks-pycascades-2023.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2023</category></item><item><title>Charlas Relámpago</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2022/charlas-relampago.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlos Maldonado</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-08-25:/pycon-latam-2022/charlas-relampago.html</guid><category>PyCon Latam 2022</category></item><item><title>Programacion Reactiva: Navegando en el mundo de la asincronia con RxPy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/programacion-reactiva-navegando-en-el-mundo-de-la-asincronia-con-rxpy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A medida que nuestras aplicaciones van creciendo y estas se van poniendo más complejas, el performance pudiera verse impactado por las diferentes tareas que se ejecutan, algunas inclusive llegando a bloquear el “thread” donde estas están corriendo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La programación reactiva (ReactiveX) nos ayuda con esto, permitiéndonos escribir de una forma fácil instrucciones que se ejecutarán de forma asíncrona gracias a los operadores que pueden ser usados para crear, filtrar y unificar los diferentes flujos de datos de nuestro sistema, todo esto, manteniendo nuestro código flexible, legible y fácil de mantener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esta presentación nos muestra que es la programación reactiva, en qué consiste y que nos permite hacer para nuestros programas Python puedan implementarla y así disfrutar de sus beneficios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andres Pineda</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/programacion-reactiva-navegando-en-el-mundo-de-la-asincronia-con-rxpy.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>charla</category></item><item><title>Iterando de forma eficiente en Python con Itertools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/iterando-de-forma-eficiente-en-python-con-itertools.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python viene con muchas herramientas poderosas “incluidas de fábrica”, y entre ellas se encuentran sus estructuras de bucle. Pero usarlas correctamente no siempre es tan sencillo como parece. En esta charla exploraremos el módulo itertools, una colección de funciones diseñadas para que escribas bucles más inteligentes, no más complejos. A través de ejemplos prácticos y casos del mundo real, veremos cómo aprovechar itertools para escribir código más eficiente y expresivo. Al finalizar, tendrás a tu disposición un conjunto de herramientas que te ayudarán a dominar tus bucles en Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andres Pineda</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-17:/pycon-us-2025/iterando-de-forma-eficiente-en-python-con-itertools.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2025</category></item></channel></rss>