<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Pareena Verma</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pareena-verma.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Empowering Developers: Tools and Resources for Running Generative AI on Arm CPUs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/empowering-developers-tools-and-resources-for-running-generative-ai-on-arm-cpus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pareena Verma</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/empowering-developers-tools-and-resources-for-running-generative-ai-on-arm-cpus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the demand for accessible and scalable AI solutions grows, leveraging CPUs for generative AI offers significant advantages in cost, energy efficiency and widespread availability. This sessions aims to equip developers with the ecosystem of tools, resources and technical content needed to effectively run generative AI use cases on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the demand for accessible and scalable AI solutions grows, leveraging CPUs for generative AI offers significant advantages in cost, energy efficiency and widespread availability. This sessions aims to equip developers with the ecosystem of tools, resources and technical content needed to effectively run generative AI use cases on Arm CPUs. We have launched a range of easily digestible tutorials for developers, part of our Learning Paths on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://learn.arm.com/"&gt;https://learn.arm.com/&lt;/a&gt;, which demonstrate how you can easily and efficiently run small and large language models on Arm-based devices. Learn about end-to-end workflows to accelerate PyTorch based sentiment analysis models from Hugging Face on Arm servers with optimizations in Arm Compute Library kernels for fp32 and bfloat16. Use the new KleidiAI library to accelerate LLMs with AI frameworks and build an Android chat app on your Arm mobile device with ExecuTorch, and XNNPACK. Find out about our roadmap for learning content demonstrating the feasibility and successful deployment of generative AI on Arm-based devices. Help us shape the support that we offer developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category><category term="Lightning Talk"></category></entry></feed>