<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SciPy 2013 Keynote: The New Scientific Publishers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/scipy-2013-keynote-the-new-scientific-publishers-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;...As software becomes increasingly important to the practice of
science, and data becomes larger and more complex, the conventional
scientific journal is no longer an adequate vehicle to communicate
scientific findings and ensure reproducibility. So who are the new
scientific publishers filling these needs, and what roles will they play
in the future of science?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presenter: William Schroeder, Kitware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: Keynotes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific societies such as the Royal Society were formed in the 17th
century with the goals of sharing information and ensuring
reproducibility. Very quickly scientific letters and publications were
assembled into collected transactions and eventually journals. For
hundreds of years publishers served admirably as disseminators of
scientific knowledge. Publications, and the associated peer review
process, became central to the scientific process, greatly impacting how
science is practiced, knowledge disseminated, and careers made. However,
as software becomes increasingly important to the practice of science,
and data becomes larger and more complex, the conventional scientific
journal is no longer an adequate vehicle to communicate scientific
findings and ensure reproducibility. So who are the new scientific
publishers filling these needs, and what roles will they play in the
future of science?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation we'll discuss the central mandate of
reproducibility, and the role of Open Science, in particular Open
Access, Open Source and Open Data, and how emerging communities and
organizations are filling the needs of the scientific community. We'll
also discuss the challenges of curating the avalanche of scientific
knowledge, whether it be software, data or publications, and how these
communities and organizations can work together to support science
progress, and ensure continued technological innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">William Schroeder</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-01:scipy-2013/scipy-2013-keynote-the-new-scientific-publishers-0.html</guid><category>open science</category><category>reproducibility</category></item></channel></rss>