<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Gabriella Lio</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_gabriella-lio.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Create a Custom Chat Bot With Python and Azure Bot Service</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2020/create-a-custom-chat-bot-with-python-and-azure-bot-service.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriella Lio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-25:/pyohio-2020/create-a-custom-chat-bot-with-python-and-azure-bot-service.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an abundance of chat bot options on the market, it can be hard to
evaluate which platform is the best fit. Finding an option which has
pre-built domains and services, but also allows for customization, will
help you decrease the level of effort and time to implement while …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an abundance of chat bot options on the market, it can be hard to
evaluate which platform is the best fit. Finding an option which has
pre-built domains and services, but also allows for customization, will
help you decrease the level of effort and time to implement while still
providing complete control over the resulting product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how Python NLP can be used in conjunction
with Azure Chat Bot services to quickly spin up a chat bot that can be
customized for your specific use case. Gaby Lio will review the
different options on the market, highlight the benefits of Azure Chat
Bot, and finish with an architectural overview and quick demo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Bridge the Trust Gap with Ethical AI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2020/bridge-the-trust-gap-with-ethical-ai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriella Lio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-25:/pytexas-2020/bridge-the-trust-gap-with-ethical-ai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you prioritize Ethical AI, it can be daunting to determine the correct path forward. This session will arm you with simple tools and technologies to build trust in your models and start implementing ethical AI within your organization today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Gabriella Lio
I am 25 years young and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you prioritize Ethical AI, it can be daunting to determine the correct path forward. This session will arm you with simple tools and technologies to build trust in your models and start implementing ethical AI within your organization today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Gabriella Lio
I am 25 years young and hail from the great state of Texas. After completing my Masters of Science in Business Analytics degree from UT Austin (Hook em' Horns forever), I joined the brilliant, creative, human, and fun Data Science team at Sense Corp, a tech consulting firm headquartered in Austin. When I'm not building models in Python and hanging out with my co-workers, you can find me exploring all the trails Austin has to offer, lounging on the lake, or catching my favorite band, the Spazmatics every Wednesday!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2020"></category></entry></feed>