<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Leila Verhaegen</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Day 2 Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/day-2-lightning-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon Europe Crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Körner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-24:/djangocon-europe-2018/day-2-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2018</category></item><item><title>Ceci n'est pas un job - Leila Verhaegen</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2020/ceci-nest-pas-un-job-leila-verhaegen.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon Europe 2020 (Virtual)
September 19, 2020 - 09h15 (GMT+1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ceci n'est pas un job&amp;quot; by Leila Verhaegen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than once I have had the pleasure of being informed that my job (which by the way, is also the job of quite a few members of the DjangoCon audience) is not a “real” job. In this talk I will try to discover what a “real job” is. I will also find out more about what is “real”, and what is a “job”. As a person who allegedly does not have a real job, and who comes from a country (Belgium) whose reality some people also doubt, I am ideally placed to make these discoveries. I will enlist the assistance of some famous Belgians, including the famous philosopher-actor Jean-Claude Van Damme (not a real actor, according to some; not a real philosopher, according to others) and the artist René Magritte. I plan to show that being a web developer is not really a job - it’s much more important than that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leila Verhaegen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-19:/djangocon-europe-2020/ceci-nest-pas-un-job-leila-verhaegen.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2020</category></item><item><title>We made a clock with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/we-made-a-clock-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session is about the story of two girls who decided to make a clock
themselves after searching a lot on the internet and without finding
what they were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will tell you what we used and how we used it, we will
also tell you how we made plans and then how we made circuits (timing,
requirements, how difficult and fun it was)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will finally tell you more about code and why exactly we wrote it
like that (Spoiler: there was a module with the RTC we used but the
memory of the trinket was to small to support the original code to do
what exactly we wanted to do)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leila Verhaegen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-17:/pycon-uk-2018/we-made-a-clock-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2018</category></item></channel></rss>