<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_russell-sherwood.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The ‘Agile Movement’</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/the-agile-movement.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Russell Sherwood</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/the-agile-movement.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="bdd"></category><category term="continuous-integration"></category><category term="project-management"></category><category term="agile"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="principles"></category><category term="tdd"></category><category term="pair-programming"></category><category term="XP"></category></entry><entry><title>Behaviour Driven Development at BSkyB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/behaviour-driven-development-at-bskyb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Sale</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-06:europython-2012/behaviour-driven-development-at-bskyb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] Russell Sherwood- David Sale - 5 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track
Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSkyB is a major player in the broadcasting and telecoms market in the
United Kingdom. Skyâ??s offering of premium sports, movies and
entertainment channels puts it at the forefront of Television
entertainment in more than 10 million homes. Its ample broadband and
telephone products have allowed the company to expand its customer base
and offer an all round package to its customers. With a focus on quality
and stability in everything Sky produces, testing of applications is
paramount. As part of this business, the company needs a successful and
efficient way to sell these products to its customers and as such the
modelling, rules and pricing of packages need to lay a firm foundation
for different parts of a sales application to function well. Testing
plays a key role to ensure that delivery of a product is always as
incident free as possible. Within the agile framework, unit tests,
behaviour driven development (BDD) and continuous integration play a key
role in making this possible. Ensuring we discover defects early enables
us to deliver software fortnightly. BDD tests allow the team to test the
application as the user will use it, highlighting any issues from front
end through to back end. More importantly with BDD tests written in
plain English and python code underneath it allows the Quality Assurance
personnel (QAâ??s), developers and business owners to work together in
constructing and writing tests. This brings together the entire team
rather than separating the separate stages of application development.
In this EuroPython presentation, we will cover the following aspects of
BDD: â?¢ The role of BDD in Agile Development â?? a brief introduction
to the usage of BDD on a daily basis and the process of QAâ??s and
developers working together to form quality tests. â?¢ Creating a
successful and useful BDD test â?? writing the feature file (plain
English definition of what the test will achieve), underlying step
definitions and how working collectively can maximize the coverage of
routes through the code. â?¢ BDD usage in continuous integration â?? the
movement of code through a continuous build process, catching defects
early and how BDD tests ensure confidence in your application as it
moves into production.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>