<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sam Bishop</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sam-bishop.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Snakes all the way down, building Worlds with Python code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/snakes-all-the-way-down-building-worlds-with-python-code.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sam Bishop</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/snakes-all-the-way-down-building-worlds-with-python-code.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Sam Bishop) This talk will introduce and demonstrate a selection of procedural content generation tools built with Python. From planets, to plants, to pantheons of Gods, there is Python code out there to help generate them for you. It doesn't matter why you want to generate content, Python is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Sam Bishop) This talk will introduce and demonstrate a selection of procedural content generation tools built with Python. From planets, to plants, to pantheons of Gods, there is Python code out there to help generate them for you. It doesn't matter why you want to generate content, Python is here to help you get more done in less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenters note: This video contains a mistake, when I was discussing “Seraphs: NanoGenMo” instead of using the correct author Liza Daly (&amp;#64;liza on Twitter) I attributed it to a nonexistent guy called Seraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Sep 11 14:45:00 2021 at Platypus Hall&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="SamBishop"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry></feed>