<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pankaj-gupta.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Improving Model Lifecycle Management for Machine Learning Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/improving-model-lifecycle-management-for-machine-learning-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pankaj Gupta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-04:pydata-delhi-2019/improving-model-lifecycle-management-for-machine-learning-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents a systematic approach to improve model lifecycle
management for machine learning models, using Python/DevOps tools and
processes to enable self-served model development and deployment; a
four-step workflow guides the developer/modeler to develop, automate,
test and implement the model in a virtual environment in a
production-ready manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical/machine-learning modeling is often subject to regulatory
mandates on model development, validation, deployment and monitoring.
These mandates are liable to require that production models are
fit-for-purpose, are accurately implemented and obey with local laws and
regulations. However in many environment complying with such mandates is
extremely onerous and time consuming, e.g. due to the use of legacy
technologies and workflows or unstructured model development by data
scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk presents a systematic approach to this challenge, using
Python/DevOps tools and processes to enable self-served model
development and deployment; a four-step workflow guides the modeler to
develop, automate, test and implement the model in a virtual environment
in a production-ready manner. The approach is in use by the Quantitative
Analytics team at Barclays bank, but we believe that the issues and
potential solutions are relevant to the other regulated industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>