<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Federico Scrinzi</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fuzzing Python code with Atheris</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/fuzzing-python-code-with-atheris.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuzzing Python code with Atheris - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuzz testing is a well-known technique for uncovering programming
errors. Atheris is an open-source fuzzing engine for finding bugs in
Python code and native extensions, released by the Google Information
Security team. With this talk we’ll learn how Atheris works and how it
can be used in practice. Fuzz testing is a well-known technique for
uncovering programming errors. Many of these detectable errors have
serious security implications. Atheris ( is an open-source fuzzing
engine for automatically finding bugs in Python code and native
extensions. Atheris is a “coverage-guided” fuzzer, which means that
Atheris will repeatedly try various inputs to your program while
watching how it executes, and try to find interesting execution paths.
In the past, Atheris was used to find bugs in Pillow’s native code
(CVE-2020-35653) or to find differences in JSON parsing between Python’s
standard library and Ultrajson, or between Python’s idna package and the
native libidn2 library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you can learn the basics of fuzzing, how Atheris works
internally, and how it can be used for bug hunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Federico Scrinzi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Federico Scrinzi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/fuzzing-python-code-with-atheris.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>code analysis</category><category>open source</category><category>security</category><category>testing</category></item></channel></rss>