<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Is your code tainted? Finding security vulnerabilities using taint-tracking.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/is-your-code-tainted-finding-security-vulnerabilities-using-taint-tracking.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Taint tracking” is a technique used in code analysis to find security
vulnerabilities and other problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any data that comes from an untrusted source, for example a HTTP
request, is treated as “tainted”. If that “tainted” data is able to
reach a vulnerable part of your code, then you have a problem.
Sophisticated code analysis tools can track this data, and reveal
potential security problems. Examples of the sort of problem that can be
found include cross-site scripting (XSS), code injection, SQL injection
and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will show how taint tracking analysis works in practice,
introducing the concepts of source, sink and sanitizer. I will then
demonstrate using taint tracking to find a XSS vulnerability in a django
app. (We will chose a project that is designed to teach django security,
where the vulnerability is deliberate.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also explain how thinking in terms of “taint” can help you write
safer code, even without access to code analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk I will use the code analysis tools on lgtm.com to
demonstrate the analysis. lgtm.com is free to use for open-source
projects. A paid version is available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/is-your-code-tainted-finding-security-vulnerabilities-using-taint-tracking.html</guid></item><item><title>Finding bugs for free - The magic of code analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/finding-bugs-for-free-the-magic-of-code-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code analysis is a powerful technique for improving the quality of software. It allows you to find bugs in your Python code that would be very hard to find with testing, and without the need for any annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I show examples of &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; bugs that we at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://lgtm.com/"&gt;https://lgtm.com/&lt;/a&gt; have found in real code. For each example, I will describe how we can find that type of error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid unnecessary embarrassment, all examples will be anonymised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intended Audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Python developers. I will assume that the audience knows Python reasonably well, but knows little or nothing about code analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://lgtm.com/"&gt;https://lgtm.com/&lt;/a&gt; we provide state-of-the-art analysis for a number of languages including Python. We have found bugs in the standard library, requests, numpy and many other&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/finding-bugs-for-free-the-magic-of-code-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>Finding bugs for free: The magic of static analysis.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/finding-bugs-for-free-the-magic-of-static-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Static analysis is a powerful technique for improving the quality of
software. It allows you to find bugs in your Python code without any
the need for any annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At lgtm.com we provide state-of-the-art static analysis for a number
of languages including Python. Our Python analysis can find bugs
without the annoyance of many false positives. We have already found
bugs in the standard library, requests, numpy and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will briefly describe what static analysis is, how it
can be useful to you, and then give an overview of the techniques we
use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intended Audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at all Python developers, although I expect that
those who have used pyflakes, pep8, pylint or mypy in the past will
find it the most accessible. I hope that this talk will inspire
developers to start using static analysis tools (hopefully ours) and
to produce better code as a result. I will assume that the audience
knows Python well, but knows little or nothing about static analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(lgtm.com is a commercial project that is free to use for open-source software)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:europython-2017/finding-bugs-for-free-the-magic-of-static-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>Making CPython Fast Using Trace-based Optimisations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/making-cpython-fast-using-trace-based-optimisatio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Mark Shannon - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CPython can be made faster by implementing the sort of optimizations
used in the PyPy VM, and in my HotPy VM. All the necessary changes can
be made without modifying the language or the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPython VM can be modified to support optimizations by adding an
effective garbage collector and by separating the virtual-machine state
from the real- machine state (like Stackless).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimizations can be implemented incrementally. Since almost all of the
optimizations are implemented in the interpreter, all hardware platforms
can benefit. JIT compiler(s) can then be added for common platforms
(intel, ARM, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hotpy.blogspot.com/"&gt;http://hotpy.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/making-cpython-fast-using-trace-based-optimisatio.html</guid><category>cpython</category><category>jit</category><category>pypy</category><category>vm</category></item><item><title>HotPy (2) - A High Performance Binary-Compatible Virtual Machine for Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/hotpy-2-a-high-performance-binary-compatible.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] Mark Shannon - 5 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HotPy (2) is a new interpreter for Python. It is binary compatible with
CPython and reuses CPython’s object and module implementations. The core
interpreter is new and uses many of the techniques developed during the
1990s and 2000s plus a technique developed during my PhD. Once the first
stage of the optimisation chain is completed (May or June), HotPy is
expected to be between 2 and 3 times as fast as CPython. It will
probably never be as fast as PyPy, but it might be possible to get
close. During the talk I will explain how it works (with lots of
pictures), and how it compares to CPython and PyPy. I will also discuss
whether the techniques used in HotPy would be suitable for Jython and
IronPython.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-06:europython-2012/hotpy-2-a-high-performance-binary-compatible.html</guid></item></channel></rss>