<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Unified Release of Python &amp; IRAF software for astronomy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/a-unified-release-of-python-iraf-software-for-a.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As astronomical software development expands from historical data
reduction platforms towards more sophisticated Python applications,
non-technically- focused users can struggle with installing and
maintaining a large number of heterogeneous dependencies. PyRAF has
successfully bridged the gap between IRAF and Python, but managing
dependencies falls outside its scope. A few existing Python
distributions make installation easy, but don't cater for specific needs
(such as dependence on IRAF). STScI and Gemini have therefore developed
a prototype, easy-to-install software distribution for Linux and OSX
known provisionally as the 'Unified Release' (UR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the UR includes STScI Python and its dependencies (eg. Python,
NumPy, IRAF 2.15), as well as Matplotlib &amp;amp; Tk, SciPy, a number of IRAF
packages, DS9, X11IRAF and some testing and documentation tools. Its
scope extends to complementary non-Python/IRAF software, but we do not
intend to produce a comprehensive (Scisoft-like) distribution of tools
for astronomy, nor to satisfy every installation preference. Our focus
is on providing a simple way to run key tools, for users with minimal
support resources and who may not have administrative privileges. Unlike
most comparable distributions, our approach includes basic provision for
in-place software additions and updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently we have completed a first internal version of the UR for both
Linux and OSX, which we shall briefly demonstrate. We plan to make our
first public release during the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James E.H. Turner</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/a-unified-release-of-python-iraf-software-for-a.html</guid><category>Astronomy Mini-Symposia</category></item></channel></rss>