<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Johannes Messner</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modern, typed Python for (multimodal) ML: From training to deployment (Sponsor: Jina.ai)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/modern-typed-python-for-multimodal-ml-from-training-to-deployment-sponsor-jinaai.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typing&lt;/strong&gt; is at the center of „modern Python“, and tools (&lt;em&gt;mypy,
beartype&lt;/em&gt;) and libraries (&lt;em&gt;FastAPI, SQLModel, Pydantic, DocArray&lt;/em&gt;) based
on it are slowly eating the Python world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks explores the benefits of Python type hints, and shows how
they are infiltrating the next big domain: Machine Learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target audience:&lt;/strong&gt; Mainly &lt;em&gt;machine learning practitioners&lt;/em&gt; that care
about improving their code quality and making use of the ever evolving
Python ecosystem. This includes people that focus on &lt;em&gt;model training&lt;/em&gt; as
well as people that focus on &lt;em&gt;model deployment and serving&lt;/em&gt;. The
secondary target audience is anyone that likes to &lt;em&gt;know more about
Python type hints&lt;/em&gt; and how they can be helpful in their code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intended takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt; The audience should leave the talk with three
main learnings: - Why Python type hints are useful - Why they are
particularly useful in the ML domain - How they can leverage libraries
like DocArray in practice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preliminary outline:&lt;/strong&gt; The talk can be seen as two parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 1: Typing in Python&lt;/em&gt; - min 0-5: Introduction - min 5-15: Typing
and type hints in Python: Short history, and why is it useful? - min
25-25: Tool landscape: Type checkers (mypy, beartype) and other
libraries (Pydantic, FastAPI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 2: Python type hints in ML&lt;/em&gt; - min 25-40: Why is typing useful in
ML? Tensor shapes, multi-modal data, and more - min 40-60: How to get
the most out of typing focused tools for ML: jaxtyping and DocArray -
How to organize your data using type hints - How to keep track of your
tensor shapes using type hints - How to bridge the gap between training
and deployment thanks to typing focused libraries&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Johannes Messner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/modern-typed-python-for-multimodal-ml-from-training-to-deployment-sponsor-jinaai.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>