<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lorena-barba.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Land on Vector Spaces: Practical Linear Algebra with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/land-on-vector-spaces-practical-linear-algebra-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorena Barba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/land-on-vector-spaces-practical-linear-algebra-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linear algebra is the foundational mathematical subject that everyone needs to know today. Get lost, calculus! Conventional presentations of linear algebra in undergraduate STEM curricula are overly focused on rules and memorization, overloaded with nomenclature, and slowed down by pen-and-paper methods. This tutorial skips the rule-based procedures and instead uses a visualization-rich approach and computation with NumPy to illuminate the concepts and usefulness of linear algebra. We promise a launching pad for participants to venture into this subject and continue learning after, with a solid conceptual grasp and none of the slog. You don't need previous experience in the subject; some recollection of having learned about matrices and linear systems of equations could help, but is not required.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Engineers Code: Re-usable, Open Educational Modules for Engineering Undergraduates</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/engineers-code-re-usable-open-educational-modules-for-engineering-undergraduates.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorena Barba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/engineers-code-re-usable-open-educational-modules-for-engineering-undergraduates.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents the concepts and design principles behind new
learning modules for teaching undergraduate engineering students to use
Python to learn. Find the modules at:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/engineersCode/EngComp"&gt;https://github.com/engineersCode/EngComp&lt;/a&gt; — I aim to start a community of
educators sharing and remixing learning modules like these, to teach
engineering subjects at all levels. The goal of this talk is to set in
motion the conversations that can create this community.Presenter(s):
Speaker: Lorena Barba, George Washington University&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Diversity Luncheon: Bias, Diversity, Backlash, Manifestos, and Rebuttals</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/diversity-luncheon-bias-diversity-backlash-manifestos-and-rebuttals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorena Barba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-12:scipy-2018/diversity-luncheon-bias-diversity-backlash-manifestos-and-rebuttals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been in a meeting where a colleague says “I’m a great
supporter of gender equality, but I’m totally opposed to quotas!” Or, “I
believe in diversity, but I won’t stand for positive discrimination.”
Maybe you felt a bit troubled by such statements, thinking: that sounds
fair, but somehow I don’t think it is… how do I rebut this? We all know
that bias is omnipresent in our society, and some of us are keenly aware
of rampant bias in sectors like technology, engineering and politics.
Efforts to thwart the effects of bias in communities and institutions
prompt a spectrum of diversity initiatives. Many times these lead to
backlash. It’s been just a year since the memo &amp;quot;Google's Ideological
Echo Chamber” spread through the company’s internal channels, before
becoming public. Yet, another wrangle already is blasting online with
the recent article &amp;quot;Why Women Don’t Code,” by a university lecturer.
What do we do when privileged individuals continue to turn a blind eye
on the injustices around them? They insist on points like “women are
less likely to choose computer science,” and that’s just due to natural
differences. Community and institution leaders have much of the power to
catalyze change, but in the meantime, I want us to build, share and
refine a portfolio of rebuttals for the recurring themes of the
anti-diversity manifestos. Let’s get started.Presenter(s): Speaker:
Lorena Barba, George Washington University&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks 2017-07-13</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stéfan van der Walt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:scipy-2017/lightning-talks-2017-07-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks 2017-07-13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="12%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="23%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="65%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Start&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Speakers&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;1:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Stephan van der
Walt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elegant SciPy book&lt;/strong&gt;
- Its free online with executable notebooks, explore
the table of contents.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;7:20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Loranna&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JOSS&lt;/strong&gt;
- Journal of Open Source Science seeks to rewards
contributors of software.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;17:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Daniel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MolSSI&lt;/strong&gt;
- Molecular Software Sciences Institute is a new, well
funded, open source (OSI) institute.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;20:15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Meagan Lang&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cykdtree &amp;amp; cgal4py&lt;/strong&gt;
- Build KD-trees (e.g., load balancing) and Delanay
Transformations (e.g., continuous distributions).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;24:15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Tobi Shenk&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNA dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;
- Made a DNA dashboard.  Genetists should visualize
more with Bokeh.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;29:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;Prabhu
Ramachandran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching Old Dogs New Tricks&lt;/strong&gt;
- Jupyter presentation tools: tex2ipy, ipyaml&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;35:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Christian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible Self-publishing&lt;/strong&gt;
- Making pretty papers and presentations reexecutable,
Latex + Python + data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;40:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Matt Craig&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vpython-Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;
- Teaching Physics and Astronomy; simple visual models
with physics;  GlowScript instead of install.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;44:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Jason Grout&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter Lab&lt;/strong&gt;
- New computation environment: collapsible cells, lots
of media viewers, more&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;50:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Henry Senyondo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Package Manager&lt;/strong&gt;
- Data Retriever to download, clean, and stick into
your databases.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;54:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Justin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;The Bachelor&amp;quot; Fantasy League&lt;/strong&gt;
- scrape Wikipedia; use Plot.ly;  web visualization
with Dash;  deploy on Heroku&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Numba - Tell Those C++ Bullies to Get Lost</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/numba-tell-those-c-bullies-to-get-lost.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gil Forsyth</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-11:scipy-2017/numba-tell-those-c-bullies-to-get-lost.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you spent hours fighting with SWIG? Are you mystified by complicated NumPy array operations that you wrote only 2 months ago? Come and learn how to accelerate your existing Python code by an order (or orders!) of magnitude using Numba. You'll learn about using just-in-time compilation, writing custom NumPy ufuncs (the easy way!), and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire tutorial is presented as a series of Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote - Data driven Education and the Quantified Student</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/keynote-data-driven-education-and-the-quantified-student.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorena Barba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-26:pydata-seattle-2015/keynote-data-driven-education-and-the-quantified-student.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education has seen the rise of a new trend in the last few years: Learning Analytics. This talk will weave through the complex interacting issues and concerns involving learning analytics, at a high level. The goal is to whet the appetite and motivate reflection on how data scientists can work with educators and learning scientists in this swelling field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higher education has used analytics for a long time to guide administrative decisions. Universities are already adept at developing data-driven admissions strategies and increasingly they are using analytics in fund-raising. Learning analytics is a newer trend. Its core goal is to improve teaching, learning and student success through data. This is very appealing, but it's also fraught with complex interactions among many concerns and with disciplinary gaps between the various players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faculty have always collected data on students' performance on assessments and responses on surveys for the purposes of grading and complying with accreditation, sometimes also for improving teaching methods and more rarely for research on how students learn. To call it Learning Analytics, though, requires scale and some form of systemic effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some early university efforts in analytics developed predictive models to identify at-risk first-year students, aiming to improve freshman retention (e.g., Purdue's &amp;quot;Signals&amp;quot; project). Others built alert systems in support of student advising, with the goal of increasing graduation rates (e.g., Arizona State University's &amp;quot;eAdvisor&amp;quot; system). Experts now segregate these efforts out of learning analytics, proper, because retention and graduation are not the same as learning. The goal, in that case, is to improve the function of the educational system, while learning analytics should be guided by educational research and be aimed at enhancing learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elucidate what is learning analytics, it looks like we first need to answer: what is learning? What is knowledge? And can more data lead to better learning? That is perhaps the zeroth assumption of learning analytics—and it needs to be tested. There are assumptions behind any data system that go as far back as selecting what to track, where it will be tracked, how it will be collected, stored and delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most analytics is based on log data in the Learning Management System (LMS). This &amp;quot;learning in a box&amp;quot; model is inadequate, but the diverse ecosystem of apps and services used by faculty and students poses a huge interoperability problem. The billion-dollar education industry of LMS platforms, textbook publishers and testing companies all want a part in the prospect of &amp;quot;changing education&amp;quot; through analytics. They're all marketing their dazzling dashboards in a worrying wave of ed-tech solutionism. Meanwhile, students' every move gets tracked and logged, often without their knowledge or consent, adding ethical and legal issues of privacy for the quantified student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://figshare.com/articles/Data_driven_Education_and_the_Quantified_Student/1495511"&gt;http://figshare.com/articles/Data_driven_Education_and_the_Quantified_Student/1495511&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/lorena-barba-keynote-pycon-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorena Barba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-30:pycon-us-2016/lorena-barba-keynote-pycon-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Lorena Barba&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keynote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Computational Thinking is Computational Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/keynote-lorena-barba.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorena Barba</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/keynote-lorena-barba.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>