<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smart Banking - Real Time Driven</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2016/smart-banking-real-time-driven.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harnessing the power of machine intelligence to empower users with advanced and smarter banking solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banking has been the one of the most ancient professions for humans. Yet, when it comes to advanced or smart banking solutions we haven’t experienced a radical shift even in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, at Number26, aim to enrich that experience and provide an advanced, mobile banking platform for our customers. Each of our features, revolves around users - their interests and personal preferences.
We achieve such flexibility by the use of state-of-the-art machine learning and statistical learning methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, we would like to present a deeper insight into two major features we use in our product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automatic real time categorisation of transactions: how we combine the power of the cloud computing service (AWS), with the intelligence of machine learning based models to achieve this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;predictive modelling of users future financial status: how artificial neural networks do the smart thinking for our users to come up his predicted personal finances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech stack ranges from Python (Keras, scikit-learn and more), Dockers, AWS lambda, EBS, NLP (stanford nltk) and machine learning classifiers and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we would like to make the message clear, how machine learning can make even the age old traditional ways of banking a fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Arnab Dutta</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-01:pydata-berlin-2016/smart-banking-real-time-driven.html</guid></item></channel></rss>