<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - James Nightingale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_james-nightingale.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>PyAutoFit: A Classy Probabilistic Programming Language For Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/pyautofit-a-classy-probabilistic-programming-language-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Nightingale</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/pyautofit-a-classy-probabilistic-programming-language-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyAutoFit: A Classy Probabilistic Programming Language For Data Science
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By James Nightingale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major trend in data science is the rapid adoption of Bayesian statistics for data analysis and modeling. With modern data-sets growing by orders of magnitude in size, the focus is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyAutoFit: A Classy Probabilistic Programming Language For Data Science
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By James Nightingale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major trend in data science is the rapid adoption of Bayesian statistics for data analysis and modeling. With modern data-sets growing by orders of magnitude in size, the focus is now on developing methods capable of applying contemporary inference techniques to extremely large datasets. To this aim, I present PyAutoFit (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/rhayes777/PyAutoFit"&gt;https://github.com/rhayes777/PyAutoFit&lt;/a&gt;), an open-source probabilistic programming language for automated Bayesian inference that was recently published in the Journal of Open Source Software (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://joss.theoj.org/papers/10.21105/joss.02550"&gt;https://joss.theoj.org/papers/10.21105/joss.02550&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will begin by giving an overview of PyAutoFit’s core features, in particular how it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makes it simple to compose and fit probabilistic models using a range of Bayesian inference libraries, such as emcee (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/dfm/emcee"&gt;https://github.com/dfm/emcee&lt;/a&gt;) and dynesty (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/joshspeagle/dynesty"&gt;https://github.com/joshspeagle/dynesty&lt;/a&gt;).
Handles the 'heavy lifting' that comes with model-fitting, including model composition &amp;amp;amp; customization, outputting results, model-specific visualization and posterior analysis.
Is built for big-data analysis, whereby results are output as a sqlite database which can be queried after model-fitting is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyAutoFit was developed by Astronomers seeking to fit large libraries of galaxy images to better understand the nature of dark matter. Using this science-case, I will describe PyAutoFit’s advanced features, such as multi-level models, automated model-fitting pipelines and support for massively parallel computing infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to introduce the audience to PyAutoFit so they can adopt it for their use-case. The only prerequisite is a basic understanding of object oriented programming in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry></feed>