<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Large-scale media analysis for driving accountability</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/large-scale-media-analysis-for-driving-accountability.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an age where fake news is an emerging concern, digestion of
digital media should be assisted by informative measures that are
exemplary of integrity, responsibility, equal representation, and a
lack of personal agenda. Such metrics are intrinsically complex and
their derivation, calculation and implementation should be handled
with care. At the core of developing such accountability measures is
the ability to ingest, process, analyze and draw insights from
digital media. To achieve this, Media Monitoring Africa has developed
a cloud-based platform, built on Flask, with a full Python stack, to
automatically ingest digital media from several countries
(particularly South Africa and other African countries). The system
then performs Natural Language Processing to highlight important
sources, topics, and entities, and allows for advanced analytics on
the resulting data to be performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present the rationale, data flow and cloud implementation
of this platform, as well as its application to driving accountability
and insights in South African media. The intended audience is broad,
where members can see a detailed road-map of constructing a Python-based
Big Data type system, the analyses that can be performed with it, as
well as the impact it can have on a society's approach to digital media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matthew Adendorff</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-05:pycon-za-2017/large-scale-media-analysis-for-driving-accountability.html</guid></item></channel></rss>