<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_luca-antiga.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>RedisAI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/redisai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca Antiga</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/redisai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking deep learning models to production and doing so reliably is one
of the next frontiers of DevOps. With the advent of Redis modules and
the availability of C APIs for the major deep learning frameworks, it is
now possible to turn Redis into a reliable runtime for deep learning
workloads, providing a simple solution for a model serving microservice.
In this talk we will introduce RedisAI, a joint effort by Orobix and
RedisLabs that introduces tensors and graphs as new Redis data types and
allows to execute graphs over tensors using multiple backends (PyTorch,
TensorFlow, and ONNXRuntime), both on the CPU and GPU. The module also
supports scripting with TorchScript, which provides a Python-like tensor
language that can be used to facilitate pre- and post-processing
operations, like input shaping or output ensambling. In addition, thanks
to its support for the ONNX standard, including ONNX-ML, RedisAI is not
strictly limited to deep learning, but it offers support for general
machine learning algorithms. In this talk, we will demonstrate a full,
Python-powered journey from fine tuning a model to a scalable Flask +
RedisAI deployment. Last, we will lay down the roadmap for the future,
like automated batching, sharding, integration with Redis data types
(e.g. streams) and advanced monitoring. The talk will include sample
code, best practices and a live demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1756"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="database"></category><category term="redis"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="neural network"></category></entry><entry><title>Orobix: AI gets to work!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/orobix-ai-gets-to-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca Antiga</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/orobix-ai-gets-to-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orobix is an engineering company focused on delivering AI-based
solutions to businesses, in multiple domains including life-science and
manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application of deep learning to real world problems and mission
critical contexts is laden with potential pitfalls, involving project
execution all the way to the deployment of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;models in production. Orobix has engineered systems with deep learning
at their core, ranging from medical image segmentation to industrial
quality inspection. In its operations, Orobix has devised strategies to
cope with the cost of collecting data, gathering annotations from
experts, training data- efficient models, deploying models in
production, monitoring and communicating results back to experts. This
talk represents an opportunity for us to share where we started from and
where we’re at, what worked and what didn’t, and what we think is laying
ahead of us, both individually and collectively in the applied AI
community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1807"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1807&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>