<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sunaina-pai.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Mock Object Library Common Pitfalls and Best Practices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/mock-object-library-common-pitfalls-and-best-practices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sunaina Pai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-15:pycon-uk-2019/mock-object-library-common-pitfalls-and-best-practices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is an introduction to the mock object library along with a detailed discussion on common pitfalls associated with patching objects with mocks and the best practices for it. The talk would present code examples, common pitfalls, and best practices to demonstrate how to use mocks effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Trending on Hacker News and GitHub with 120 lines of Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/trending-on-hacker-news-and-github-with-120-lines-of-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sunaina Pai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-17:pycon-uk-2018/trending-on-hacker-news-and-github-with-120-lines-of-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From writing and committing to publishing and promoting makesite.py, a static site generator for Python coders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session is about my personal journey of creating and publishing my
first successful open source project in Python. I will share a story
that starts with rewriting my static, shell-script-powered personal blog
generator, then writing 120 lines of Python code, publishing it on
Hacker News, and then trending on Hacker News and GitHub (right next to
Linus Torvalds :-D) for a day of hacker-fame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, I will share how 120 lines of Python code written to
solve a personal need helped me to connect with developers across the
world and become a part of a small community of Python coders. I believe
this session will be very useful to beginners who want to take their
first step into creating their own personal Python project and make it
successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/sunainapai/makesite"&gt;https://github.com/sunainapai/makesite&lt;/a&gt; to see the source code of
this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>