<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python at Massive Scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2018/python-at-massive-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk describes how JPMorgan has scaled its Athena Python trading and
risk analytics platform over 10 years to 35m LOC/150k Python modules,
and several thousand developers. The talk will also cover key parts of
the infrastructure and tooling for data analytics and visualization, and
explain how those have been adapted for workloads orders of magnitude
larger than originally envisaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Simmons</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-28:pydata-london-2018/python-at-massive-scale.html</guid></item><item><title>PyCon UK 2017 - JP Morgan Sponsor Session</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/pycon-uk-2017-jp-morgan-sponsor-session.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Simmons</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/pycon-uk-2017-jp-morgan-sponsor-session.html</guid></item><item><title>Pandas from the Inside / "Big Pandas"</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/pandas-from-the-inside-big-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is great for data analysis in Python. It promises intuitive DataFrames from R; speed like numpy; groupby like SQL. But there are plenty of pitfalls. This tutorial looks inside pandas to see how DataFrames actually work when building, indexing and grouping tables. You will learn how to write fast, efficient code, and how to scale up to bigger problems with libraries like Dask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandas is great way to quickly get started with data analysis in Python: intuitive DataFrames from R; fast numpy arrays under the hood; groupby just like SQL. But this familiarity is deceptive and both new and experienced pandas users often get stuck on things they feel should be simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this tutorial, we look inside pandas to see how DataFrames actually work when building, indexing and grouping tables. We will learn which pandas operations are fast and why, and how to avoid common performance pitfalls. By the end of the tutorial, you will develop a strong and reliable intuition about using pandas effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part, we switch gear to bigger problems where our data sets can't fit in local memory. First we see how pandas behaves as we start to hit memory limits. Then we look at Dask, whose distributed/deferred DataFrames are a near drop-in replacement for pandas. Then we come back to pure pandas and look for ways to manage bigger datasets with clever data storage,.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this tutorial, you are welcome to follow along on your laptop with the sample data sets and example code in a Jupyter notebook. These will be made available on GitHub here just before the tutorial. The code targets Python 3 and the latest pandas/dask release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Simmons</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/pandas-from-the-inside-big-pandas.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Pandas from the Inside</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/pandas-from-the-inside.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandas is great for data analysis in Python: intuitive DataFrames from R; fast numpy arrays under the hood; groupby like in SQL. But this familiarity is deceptive: pandas users often get stuck on things they feel should be simple. This talk look inside pandas to see how DataFrames actually work when building, indexing and grouping tables. You will learn how to write fast, efficient pandas code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Simmons</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-07:pydata-dc-2016/pandas-from-the-inside.html</guid><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Where am I? What am I doing here?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/where-am-i-what-am-i-doing-here.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where am I? What am I doing here?&amp;quot; -- Motion detection and sensor fusion on wearables and Micro:Bit with Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Simmons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerometers, gyroscopes and magnetometers are suddenly everywhere -- in phones, wearables, and even in the BBC micro:bit. They are cheap, ultra-low power, and often can be read remotely using Bluetooth Low Energy. In this talk, learn how Python can help you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collect raw multi-axis data in real time;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;combine them optimally into a useful representation for analysis;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deal with noisy and missing data with Kalman filters; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extract high-level gesture information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will include examples using MetaWear CPRO wearables and the BBC micro:bit&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Simmons</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pycon-uk-2016/where-am-i-what-am-i-doing-here.html</guid></item><item><title>Pandas from the inside</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2016/stephen-simmons-pandas-from-the-inside.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData London 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[THIS SESSION WILL BEGIN AT 11:00] Pandas is great way to quickly get started with data analysis in Python: intuitive DataFrames from R; fast numpy arrays under the hood; groupby like SQL. But this familiarity is deceptive and new Pandas users often get stuck on things they feel should be simple. This tutorial/talk takes a look inside Pandas to see how DataFrames actually work when indexing, grouping and joining tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We briefly set the scene with a map of the evolving Pandas landscape for large scale analytics. This is all very exciting and brings many new options. However for many users, Pandas' sweet spot remains much smaller scale. For this talk, we focus in on the DataFrame and how it actually works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will dig deeper and deeper into the components of a DataFrame, including Series and Categorical, DataFrame, Index, MultiIndex and GroupBy objects. For common operations like selecting rows, grouping, subtotals and joins, we will see what internal structures are created and how they fit together. From this, get a better understanding of the various API layers, and how to use them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conclude the talk with a jump back to large scale data analysis and a quick look at how a distributed storage solution like Dask solves one of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/SteveSimmons/PyData-PandasFromTheInside/blob/master/pfi.pdf"&gt;https://github.com/SteveSimmons/PyData-PandasFromTheInside/blob/master/pfi.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
GitHub Repo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/SteveSimmons/PyData-PandasFromTheInside"&gt;https://github.com/SteveSimmons/PyData-PandasFromTheInside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Simmons</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-11:pydata-london-2016/stephen-simmons-pandas-from-the-inside.html</guid></item></channel></rss>