<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dan-johnson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Trial by Fire: real world performance optimization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2013/trial-by-fire-real-world-performance-optimization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joseph Jasinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-01:djangocon-us-2013/trial-by-fire-real-world-performance-optimization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trial by Fire: real world performance optimization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 12:15 p.m.--1 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your site is slow. But why is your site slow? There are a myriad of
different problems that can cause this slowness. Drawn from real world
experiences, this talk will help identify different problem areas and
techniques for increasing performance. This involves both evaluating
your performance on the backend and understand bottlenecks on the
frontend. Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is will share with the audience our experience of improving
page load performance on a site. Performance evaluation is a scary
thing, especially for the inexperienced. This talk is not purely a &amp;quot;How
to Optimize Django&amp;quot; as it will discuss various aspects of what makes a
site appear slow to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is slow? - How to identify where the problem and where to start&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance Evaluation: - Django performance evaluation through
middleware and debug toolbar - Browser performance evaluation through
firebug, chrome developer toolkit, and third party tools, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance Enhancement: - Reducing SQL queries - Leveraging server-side
caching - fragment caching - lower level caching - using a database
connection pooler - asset compression - CDN for media delivery - ajax
page loading - message queues&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>