<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tyler McInnes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tyler-mcinnes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Converting Posit-Enthusiasm into Posit-Action</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/converting-posit-enthusiasm-into-posit-action.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tyler McInnes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/converting-posit-enthusiasm-into-posit-action.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did posit::conf(2023) influence my role as coordinator of a nationwide bioinformatics training programme in Aotearoa New Zealand? Inspired by the talks and workshops I attended at last year's conference, I set myself 17 tasks that would strengthen the local data science community, showcase Posit tools, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did posit::conf(2023) influence my role as coordinator of a nationwide bioinformatics training programme in Aotearoa New Zealand? Inspired by the talks and workshops I attended at last year's conference, I set myself 17 tasks that would strengthen the local data science community, showcase Posit tools, and improve my own skill set. Post-conference enthusiasm was at an all-time high. Could I translate this enthusiasm into action to improve the data science training community? This talk will demonstrate how I was able to implement skills and tools from posit::conf to improve my community and highlight the current state of training in New Zealand, including the methods used to connect a small but widely dispersed group of researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>