<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_fabio-lamanna.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Unveiling the potential of graph databases with Python and Neo4j</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/unveiling-the-potential-of-graph-databases-with-python-and-neo4j.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Fabio Lamanna</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/unveiling-the-potential-of-graph-databases-with-python-and-neo4j.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time we are dealing with data coming from the real world, big and
not so big, you know that usually 80% of the time is needed to clean,
prepare and arrange them. We can then spend the other 20% of the time
enjoying our beloved data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing that you may know less is that in the last years, the Neo4j
graph database went into the light of being the “right” place to store
data, thanks to its capacity of direct modelling relations among data,
its high availability and its easy, fast and clean query language
Cypher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’m going to show you some tips to set up in the right way
your data using Pandas, in order to proper model and import them into
Neo4j. A Neo4j Python driver is available to easily import Cypher
queries embedded in Python code. Still, the py2neo package allows
building and querying your database right within your favourite snake
command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget about “tall as teen” SQL queries here; thanks to Pandas, Python
and Cypher modelling, loading and query your database is going to be
really straightforward. After this talk, you’ll can’t wait to give Neo4j
a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: a little knowledge of Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="database"></category><category term="graph"></category><category term="storage"></category><category term="neo4j"></category><category term="data"></category><category term="pandas"></category></entry></feed>