<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hendrik-heuer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hacking Human Language</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/hacking-human-language.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hendrik Heuer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/hacking-human-language.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you convert words into vectors, you can do interesting things with
them. You can compare the topics in a book, make better translations
and tell if a sentence is positive or negative. Python libraries like
gensim and spaCy make it easy to play with this for fun, profit or
social science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces Computational Social Science as a new research
discipline, gives a brief introduction to Natural Language Processing
and explains how Word Vector Representations are computed and how to use
them in Python. Word Vector Representations like word2vec encode
semantic relationships like gender and &amp;quot;is the capital city of&amp;quot;. This
makes it easy to find similar words and compare them visually. To
illustrate this, I am using the gensim and scikit-learn Python libraries
to compare my own Google searches from 2011 and 2014. I will also
explain how to use this to compare the topics in books and book
summaries.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Philip Nye</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks! 5 minutes! GO!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why would a journalist want to learn Python? —&amp;nbsp;Philip Nye&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story detection using LDAs —&amp;nbsp;Hendrik Heuer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A model may be right, but irrelevant — Maria Koroliuk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why I love the days I get to optimise things —&amp;nbsp;Gemma Hentsch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethics? &amp;amp; Data Science ... —&amp;nbsp;Roelof Pieters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love letter to Russel Winder —&amp;nbsp;Tony Simpson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let's go to Mars — Juan Luis Cano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing with Hypothesis —&amp;nbsp;David McGiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing (Plotly) Widgets —&amp;nbsp;Carole Griffiths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... DONE!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Science for Digital Humanities: Extracting meaning from Images and Text</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-for-digital-humanities-extracting-meaning-from-images-and-text.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hendrik Heuer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-for-digital-humanities-extracting-meaning-from-images-and-text.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analyzing millions of images and enormous text sources using machine learning and deep learning techniques is simple and straightforward in the Python ecosystem. Powerful machine learning algorithms and interactive visualization frameworks make it easy to conduct and communicate large scale experiments. Exploring this data can yield new insights for researchers, journalists, and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of this talk is extracting meaning from data and making powerful methods usable by everybody. With the advent of big data, new approaches and technologies are needed to tackle the increase in volume, variety, and velocity of data. This talk illustrates how analysts, journalists, and scientists can benefit from exploratory data analysis and data science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a journalist who wants to cross-reference the names on the guest list of a parliament with online information about lobbyists to identify which party meets which company. A business analyst might want to quantify what topics certain customers are discussing on Twitter or how their sentiment towards a particular product is. Exploratory data analysis and data science techniques enable researchers, journalists and businesses to ask bigger and more ambitious questions than anybody before them and to leverage the abundance of information that is available today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Humanities are located at the intersection of computing and the disciplines of the humanities. They can benefit from the massive-scale automated analysis of content like images and text. Researchers, analysts, and journalists can quantify the state of society from publicly available data like tweets. It is now possible to construct an almost complete map of our civilization just by looking at the tags and GPS coordinates of Flickr photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A vast Python ecosystem is supporting this including machine learning frameworks like scikit-learn, dedicated deep learning frameworks like Keras, and topic modeling tools like gensim. All these tools are open source and can be integrated into powerful data science pipelines. Rather than training neural networks from scratch, pretrained features for text and images can be adapted for fast results.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ethics in Machine Learning Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advances in AI are happening at a tremendous pace, and especially Machine Learning systems are hastily deployed in settings that span as wide as social media, search engines, advertising, military use, and legal systems. At first sight results are often promising, but more and more &amp;quot;outliers&amp;quot; are becoming visible as well. Systemic bias in culture, language, or business practices often become intensified: From the Tay-chatbot turning racist, to both Google and Flickr classifying images of African-Americans as &amp;quot;monkeys&amp;quot;, to discrimination and sexism encoded in language models used for everything from translation, to court sentencing decision. Luckily, initiatives that address some of these concerns is happening through more interpretable models, new privacy regulations, novel privacy-preserving learning algorithms, and researchers and engineers standing up for more just and transparent machine learning models and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel aims to debate these themes with speakers, and the audience, and go beyond the usual &amp;quot;AI hype&amp;quot; and discuss both the amazing progress, as well as the setbacks, in making societies better, more humane, and ready for the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the panel will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roelof Pieters, Panel Host, Co-founder at creative.ai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marek Rosa, CEO/CTO at GoodAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Françoise Provencher, Data Team Lead at Shopify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hendrik Heuer, Researcher at Institute for Information Management (ifib) at the University of Bremen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andreas Dewes, Founder at 7scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katharine Jarmul, Founder at kjamistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to Q&amp;amp;A: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw"&gt;https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw&lt;/a&gt; (Second pyvideo tab)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="panel"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Hacking Human Language</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2015/hacking-human-language.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hendrik Heuer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-25:pycon-se-2015/hacking-human-language.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you convert words into numbers, you can do interesting things with
them. You can compare the topics in a book, make better translations and
tell if a sentence is positive or negative. Python libraries like gensim
and spaCy make it easy to play with this for fun, profit or social
science.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>