<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Alexandra Perkins</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Making Yourself Redundant on Day One - Internal documentation to teach the next hire what you've learned</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-australia-2018/making-yourself-redundant-on-day-one-internal-documentation-to-teach-the-next-hire-what-youve-learned.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first few weeks at a new job are hard. There seem to be too many
questions and not enough answers, and so much assumed knowledge about
the company you joined and the products they make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to talk about how you can make those first few weeks your most
productive and valuable to your new company. By writing internal
documentation that answers all the questions only someone new on the
block knows to ask, you can help pave the way for new hires in the
future, and even help identify and solve customer pain points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing from my own experiences working as an intern and support agent
among highly technical teams, I will go over deciding what to document
based on the level of technical proficiency you would expect the reader
to have, how to use tone to convey the company’s spirit and keep a
future reader interested, and how to future-proof your internal
documentation so it doesn’t stop being updated when you move on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexandra Perkins</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-15:/write-the-docs-australia-2018/making-yourself-redundant-on-day-one-internal-documentation-to-teach-the-next-hire-what-youve-learned.html</guid><category>Write the Docs Australia 2018</category><category>18-11-18</category><category>WTD Australia 2018</category><category>wtd australia 2018</category></item></channel></rss>