<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kevin Tyle</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kevin-tyle.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Project Pythia: A Community Built Training Resource</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/project-pythia-a-community-built-training-resource.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Tyle</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/project-pythia-a-community-built-training-resource.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we invite the SciPy community to use and contribute to Project Pythia (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://projectpythia.org/"&gt;https://projectpythia.org/&lt;/a&gt;), a currently-funded NSF EarthCube project (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.earthcube.org/"&gt;https://www.earthcube.org/&lt;/a&gt;). Project Pythia is a web-based, community-owned, educational resource whose aim is to help teach geoscientists of all stripes and experience levels how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we invite the SciPy community to use and contribute to Project Pythia (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://projectpythia.org/"&gt;https://projectpythia.org/&lt;/a&gt;), a currently-funded NSF EarthCube project (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.earthcube.org/"&gt;https://www.earthcube.org/&lt;/a&gt;). Project Pythia is a web-based, community-owned, educational resource whose aim is to help teach geoscientists of all stripes and experience levels how to make effective use of the Geoscientific Python Ecosystem for the analysis and visualization of their data. Project Pythia was inspired by, and represents the educational efforts of, the Pangeo project (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pangeo.io"&gt;https://pangeo.io&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Better (Open Source) Homes and Gardens with Project Pythia | SciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/better-open-source-homes-and-gardens-with-project-pythia-scipy-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Drew Camron</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/better-open-source-homes-and-gardens-with-project-pythia-scipy-2023.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As scientists continue to embrace the Jupyter ecosystem for constructing computational narratives of their science through code, data, and rich text, they may encounter technical and community barriers to maintaining and sharing their science with new and existing audiences. We demonstrate the value of open-source science community building and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As scientists continue to embrace the Jupyter ecosystem for constructing computational narratives of their science through code, data, and rich text, they may encounter technical and community barriers to maintaining and sharing their science with new and existing audiences. We demonstrate the value of open-source science community building and getting there through reliance on the open-source Jupyter ecosystem, pre-packaged GitHub and BinderHub-based infrastructure, and documentation for creating, sharing, testing, and maintaining Pythia Cookbooks for their computational narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>