<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Aaron Jacobs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aaron-jacobs.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Auth is the product, making data access simple with Posit Workbench</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/auth-is-the-product-making-data-access-simple-with-posit-workbench.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Jacobs</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/auth-is-the-product-making-data-access-simple-with-posit-workbench.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accessing data is a critical early step in data science projects, but is often complicated by security and technical challenges in enterprises. This talk will explore how Posit Workbench facilitates secure data access in IDEs like RStudio, JupyterLab, and VS Code through authentication and authorization aligned with existing data …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accessing data is a critical early step in data science projects, but is often complicated by security and technical challenges in enterprises. This talk will explore how Posit Workbench facilitates secure data access in IDEs like RStudio, JupyterLab, and VS Code through authentication and authorization aligned with existing data governance frameworks. Workbench manages and refreshes short-lived credentials on behalf of users for AWS, Azure, Databricks, and Snowflake, simplifying secure data access for open-source data science teams. Attendees will gain insights into overcoming data access challenges and leveraging Posit Workbench for secure, efficient data science workflows in an enterprise environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>