<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_richard-plangger.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Optimizing Python programs, PyPy to the rescue</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/optimizing-python-programs-pypy-to-the-rescue.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Plangger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/optimizing-python-programs-pypy-to-the-rescue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I want to show how you can use PyPy for your benefit. It
will kick off with a short introduction covering PyPy and its just in
time compiler. PyPy is the most advanced Python interpreter around and
while it should generally just speed up your programs there is a wide
range of performance that you can get out of PyPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the talk some developer statements and big applications will
motivate why PyPy is a viable option to optimize your Python programs.
In addition I will present the companies value after switching to PyPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part, will cover considerations why one should write Python
programs, and only spend fractions of the development time to optimize
your program. The second part of this session will be about this small
part of time: in cases where you need it, I'll show tools that help you
inspect and change your program to improve it. We will also dive into
one tool more elaborately. VMProf, a platform to inspect your program
while it is running, imposing very little overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this talk, an audience member should be equipped with
tools that helps him to understand performance issues and optimize
programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>