<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Django Migrations: para entender e perder o medo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2017/django-migrations-para-entender-e-perder-o-medo.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kátia Nakamura</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:python-brasil-2017/django-migrations-para-entender-e-perder-o-medo.html</guid></item><item><title>import community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/import-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, is its effort
to improve diversity. The authors will share experiences on diversity
obtained from ten different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil,
Italy, Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada and Spain. There are other
reports, that also we would like to share, which are only beautiful
stories of how Python reaches the most distant people and places you
may never have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, in relation
to other communities, is its effort to improve diversity. There is
even a Diversity Statement at PSF: &amp;quot;We have created this diversity
statement because we believe that a diverse Python community is
stronger and more vibrant. A diverse community where people treat each
other with respect has more potential contributors and more sources
for ideas.&amp;quot; The authors will share experiences on diversity obtained
from ten different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil, Italy,
Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada and Spain. There are other reports
that we also would like to share, which are only beautiful stories of
how Python reaches the most distant people and places you may never
have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/import-community.html</guid></item></channel></rss>