<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Large Scale Graph Mining with Spark: What I learned from mapping &gt;15 million websites</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/large-scale-graph-mining-with-spark-what-i-learned-from-mapping-15-million-websites.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the web grows ever larger and more content-rich, graph analysis may be one of the most powerful tools for unlocking insights within the mythical big data. That's totally not fluff, because WIRED wrote about it (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wired.com/insights/2014/03/graph-theory-key-understanding-big-data/"&gt;https://www.wired.com/insights/2014/03/graph-theory-key-understanding-big-data/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk relates to ongoing research into large-scale graph mining, and to find insights into how different websites interact with each other (sometimes in surprising ways!). Spark GraphFrames was integral to exploring the enormous Common Crawl dataset, and the data size really pushed the tool to its limits. Along the way, I learned a great deal about optimizations in representing and computing graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll talk about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why graphs are so fascinating and the types of problems they can help solve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Spark GraphFrames work under the hood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to find clusters of interest in your graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips that may help you in your journey (hint: you're only as good as your data structure).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And much more! Github repo with all code will also be shared.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Win Suen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pygotham-2018/large-scale-graph-mining-with-spark-what-i-learned-from-mapping-15-million-websites.html</guid></item><item><title>Spark Streaming for World Domination (and other projects)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2017/spark-streaming-for-world-domination-and-other-projects.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ask not what you can do for real time data streams but what they can do for you. This talk will give an overview of Apache Spark and pyspark (Spark's Python API), with an emphasis on Spark's Streaming API. We'll be munging and visualizing Twitter data streams as a motivating example. Learn how your streaming data projects can benefit from bigger, better, faster data processing and analytics. Your life will be changed for the better - master streaming data, achieve world domination!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Win Suen</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:pygotham-2017/spark-streaming-for-world-domination-and-other-projects.html</guid></item></channel></rss>