<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>43. What is IPv6 and why does my website I need it</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/43-what-is-ipv6-and-why-does-my-website-i-need-i.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 3rd, 2011 the world ran out of the IPv4 addresses that we
know and love. Clearly the Internet has survived even though hardly
anyone has deployed IPv4's successor, IPv6. Drop by to learn about what
IPv6 is, why you should deploy it and some of the hurdles to deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 3rd, 2011 the world ran out of the IPv4 addresses that we
know and love. The Internet continues to work thanks to technologies
like NAT that enable private IP addresses like 192.168.1.1 and 10.0.0.1
to be reused across organizations. However, even these large blocks of
private IP addresses are not large enough for large ISPs like Comcast in
the United States that give several IP addresses to each customer (ex.
cable set top box, voip, cable modem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continue adding new customers large ISPs have begun deploying two
technologies: IPv6 and large scale NAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large scale NAT is a way for large ISPs to put several of their
customers behind a single public IP address. This means that the one
public IPv4 address you used to have to yourself is now shared by you
and several of your neighbors. It means that as a website owner it is
now more difficult to discern anything useful from the IP addresses
visiting your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPv6 solves the address exhaustion problem by moving from approximately
4 billion IP addresses to 3.4×10^38 IP addresses; more than the number
of atoms on Earth. With plenty of IP addresses ISPs can now return to
giving out unique, public IP addresses to each customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many mobile operators are already beginning to deploy IPv6. In 2009
Verizon issued a mandate that any LTE devices on its network support
IPv6 with IPv4 support being listed as optional [1]. An IPv6-only device
will still need access to the IPv4 Internet, however, IPv6 and IPv4 are
not compatible. Providers like Verizon are putting in place protocol
translation devices that inspect Internet traffic going through them and
proxy IPv4-only websites to their IPv6 customers. While this may sound
wonderful it means that mobile providers are inspecting and rewriting
your packets. Making things more interesting is that this won't work
securely over SSL. The solution is to enable IPv6 on your website so
that IPv6-only hosts can directly access your content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joining the IPv6 bandwagon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon's Elastic Load Balancer supports IPv6 and is already enabled in
all east coast availability zones [2]. If you're already using ELB
enabling IPv6 on your website is as easy as making a single DNS change.
Or so we'd hope, there are still some impediments to a world where your
site runs seamlessly on IPv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The user with broken IPv6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people in the world with broken or inferior IPv6 connectivity
and a web browser or operating system that attempt to use IPv6 anyway.
What this means is that if you turn on IPv6 on your website you have the
potential to cut off those users from your site. In this talk I'll
discuss methods for measuring and analyzing this loss before your
broadly enable IPv6 so that you can make an informed decision about when
and how to flip the switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geo IP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geo IP libraries today are still coming to terms with IPv6. One vendor
in particular is working on IPv6 but only provides limited support in
their free libraries and not yet in their python driver. In their
commercial library, the one generally considered better, they do not
support IPv6 yet due to lack of data [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IPv6 without Amazon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Eventbrite we do development inside of Virtual Box virtual machines.
In this talk I'll discuss how we configure IPv6 on both the host and
guest operating systems so that we can test IPv6 before we push to
Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IP Address Validation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you accept IP addresses from end users check your IP address
validation routines (Django has support, see GenericIPAddressField).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1]
[&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.circleid.com/posts/20090609_verizon_mandates_ipv6_support_for_next_gen_cell_phones/](http://www.circleid.com/posts/20090609_verizon_mandates_ipv6_support_for_next_gen_cell_phones/"&gt;http://www.circleid.com/posts/20090609_verizon_mandates_ipv6_support_for_next_gen_cell_phones/](http://www.circleid.com/posts/20090609_verizon_mandates_ipv6_support_for_next_gen_cell_phones/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2]
[&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2011/05/aws_ipv6.html](http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2011/05/aws_ipv6.html"&gt;http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2011/05/aws_ipv6.html](http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2011/05/aws_ipv6.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[3]
[&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.maxmind.com/app/ipv6](http://www.maxmind.com/app/ipv6"&gt;http://www.maxmind.com/app/ipv6](http://www.maxmind.com/app/ipv6&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bob Van Zant</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-11:pycon-us-2012/43-what-is-ipv6-and-why-does-my-website-i-need-i.html</guid></item></channel></rss>