<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kajal-puri.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>DIY guide to convert Speech-to-text with DeepSpeech AND Text-to-speech with WaveNet</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2018/diy-guide-to-convert-speech-to-text-with-deepspeech-and-text-to-speech-with-wavenet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kajal Puri</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-fr-2018/diy-guide-to-convert-speech-to-text-with-deepspeech-and-text-to-speech-with-wavenet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching Google I/O 2018, one thing we've realized is that the
voice of the artificially intelligent system is going to be a
significant interface to interact with a human, apart from the text. The
research on speech-to-text has been going on since quite a few years
after we've taken a big leap on the Deep Learning approach. In this
talk, I'm going to talk mainly about the Mozilla's DeepSpeech open
source project to convert speech-to-text in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the new problem at hand is how an artificially intelligent system
can give a human-like voice to the written text because when a human
speaks, there are a lot of intricacies in our speech that is so obvious
for the human brain. Expressions in our voice, where to give a pause,
and accent etc are few important factors that play a big role in how
humans talk to each other. So, here I'm going to introduce WaveNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be divided in following four segments :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0-5 minutes: The talk will begin with explaining the Speech-to-text
earlier existing libraries and which machine learning models they
used. Comparison of various libraries like Cloud speech-to-text by
Google, IBM Watson and DeepSpeech will be done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5-25 minutes: DeepSpeech is based on Baidu's DeepSpeech research
paper. This model directly translates raw audio data into text -
without any domain specific code in between. I'll quickly brief about
the underlying deep learning architecture used in DeepSpeech. A short
live-demo will be given and the code, written in Python, will be
explained with the tips on hyper-parametric tuning to get the best
possible results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25-45 minutes: Now, the talk will switch to the latest research going
on in the field of Text-to-speech and how products like Alexa, Siri,
Google Assistant etc are leveraging this to behave like a human. The
deep learning architecture of WaveNet, open sourced by Google's
DeepMind, will be discussed followed by the live-demo and explaining
the code written in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45-50 minutes: For QA session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Build text classification models ( CBOW and Skip-gram) with FastText in python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/build-text-classification-models-cbow-and-skip-gram-with-fasttext-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kajal Puri</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/build-text-classification-models-cbow-and-skip-gram-with-fasttext-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;FastText has been open-sourced by Facebook in 2016 and with its release,
it became the fastest and most accurate library in Python for text
classification and word representation. It is to be seen as a substitute
for gensim package's word2vec. It includes the implementation of two
extremely important methodologies in NLP i.e Continuous Bag of Words and
Skip-gram model. Fasttext performs exceptionally well with supervised as
well as unsupervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will be divided in following four segments :&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry></feed>