<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Zero to kind of a hero: Getting your Python side project ready for deployment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2018/from-zero-to-kind-of-a-hero-getting-your-python-side-project-ready-for-deployment.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One evening, my little sister asked me for help with her homework at
9pm. She had already asked her classmates on a WhatsApp group, but
nobody was able to help as all her peers had the same limited resources
available to them. This gave me the idea for Buza (Zulu for “ask”), a
platform for high school learners to ask questions that could be
answered by volunteer university students in their free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buza is the first side project of mine that I’ve ever truly wanted to
deploy. After months of coding and adding loads of features, I finally
reached out to a senior developer to help me deploy my truck of
features. The first thing she said was “A lot of this code will have to
be replaced with production-ready code”. These are words you never want
to hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University Computer Science equipped me with the ability to write code
to solve problems, but in industry extra skills were required to build
production-ready software. This talk will share the valuable lessons I
learned from getting this Django web app production-ready. This will
start with how to c &lt;strong&gt;hoose the right tools, framework, environment for
your project&lt;/strong&gt;. I will also cover how to set up &lt;strong&gt;testing and continuous
integration for your project&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I will cover (Zero to Hero):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No code is the best code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Framework: DJango&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment: Pipenv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static Tests: Flake8, Mypy (checks types), isort(sorts imports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test Driven Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated testing: Tox and Travis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sewagodimo Matlapeng</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-12:pycon-za-2018/from-zero-to-kind-of-a-hero-getting-your-python-side-project-ready-for-deployment.html</guid></item></channel></rss>