<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>An Introduction to Deep Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/an-introduction-to-deep-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geoff French - An Introduction to Deep Learning
[EuroPython 2016]
[22 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/an-introduction-to-deep-learning"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/an-introduction-to-deep-learning&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning: how it works, how to train a deep neural network, the
theory behind deep learning, recent developments and applications.
(length: 60 mins)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(length: 60 mins)    In the last few years, deep neural networks have
been used to generate state of the art results in image
classification, segmentation and object detection. They have also
successfully been used for speech recognition and textual analysis. In
this talk, I will give an introduction to deep neural networks. I will
cover how they work, how they are trained, and a little bit on how to
get going. I will briefly discuss some of the recent exciting and
amusing applications of deep learning. The talk will primarily focus
on image processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you completely new to deep learning, please attend T. Rashid's talk
'A Gentle Introduction to Neural Networks (with Python)'. His talk is
in the same room immediately before mine and his material is really
good and will give you a good grounding in what I will present to you.
:)
You may also want to attend I' Lewis' talk 'Deep Learning with Python
&amp;amp; TensorFlow' after Lunch in the PyCharm room to round it all off! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Geoff French</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/an-introduction-to-deep-learning.html</guid><category>deep learning</category></item></channel></rss>