<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_zuria-bauer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Desde imágenes RGB a mapas de profundidad pasando por redes convolucionales profundas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2018/desde-imagenes-rgb-a-mapas-de-profundidad-pasando-por-redes-convolucionales-profundas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zuria Bauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-es-2018/desde-imagenes-rgb-a-mapas-de-profundidad-pasando-por-redes-convolucionales-profundas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Poder determinar la distancia entre objetos a partir de una imagen en dos dimensiones es una tarea que ha intrigado a multitud de investigadores en estos últimos años. Esto permitiría la estimación de la profundidad en imágenes monoculares, siendo capaces de realizar predicciones precisas en mapas de profundidad. Las ventajas son evidentes, ya que, cualquier cámara de color detectaría datos tridimensionales. Esta capacidad es importante para crear sistemas de asistencia de bajo coste para ayudar a personas con discapacidad visual a desplazarse y desarrollar su vida en entornos exteriores de forma autónoma. Entre otras aplicaciones, esta técnica permitiría generar reconstrucciones tridimensionales de un objeto o escena sin necesidad de disponer de dispositivos específicos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En esta charla se mostrará un sistema basado en visión capaz de detectar estas distancias a partir de imágenes en 2D, con el objetivo de implementarse en sistemas para ayudar a personas con discapacidad visual a desplazarse en entornos exteriores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durante la charla se hablará de conceptos relacionados con el Deep Learning, empleando la herramienta Tensorflow. La charla está dirigida a todos los públicos, pues se tratarán los conceptos de una manera sencilla, y desde la perspectiva del trabajo con Python de una persona que no ha estudiado informática. Por otro lado, el proyecto que se presenta está englobado en el proyecto nacional RETOGAR (RETOrno al HoGAR) financiado por el Ministerio de Economía y Competitividad del Gobierno de España y en el cual se tratan diversos temas de la robótica social enfocada a personas dependientes.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to Improve Your Diet and Save Money with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2016/how-to-improve-your-diet-and-save-money-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zuria Bauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pycon-es-2016/how-to-improve-your-diet-and-save-money-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optimization (also known as mathematical programming) can be simplified to a selection of the best element/s (minimum or maximum) for a given circumstance (objective function), which may include some conditions (subject to restrictions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the classic problems in field optimization is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.neos-guide.org/content/diet-problem"&gt;diet problem&lt;/a&gt;. This problem came up during the Second World War when the Army wanted to minimize the cost of feeding their soldiers in the field (objective function) while maintaining a balanced diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this occasion, we will take as an example a set of foods from a well-know fast food restaurant and try to minimize the cost of the menu while being as healthy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, there are plenty of commercial algebraic modeling languages —such as GAMS and AMPL—, which are used mainly in academia and professional environments. But as Python lovers, we can use several libraries for solving such optimization problems, —e.g. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cvxopt.org/"&gt;CVXOpt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cvxpy.org/en/latest/"&gt;CVXPy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pythonhosted.org/PuLP/"&gt;PULP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://openopt.org/Welcome"&gt;OpenOpt&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pyomo.org/"&gt;Pyomo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will use Pyomo because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use it as an Algebraic Modeling Language, being similar to AMPL and GAMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve these problems by means of a variety of solvers such as GLPK, Gurobi, CPLEX, CBC and PICO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a free, open source library (BSD license), being developed by Sandia National Laboratories, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports Python 3 and is easy to install.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moreover, it automatically connects with NEOS server (web platform that gives free access to commercial solvers).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be divided in three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Mathematical Programming/Optimization (10 min): visual introduction to optimization concepts including restrictions and non linearties (linear Programming, Nonlinear Programming, ILP, MIP, MINLP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to the diet problem, Pyomo sintax and a quick note for the installation (15 min): showing how to improve your diet and save money when ordering food in fast food restaurants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimization problems in engineering (5 min): showing more advanced optimization examples in the area of process engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't miss this talk if are one of those &amp;quot;undecided pythonistas&amp;quot; that want to learn how to solve optimization problems with determination ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2016.es.pycon.org/"&gt;http://2016.es.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to improve your diet and save money with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/how-to-improve-your-diet-and-save-money-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zuria Bauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-31:europython-2016/how-to-improve-your-diet-and-save-money-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zuria Bauer/Daniel Domene López - How to improve your diet and save money with Python
[EuroPython 2016]
[19 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-to-improve-your-diet-and-save-money-with-python"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-to-improve-your-diet-and-save-money-with-python&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimization in Python (also known as mathematical programming) can be
performed by minimization (or maximization) of an objective function
within a model that can include discrete variables subject to a set of
constrains. At this talk, chemical engineering students of the
University of Alicante will introduce the audience to the
possibilities of optimization, presenting Pyomo and showing real world
examples such as how to improve your diet and save money at fast food
restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process optimization in industry has become essential in order to
maximize the resources available and reduce energy consumption.
Optimization problems become interesting when dealing with
restrictions (linear or nonlinear) and integer variables (modeling the
discrete decisions). Python ecosystem presents different libraries to
solve optimization problems, some of them are CVXOpt, CVXPy, PulP,
OpenOpt, or Pyomo.
Among them, Pyomo results interesting because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can be used for Mathematical modeling in Python similarly to AMPL (and GAMS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It communicates with the main solvers used in this field such as GLPK, Gurobi, CPLEX, CBC and PICO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's free and open source Python library (BSD license), being developed by Sandia National Laboratories, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It supports Python 3 and it is easy to install.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be divided in three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction to Mathematical Programming/Optimization (15 min)&lt;/em&gt;: visual introduction to optimization concepts including restrictions and non linearties (linear Programming, Nonlinear Programming, ILP, MIP, MINLP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction to the Pyomo sintax and a quick note for the installation (20 min):&lt;/em&gt; showing how to improve their diet and save money when ordering food in fast food restaurants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Optimization problems in engineering (10 min):&lt;/em&gt; showing more advanced optimization examples that include decision variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>