<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Image Recognition DL WORKSHOP</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/image-recognition-dl-workshop.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A DL workshop where we apply Deep Learning to satelite imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipple will be presenting a workshop that will give the audience a
hands-on tutorial focusing on deep learning. Deep-learning is part of
the world’s most cutting edge technology that will undoubtedly impact
human life in the upcoming years. It is used in driverless cars, voice
assistance, facial recognition and even controversial topics like
deepfakes. During the workshop the audience will be guided in the
mathematics that is involved in this subset of machine learning and
artificial intelligence, after which they will develop their own deep
learning network by the use of a Jupyter Notebook tutorial. The goal of
this tutorial is to classify roof shapes and materials of houses in an
aerial image. A real-life use-case of how 510 (i.e. Data team of the
Netherlands Red Cross) was able to improve damage assesment to improve
humanitarian aid in disaster responses. After the tutorial, participants
are encouraged to further improve their models during Friday/Saturday.
The winning team will be made public on Saturday during the conference
talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to receive access to the course materials we would like you to
register here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pipple.nl/pydata-2019-workshop/"&gt;https://www.pipple.nl/pydata-2019-workshop/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pipple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-29:pydata-eindhoven-2019/image-recognition-dl-workshop.html</guid></item></channel></rss>