<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tavis-rudd.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python to Code by Voice</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/using-python-to-code-by-voice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tavis Rudd</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-17:pycon-us-2013/using-python-to-code-by-voice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I dictate my code using a voice recognition system with Python embedded
in it. In a fast paced live demo, I will code a small system and deploy
it without touching the keyboard. I hope to convince you that voice
recognition is no longer a crutch for the disabled or limited to plain
prose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I developed a case of Emacs Pinkie (RSI) so severe my
hands went numb and I could no longer type or work. Desperate, I tried
voice recognition. At first programming with it was painfully slow but,
as I couldn’t type, I persevered. After several months of vocab tweaking
and duct-tape coding in Python and Emacs Lisp, I had a system that
enabled me to code faster and more efficiently by voice than I ever had
by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a fast-paced live demo, I will create a small system using Python,
plus a few other languages for good measure, and deploy it without
touching the keyboard. The demo gods will make a scheduled appearance. I
hope to convince you that voice recognition is no longer a crutch for
the disabled or limited to plain prose. It’s now a highly effective tool
that could benefit all programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry></feed>