<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lisa Tagliaferri</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Software Supply Chain and You: How to Build and Ship More Secure Django Apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/the-software-supply-chain-and-you-how-to-build-and-ship-more-secure-django-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a high-level overview of the developer-first open source project, Sigstore, within the Django context. We’ll go through each component of Sigstore, including how to sign a software artifact with Cosign, how Fulcio issues certificates, and finally how developers and end users alike can verify claims made on the Rekor public ledger. We’ll discuss how PyPI is leveraging Sigstore to help with verifying and trusting dependencies we all rely on. Finally, we’ll go through a demonstration of creating, publishing, and signing a containerized Django app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will walk away with an understanding of how they can navigate software security more effectively and be better citizens of open source through implementing recommended security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lisa Tagliaferri</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-18:/djangocon-us-2022/the-software-supply-chain-and-you-how-to-build-and-ship-more-secure-django-apps.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>Oh, the Humanities! Interdisciplinary Thinking in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/oh-the-humanities-interdisciplinary-thinking-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The humanities — fields like history, literature, and philosophy — are not
often incorporated into our thought processes in the tech industry. However,
bringing humanities contexts into our everyday work can strengthen the
software we build and ensure that it is serving our communities. Learn about
how creating software for humanities researchers has developed better Python
programmers at MIT, and how our own self-learning can benefit from tackling
projects with humanistic values at their core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide you with an overview of how Python has been used to
help solve humanities research problems, while also demonstrating how
incorporating the humanities into Python development processes can improve
software. We will go over what things you should consider to think in more
interdisciplinary ways, and how broader contexts can ensure that the
software we build serves its users well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lisa Tagliaferri</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-05:/pygotham-2019/oh-the-humanities-interdisciplinary-thinking-in-python.html</guid><category>PyGotham 2019</category></item></channel></rss>