<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Amy Arambulo Negrette</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_amy-arambulo-negrette.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Automating your Cloud Cost Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2023/automating-your-cloud-cost-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Amy Arambulo Negrette</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-01:/pytexas-2023/automating-your-cloud-cost-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Automating your Cloud Cost Analysis&amp;quot;
Public Cloud is often touted as a cheaper option, but the bills we get in the mail can be long and convoluted. For better or worse, any dollar spent in the cloud is a result of an architecture decision. This talk will give attendees …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Automating your Cloud Cost Analysis&amp;quot;
Public Cloud is often touted as a cheaper option, but the bills we get in the mail can be long and convoluted. For better or worse, any dollar spent in the cloud is a result of an architecture decision. This talk will give attendees a firm understanding of the relationship between the architecture and the invoice and the key metrics to keep an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover:
What is FinOps and why is it important
Key metrics for measuring Cloud spend
Automating Cloud Invoices
Using Python, a SQL database, and FaaS, we can build a pipeline that automatically retrieves our invoice, and populates a searchable table to derive insights such as our top 5 most used services and biggest growing services. Attendees with small developers account to large multi-account deployments will better understand the impact of their architecture on their wallet.
Speaker: Amy Arambulo Negrette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With fifteen years of industry experience, Amy Arambulo Negrette has built web applications for a variety of industries including Yahoo! Fantasy Sports and NASA Ames Research Center. One of her projects modernized two legacy systems impacting the entire research center and won her a Certificate of Excellence from the Ames Contractor Council. More recently, she built APIs for enterprise clients for a cloud consulting firms and led a team of Cloud Software Engineers. Amy has survived acquisitions, layoffs, and balancing life with two children.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2023"></category></entry></feed>