<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_victor-zabalza.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-27T11:30:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Automated data exploration edit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/automated-data-exploration-edit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T11:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T11:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Víctor Zabalza</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-27:pycon-uk-2017/automated-data-exploration-edit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step in any data-intensive project is understanding the available data. To this end, data scientists spend a significant part of their time carrying out data quality assessments and data exploration. In spite of this being a crucial step, it usually requires repeating a series of menial tasks before the data scientist gains an understanding ofthe dataset and can progress to the next steps in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will detail the inner workings of a Python package that we have built which automates this drudge work, enables efficient data exploration, and kickstarts data science projects. A summary is generated for each dataset, including:     General information about the dataset, including data quality of each of the columns;     Distribution of each of the columns through statistics and plots (histogram, CDF, KDE), optionally grouped by other categorical variables;     2D distribution between pairs of columns;     Correlation coefficient matrix for all numerical columns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building this tool has provided a unique view into the full Python data stack, from the parallelised analysis of a dataframe within a Dask custom execution graph, to the interactive visualisation with Jupyter widgets and Plotly. During the talk, I will also introduce how Dask works, and demonstrate how to migrate data pipelines to take advantage of its scalable capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>