<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_j-gregory-caporaso.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>scikit-bio: core bioinformatics data structures and algorithms in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/scikit-bio-core-bioinformatics-data-structures-a.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>J Gregory Caporaso</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-10:scipy-2014/scikit-bio-core-bioinformatics-data-structures-a.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present scikit-bio, a library based on the Python scientific
computing stack implementing core bioinformatics data structures,
algorithms and parsers. scikit-bio is useful for students in
bioinformatics, who can learn topics such as iterative progressive
multiple sequence alignment from the source code and accompanying
documentation, and for real-world bioinformatics applications
developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is widely used in computational biology, with many high profile
bioinformatics software projects, such as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://galaxyproject.org/"&gt;Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://khmer.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;Khmer&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.qiime.org"&gt;QIIME&lt;/a&gt;, being largely or entirely written in
Python. We present &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scikit-bio.org"&gt;scikit-bio&lt;/a&gt;, a new
library based on the standard Python scientific computing stack (e.g.,
numpy, scipy, and matplotlib) implementing core bioinformatics data
structures, algorithms, parsers, and formatters. scikit-bio is the first
bioinformatics-centric &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scikits.appspot.com/"&gt;scikit&lt;/a&gt;, and
arises from over ten years of development efforts on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pycogent.org"&gt;PyCogent&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.qiime.org"&gt;QIIME&lt;/a&gt;, representing an effort to update the
functionality provided by these extensively used tools, and to make that
functionality more accessible. scikit-bio is intended to be useful both
as a resource for students, who can learn topics such as heuristic-based
sequence database searching or iterative progressive multiple sequence
alignment from the source code and accompanying documentation, and as a
powerful library for 'real-world' bioinformatics developers. To achieve
these goals, scikit-bio development is centered around test-driven,
peer-reviewed software development; C/Cython integration for
computationally expensive algorithms; extensive API documentation and
doc-testing based on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/numpy/numpy/blob/master/doc/HOWTO_DOCUMENT.rst.txt"&gt;numpy docstring
standards&lt;/a&gt;;
user documentation and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://caporasolab.us/An-Introduction-To-Applied-Bioinformatics/"&gt;theoretical discussion of topics in IPython
Notebooks&lt;/a&gt;;
adherence to PEP8; and continuous integration testing. scikit-bio is
available free of charge under the BSD license.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>