<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_petr-zikan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python for physicists</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/python-for-physicists.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Petr Zikán</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:pycon-cz-2017/python-for-physicists.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new subject for spring semester 2017 was prepared at Masaryk
University: Python for physicists. The goal of the subject was not
easy at all. Effective scientific data processing using Python for
anyone without any prior knowledge of the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentals of scientific Python (numpy, scipy, pandas) and graphics
(matplotlib) introduced using simple real-word examples such as: line
regression, bifurcation method, particle tracing in electromagnetic
fields, fourier analysis of plasma voltage response, linear algebra
using numpy and introduction to machine learning. All accompanied
with introduction of concepts such as: basic data structures, reading
data from file, introduction to functions, modules and classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject was prepared as a collective work of 8 people. Not
everything went exactly as was planned. Do you want to hear lessons
we all (students and teachers) have learnt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petr Zikán is a PhD student of Plasma physics at Masaryk University
in Brno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among his main interests are numerical modeling of various physical
systems, data processing and data mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He works for Gauss Algorithmic as a data analyst and he is also a
co-founder of PlasmaSolve company, where his main expertise lies in
the field of particle plasma modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>