<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sara Jakša</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sara-jaksa.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Introduction to Network Analysis by Analyzing Characters in Harry Potter Fanfiction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/introduction-to-network-analysis-by-analyzing-characters-in-harry-potter-fanfiction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sara Jakša</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/introduction-to-network-analysis-by-analyzing-characters-in-harry-potter-fanfiction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Network Analysis by Analyzing Characters in Harry Potter
Fanfiction - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Ginny considered the best girl for Harry? Do Hermione and Snape
really go well together? In this talk, I will go through the process of
analyzing the tags data from the fanfiction website, which …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Network Analysis by Analyzing Characters in Harry Potter
Fanfiction - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Ginny considered the best girl for Harry? Do Hermione and Snape
really go well together? In this talk, I will go through the process of
analyzing the tags data from the fanfiction website, which might help
answer these and some similar questions. In the more and more globalized
world, network analysis is becoming more and more prominent in helping
us realize how different people and things are connected. Let it be how
the power grid will need to change, to accommodate the move to renewable
sources or how the different political and corporate actors are
connected, explaining why some changes can happen as some do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or it can be done to answer some other, in some way just as interesting.
Is Ginny considered the best girl for Harry? Do Hermione and Snape
really go well together? And many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will go through the process of analyzing the tags data
from the fanfiction website. I will go through the formatting of the
data for analysis with the networkx library, some simple analysis and
the visualization of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not assume any network analysis knowledge, but I will assume that
you are comfortable programming in Python on a level, that if you need
to create a quick script, you could do it easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sara Jakša&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Italia 2022"></category><category term="analytics"></category></entry></feed>