<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Froilán Irizarry Rivera</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_froilan-irizarry-rivera.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python, Government, and Contracts: providing a tool to investigate corruption</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2019/python-government-and-contracts-providing-a-tool-to-investigate-corruption.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Froilán Irizarry Rivera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:/north-bay-python-2019/python-government-and-contracts-providing-a-tool-to-investigate-corruption.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="North Bay Python 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Impacto y lecciones aprendidas con Civic Tech</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2021/impacto-y-lecciones-aprendidas-con-civic-tech.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Froilán Irizarry Rivera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-08-27:/pycon-latam-2021/impacto-y-lecciones-aprendidas-con-civic-tech.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a software developer from Puerto Rico living in Washington DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I've worked in Puerto Rico as a consultant and developer while contributing to the creation of a couple of tech communities in the San Juan metro area. The latest being Fullstack Nights and Code for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a software developer from Puerto Rico living in Washington DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I've worked in Puerto Rico as a consultant and developer while contributing to the creation of a couple of tech communities in the San Juan metro area. The latest being Fullstack Nights and Code for Puerto Rico&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I moved to Washington DC to join the United States Digital Service. Afterwards I stayed in the city to join Code.gov as a tech lead and later GitHub where I helped the Dept. of Veterans Affairs in their digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm currently working with Uplight, Inc. as a senior engineer on their platform team, where we are building the APIs to help transform the energy industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While essentially a blog, I'm going to be using this space as a place to record thoughts, ideas, and have a place where I can save things that I don't want to forget. You'll see posts in English, Spanish, and &amp;quot;Spanglish&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for being here and I hope you enjoy this ride with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Latam 2021"></category></entry></feed>