<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lori-burns.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Composing and Decomposing Quantum Chemistry Software: Transitioning a Field from ASCII Text to Relational Data Documents and Schema</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/composing-and-decomposing-quantum-chemistry-software-transitioning-a-field-from-ascii-text-to-relational-data-documents-and-schema.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lori Burns</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/composing-and-decomposing-quantum-chemistry-software-transitioning-a-field-from-ascii-text-to-relational-data-documents-and-schema.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practitioners in computational chemistry are loath to give up neither their many formats of ASCII output files that summarize the precious results of terabytes of algorithm crunching nor the exact software configurations to which they trained in their youth. This paper describes a year of refactoring several open source quantum chemistry projects into modularity and imposing archivable data interchange, while sustaining development over the Psi4, QCDB common driver, and Molecular Sciences Software Institute (MolSSI) Quantum Chemistry Archive integrated software ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>QCDB Database Tools for Managing and Harmonizing Quantum Chemistry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/qcdb-database-tools-for-managing-and-harmonizing-quantum-chemistry-scipy-2016-lori-burns.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lori Burns</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/qcdb-database-tools-for-managing-and-harmonizing-quantum-chemistry-scipy-2016-lori-burns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Workflows in computational chemistry must manage large quantities of expensively computed and metadata-laden data, each to be accessed in its own right or recycled into complex methodologies. QCDB manages such datasets in collection, application of recognized and exploratory work-up procedures through Pandas, visualization through matplotlib, and facilitation of open-access. It is demonstrated applied to a set of nonbonded structures from the protein databank (PDB).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="SciPy 2016"></category></entry></feed>