<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Just ask: designing intent-driven algos</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/just-ask-designing-intent-driven-algos.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classic recommender systems are great for answering the question “what does a user want in general?”. However, they only get you partway to an answer to “what does a user want right now?”. To close the gap, it helps to capture and act on real-time user intent. I’ll share examples of this paradigm, and the resulting changes to our algorithms and architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:pydata-london-2019/just-ask-designing-intent-driven-algos.html</guid></item><item><title>Navigating unconscious bias</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2018/navigating-unconscious-bias.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people don’t want to be racist, sexist, or prejudiced in general. Yet many of us are unconsciously biased against fellow Pythonistas whom we consciously respect. I'll share evidence-based, positive tools for dealing with biased situations, whether you're the target, the speaker, or a bystander.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-01-22:pycascades-2018/navigating-unconscious-bias.html</guid></item><item><title>Navigating unconscious bias</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/navigating-unconscious-bias.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people do not want to be racist, sexist, or prejudiced in general. Yet simply living in the world exposes everyone to negative stereotypes about various groups of people, which can lead anyone to internalize harmful &amp;quot;unconscious bias&amp;quot; and accidentally discriminate against people they consciously respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am endlessly impressed by Django's dedication to improving our community. Every day I hear individual Djangonauts becoming aware of the dialog around unconscious bias, and searching for tools to be better to all the people in their lives. In addition, many of the tech companies, academic institutions, and open source communities where we work have pledged to tackle diversity, equity, and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a board member of the Unconscious Bias Project, a group of tech folks, scientists, and artists who translate the social science literature into evidence-based, empowering, and empathetic resources for our peers. In this talk, I’ll give folks from all backgrounds a toolkit to identify and counteract the effects of biased comments in our tech communities, whether you're the target, the speaker, or a bystander.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/navigating-unconscious-bias.html</guid></item><item><title>Django for IOT: From Hackathon to Production</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/django-for-iot-from-hackathon-to-production.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django for IOT: From Hackathon to Production by Anna Schneider&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s Friday night of hackathon weekend. The latest snazzy Internet-connected thingy is sitting on the table next to your beverage of choice, the device’s API docs are open in a browser tab, and your fingers are itching to write some Django. What’s the fastest way to get started? And next month when you come back to it, what will you want to upgrade?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk through a common IoT use case, sending HTTP requests to turn on and off a device in response to some external data. I do this all the time at WattTime and I'll share some of the tricks I've picked up over the last couple years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll focus on two big differences from your typical blog or polls app: the data model abstractions that fit the problem, and the need to run frequent periodic tasks to hit the device’s API. I'll share a data model that's worked well for me across a bunch of IoT apps. And I'll show you two ways to run those periodic background tasks in Django: a hackathon-friendly version, and a production-friendly version using Celery. You'll walk away with a complete demo template that you can use in your own projects!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:djangocon-us-2016/django-for-iot-from-hackathon-to-production.html</guid></item><item><title>IoT with Django: From hackathon to production</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/iot-with-django-from-hackathon-to-production.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/9"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/iot-with-django-from-hackathon-to-production-by-anna-schneider/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/iot-with-django-from-hackathon-to-production.html</guid><category>django</category></item></channel></rss>