<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mayank Jindal</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mayank-jindal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Unleashing Python's Power: Serverless Innovations with AWS Lambda</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2023/Unleashing_Pythons_Power_Serverless_Innovations_with_AWS_Lambda.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-08T18:54:27+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-08T18:54:27+00:00</updated><author><name>Mayank Jindal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-08:/pybay-2023/Unleashing_Pythons_Power_Serverless_Innovations_with_AWS_Lambda.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, serverless computing has brought about a paradigm shift in the realm of software development and deployment. This transformation has not only revolutionized application construction but has also introduced unparalleled ease in scaling, cost-effectiveness, and maintenance. As the domain of serverless continues to grow, AWS Lambda has …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, serverless computing has brought about a paradigm shift in the realm of software development and deployment. This transformation has not only revolutionized application construction but has also introduced unparalleled ease in scaling, cost-effectiveness, and maintenance. As the domain of serverless continues to grow, AWS Lambda has risen as a platform that grants developers an exceptional chance to deploy Python applications without the burden of traditional server administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session aims to offer insights and practical expertise in fully utilizing the capabilities of serverless architecture. This will empower attendees to create Python applications that effortlessly combine innovation with efficiency, using the capabilities of AWS Lambda through the boto3 library.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Embracing MLOps: Bridging the Gap Between Machine Learning and DevOps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2024/embracing-mlops-bridging-the-gap-between-machine-learning-and-devops.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mayank Jindal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-04-06:/pycascades-2024/embracing-mlops-bridging-the-gap-between-machine-learning-and-devops.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the dynamic field of machine learning, MLOps (Machine Learning Operations) has emerged as a crucial discipline combining aspects of machine learning, data science and operations. This talk aims to demystify MLOps differentiating it from traditional DevOps practices and highlighting its growing importance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2024"></category></entry></feed>