<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_roelof-pieters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Philip Nye</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks! 5 minutes! GO!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why would a journalist want to learn Python? —&amp;nbsp;Philip Nye&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story detection using LDAs —&amp;nbsp;Hendrik Heuer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A model may be right, but irrelevant — Maria Koroliuk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why I love the days I get to optimise things —&amp;nbsp;Gemma Hentsch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethics? &amp;amp; Data Science ... —&amp;nbsp;Roelof Pieters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love letter to Russel Winder —&amp;nbsp;Tony Simpson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let's go to Mars — Juan Luis Cano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing with Hypothesis —&amp;nbsp;David McGiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing (Plotly) Widgets —&amp;nbsp;Carole Griffiths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... DONE!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Python for Image and Text Understanding: One Model to rule them all!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/python-for-image-and-text-understanding-one-model-to-rule-them-all.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/python-for-image-and-text-understanding-one-model-to-rule-them-all.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning is an exciting trend in machine learning, where neural
networks of many layers “deep” can automatically learn features from
large volumes of data, setting new standards for image, audio and
language understanding. In this interactive session we will go over
some of the most popular python libraries for deep learning and will
train an actual deep neural nets end to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/roelofp/python-for-image-understanding-deep-learning-with-convolutional-neural-nets"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/roelofp/python-for-image-understanding-deep-learning-with-convolutional-neural-nets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning is an exciting trend in machine learning, where neural
networks of many layers “deep” can automatically learn features from
large volumes of data, in turn setting new standards for audio, image,
and language understanding, machine translation, object and face
recognition, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will start with a short overview of Deep Learning, both the
deserved praise, as well as some of its criticisms, and explain some of
the ways in which both text and vision data can be represented within a
single united model. Such a single model has not only amazingly accurate
results for existing language and vision tasks, but also offers new
possibilities for business and society at large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second portion of the talk I will tell a bit about how one would
go about training a deep neural net for the first time, and what are
some of the established practices to follow. We will go over one or more
of the most widely used python packages (theano, pylearn, caffe) which
enable machine learning enthusiasts to easily prototype and run deep
architectures. Aided by iPython notebook(s) we will do some live coding
to create and run a deep neural net, and see how it performs in the wild
on a language or vision task.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>AI assisted creativity</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/ai-assisted-creativity.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/ai-assisted-creativity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new wave of creative applications of AI has arrived, making science fiction authors struggle to keep up with reality. Recent advances in Deep Learning, especially generative models, make it possible to generate text, audio, speech, and images. There's a wonderfully trippy world of neural nets &amp;quot;going wild&amp;quot; out there, which you, the python enthusiastic, can be part of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new wave of creative applications of AI has arrived, making science fiction authors struggle to keep up with reality. Recent advances in Deep Learning, especially generative models, make it possible to generate text, audio, speech, and images. There's a wonderfully trippy world of neural nets &amp;quot;going wild&amp;quot; out there, with AI choreographed dancing moves, freestyle raps, impressionist paintings, and Trump impersonating bots. Such &amp;quot;bots&amp;quot; and experiments are but one novel use of this kind of &amp;quot;Creative AI&amp;quot;. Taking a more human-centered approach, allowing for control and agency, has the potential to turn these content-generating neural nets, into tools for creative use and explorations of human-machine interaction, where the main theorem is &amp;quot;augmentation, not automation&amp;quot;. The talk will particularly focus on &amp;quot;generative&amp;quot; models, and show the python fanatic how to make your move with these particular forms of Deep Neural Nets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ethics in Machine Learning Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advances in AI are happening at a tremendous pace, and especially Machine Learning systems are hastily deployed in settings that span as wide as social media, search engines, advertising, military use, and legal systems. At first sight results are often promising, but more and more &amp;quot;outliers&amp;quot; are becoming visible as well. Systemic bias in culture, language, or business practices often become intensified: From the Tay-chatbot turning racist, to both Google and Flickr classifying images of African-Americans as &amp;quot;monkeys&amp;quot;, to discrimination and sexism encoded in language models used for everything from translation, to court sentencing decision. Luckily, initiatives that address some of these concerns is happening through more interpretable models, new privacy regulations, novel privacy-preserving learning algorithms, and researchers and engineers standing up for more just and transparent machine learning models and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel aims to debate these themes with speakers, and the audience, and go beyond the usual &amp;quot;AI hype&amp;quot; and discuss both the amazing progress, as well as the setbacks, in making societies better, more humane, and ready for the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the panel will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roelof Pieters, Panel Host, Co-founder at creative.ai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marek Rosa, CEO/CTO at GoodAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Françoise Provencher, Data Team Lead at Shopify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hendrik Heuer, Researcher at Institute for Information Management (ifib) at the University of Bremen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andreas Dewes, Founder at 7scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katharine Jarmul, Founder at kjamistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to Q&amp;amp;A: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw"&gt;https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw&lt;/a&gt; (Second pyvideo tab)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="panel"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Creativity and AI: Deep Neural Nets "Going Wild"</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2017/creativity-and-ai-deep-neural-nets-going-wild.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pydata-amsterdam-2017/creativity-and-ai-deep-neural-nets-going-wild.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in times, where science fiction authors are struggling to keep up with reality. This talk will make sense of the explosion of research and experiments that deal with creativity and A.I. and take you through the wonderful trippy world of neural nets &amp;quot;going wild&amp;quot; and show some of the exciting possibilities new technologies offer for making us all more creative, more of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in times, where science fiction authors are struggling to keep up with reality. This talk will make sense of the explosion of research and experiments that deal with creativity and A.I. and take you through the wonderful trippy world of neural nets &amp;quot;going wild&amp;quot; with their dancing moves, freestyle raps, impressionist paintings. and show some of the exciting possibilities new technologies offer for creative use and explorations of human-machine interaction, where the main theorem is &amp;quot;augmentation, not automation&amp;quot;. The talk will particularly focus on &amp;quot;generative&amp;quot; models, and show the python fanatic how to make your move with these particular forms of Deep Neural Nets, to then finish with an &amp;quot;experiment&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Deep Learning and Deep Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2015/deep-learning-and-deep-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-25:pycon-se-2015/deep-learning-and-deep-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning, anyone who has followed machine learning over the past
years has heard it. In this talk I will go past the hype and show what
deep learning actually means and how one goes about solving complex
machine learning task with a minimum amount of code, with the help of
theano, an amazing python library for deep learning. I will show
examples from my own research in language and vision, and hope to show
that Deep Learning is not only fun, but also not as difficult as one
might expect.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>