<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Paul Ebreo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_paul-ebreo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-06-13T18:30:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python: The Language for Understanding and Building the Future of AI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/chipy/Python_The_Language_for_Understanding_and_Building_the_Future_of_AI.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-06-13T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-13T18:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Ebreo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-06-13:/chipy/Python_The_Language_for_Understanding_and_Building_the_Future_of_AI.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk explores a new framework for building Artificial Intelligence (AI) inspired by the human brain and leveraging the power of Python. We'll delve into the concept of consciousness as a combination of memory, prediction, and experience. By using hierarchical probabilities, similar to Google's PageRank algorithm, we can build …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk explores a new framework for building Artificial Intelligence (AI) inspired by the human brain and leveraging the power of Python. We'll delve into the concept of consciousness as a combination of memory, prediction, and experience. By using hierarchical probabilities, similar to Google's PageRank algorithm, we can build AI systems that are not only powerful but also understandable and aligned with human values. Python will be our toolset as we explore the exciting future of AI development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="ChiPy"></category></entry><entry><title>How Open Source Hardware Will Change the World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/chipy/how-open-source-hardware-will-change-the-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Ebreo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-11-14:/chipy/how-open-source-hardware-will-change-the-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if there was an open source project that changed how we produce the
most fundamental apsects of our lives? From the food we eat, to the
houses we live in, this project wants to open source the tools we use to
obtain what we need to live. Come …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if there was an open source project that changed how we produce the
most fundamental apsects of our lives? From the food we eat, to the
houses we live in, this project wants to open source the tools we use to
obtain what we need to live. Come to the ChiPy meeting to find out the
name of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="ChiPy"></category></entry></feed>