<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_akos-hochrein.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Asyncio in the Wild</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2019/asyncio-in-the-wild.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Akos Hochrein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-31:pycon-se-2019/asyncio-in-the-wild.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asyncio is a fairly new tool and no often used in production. In this talk we will be aiming for use-cases and examples so people can get more confidence moving away from the synchronous world. The talk aims to solve the problem of uncertainty when getting started with asynchronous programming in Python. After the talk the audience will be equipped with new tools they can look up at home to get started with asynchronous web development in Python, also, hopefully, they will have some extra confidence in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="async"></category><category term="asyncio"></category></entry><entry><title>An ODe to OAuth</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/an-ode-to-oauth.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Akos Hochrein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-25:djangocon-europe-2018/an-ode-to-oauth.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all know that remembering passwords is hard, so why not leave it to someone else? In this talk, I would like to introduce how we improved our social authentication system in our Django applications at Prezi with the aid of the Python Social Auth package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a long time coming, we at Prezi introduced social authentication using Google mid last year. This seemingly trivial problem soon became a nightmare after we realized that our custom built session management systems completely misalign with the standards of the industry and open source. However, our team did not give up the dream of having a fully scalable and easy-to-maintain component that we can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I would like to present you the war story of how we revamped the social authentication systems at Prezi (whilst becoming open source contributors) using the Python Social Auth package, enabling a significant amount of users to access our services on all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akos Hochrein&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Messenger chat with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/messenger-chat-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Akos Hochrein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/messenger-chat-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatbots are getting more and more in mainstream product development. In this talk, I would like to show you how to setup a one on the Facebook Messenger platform using Python and Heroku, so you can get started right away!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="chatbot"></category></entry></feed>