<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dr-anthony-scopatz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Keynote: Data Science Community and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/keynote-data-science-community-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Anthony Scopatz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-16:pydata-carolinas-2016/keynote-data-science-community-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Big Data is a prominent, rapidly emerging discipline with far-reaching
scientific and economic potential, yet there remains a gap in the
translation of Big Data research findings into economic growth and
end-user impact. To exploit the full potential of Big Data, the Big
Data Innovation Hubs endeavor to foster innovation through
collaboration, diversity, education, and workforce development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recognition of the substantial and growing impact of big data to
the U.S., across sectors, in 2012 the White House launched a multi-
agency research initiative to foster and coordinate big data
innovation across the US. Under this initiative, the National
Foundation launched four Big Data Regional Innovation Hubs, new
organizations intended to develop the Big Data innovation ecosystem
and facilitate thematic communities’ use of data sciences for societal
benefit. Specifically, the Big Data Regional Innovation Hubs
accelerate partnerships among people in business, academia, and
government who apply data science and analytics to help solve regional
and national challenges. The Big Data Hubs cover all 50 states and
currently include several hundred universities, corporations, federal
agencies, and non-governmental organizations. Dr. Shanley will
introduce the Big Data Hubs and report on some of the significant
activities of the South Big Data Innovation Hub. Finally, she will
discuss opportunities to engage with the Big Data Hubs and our growing
networks of Public/Private partnerships. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://southbigdatahub.org"&gt;http://southbigdatahub.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>