<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_julia-rohrer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Keynote: How to Fix a Scientific Culture: Psychology as a Cautionary Tale and Paragon</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2017/keynote-how-to-fix-a-scientific-culture-psychology-as-a-cautionary-tale-and-paragon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Julia Rohrer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-31:euroscipy-2017/keynote-how-to-fix-a-scientific-culture-psychology-as-a-cautionary-tale-and-paragon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last six years, small- and large-scale replication efforts have
raised the suspicion that a large number of psychological
findings—including some of our dearest effects—are flimsy at best.
“Standard Operating Procedures” of the field have been shown to result
in false-positive rates close to 100%; articles are filled with
reporting errors and impossible statistics; transparency of the
scientific process is often abysmal. These shortcomings have resulted in
an unprecedented level of scientific introspection, giving rise to the
development of new meta-scientific methods, new modes of scientific
publishing, and a strong push towards Open Science, which will be
covered in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="biographical-sketch"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Biographical sketch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julia Rohrer is a personality psychologist and pursues her PhD at the
International Max Planck Research School on the Life Course, the German
Institute for Economic Research, the Free University of Berlin, and the
University of Leipzig. She is an outspoken advocate for Open Science and
the current movement towards greater methodological rigor in psychology.
She is one of the authors of the meta-scientific blog “The 100% CI.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry></feed>