<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jiaqi-liu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building a Data Pipeline with Testing in Mind</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/building-a-data-pipeline-with-testing-in-mind.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jiaqi Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/building-a-data-pipeline-with-testing-in-mind.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s one thing to build a robust data pipeline process in python but a whole other challenge to find tooling and build out the framework that allows for testing a data process. In order to truly iterate and develop a codebase, one has to be able to confidently test during the development process and monitor the production system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I hope to address the key components for building out end to end testing for data pipelines by borrowing concepts from how we test python web services. Just like how we want to check for healthy status codes from our API responses, we want to be able to check that a pipeline is working as expected given the correct inputs. We’ll talk about key features that allows a data pipeline to be easily testable and how to identify timeseries metrics that can be used to monitor the health of a data pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Fuzzy Search Algorithms: How and When to Use Them</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/fuzzy-search-algorithms-how-and-when-to-use-them.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jiaqi Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pycon-us-2017/fuzzy-search-algorithms-how-and-when-to-use-them.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuzzy Searching or approximate string matching is powerful because often
text data is messy. For example, shorthand and abbreviated text are
common in various data sets. In addition, outputs from OCR or voice to
text conversions tend to be messy or imperfect. Thus, we want to be able
to make the most of our data by extrapolating as much information as
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the various approaches used in fuzzy
string matching and demonstrate how they can be used as a feature in a
model or a component in your python code. We will dive deep into the
approaches of different algorithms such as Soundex, Trigram/n-gram
search, and Levenshtein distances and what the best use cases are. We
will also discuss situations where it’s important to take into account
the meaning or intent of a word and demonstrate approaches for measuring
semantic similarity using nltk and word2vec. Furthermore, we will
demonstrate via live coding how to implement some of these fuzzy search
algorithms using python and/or built-in fuzzy search functions within
PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Fuzzy Search Algorithms How and When to Use Them</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/fuzzy-search-algorithms-how-and-when-to-use-them.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jiaqi Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/fuzzy-search-algorithms-how-and-when-to-use-them.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of data science is about understanding the context around your data. In this talk, we hope to address how to work with messy text data by leveraging fuzzy search algorithms in python or against a database such as PostgreSQL. We will talk specifically about fuzzy algorithms such as Soundex, Trigram/n-gram search, and Levenshtein distances and demonstrate use cases in an ipython notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="search"></category></entry></feed>