<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Turning Spatial Data into Arrays: Python Coming Handy for GIS People!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/turning-spatial-data-into-arrays-python-coming-handy-for-gis-people.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GIS software is used to analyze spatial data. In some cases, GIS data can be voluminous and Python can come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a case will be described here. I was trying to visualize superpositions between rectangular extents (a lot of rectangular extents !) and found QGIS and PostGIS too slow for the job (although I must say I'm no PostGIS guru). I then used Python to convert my extents into arrays of 0 and 1 and could add them all in a few minutes, and visualize superpositions by turning the resulting array into an asc file. Sorry if this is not quite clear, it's easier to explain with a few pictures, as often is the case with spatial data !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then tried to substract 2 of the resulting asc files to visualize the evolution between 2 dates, and stumbled upon a problem in Python : the files were too big to be held in memory. A developer helped me solved this problem and I undestood better how memory is used in Python and how to hold in memory only one line of a file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, this is a story about GIS people venturing into Python programming !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scripts can be found here : &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/UMR-PASSAGES/metadata-extents"&gt;https://github.com/UMR-PASSAGES/metadata-extents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julie Pierson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:pycon-fr-2019/turning-spatial-data-into-arrays-python-coming-handy-for-gis-people.html</guid></item></channel></rss>