<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jayesh Ahire</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jayesh-ahire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Fake News' Foe: Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2020/fake-news-foe-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jayesh Ahire</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-06-19:/python-web-conf-2020/fake-news-foe-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Fake News' Foe: Machine Learning&amp;quot; by: Jayesh Ahire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fake news has become a huge issue in our digitally-connected world and it is no longer limited to little squabbles – fake news spreads like wildfire and is impacting millions of people every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you deal with such a sensitive …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Fake News' Foe: Machine Learning&amp;quot; by: Jayesh Ahire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fake news has become a huge issue in our digitally-connected world and it is no longer limited to little squabbles – fake news spreads like wildfire and is impacting millions of people every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you deal with such a sensitive issue? Countless articles are being churned out every day on the internet – how do you tell real from fake? It’s not as easy as turning to a simple fact-checker which is typically built on a story-by-story basis. As developers, can we turn to machine learning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, We will try to live code an application using TensorFlow and twilio WhatsApp API to detect fake news! While going through the code we will explore various machine learning concepts and new features in TensorFlow 2.0 which simplifies our job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also touch base on how we can use Advanced pre-trained NLP models like BERT, GPT-2, XLNet, Grover etc, to achieve our goal! This will be insightful session for beginners as well as intermediate level audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2020 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2020.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2020"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Towards Reliability</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/towards-reliability.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jayesh Ahire</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/towards-reliability.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applications are evolving continuously. In modern cloud-native microservice architecture-based applications, finding out if your application is reliable or not is hard. Being able to Observe your system doesn't really mean it's reliable. In this talk, we will learn about how to make your software more reliable, touch base on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applications are evolving continuously. In modern cloud-native microservice architecture-based applications, finding out if your application is reliable or not is hard. Being able to Observe your system doesn't really mean it's reliable. In this talk, we will learn about how to make your software more reliable, touch base on the concept of SLOs, and see a demo of how we can easily collect telemetry data and ensure the reliability of a Python-based microservice application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>