<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Joshua Taillon</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_joshua-taillon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>HyperSpy - Your Multidimensional Data Analysis Toolbox</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/hyperspy-your-multidimensional-data-analysis-toolbox.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joshua Taillon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/hyperspy-your-multidimensional-data-analysis-toolbox.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HyperSpy is a community-developed open-source library providing a framework to facilitate interactive and reproducible analyses of multidimensional datasets. Born out of the electron microscopy scientific community and building on the extensive scientific Python environment, HyperSpy provides tools to efficiently explore, manipulate, and visualize complex datasets of arbitrary dimensionality, including …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HyperSpy is a community-developed open-source library providing a framework to facilitate interactive and reproducible analyses of multidimensional datasets. Born out of the electron microscopy scientific community and building on the extensive scientific Python environment, HyperSpy provides tools to efficiently explore, manipulate, and visualize complex datasets of arbitrary dimensionality, including those larger than a system's memory. After 14 years of development, HyperSpy recently celebrated its 2.0 version release. This presentation will (re)introduce HyperSpy's features and community, with a focus on recent efforts paring the library into a domain-agnostic core and a robust ecosystem of extensions providing specific scientific functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>