<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pymove 3D</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/pymove-3d.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/pymove-3d.html</guid></item><item><title>MSS - Software for planning research aircraft missions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/mss-software-for-planning-research-aircraft-missions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.geosci-model-dev.net/5/55/2012/"&gt;http://www.geosci-model-dev.net/5/55/2012/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific aircraft research flights have to be planned beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that it is necessary to have model forecasts of relevant
quantities such as meteorological parameters, chemical composition or
particle information to guide the aircraft to the location of
interest. Typically, many scientific instruments on board those
aircrafts used to investigate e.g. the chemical composition of the
air in order to get new insights often with the involvement of
different science groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For discussion of the possibilites of the research flights, the
Mission Support System (MSS) was developed (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mss.rtfd.io"&gt;http://mss.rtfd.io&lt;/a&gt;). This
software helps to review a big amount of metereological and model
data by viewing the forecasted parameters of interest along possible
regions of a proposed flight path. Data and possible flight paths can
be displayed on a hoizontal view (map projection) or on a vertical
view (along the proposed flight path). Flight paths can be
constructed and modified on these views. Exchange through a waypoint
table is also possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk gives a brief insight into the MSS software development
current state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using the OWS interface standard.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://geopython.github.io/OWSLib/"&gt;https://geopython.github.io/OWSLib/&lt;/a&gt; MSS is a client/server
application. The QT client interacts with a paste wsgi server. The
software is available for all platforms on conda-forge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/mss-software-for-planning-research-aircraft-missions.html</guid></item><item><title>MSS - Software for planning research aircraft missions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/fosdem-2017/mss-software-for-planning-research-aircraft-missions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific aircraft research flights have to be planned beforehand. For that it is necessary to have model forecasts of relevant quantities such as meteorological parameters, chemical composition or particle information to guide the aircraft to the location of interest.We develop the MSS Project to make decissions easier where to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-05:fosdem-2017/mss-software-for-planning-research-aircraft-missions.html</guid></item><item><title>MSS - Software for planning research aircraft missions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2016/mss-software-for-planning-research-aircraft-missions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific aircraft research flights have to be planned beforehand. For that it is necessary to have model forecasts of relevant quantities suchas meteorological parameters, chemical composition or particle information to guide the aircraft to the location of interest. Typically, many scientific instruments on board those aircrafts used to investigate e.g. the chemical composition of the air in order to get new insights often with the involvement of different science groups.For discussion of the possibilites of the research flights, the Mission Support System (MSS) was developed. This software helps to review a bigamount of metereological and model data by viewing the forecasted parameters of interest along possible regions of a proposed flight path. Data and possible flight paths can be displayed on a horizontal view (map projection) or on a vertical view (along the proposed flight path). Flight paths can be constructed and modified on these views. I/O through a waypoint table is also possible.The talk gives a brief insight into the MSS software development.We are using the OWS interface standard.https://geopython.github.io/OWSLib/MSS is a client/server application. The QT client interacts with a paste wsgi server. The software is available for all platforms on conda-forge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-30:pycon-de-2016/mss-software-for-planning-research-aircraft-missions.html</guid></item><item><title>pymove3D - Python moves the world - Attractive programming for young people</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/pymove3d-python-moves-the-world-attractive-pr.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second time a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pymove3d.pysv.org/"&gt;contest&lt;/a&gt; for schoolar
students is organized by the Python Software Verband e.V.. It is about
to write a Python program that is executable in Blender using its 3D
capabilities. The talk overall gives an overview what experience we got
by these ideas and how we want to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/pymove3d-python-moves-the-world-attractive-pr.html</guid></item><item><title>pymove3D Winner Announcement</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/pymove3d-winner-announcement.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The winner of the pymove3D competition is announced. The pymove3D
competition ran until May 1st, 2014. The goal was to write a Python
program that uses the 3D capabilities of Blender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mika Greif, a 13 year old school student gets the first price at the
pymove3D contest 2014 by his application Eiszapfenhöhle (icicle cave).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mika Greif</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-21:europython-2014/pymove3d-winner-announcement.html</guid></item><item><title>Anwendung von Wiki zur Unterstützung kooperativer Forschungsarbeiten</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2011/anwendung-von-wiki-zur-unterstutzung-kooperativer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag behandelt einige praktische Elemente zur Unterstützung
kollaborativer python Umgebungen und konzentriert sich hauptsächlich auf
die Wiki Software MoinMoin und deren Verwendung im wissenschaftlichem
Umfeld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[AUDIO : house sound flipped out and was turned off at 7:30, camera mic
was the only functioning mic in the room.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-07:pycon-de-2011/anwendung-von-wiki-zur-unterstutzung-kooperativer.html</guid></item><item><title>moin-2, wie man eine wiki software eigentlich schreiben sollte.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2011/moin-2-wie-man-eine-wiki-software-eigentlich-sch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stand der Entwicklung von moin-2.0 und Unterschiede zu moin-1.x.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-10-06:pycon-de-2011/moin-2-wie-man-eine-wiki-software-eigentlich-sch.html</guid></item><item><title>Flugplanung, Datenverwaltung, Visualisierung mit einem Wiki zur Unterstützung von Meßkampagnen</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/flugplanung-datenverwaltung-visualisierung-mit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag zeigt auf, wie man ein MoinMoin Wiki verwenden kann, um
meteorologische Daten für Flugplanungen mit einem Forschungsflugzeug
bereitzustellen. Die Werkzeuge, die bei einer Messkampagne eine
Plattform für den Austausch von Daten sowie Beschreibungen bilden,
werden vorgestellt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im Vortrag werden einige Werkzeuge und deren API vorgestellt. Z.B.
arnica, ein MoinMoin Wiki Plugin, das u.a. für die Darstellung von
Vorhersage Modell Daten für die Flugplanung von Forschungsmissionen
Verwendung findet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andere Werkzeuge dienen dem Organisieren von Informationen auf Wiki
Seiten und deren Darstellung. Es wird z.B. gezeigt wie Seiteninhalte in
Tabellen abgebildet werden können.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Beispiele können auch für die Entwicklung eigener Plugins
herangezogen werden.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-11-01:pycon-de-2012/flugplanung-datenverwaltung-visualisierung-mit.html</guid><category>moinmoin</category><category>plugin</category><category>python</category><category>wiki</category><category>wissenschaft</category></item><item><title>Die Infrastruktur für Erweiterungen der Wiki-Software MoinMoin (moin2).</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/die-infrastruktur-fur-erweiterungen-der-wiki-soft.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Wiki Software moin2 kann mehr als nur ein Wiki betreiben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.a. kann man moin2 für einen Pastebin, Blog und ein Ticket-System
verwenden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortrag gibt Einblick in Erweiterungen und den Stand der
Entwicklung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;moin2 ist ein Redesign der Wiki-Software von moin1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es hat viele Merkmale mit einigen anderen Webanwendungen gemeinsam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durch die offene Architektur und die vorhandenen Sicherheitsmechanismen
gegen Spam ist es z.B. möglich einen pastebin analog zu lodgeit zu
integrieren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog Posts unterscheiden sich auch nicht wesentlich von Wiki Items. Mit
einem Ticket-System lassen sich Arbeitsabläufe optimieren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortrag zeigt, wie in moin2 solche Erweiterungen integriert werden
und zeigt den Stand der aktuellen Entwicklung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Für Eigenentwicklungen wird ein Einblick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;auf das neue Plugin Konzept gegeben.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-31:pycon-de-2012/die-infrastruktur-fur-erweiterungen-der-wiki-soft.html</guid><category>moinmoin</category><category>plugins</category><category>python</category><category>wiki</category></item><item><title>Wiki-Restauration aus dem Web Cache</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/wiki-restauration-aus-dem-web-cache.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nach einem Totalschaden ist bei Webanwendungen nicht unbedingt alles
verloren. Die Inhalte sind in der Regel auf eine begrenzte Zeit in
Suchmaschinen wieder zu finden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortrag beschreibt ein Verfahren das Anfang des Jahres zum Einsatz
kam um Wiki-Seiten aus dem HTML Webcache zurück in Wiki-Seiten Markup zu
übersetzen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-16:pycon-de-2013/wiki-restauration-aus-dem-web-cache.html</guid><category>adapter pattern</category><category>html</category><category>markup</category><category>moinmoin</category><category>python</category></item><item><title>Python Einsteiger-Programmierwettbewerb</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/python-einsteiger-programmierwettbewerb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Im Planungsprozess der diesjährigen PyCon DE ist ein
Programmierwettbewerb für SchülerInnen im Alter von 13 bis zum
vollendetetem 21 Lebensjahr enthalten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Techniken, die zur Vorbereitung eingesetzt wurden, sowie die Medien
und die Python Software des Portals pymove3d.pysv.org werden
dargestellt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das Ergebnis des Wettbewerbs und der Ausblick auf 2014 mit der
Zielvorgabe diesen Wettbewerb zur Europython fortzusetzen bedarf großer
Aufmerksamkeit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reimar Bauer</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-15:pycon-de-2013/python-einsteiger-programmierwettbewerb.html</guid><category>einsteiger</category><category>pymove3d</category><category>wettbewerb</category></item></channel></rss>