<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python on the blockchain: Triumphs and tribulations in a crypto startup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/python-on-the-blockchain-triumphs-and-tribulations-in-a-crypto-startup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many cryptographic components of blockchain protocols can be
extremely complex, blockchain systems themselves are relatively easy to
understand when viewed from a distance. To take the example of Bitcoin,
users store digital currency in hardware or software wallets, and use
private keys to sign and broadcast transactions. Broadcasted
transactions are grouped together into a block through a cryptographic
process known as mining, with miners rewarded through the collection of
transaction fees and the issuance of new coins. The mined block of
transactions is appended to the existing chain, and verified by a global
network of nodes. This process repeats in perpetuity, with each newly
added block adding to the trustedness and security of data stored on the
chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased interest in and demand for cryptocurrencies has brought about
a need for places where digital assets can easily be bought, sold or
traded. Our platform, Bitpanda, accomplishes this with a backend written
in Python, and relying heavily on Django and MySQL databases. In our
presentation, we begin by providing a brief overview of how blockchains
work. Following this, we describe the Python architecture that (e.g.)
generates cryptocurrency wallets, builds, signs and sends transactions,
and monitors blockchains for new, relevant data. Key challenges,
solutions and failures encountered during the development of the system,
and growth of our team, are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout our talk, we also highlight a number of broader social
implications of blockchains, and our work with them. More specifically,
we describe the need for open-innovation based approaches to blockchain
development, the value of open-source within the blockchain community,
and the current lack of critical discourse surrounding the potential
uses of blockchains as mechanisms of surveillance and control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Danny McDonald</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/python-on-the-blockchain-triumphs-and-tribulations-in-a-crypto-startup.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Community</category><category>Django</category><category>Infrastructure</category><category>Python</category></item></channel></rss>