<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Joe Roberts</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_joe-roberts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love Public Packages</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-public-packages.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joe Roberts</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-public-packages.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The popularity of R and Python for data science is in no small part attributable to the vast collection of extension packages available for everything from common tasks like data cleaning to highly-specialized domain-specific functions. However, with that ease of sharing packages comes a larger target for bad actors …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The popularity of R and Python for data science is in no small part attributable to the vast collection of extension packages available for everything from common tasks like data cleaning to highly-specialized domain-specific functions. However, with that ease of sharing packages comes a larger target for bad actors trying to exploit them. We'll explore these security risks along with approaches you can take to mitigate them using Posit Package Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Saving time (and pain) with Posit Public Package Manager</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/saving-time-and-pain-with-posit-public-package-manager.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joe Roberts</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/saving-time-and-pain-with-posit-public-package-manager.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CRAN, Bioconductor, and PyPI are incredible resources for packages that make performing data science in R and Python better. But there’s also a better way to obtain those packages! Companies like Databricks are leveraging Posit Public Package Manager to make their users’ package installation faster and more reproducible …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CRAN, Bioconductor, and PyPI are incredible resources for packages that make performing data science in R and Python better. But there’s also a better way to obtain those packages! Companies like Databricks are leveraging Posit Public Package Manager to make their users’ package installation faster and more reproducible. Learn why, and how anyone – anywhere – can easily get started using Public Package Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>