<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rodrigo-agundez.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hands-on introduction to Deep Learning with Keras and Tensorflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/hands-on-introduction-to-deep-learning-with-keras-and-tensorflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Agundez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/hands-on-introduction-to-deep-learning-with-keras-and-tensorflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning has already conquered areas such as image recognition, NLP, voice recognition, and is a must-know tool for every Data Practitioner. This tutorial for aspiring Deep Learners will consist of a quick blunt Deep Learning overview followed by a hands-on tutorial that will teach you how to get started using Keras and Tesorflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="keras"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a live face recognition system in the blink of a very slow eye</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/building-a-live-face-recognition-system-in-the-blink-of-a-very-slow-eye.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Agundez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/building-a-live-face-recognition-system-in-the-blink-of-a-very-slow-eye.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we will create a face recognition application from scratch, it will provide you hands-on experience on the basics of Face Recognition. We will use the OpenCV library which makes the tutorial accessible to beginners. Together, we'll go from building our face dataset to recognizing faces in a live video. If time permits we will use this face recognition system to classify banking da&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a live face recognition system in the blink of a very slow eye&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this hands-on tutorial we will build a live face recognition system from scratch with the use of the OpenCV methods. Since face recognition is the main goal of this tutorial we will form teams of 2-3 people and recognize the faces in a live feed. We will make use of the OpenCV computer vision and machine learning library. OpenCV includes a comprehensive set of both classic and state-of-the-art computer vision and machine learning algorithms&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="opencv"></category></entry></feed>