<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Salar Rahmanian</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_salar-rahmanian.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-08T15:45:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning Talks Day 3 Round 1</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/lightning-talks-day-3-round-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katy Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:/pybay-2018/lightning-talks-day-3-round-1.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyBay 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>Elevating Python Development with Nix Package Manager</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2023/Elevating_Python_Development_with_Nix_Package_Manager.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-08T15:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-08T15:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Salar Rahmanian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-08:/pybay-2023/Elevating_Python_Development_with_Nix_Package_Manager.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of Python development, managing dependencies and ensuring reproducibility remain pivotal challenges. Enter the Nix Package Manager – a powerful tool that transcends conventional package management approaches. Join us in this talk as we embark on a journey through the intricacies of Nix and its profound impact …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of Python development, managing dependencies and ensuring reproducibility remain pivotal challenges. Enter the Nix Package Manager – a powerful tool that transcends conventional package management approaches. Join us in this talk as we embark on a journey through the intricacies of Nix and its profound impact on Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dive into the heart of Nix as we demystify its functionality and reveal its potential to transform your Python development workflow. Uncover how Nix transcends the limitations of traditional package managers by providing declarative configuration, fine-grained control over dependencies, and unmatched reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our discussion delves deep into Nix's utility for Python projects, demonstrating how it streamlines package management and safeguards your projects against the pitfalls of dependency chaos. Witness how Nix ensures consistent environments across development, testing, and deployment, fostering collaboration and expediting development cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing upon a decade of Python expertise, our speaker brings firsthand insights into how Nix can enhance the Python ecosystem. From managing intricate dependency graphs to crafting resilient virtual environments, Nix empowers you to focus on code rather than package wrangling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this talk, we will showcase practical examples and real-world scenarios, illuminating how Nix orchestrates Python projects with elegance and precision. Whether you're a seasoned Pythonista or a curious newcomer, this talk equips you with the knowledge to integrate Nix into your workflow, revolutionizing the way you approach Python development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2023"></category></entry></feed>