<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_r-dopieralski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hands on with Pygame</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/hands-on-with-pygame.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>R Dopieralski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-04:europython-2012/hands-on-with-pygame.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] R Dopieralski - 3 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Pizza Napoli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyGame continues to be Python’s most popular 2D game library, even
though there is growing competition from more modern OpenGL-based
libraries. It is still an excellent way to learn how our favorite games
work internally and to write similar games ourselves. During this
tutorial I want to introduce the basics of using PyGame to create
interactive, animated graphical applications (such as games), and then
help the participants make their own start at a simple adventure game,
which they can later develop further into projects of their own. I want
to concentrate on commonly used techniques and patterns in game
development, which are useful no matter what library is used in the
implementation. In particular I will be discussing animations,
tile-based maps, collision detection, event systems, internal
representation of game state and different approaches to code
organisation and internal structure of games. I have previously created
a (much simpler) tutorial for creating a turn-based tile-based PyGame
game and a couple of games, such as Z-Day and Jelly . I will be using
the materials and experiences from those projects in the tutorial.
Please bring your laptop with Python 2.7 and PyGame installed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>