<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jacqueline-kazil.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Keynote: User-centered software projects</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2016/keynote-user-centered-software-projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacqueline Kazil</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-28:pycon-cz-2016/keynote-user-centered-software-projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open-sourced and inner-sourced projects often struggle to get
engagement. Communities, such as Github and PyPi, are host to
redundant projects and libraries. In the development space, how do
you distinguish your project from others, get people excited to
contribute to it, and ultimately create a successful open source
project? The answer is to apply user-centered design techniques to
the development of your project. User-centered design is usually
applied to web applications and products on the front-end of a
website, but these techniques can be applied to open source
libraries. In user-centered open source projects, your users are
those who type &lt;cite&gt;pip install $your_library&lt;/cite&gt;. In this talk, Jackie will
illustrate some user-centered techniques that have been used on her
own project - Mesa (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/projectmesa/mesa"&gt;https://github.com/projectmesa/mesa&lt;/a&gt;), along with
other successful open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python for data lovers: explore it, analyze it, map it</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/python-for-data-lovers-explore-it-analyze-it-m.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dana Bauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-10:pycon-us-2012/python-for-data-lovers-explore-it-analyze-it-m.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploring and analyzing data can be daunting and time-consuming, even
for data lovers. Python can make the process fun and exciting. We will
present techniques of data analysis, along with python tools that help
you explore and map data. Our talk includes examples that show how
python libraries such as csvkit, matplotlib, scipy, networkx and pysal
can help you dig into and make sense of your data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Who are we? A sociological analysis of the indigenous Python tribe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/who-are-we-a-sociological-analysis-of-the-indige.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacqueline Kazil</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-16:pycon-us-2013/who-are-we-a-sociological-analysis-of-the-indige.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you look at a history of programming languages, over time languages
combine or diverge to form new languages. Here we are, the people of
Python, but who are we? Will we survive? Will we evolve from a tribe to
state? What is important to us as a people? This talk will aim at
providing insight by looking at data in Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Analyzing Social Networks with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/analyzing-social-networks-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Kouznetsov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-13:pycon-us-2013/analyzing-social-networks-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social Network data is not just Twitter and Facebook - networks permeate
our world - yet we often don't know what to do with them. In this
tutorial, we will introduce both theory and practice of Social Network
Analysis - gathering, analyzing and visualizing data using Python,
NetworkX and PiCloud. We will walk the attendees through an entire
project, from gathering data to presenting results.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry></feed>