<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_emily-bache.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Development culture &amp; helping the business to win</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/development-culture-helping-the-business-to-win.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emily Bache</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/development-culture-helping-the-business-to-win.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emily Bache is a consultant with nearly 20 years of experience working as a software developer and test automation architect in organizations as diverse as multinational corporations to small startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily is the author of “The Coding Dojo Handbook: a practical guide to creating a space where good programmers can become great programmers” and loves to coach and teach about Test Driven Development, designing Test Cases, Refactoring, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily has spoken at events such as Agile Testing Days, XP2013, ACCU, Europython and EuroSTAR before and we are thrilled to welcome her as a keynote speaker at PyCon Sweden 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Will I still be able to get a job in 2024 if I don't do TDD</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/will-i-still-be-able-to-get-a-job-in-2024-if-i-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emily Bache</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/will-i-still-be-able-to-get-a-job-in-2024-if-i-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Moores's book &amp;quot;Crossing the chasm&amp;quot; outlines the difficulties
faced by a new, disruptive technology, when adoption moves from
innovators and visionaries into the mainstream. Test Driven Development
is clearly a disruptive technology, that changes the way you approach
software design and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TDD hasn't yet been embraced by everyone, but is it just a matter of
time? Ten years from now, will a non-TDD practicing developer experience
the horror of being labelled a technology adoption 'laggard', and be
left working exclusively on dreadfully boring legacy systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be a smart move to get down to your nearest Coding Dojo and
practice TDD on some Code Katas. On the other hand, the thing with
disruptive technologies is that even they can become disrupted when
something better comes along. What about Property-Based Testing?
Approval Testing? Outside-In Development?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'd like to look at the chasm-crossing potential of TDD
and some related technologies. My aim is that both you and I will still
be able to get a good job in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>