<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Design Patterns in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/montreal-python/design-patterns-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean-Philippe Caissy and Rory Geoghegan present &amp;quot;Design Patterns in Python&amp;quot;
Source: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://montrealpython.org/2013/06/mp38/"&gt;http://montrealpython.org/2013/06/mp38/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jean-Philippe Caissy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-06-10:montreal-python/design-patterns-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>From idea to production in 20 minutes: engineering at scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/from-idea-to-production-in-20-minutes-engineering-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shopify strives to be an ever moving company. With a strong force of
hundreds in the R&amp;amp;D team, the challenges to keep delivering and shipping
scaled accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a manual CLI that only ops could execute just a few years back, to
today’s automatic 180+ deploys a day, this talk will highlight the
different tools, processes and integrations used throughout the team
that fuels today's scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="jean-philippe-caissy-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jean-Philippe Caissy Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean-Philippe is a senior software developer at Shopify, working in
their Montreal's office. For the past 4 years, he helped organized the
local Montréal-Python user group. A seasoned Python and Ruby developer,
he likes to talk about scaling problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jean-Philippe Caissy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/from-idea-to-production-in-20-minutes-engineering-at-scale.html</guid></item><item><title>Static type-checking is dead, long live static type-checking in Python!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/static-type-checking-is-dead-long-live-static-type-checking-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean-Philippe Caissy - Static type-checking is dead, long live static type-checking in Python!
[EuroPython 2015]
[24 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, Guido unfolded PEP 484, which was highlighted at
PyCon 2015 as a keynote presentation. This proposal would introduce
type hints for Python 3.5. While the debate is still roaring and
without taking a side, I believe that there is much to learn from
static type-checking systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to introduce ways that could be used to
fully take over the amazing power that comes with static types, inside
a dynamic type language such as Python. The talk will go over what
exactly a static type system is, and what kind of problem it tries to
solve. We will also review Guido's proposal of type hinting, and what
it could mean to you. Finally, I will present a few libraries that are
available, such as Hypothesis  or various QuickCheck-inspired library
that tries to build more robust tests, how they achieve it and their
limitations. Throughout the talk, a lot of examples will used to fully
illustrate the ideas being explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk, you should have a better understanding of the
wonderful world of type systems, and what it really means to you. It
should help you decide wether using type hints will be helpful to you
and also if an external library trying to fuzz your tests has its
place inside your project&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jean-Philippe Caissy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:europython-2015/static-type-checking-is-dead-long-live-static-type-checking-in-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>