<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sophia Vargas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sophia-vargas.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How can we protect vulnerable groups</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/how-can-we-protect-vulnerable-groups.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sophia Vargas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/how-can-we-protect-vulnerable-groups.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity, equity and inclusion initiatives often start with measurement - what do our communities look like today and how can we track progress against our goals? However, data collected through APIs, web scraping, surveys, interviews, inference etc. have the potential to expose more details about an individual than they were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity, equity and inclusion initiatives often start with measurement - what do our communities look like today and how can we track progress against our goals? However, data collected through APIs, web scraping, surveys, interviews, inference etc. have the potential to expose more details about an individual than they were expecting, especially when aggregated across platforms and shared in public forums. This talk will discuss tactics, opportunities and challenges when collecting sensitive data in and around open source communities, while aligning with policies and regulations, respecting the right to anonymity and ensuring the safety of all members of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry></feed>