<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tyler-hobbs.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Cassandra for Python Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2011/cassandra-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tyler Hobbs</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-10:pytexas-2011/cassandra-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apache Cassandra is an open source, distributed (NoSQL) database. This
will give a high level introduction to Cassandra and its data model; it
will detail the features of pycassa, the Python client library for
Cassandra, and how to interact with Cassandra through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being non-relational, Cassandra's data model is fundamentally different
from that of a relational database. In addition, it uses an RPC based
API rather than a query language. On top of that, Cassandra is a
distributed database, so the client must be aware of and interact with
multiple nodes in the cluster. All of these attributes of Cassandra make
the client libraries a different experience. Fortunately, the Python
client library is the easiest way to use Cassandra. This talk will start
with a high level overview of the clustering model of Cassandra then its
data model. A large portion of the talk will cover the pycassa methods
that interact with the data model of Cassandra, i.e. inserting,
fetching, and removing data. A small amount of time will be dedicated to
describing connection pooling in pycassa -- how it handles node
failures, distributes requests, etc. The final 10 minutes will be
devoted to Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="fetching"></category></entry></feed>