<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Guide to choose right deep Learning framework for your AI project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2018/guide-to-choose-right-deep-learning-framework-for-your-ai-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As world rolling around Artificial Intelligence (AI), demand for the
AI-based product seen exponential growth, so the AI research. Deep
learning algorithms and techniques are widely used for research and
development of these products. Good news is that year by year Deep
Learning has seen its glory in the release of many open source
frameworks which ease the pain to develop and implement these
algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As there are many deep learning frameworks out there and it can lead to
confusion as to which one is better for your task. And choosing a deep
learning framework for an AI project is as important as choosing a
programming language to code product, Data science project coupled with
the right deep learning framework has truly amplified the overall
productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will discuss the common points which help developers to
understand which framework will be the perfect fit for solving given
business challenges. Also, we will look into some of the most widely
used frameworks and comparing with standard benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Following deep learning/machine learning frameworks will be discussed:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Tensorflow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;PyTorch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Chainer&lt;/strong&gt; and/or &lt;strong&gt;MXNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Highlight of this talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define key points to judge any deep learning framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hardware dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anatomy of widely used open source frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comparison of above-mentioned frameworks as per defined key points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is the audience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who inspired to code deep learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience Level&lt;/strong&gt; : Beginner to Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rishikesh</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-12:pycon-za-2018/guide-to-choose-right-deep-learning-framework-for-your-ai-project.html</guid></item></channel></rss>