<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Cliff Kerr</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python vs. the Pandemic: A Case Study in High Stakes Software Development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/python-vs-the-pandemic-a-case-study-in-high-stakes-software-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When COVID turned the world upside down in early 2020, health officials asked academic disease modelers like us for urgent guidance. Here we describe how we built Covasim (covasim.org), an agent-based COVID model, by using standard Python libraries like NumPy, Numba, and SciPy along with less common ones like Sciris (sciris.org). Covasim was created in a few weeks, an order of magnitude faster than the typical model development process, and achieves performance comparable to C++ despite being written in pure Python. It is now used by researchers and policymakers in more than a dozen countries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cliff Kerr</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/python-vs-the-pandemic-a-case-study-in-high-stakes-software-development.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item><item><title>Starsim: A flexible framework for agent-based modeling of health and disease</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/starsim-a-flexible-framework-for-agent-based-modeling-of-health-and-disease.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agent-based models (ABMs) are powerful tools for understanding how people behave and interact. However, many ABMs are slow, cumbersome to use, or both. Here we introduce Starsim (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://starsim.org/"&gt;http://starsim.org/&lt;/a&gt;), an open-source, high-performance ABM specialized for modeling different diseases (such as HIV, STIs, and tuberculosis). Built on NumPy, Numba, and SciPy, Starsim's performance rivals ABMs implemented in Java or C++, but with the convenience provided by Python: specifically, the ability to quickly implement and refine new disease modules. Starsim can also be extended to other applications in which people interact on timescales from days to decades, including economics and social science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cliff Kerr</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/starsim-a-flexible-framework-for-agent-based-modeling-of-health-and-disease.html</guid><category>SciPy 2024</category></item></channel></rss>