<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Anthony Harrison</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Python to manage Software Bill of Materials</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/using-python-to-manage-software-bill-of-materials.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Using Python to manage Software Bill of Materials - presented by Anthony Harrison&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software has become increasingly complex as it is constructed from a multitude of software components. In many cases the identification of these components are hidden as they are included through implicit dependencies. Without fully understanding the dependencies of your product it is not possible to understand the current vulnerability status of your software product or system.
In the past 12 months, there has been an increasing focus on the use Software Bill of Materials (SBOMs) as a key artefact to be delivered with a software product; it will be mandated for all software products in some markets later in 2022. SBOMs which were initially developed to capture the inter-dependencies between components (the focus was on capturing the different types of open source licences used within a product) but with the latest evolution, tracking of vulnerabilities within a product can now be performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the SBOM concept and show how Python and its ecosystem can be used to create, manage and use SBOMs as part of your development pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anthony Harrison</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/using-python-to-manage-software-bill-of-materials.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>SBOMs are coming. How will Python help?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/sboms-are-coming-how-will-python-help.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As software is increasingly integrated with many third party components, particularly open-source components, it is essential to have a clear understanding of all of the software that is being deployed. With an increasing focus on improving the Cybersecurity of the many different parts of the supply chain, there is a growing expectation that a Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) will become a key artefact of any software component to help capture all of the software assets being used. This talk will briefly introduce the concept of SBOMs and show how a number of Python tools will help in the production, management and use of SBOMs as part of a system lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anthony Harrison</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-18:/pycascades-2023/sboms-are-coming-how-will-python-help.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2023</category></item></channel></rss>