<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jarek-potiuk.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>What's coming in Apache Airflow 2.0</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/whats-coming-in-apache-airflow-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jarek Potiuk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-12:pydata-warsaw-2019/whats-coming-in-apache-airflow-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apache Airflow is one of the most popular Data processing orchestration
engines. After a long line of 1.10.x releases in December we wil be
quickly approaching 2.0 release. The release is not backwards compatible
and it will contain many improvement and changes. This talk will outline
the most important changes coming in Apache Airflow 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarek - as an Apache Airflow PMC member and one of the more active
members of Apache Airflow community will talk about what is coming in
Apache Airflow 2.0. The Apache Airflow 2.0 is not backwards compatible
and the community puts a lot of effort into cleaning up, refactoring and
improving the code and building functionaliities that are going to make
life easier for the users of this - one of the most popular -
orchestration engine for Data and Machine Learning processing jobs. Some
of the most long-standing requests from the community, such as DAG
serialisation to database and stateles webserver are only scratching the
surface of what's coming in Airflow 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be targeted mainly for Apache Airflow users who would
like to learn what can they do with the upcoming Airflow 2.0 as well as
how to migrate to Apache 2.0 i painlessly. It will also be a unique
opportunity to provide feedback on early versions of Apache 2.0 that
will be available by then and discuss your proposals and questions with
an Apache Airflow Commiter, so there will be plenty of time for
questions - during and after the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>