<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Carson Sievert</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Towards the Next Generation of Shiny UI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/towards-the-next-generation-of-shiny-ui.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create awesome looking and feature rich Shiny dashboards using the bslib R package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiny recently celebrated its 10th birthday, and since its birth, has grown tremendously in many areas; however, a hello world Shiny app still looks roughly like it did 10 years ago. The bslib R package helps solve this problem making very easy to apply modern and customizable styling your Shiny apps, R Markdown / Quarto documents, and more. In addition, bslib also provides dashboard-focused UI components like expandable cards, value boxes, sidebar layouts, and more to help you create delightful Shiny dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rstudio.github.io/bslib/"&gt;https://rstudio.github.io/bslib/&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bslib.shinyapps.io/flights/"&gt;https://bslib.shinyapps.io/flights/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carson Sievert</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/towards-the-next-generation-of-shiny-ui.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Supercharge Your Shiny (for Python) App: Unleashing Interactive Jupyter Widgets</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/supercharge-your-shiny-for-python-app-unleashing-interactive-jupyter-widgets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most Python packages that provide interactive web-based visualizations (e.g., altair, plotly, bokeh, ipyleaflet, etc.) can render in Jupyter notebooks via the ipywidgets standard. The shinywidgets package brings that ipywidgets standard to Shiny, enabling the use of 100s of Jupyter Widgets as Shiny outputs. In this talk, you'll not only learn how to render Jupyter Widgets in Shiny to get interactive output, but also how to leverage user interaction with widgets to create delightful and bespoke experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carson Sievert</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/supercharge-your-shiny-for-python-app-unleashing-interactive-jupyter-widgets.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>