<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_charles-doutriaux.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Virtual Laboratories Vision for an Earth Sciences</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/virtual-laboratories-vision-for-an-earth-sciences.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Charles Doutriaux</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/virtual-laboratories-vision-for-an-earth-sciences.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016
Charles Doutriaux | Virtual Laboratories Vision for an Earth Sciences Collaborative And Distributed Environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth Sciences and Climate Sciences in particular have become invaluable for policy makers. With advances in technologies the amount of data available is ever increasing making in situ analysis impossible. We envision to merge the Eart System Grid Federation and Climate Data Analysis Tools projects into Virtual Laboratories offering a remote distributed environment for Earth Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of IPCC reports, Earth Sciences in general, and Climate Sciences in particular, have become an invaluable tool for policy makers. With advances in technologies, both in computation power and in storage capabilities, the amount of data available to scientists and policy makers is ever increasing. As a result, it has become nearly impossible for a scientific group (institution), to hold all the necessary data for a study at a single computer (facility). On one hand the Earth Science Grid Federation (ESGF) project solves the data distribution, on another hand the Climate Data Analysis Tools software offers advanced tools for earth science data analysis. “Virtual Laboratories” aim at combining both projects (non-exclusively) to allow scientists and policy makers to work in a remote and distributed environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>