<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Mikhail Zolotukhin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mikhail-zolotukhin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>DL Compiler Panel Discussion</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/dl-compiler-panel-discussion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Philip Tillet</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/dl-compiler-panel-discussion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DL Compiler Panel Discussion - Philip Tillet, OpenAI; Jason Ansel, Meta; Jacques Pienaar, Google; Tianqi Chen, CMU &amp;amp; OctoAI; Mikhail Zolotukhin, Modular; Peng Wu, Meta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the release of PyTorch 2 in 2023, torch.compile() has spurred significant new thinking around DL compiler designs at the framework level. In this session …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DL Compiler Panel Discussion - Philip Tillet, OpenAI; Jason Ansel, Meta; Jacques Pienaar, Google; Tianqi Chen, CMU &amp;amp; OctoAI; Mikhail Zolotukhin, Modular; Peng Wu, Meta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the release of PyTorch 2 in 2023, torch.compile() has spurred significant new thinking around DL compiler designs at the framework level. In this session, we invite leaders in this space to share their insights based on real experiences of building DL compilers – Triton, TorchInductor, Halide, TVM, OpenXLA, and Mojo – and growing their ecosystems. We also invite a ‘compiler user representative,’ together.ai, to share their recent journey of redesigning the LLM inference stack around torch.compile(). Each leader will give a 10-minute lightning talk and an engaging panel discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>[MOJO] Lifting PT to New Heights with MAX and Mojo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/mojo-lifting-pt-to-new-heights-with-max-and-mojo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mikhail Zolotukhin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/mojo-lifting-pt-to-new-heights-with-max-and-mojo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll peek into Modular's inference engine: how it builds on and works with PyTorch and what is unique about it. We will look into how Mojo language can be used to define performant kernels and what optimizations the inference engine can perform. We will also talk …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll peek into Modular's inference engine: how it builds on and works with PyTorch and what is unique about it. We will look into how Mojo language can be used to define performant kernels and what optimizations the inference engine can perform. We will also talk briefly about our experience of developing a third party backend for torch.compile.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>