<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_luca-de-alfaro.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The UCSC IoT Python Platform</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2016/the-ucsc-iot-python-platform.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca De Alfaro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-07:depy-2016/the-ucsc-iot-python-platform.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof. Luca de Alfaro works in the areas of reputation systems for ecommerce and collaboration, crowdsourcing, game theory, and formal methods for system design and verification. Luca is author of many tools including Crowdgrader and Similcheck. He is also the CTO of Camio.com. This talk is about a new tool for the Internet of Things that he is about to release.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Teaching web app development with web2py and crowdsourced grading</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/teaching-web-app-development-with-web2py-and-crow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca de Alfaro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:depy-2015/teaching-web-app-development-with-web2py-and-crow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we describe how web2py together with crowdsourced grading
enable teaching web applications at scale. Web2py is unique in allowing
the easy packaging and sharing of applications. A student can write a
web app, package it into a single file, then share it; other students
can with the click of a mouse unpack and load the application, and use
it. This allows teaching web development in a peer-driven fashion:
students submit solutions to homework assignments, then review and grade
each other's work, in the process learning from studying the solutions
that other students submitted for the same problem. We have successfully
used this approach at UC Santa Cruz for three years now, in the process
building a tool, CrowdGrader, for the peer review and grading of the
applications. The talk will describe the peer-driven approach and the
tool, and present results on tool accuracy and student satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>