<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Karin Knudson</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_karin-knudson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python for Global Applications: Law and Diplomacy Students</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/python-for-global-applications-law-and-diplomacy-students.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Karin Knudson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/python-for-global-applications-law-and-diplomacy-students.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students in fields like international affairs are increasingly seeking to gain proficiency in data science skills with Python. Such students have the potential to connect data science to its societal context in a sophisticated way. For educators working with such students to support this potential, it is essential to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students in fields like international affairs are increasingly seeking to gain proficiency in data science skills with Python. Such students have the potential to connect data science to its societal context in a sophisticated way. For educators working with such students to support this potential, it is essential to 1) welcome newcomers and center student perspectives and 2) consistently and authentically connect technical content with societal context. We present a framework for teaching Python based introductory data science skills in a highly contextualized and domain flexible environment, based on our experience teaching introductory data science to law and diplomacy students.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Python to Protect Voting Rights</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/python-to-protect-voting-rights.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Karin Knudson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/python-to-protect-voting-rights.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important question in some voting rights and redistricting litigation in the U.S. is whether and to what degree voting is racially polarized. We developed Python software that brings together a family of statistical methods that pair voting outcomes with demographic information to infer voting patterns. In this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important question in some voting rights and redistricting litigation in the U.S. is whether and to what degree voting is racially polarized. We developed Python software that brings together a family of statistical methods that pair voting outcomes with demographic information to infer voting patterns. In this talk we discuss the statistical models and our implementation using scientific Python tools (most notably PyMC3 and ArviZ) and demonstrate how the software has been applied in service of informing redistricting litigation and mapmaking over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>