<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Daniel Moisset</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daniel-moisset.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Pattern Matching in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/pattern-matching-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Moisset</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/pattern-matching-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pattern Matching in Python
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Daniel Moisset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Python 3.10 comes out in October 2021, it will include a new feature called “Structural Pattern Matching”. Structural Pattern Matching has been a staple of functional programming languages, but it has recently appeared or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pattern Matching in Python
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Daniel Moisset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Python 3.10 comes out in October 2021, it will include a new feature called “Structural Pattern Matching”. Structural Pattern Matching has been a staple of functional programming languages, but it has recently appeared or been proposed as future additions to imperative and OOP programming languages (like JavaScript, C++, and Rust). It provides an elegant way of processing and deconstructing heterogeneous data structures, and it enables an alternative paradigm to method dispatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of this feature's contributors, my goals in this presentation are to describe the motivation for this new functionality, present some of the problems that its use will effectively solve, and give a brief introduction of how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at intermediate Python developers (although a beginner will be able to understand it). After attending you should be able to understand not just how to use pattern matching, but also when it’s a good idea to use it and what are the possible pitfalls to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a Q&amp;amp;amp;A session which could be a good chance to discuss your questions about why certain design decisions were made when introducing pattern matching into Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry></feed>