<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Bharath Ramsundar</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_bharath-ramsundar.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Building Scientific Computing Infrastructure Software with the PyTorch Ecosystem</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/building-scientific-computing-infrastructure-software-with-the-pytorch-ecosystem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bharath Ramsundar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/building-scientific-computing-infrastructure-software-with-the-pytorch-ecosystem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building Scientific Computing Infrastructure Software with the PyTorch Ecosystem - Bharath Ramsundar, Deep Forest Sciences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DeepChem library is a scientific computing library that implements deep learning infrastructure for drug discovery, materials discovery, and biology. The DeepChem community is one of the largest scientific open source projects built in PyTorch …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building Scientific Computing Infrastructure Software with the PyTorch Ecosystem - Bharath Ramsundar, Deep Forest Sciences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DeepChem library is a scientific computing library that implements deep learning infrastructure for drug discovery, materials discovery, and biology. The DeepChem community is one of the largest scientific open source projects built in PyTorch, with over 5K stars on Github and thousands of citations. The DeepChem community has learned a number of useful lessons for building and maintaining high quality scientific code built on top of PyTorch. In this talk, I will share our learnings with the PyTorch community and also highlight opportunities for improving scientific support in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry></feed>