<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Brian MacDonald</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brian-macdonald.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Verbs, Not Nouns: Writing Documentation Users Want to Read</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2025/verbs-not-nouns-writing-documentation-users-want-to-read.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian MacDonald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-13:/pytexas-2025/verbs-not-nouns-writing-documentation-users-want-to-read.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lots of documentation is dull and tough to read. That's because most documentation focuses on describing product features, and those are nouns. Your user's primary concern isn't what your product is, or how it's made. Your user has a problem they want to solve, and they want to know …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lots of documentation is dull and tough to read. That's because most documentation focuses on describing product features, and those are nouns. Your user's primary concern isn't what your product is, or how it's made. Your user has a problem they want to solve, and they want to know how to use your product to do that. They're looking for a verb. In this talk, you'll find the verbs that go with your nouns, and how that translates into readable documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing the Next Great Tech Book</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-portland-2018/writing-the-next-great-tech-book.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian MacDonald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-06:/write-the-docs-portland-2018/writing-the-next-great-tech-book.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have an idea for the next great technical book. Maybe you're excited
about a new technology that nobody's written about yet. Maybe you're
unimpressed with the books that are out there on your favorite topic.
Maybe writing a book is on your bucket list. This session will help …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have an idea for the next great technical book. Maybe you're excited
about a new technology that nobody's written about yet. Maybe you're
unimpressed with the books that are out there on your favorite topic.
Maybe writing a book is on your bucket list. This session will help your
idea reach its potential as a published book. Technical publishing is an
opaque process with a lot of moving parts, which can be confusing for
outsiders to navigate. This session will guide you through the steps you
should take to turn an idea into a proposal that a publisher will
accept, and what to expect from the publishing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a great technical book takes more than a good idea. It also
requires a knowledge of the market, to determine whether there's an
audience willing to buy, or whether the space is too crowded to accept
new entries. Publishers vary in their approach and target markets, so
you need to determine which one will provide the best chance of success.
Self-publishing is an option, but carries its own risks and benefits.
Doing the setup work that you may not have thought about yet will help
you create a proposal that will appeal to publishers, and will also make
the writing process easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a contract with a publisher, or have decided to
self-publish, it's more than just a matter of putting the words in
order. Finding the right environment, setting a schedule, and
communicating with your editor are all critical to success. This session
will explain how the process works, highlight the parts you may not
know, and give you advice on how not to get overwhelmed by your project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Portland 2018"></category></entry></feed>