<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Vi Rapp</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vi-rapp.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python for early-stage design of sustainable aviation fuels</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/python-for-early-stage-design-of-sustainable-aviation-fuels.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ali Martz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/python-for-early-stage-design-of-sustainable-aviation-fuels.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aviation accounts for 2% of global greenhouse gas emissions, and reliance on liquid petroleum-based fuels makes this sector challenging to decarbonize. We seek to accelerate the development of sustainable aviation fuels using an early-stage design tool with a data-driven approach. We developed our strategy using the Python-based optimization packages …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aviation accounts for 2% of global greenhouse gas emissions, and reliance on liquid petroleum-based fuels makes this sector challenging to decarbonize. We seek to accelerate the development of sustainable aviation fuels using an early-stage design tool with a data-driven approach. We developed our strategy using the Python-based optimization packages BoTorch and Ax, and also rely on Pandas. We will discuss how to down-select from many possible fuel components to a specified number of chemical species and identify which combinations are most promising for a novel sustainable aviation fuel. We will also present its integration in our open-source web tool supporting biofuel research.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>