<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Philip Tillet</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DL Compiler Panel Discussion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/dl-compiler-panel-discussion.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DL Compiler Panel Discussion - Philip Tillet, OpenAI; Jason Ansel, Meta; Jacques Pienaar, Google; Tianqi Chen, CMU &amp;amp; OctoAI; Mikhail Zolotukhin, Modular; Peng Wu, Meta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the release of PyTorch 2 in 2023, torch.compile() has spurred significant new thinking around DL compiler designs at the framework level. In this session, we invite leaders in this space to share their insights based on real experiences of building DL compilers – Triton, TorchInductor, Halide, TVM, OpenXLA, and Mojo – and growing their ecosystems. We also invite a ‘compiler user representative,’ together.ai, to share their recent journey of redesigning the LLM inference stack around torch.compile(). Each leader will give a 10-minute lightning talk and an engaging panel discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip Tillet</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/dl-compiler-panel-discussion.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category></item><item><title>Maximizing Kernel Development Productivity Under Performance Constraints</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/maximizing-kernel-development-productivity-under-performance-constraints.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning research workflows are often bottlenecked by the development of compute kernels for new algorithms and GPU architectures. This process can be daunting, and often requires a careful trade-off between productivity and performance. In this talk, we will discuss how Triton -- a mid-level programming language for kernel development -- approaches this multi-objective optimization problem, and the design decisions that were made to that effect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip Tillet</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/maximizing-kernel-development-productivity-under-performance-constraints.html</guid><category>PyTorch Conference 2024</category></item></channel></rss>