<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Matteo Bertucci</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Learn Python automation by recreating Git Commit from scratch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/learn-python-automation-by-recreating-git-commit-from-scratch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn Python automation by recreating Git Commit from scratch
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Matteo Bertucci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is divided in two parts: the first one will explore how the Git key-value storage work and the second part will walk through recreating the fundamental git commit command with less than 80 lines of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow this talk at home using shell commands provided by the speaker and explore Git on your own. The code is also a great way to familiarize yourself with making and structuring Python utility scripts. It is also a great way to present more intermediate programming concept such as recursion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the commands and code are wrote to be as easy to understand as possible and commented by the speaker, as this talk aims to be simple to follow by Python and Git beginners. Good programming practice will be quickly shown, such as the use of f-strings and the usage of pathlib over os.path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final application is kept pretty barebone for brevity sakes, although challenges with some hints are given at the end of the talk as an exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final goal of this talk is to give the watcher a feel on how they can use Python in their every day life to automate different tasks, and some pointers toward good programming practices and continue in their Python journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is inspired from an unpublished article wrote by myself that you can consult here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.notion.so/Recreating-Git-Commit-in-Python-269f72bbc69d4f7e8aa64f67cc7d95d1"&gt;https://www.notion.so/Recreating-Git-Commit-in-Python-269f72bbc69d4f7e8aa64f67cc7d95d1&lt;/a&gt;
The final source code can be found here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/Akarys42/47085d16978947039279d75e1773725e"&gt;https://gist.github.com/Akarys42/47085d16978947039279d75e1773725e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matteo Bertucci</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/learn-python-automation-by-recreating-git-commit-from-scratch.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item></channel></rss>