<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Feeding data to AWS Redshift with Airflow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/feeding-data-to-aws-redshift-with-airflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Airflow is a powerful system to schedule workflows and define them as
a collection of interdependent scripts. It is the perfect companion
to do extract/transform/load pipelines into data warehouses, such as
Redshift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce some of the basis of Airflow and some of the
concepts that are data pipeline specific, like backfills, retries,
etc. Then there will be some examples on how to integrate this, along
with some lessons learned there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, there will be a part dedicated to Redshift, how to
structure data there, how to do some basic transformation
pre-loading, how to manage the schema using SQLAlchemy and Alembic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Federico Marani</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:europython-2017/feeding-data-to-aws-redshift-with-airflow.html</guid></item><item><title>Scaling with Ansible</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/scaling-with-ansible.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a powerful DevOps swiss-army knife tool, very easy to
configure and with many extensions built-in. This talk will quickly
introduce the basics of Ansible, then some real-life experience tips on
how to use this tool, from setting up dev VMs to multi-server setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure/Scaling is a topic really close to me, I'd like to have
the chance to talk about how we set this up in the company I work for.
Our infrastructure is around 10-15 servers, provisioned on different
cloud providers, so a good size infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation is going to be divided in 3 parts, first part is going to
be focused on comparing sysadmin and devops, then there will be an
introduction to the basic concepts of Ansible. I want to spend most on
the last part, which is going to give some tips based on our experience
with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many ideas will come from this presentation
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/fmarani/devops-with-ansible"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/fmarani/devops-with-ansible&lt;/a&gt; which i gave at
DJUGL in London, with a longer session I will have more chances to delve
into more detail, especially on how we use it, from vagrant boxes setup
to AWS and DigitalOcean boxes, network configuration, software
configurations, etc...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to offer as many real-life tips as possible, without going too
much offtopic as far as Ansible is concerned&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Federico Marani</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-23:europython-2014/scaling-with-ansible.html</guid></item></channel></rss>