<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_amber-wanner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to give a damn, and stand out</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/how-to-give-a-damn-and-stand-out.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Amber Wanner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-17:djangocon-us-2018/how-to-give-a-damn-and-stand-out.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will give you some tips and techniques as well as some real
(raw) examples of how I was able to start a company at 23 years old,
lock in an investment, and beat out my competitors who were a lot older
and more experienced than I. The talk will demonstrate different
scenarios and solutions in which it takes to stand out, and be
remembered in a saturated market, in whatever field you may be in.
Whether you are a developer interviewing for your dream job, starting a
business, or somewhere in between and just trying to make your way in
the world. Implementing emotional awareness and intelligence in your
life will change not just the way you interview but the way you are
perceived by others in your work life, as well as your social life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends call it the “Amber effect” but I call it, giving a damn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to leave a lasting impression, every time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of long term benefits vs instant gratification when it
comes to building relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to stand out as a potential job applicant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get the attention of a prospective client, including c-level
executives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to identify opportunity and advantages out of unexpected
circumstances (When things don’t go your way)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to add value beyond scope of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genuinely giving a damn without expectation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>