<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_diana-pholo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python as a tool for e-health systems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2018/python-as-a-tool-for-e-health-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Diana Pholo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-11:pycon-za-2018/python-as-a-tool-for-e-health-systems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;E-health has proven to have many benefits including reduced errors in
medical diagnosis. A number of machine learning (ML) techniques have
been applied in medical diagnosis, each having its benefits and
disadvantages. With its powerful pre-built libraries, Python is great
for implementing machine learning in the medical field, where many
people do not have an Artificial Intelligence background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on applying ML on medical datasets using
Scikit-learn, a Python module that comes packed with various machine
learning algorithms. It will be structured as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An introduction to e-health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of medical data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some Benchmark algorithms used in medical diagnosis: Decision trees,
K-Nearest Neighbours, Naive Bayes and Support Vector Machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to implement benchmark algorithms using Scikit-learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance evaluation metrics used in e-health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at people interested in real-life applications of
machine learning using Python. Although centered around ML in medicine,
the acquired skills can be extended to other fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker: Diana Pholo is a PhD student and lecturer in the
department of Computer Systems Engineering, at the Tshwane University of
Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>