<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_bence-faludi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python for data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2015/using-python-for-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bence Faludi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-25:pycon-ireland-2015/using-python-for-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you feel like using R is too complex and Java is pain in the ass? Is your company using PHP because somebody said it would be okay? You started working with R and realized you can't write a micro service and need to pick another language?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your answers, this lecture is about what your biggest problem would be if you have had chosen Python for your work in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Extract Transform Load using mETL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2014/extract-transform-load-using-metl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bence Faludi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-26:pydata-berlin-2014/extract-transform-load-using-metl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;mETL is an ETL package written in Python which was developed to load
elective data for Central European University. Program can be used in a
more general way, it can be used to load practically any kind of data to
any target. Code is open source and available for anyone who want to use
it. The main advantage to configurable via Yaml files and You have the
possibility to write any transformation in Python and You can use it
natively from any framework as well. We are using this tool in
production for many of our clients and It is really stable and reliable.
The project has a few contributors all around the world right now and I
hope many developer will join soon. I really want to show you how you
can use it in your daily work. In this tutorial We will see the most
common situations: - Installation - Write simple Yaml configration files
to load CSV, JSON, XML into MySQL or PostgreSQL Database, or convert CSV
to JSON, etc. - Add tranformations on your fields - Filter records based
on condition - Walk through a directory to feed the tool - How the
mapping works - Generate Yaml configurations automatically from data
source - Migrate a database to another database&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Extract, Transform, Load using mETL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/extract-transform-load-using-metl-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bence Faludi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:pycon-italia-2015/extract-transform-load-using-metl-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;mETL is an ETL package written in Python. Program can be used to load
practically any kind of data to any target. Code is open source and
available for anyone who want to use it. The main advantage to
configurable via Yaml files and You have the possibility to write any
transformation in Python and You can use it natively from any framework
as well. We are using this tool in production for many of our clients
and It is really stable and reliable. The project has a few contributors
all around the world right now and I hope many developer will join soon.
I want to introduce you this tool. In this presentation I will show you
the functionality and the common use cases. Furthermore I will talk
about other ETL tools in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>