<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lynn-cherny.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Goofing Off with Fun (Big) Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/goofing-off-with-fun-big-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lynn Cherny</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:pydata-london-2019/goofing-off-with-fun-big-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of us work too much and play too little. When was the last time you smiled at something you made? Playing with fun datasets, especially big data sets, opens up weird new forms of technical recreation. I'll show you some data toys I've built using AI and interesting data sets: Most of them involve both backend data science and front-end visualization tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting Your Data Joie De Vivre Back!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/getting-your-data-joie-de-vivre-back.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lynn Cherny</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/getting-your-data-joie-de-vivre-back.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of us work too much and play too little. When was the last time you
smiled at something you made? Playing with fun datasets, especially big
data sets, opens up weird new forms of technical recreation. Why not
train an amusing model in a browser tab while you're waiting for that
day-job Spark query to finish? I'll show you some data toys I've built
using AI and interesting data sets: Most of them involve both backend
data science and front-end visualization tricks. They range from
poetry-composition helpers to game log analysis to image deconstruction
and reconstruction. All of them taught me something, often about myself
and what I like artistically, and sometimes about what &amp;quot;big data&amp;quot;
actually means.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Deep Learning"></category><category term="Visualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Exploring French Job Ads</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyparis-2017/exploring-french-job-ads.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lynn Cherny</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-12:pyparis-2017/exploring-french-job-ads.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To address some faculty questions at EM-Lyon Business School, some
students and I began collecting and analysing job ads for French
companies. I’ll show some preliminary text analysis and visualization of
the content, focused on skills sought by French employers (both business
and technical).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>