<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyCon Balkan Belgrade 2018 - Day 3 - LIVE STREAM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018/pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018-day-3-live-stream.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ridhwana Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-18:pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018/pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018-day-3-live-stream.html</guid></item><item><title>PyCon Balkan Belgrade 2018 - LIVE STREAM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018/pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018-live-stream.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luka Kladarić</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-16:pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018/pycon-balkan-belgrade-2018-live-stream.html</guid></item><item><title>A journey through the eyes of a newbie female developer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/a-journey-through-the-eyes-of-a-newbie-female-dev.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a developer, my goal is to provide inspiration to capable young
women, to fathers who have daughters, brothers who have sisters, and men
who have female colleagues. To convey that I have embraced the
development environment, and that we within the tech industry should
never shy away from the opportunity to increase our pool of passionate
developers. We are proudly South African and most definitely should be
known for our diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graduating from a 90% male computer science class, to an initially 100%
male software development team, finally allowed me to realise that there
is a dire lack of women in the computer science field. Entering this
industry in a minority invokes initial feelings of the need to
constantly prove oneself and one's capabilities – normally this puts one
at an immediate disadvantage. However, given the correct circumstances,
surrounding environments and attitudes, these adverse feelings can
quickly be replaced with self-confidence. I was fortunate enough in my
daily working environment to have my opinion given the weight that it
deserved. However, experience has also taught me that the sailing is not
always so smooth within every aspect of the development field. Certain
environments are a lot less welcoming to women because of the strange
misconception that they are going against the norms of society. As a
newbie, within the development industry, one has to be able to adapt and
have an open mind to gain unbounded knowledge and learning experiences.
The world of development is a polyglot environment and striving to build
an ambitious career involves lots of hard work and dedication. I would
like to take the audience on a journey to experience the obstacles,
growth and challenges that I’ve faced. I also aim to provide concrete
suggestions on increasing female willingness to join the tech industry,
and improving co-existence in the development environment. As a
developer, my goal is to provide inspiration to capable young women, to
fathers who have daughters, brothers who have sisters, and men who have
female colleagues. To convey that I have embraced the development
environment, and that we within the tech industry should never shy away
from the opportunity to increase our pool of passionate developers. We
are proudly South African and most definitely should be known for our
diversity….&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ridhwana Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/a-journey-through-the-eyes-of-a-newbie-female-dev.html</guid><category>pyconza</category><category>pyconza2014</category></item></channel></rss>