<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Adam Symington</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creating Beautiful Geospatial Data Visualizations with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/creating-beautiful-geospatial-data-visualizations-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will give a broad overview of many of the core concepts in geospatial data visualisations. Attendees will come away with the skills needed to analyse and plot geospatial data as well as manipulate and combine geospatial datasets, generate new geospatial data from existing sources, generate insightful data maps and other geospatial data visualisations and come away from the tutorial with the confidence to seek out new datasets to apply their skills to.  When it comes to data visualisation, attendees will be encouraged to express themselves, material will be provided to get them to the point where they can generate their own visualisations without help but styling the plots will be up to them. This tutorial will provide a high-level overview of geospatial data analysis and visualisation and provide a list of open-source datasets that can be used to practice newly learned skills. Furthermore, the packages used are not all specific to geospatial data visualisation and are applicable to a wide range of scientific and data science problems. As such, it is open to everyone and hopefully beginners, intermediates and experts will all come away with a new skill or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/symmy596/PythonMaps-Scipy-2022"&gt;https://github.com/symmy596/PythonMaps-Scipy-2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Symington</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/creating-beautiful-geospatial-data-visualizations-with-python.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item></channel></rss>