<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_francesco-nazzaro.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Facing the challenge of climate change with xarray and Dask</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/facing-the-challenge-of-climate-change-with-xarray-and-dask.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Francesco Nazzaro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/facing-the-challenge-of-climate-change-with-xarray-and-dask.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last years climate change has become one of the most important
topic. For any period longer than a few days science is not able to
provide comparable forecasts, but still a lot of useful information
about future climate conditions can be gained on time scale of a few
months to even several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate forecast and climate projections data are quite complex to
analyse and represent. The Python science ecosystem proves extremely
effective as a platform to retrieve, analyse, process and present
this type of data. The backbone of the platform is the n-dimensional
array library xarray that provides the perfect mix between pandas
data structures and dask performance and parallelization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reliable climate forecasts and climate projections are now available
from the Copernicus Climate Change Service, operated by ECMWF, that
will become the central hub for European effort in study and mitigate
climate change impacts. The service also provides access to an open
cloud platform, the CDS Toolbox, that is based on the Python 3
xarray/dask/pandas stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will present how to retrieve, analyse, process and
display climate data in a generic use case with xarray and with the
Copernicus CDS Toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://slides.com/francesconazzaro/europython-2017"&gt;http://slides.com/francesconazzaro/europython-2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>