<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Fred Reiss</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_fred-reiss.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Natural Language Processing with Pandas DataFrames</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2021/natural-language-processing-with-pandas-dataframes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Fred Reiss</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-12:/scipy-2021/natural-language-processing-with-pandas-dataframes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most areas of Python data science have standardized using Pandas DataFrames for representing and manipulating structured data in memory. Natural Language Processing, not so much. In this presentation, we'll explain why you should be using Pandas for NLP. We'll start by explaining the extension system that the Pandas developers …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most areas of Python data science have standardized using Pandas DataFrames for representing and manipulating structured data in memory. Natural Language Processing, not so much. In this presentation, we'll explain why you should be using Pandas for NLP. We'll start by explaining the extension system that the Pandas developers recently added to Pandas. Then we'll Talk about our open source library, Text Extensions for Pandas (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ibm.biz/text-extensions-for-pandas"&gt;https://ibm.biz/text-extensions-for-pandas&lt;/a&gt;), which adds special data types and library integrations specifically geared to NLP use cases. We'll explain how these extensions connect to some basic NLP concepts, and then we'll finish with an example of using Pandas to build an NLP application.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2021"></category></entry></feed>