<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_linda-uruchurtu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Sudo Make me a (London) Map</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/sudo-make-me-a-london-map.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Linda Uruchurtu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/sudo-make-me-a-london-map.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A review of Python and R libraries that allow users to easily work
with shapefiles and geographic data, and create thematic maps . We
will comment on ease of use and advantages/disadvantages of each
ecosystem when it comes to novice users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many specialised tools to visualise geographic data. However,
they are often expensive and have a significant learning curve. Free
libraries in Python and R, enable users to not only work with shapefiles
but also perform a variety of exploratory analyses and visualisations.
In this talk we will look at London road works data and we use a variety
of libraries in Python and R to analyse and create thematic maps. We
will comment on ease of use and advantages/disadvantages of each
ecosystem when it comes to novice users.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Beginner's guide to Random Forests - R vs Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2014/a-beginners-guide-to-random-forests-r-vs-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Linda Uruchurtu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-02-22:pydata-london-2014/a-beginners-guide-to-random-forests-r-vs-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will give an overview of Random Forests and will show
their versatility when attempting to predict song ratings using the EMI
music data set. I will present results using the randomForest library in
R and the scikit learn implementation in Python and discuss their
performance. I will also comment on their ease of use from a beginner's
point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Survival Analysis in Python and R</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2016/linda-uruchurtu-survival-analysis-in-python-and-r.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Linda Uruchurtu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-11:pydata-london-2016/linda-uruchurtu-survival-analysis-in-python-and-r.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData London 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survival analysis is a set of statistical techniques that has many applications in the industry. This talk will discuss key concepts behind survival analysis by means of examples implemented via Lifelines, an open source python library, and in R for comparison purposes. I will also describe how we have made use of these techniques in Lyst to try to predict when items go out of stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many problems involve the understanding the duration of specific events; for example, predicting when a customer will churn, when a person will default on a credit, how long a machine will work, etc. These type of questions constitute the realm of Survival analysis, a branch of statistics historically developed by professionals in the actuarial and medical fields dealing with event durations as governed by probability laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will cover the basics of Survival analysis via examples implemented via Lifelines, an open-source python library and in R (survival and KMsurv libraries), going from survival curves to regression models. I will discuss how survival analysis can be applied to a variety of problems and in particular, I will focus on the problem of out of stock prediction for an online retailer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/1Oe1gf7"&gt;http://bit.ly/1Oe1gf7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>