<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hugo-shi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Bokeh: An Extensible Implementation of the Grammar of Graphics for Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/bokeh-an-extensible-implementation-of-the-gramma.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hugo Shi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/bokeh-an-extensible-implementation-of-the-gramma.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a new plotting framework for Python that natively understands
the relationships in multidimensional datasets, uses a Protovis-like
expression syntax scheme for creating novel visualizations, and is
designed from the ground up to be used on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it can be thought of as &amp;quot;ggplot for Python&amp;quot;, the goals of Bokeh
are much more ambitious. The Grammar of Graphics primarily addresses the
mapping of pre-built aeshetics and layouts to a particular data schema
and tuples of measure variables. It has limited facility for expressing
data interactivity, and its small set of graph types (aka &amp;quot;geoms&amp;quot; or
glyphs) are somewhat limited in both their number and in the number of
ways they can be combined with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, most existing Python plotting frameworks adopt a &amp;quot;tell
me how&amp;quot; instead of a &amp;quot;tell me what&amp;quot; approach. Thus, user plotting code
canfrequently become mired down in what amounts to details of the
rendering system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our talk, we will show various features of Bokeh, and talk about
future development. We will also go into some detail about how Bokeh
unifies the tasks of describing data mapping, building data-driven
layout, and composing novel visualizations using a single, multi-purpose
scene and data graph.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="visualization"></category></entry></feed>