<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Maria Jose Molina Contreras</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_maria-jose-molina-contreras.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>DIY Home Automation with Microcontrollers and CircuitPython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/diy-home-automation-with-microcontrollers-and-circuitpython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina-Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/diy-home-automation-with-microcontrollers-and-circuitpython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIY Home Automation with Microcontrollers and CircuitPython
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Maria Jose Molina-Contreras, PhD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, people have been filling their home with devices that are based on Microcontrollers, like virtual assistants, smart fridges, washing machines, security systems, and many others that can be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIY Home Automation with Microcontrollers and CircuitPython
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Optiver]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Maria Jose Molina-Contreras, PhD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, people have been filling their home with devices that are based on Microcontrollers, like virtual assistants, smart fridges, washing machines, security systems, and many others that can be either programmable, or even replicated with a couple of boards and our Python knowledge.
During this talk, we will start exploring CircuitPython without the need of a physical device, using a microcontroller emulator.  If you are new to the microcontroller world, don’t worry, we will have an introduction to the main concepts, so we have the base knowledge to start doing little experiments by ourselves.
After the introduction, you will be able to start programming microcontrollers using the emulator or in real life, moreover, you will see a couple of real projects (with real devices!) that could easily be replicated by yourself: a low-cost robot floor cleaner, and a plant watering and monitoring system, as examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline
Talk motivation
Introduction to Microcontrollers and CircuitPython.
How to use an emulator for hardware programming.
DIY Home Automation (Real projects) :
Low-cost robot cleaner.
Watering and monitoring plant system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Continue Thinking Small: Next level machine learning with TinyML</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/continue-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/continue-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/continue-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/continue-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things has been flourishing for many years, and Python has been playing an important role on the “easy to automate” topic for many devices. One of the challenges for the next generation ML …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/continue-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/continue-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things has been flourishing for many years, and Python has been playing an important role on the “easy to automate” topic for many devices. One of the challenges for the next generation ML is to think small, you read that right “thinking small”. It’s time to start being able to have mechanisms with super well-trained ML models in small-devices: ML on Microcontrollers. We are going to dive into TinyML and evaluate different setups to interact with sensors on microcontrollers. We will discuss the different hardware options and frameworks to start with, while checking different use cases that TinyML can solve, like: agriculture, conservation, health issues detection, ecology monitoring etc. In this talk, you will learn about Tiny Machine Learning (TinyML), which is an approach that explores machine learning to be deployed in embedded systems that enable run ML on microcontrollers. Lastly, we will discuss real use-cases and a practical case that could be implemented at home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Better Air, Better Health Creating an indoor air quality monitoring and predictive system</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2022/better-air-better-health-creating-an-indoor-air-quality-monitoring-and-predictive-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina-Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-08-25:/pycon-latam-2022/better-air-better-health-creating-an-indoor-air-quality-monitoring-and-predictive-system.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Better Air, Better Health Creating an indoor air quality monitoring and predictive system&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Latam 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to build an intelligent “indoor garden”</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2020/how-to-build-an-intelligent-indoor-garden.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina-Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-04-17:/pycon-us-2020/how-to-build-an-intelligent-indoor-garden.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon US 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Better Air, Better Health: Creating an indoor air quality monitoring and predictive system.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/better-air-better-health-creating-an-indoor-air-quality-monitoring-and-predictive-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/better-air-better-health-creating-an-indoor-air-quality-monitoring-and-predictive-system.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of years, most people have been moved to a full working from home work-style, which made us realize benefits we were not aware of, but sadly some little inconveniences as well, like health related issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to build a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of years, most people have been moved to a full working from home work-style, which made us realize benefits we were not aware of, but sadly some little inconveniences as well, like health related issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to build a functional system to track the air quality, collect our own data using different sensors and implement a predictive approach to avoid future health problems. We are going to dive into the different setups to interact with air quality sensors using Python on microcontrollers and embedded systems, collecting your own data to evaluate different factors like humidity, temperature, CO2, particles, but that’s not all, also we will go into the implementation of a predictive machine learning (ML) model to predict Indoor CO2 levels and alerting us based on predictions before critical levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main idea of this talk is to show with a practical example how Python is a great option to build an indoor air quality monitoring complemented with a predictive ML model for Indoor CO2, while having fun building and monitoring their home.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Start thinking small: Next level Machine Learning with TinyML and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/start-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/start-thinking-small-next-level-machine-learning-with-tinyml-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We usually associate the future of computing as large clusters being
able to perform tasks in a fraction of a second, but is it really the
only scenario on how computational hardware will evolve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has become an important component in our societies, we
see how people, communities …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We usually associate the future of computing as large clusters being
able to perform tasks in a fraction of a second, but is it really the
only scenario on how computational hardware will evolve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has become an important component in our societies, we
see how people, communities, and global companies are focusing their
resources into improving their technological stack, and being the leader
into the next generation of AI. At the same time that we see clusters
getting larger, GPUs more powerful, and our phones are practically
computers being capable of doing almost everything, we do see that some
of the smart devices are becoming smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things has been flourishing for many years, and Python
has been playing an important role on the “easy to automate” topic for
many devices, but can Python help us in all scenarios? One of the
challenges for the next generation ML is to think small, you read that
right “thinking small”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to start being able to have mechanisms with super well-trained
ML models in small-devices: ML on Microcontrollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to dive into TinyML and evaluate different setups to
interact with sensors on microcontrollers. We will discuss the different
hardware options and frameworks to start with, while checking different
use cases that TinyML can solve, like: agriculture, conservation, health
issues detection, ecology monitoring, autonomous vehicles, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn about Tiny Machine Learning (TinyML), which
is an approach that explores machine learning to be deployed in embedded
systems that enable run ML on microcontrollers. Similarly, I will talk
about Micropython and CircuitPython, and how they have been conquering
the microcontroller scene. Lastly, we will discuss a real use-case,
predictive machine learning model to predict anomalies for predictive
maintenance problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Personalizando LLMs: Guía para “Fine-Tuning” local de modelos Open Source en Español</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/personalizando-llms-guia-para-fine-tuning-local-de-modelos-open-source-en-espanol.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/personalizando-llms-guia-para-fine-tuning-local-de-modelos-open-source-en-espanol.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En el mundo actual, los modelos de lenguaje grandes (LLM, en inglés)
están revolucionando cómo interactuamos con la tecnología, permitiendo
tener conversaciones, organizar datos, redactar textos, y otras
actividades con mínimo esfuerzo humano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es probable que al usar algún LLM hayas recibido respuestas incorrectas
¿a qué se debe eso …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En el mundo actual, los modelos de lenguaje grandes (LLM, en inglés)
están revolucionando cómo interactuamos con la tecnología, permitiendo
tener conversaciones, organizar datos, redactar textos, y otras
actividades con mínimo esfuerzo humano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es probable que al usar algún LLM hayas recibido respuestas incorrectas
¿a qué se debe eso? Durante el entrenamiento de estos modelos, suelen
ingerir grandes cantidades de texto sin etiquetar de fuentes como
libros, páginas web, foros, los cuales desarrollan un gran entendimiento
de conocimiento pero carecen de conocimientos específicos. Por este
motivo ajustar modelos (“Fine-Tuning”, en inglés) que han sido
pre-entrenados con este gran corpus de datos es crucial para: (1)
obtener mejor rendimiento en la calidad de respuestas, y (2) ajustar el
modelo a un dominio específico al proporcionar textos específicos para
que puedan especializarse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entonces, ¿Por qué es necesario entender el “Fine-Tuning” en modelos
locales? Dentro de los diversos motivos, uno de los más relevantes es la
privacidad de datos. Puesto que al hacer el proceso de “Fine-Tuning”
localmente se puede enseñar al modelo datos que son privados, como datos
personales, datos clínicos, información confidencial de empresas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En esta charla, los asistentes aprenderán paso a paso cómo modelos LLM
Open Source, como Mixtral-8x22B-v0.1, Mistral-7B (multi lenguaje),
bloom-7b u otros modelos, son opciones muy interesantes para aprender a
realizar “Fine-Tuning” y especializar modelo para el dominio específico.
Además, se compartirá el rol de Python del proceso, la aplicación de
módulos externos para tener una implementación simple, para realizar
“Fine-Tuning” de LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conocimientos generales de Data Science son recomendables para seguir la
temática con facilidad, aunque se explicará de manera simplificada y
yendo por todos los pasos para entender cómo se realiza “Fine-Tuning”.
Outline añadido en la sección Notes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Descifrando emociones desde arte a memes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/descifrando-emociones-desde-arte-a-memes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Jose Molina Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/pycon-us-2025/descifrando-emociones-desde-arte-a-memes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;El mundo que nos rodea está lleno de información de muchos tipos, y aunque muchas personas nos comunicamos de manera verbal para transmitir información muchas veces perdemos información del contexto o la intención si no va acompañado de imágenes. Lo mismo ocurre con los modelos cuando intentamos solucionar problemas …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;El mundo que nos rodea está lleno de información de muchos tipos, y aunque muchas personas nos comunicamos de manera verbal para transmitir información muchas veces perdemos información del contexto o la intención si no va acompañado de imágenes. Lo mismo ocurre con los modelos cuando intentamos solucionar problemas muy complejos con modelos que solo pueden contener información de un tipo específico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por ese motivo es necesario soluciones que puedan integrar diferentes tipos de datos, como imágenes, texto, video o audio: los modelos multimodales. Estos sistemas combinan múltiples entradas de tipos de datos y hacen los sistemas más robustos, ayudando en áreas de la salud, seguridad, criminología, comercial, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de esta charla es mostrar cómo crear un sistema que sea capaz de identificar emociones de diverso tipo de imágenes, y en paralelo extraer emociones de textos con ese resultado (con diferentes modelos) y asociar textos a las imágenes con los textos extraídos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En esta charla, los asistentes aprenderán paso a paso cómo implementar un sistema multimodal que incluya imágenes y texto, con datos de libre acceso, y entender cómo los multimodales son una buena opción para solventar problemas complejos. Además, se compartirá el rol de Python del proceso, la aplicación de módulos externos para tener una implementación simple, para facilitar el realizar el proceso de multimodal.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry></feed>