<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_imogen-wright.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Beating the bugs: Simulating drug resistance in viral and bacterial DNA using Python and AWS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/beating-the-bugs-simulating-drug-resistance-in-viral-and-bacterial-dna-using-python-and-aws.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Imogen Wright</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/beating-the-bugs-simulating-drug-resistance-in-viral-and-bacterial-dna-using-python-and-aws.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a species, we're engaged in a crucial evolutionary struggle, and
we're losing: pathogens are evolving resistance to drugs faster than we
can make new ones. To slow down the clock and beat the bugs, we need to
make sure that resistant pathogens don't get a chance to replicate
unchecked in their human hosts. This means doing drug resistance tests
to ensure that we only give patients drugs that their infections will
respond to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Hyrax Biosciences, our software developers build web services that
use machine learning to analyse DNA for drug resistance. While building
Exatype, our drug resistance testing platform, we ran into a classic
problem: how do we build a validation test with a verified result, when
we're already the most sensitive tool on the market? To solve this
problem, we turned to simulation. This talk is about a multithreaded
python tool (Biopython, multiprocessing, numpy, pysam) that simulates
every stage of the evolution of HIV drug resistance and the DNA
sequencing process. Each run returns 300 unique, procedurally-generated
HIV samples from &amp;quot;patients&amp;quot; with different histories and drug resistance
profiles. We host the tool on AWS and integrate with Slack to run
validations and report results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code to simulate your own HIV dataset is available publicly at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/hyraxbio/simulated-data"&gt;https://github.com/hyraxbio/simulated-data&lt;/a&gt;. Other pathogens coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>