<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Programação para jornalistas: 3 meses de experiências em uma redação</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2018/programacao-para-jornalistas-3-meses-de-experiencias-em-uma-redacao.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-17:python-brasil-2018/programacao-para-jornalistas-3-meses-de-experiencias-em-uma-redacao.html</guid></item><item><title>Fernando Masanori</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-sul-2017/fernando-masanori.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seja Feliz Programando em Python&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-09:python-sul-2017/fernando-masanori.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>I love JSON module</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2012/i-love-json-module.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love JSON module
Palestrante: Fernando Masanori&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-11-23:python-brasil-2012/i-love-json-module.html</guid></item><item><title>Palestra Relâmpago: Arthur Merlin Games</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2012/palestra-relampago-arthur-merlin-games.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra Relâmpago: Arthur Merlin Games - Fernando Masanori&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-11-23:python-brasil-2012/palestra-relampago-arthur-merlin-games.html</guid></item><item><title>Python for Zombies: 12.000 enrolled in the first Brazilian MOOC to teach Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/python-for-zombies-12000-enrolled-in-the-first-brazilian-mooc-to-teach-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiences of how we spread the Python community in Brazil with a non english MOOC to teach programming. Python for Zombies is the first Massive Open Online Course to teach programming with Python in Portuguese. Our first edition had 12.000 &amp;quot;zombies&amp;quot; enrolled. This course is very different from traditional MOOCs (Edx, Coursera, etc.). First is an initiative of the brazilian Python community. Besides the difference of language, it is very &amp;quot;casual&amp;quot;, as I have little time, I recorded most of the videos on my trips between meetings, conferences or at mealtimes. This MOOC is &amp;quot;brazilian&amp;quot;, in a non traditional academic way. The size of the videos is far lower than the average traditional courses too. I'm recording the Spanish version. I will show you the most funny codes that I used in MOOC classes to teach programming: hacking basic modules and classes to obtain the &amp;quot;Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything&amp;quot;. All material is Creative Commons Share Alike. The MOOC is based in my experience to teach programming in past six years at FATEC, a public university in Brazil, with decreasing rates of failure in the introduction to programming discipline. We have 100% class in labs, Coding Dojos to training and tests in exercises. Slides for this same title in a talk I gave in Python Education Summit at PyCon Montreal: bit.ly/python-for-zombies&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-24:pycon-italia-2014/python-for-zombies-12000-enrolled-in-the-first-brazilian-mooc-to-teach-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Python for Zombies (Brazilian MOOC)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uy-2013/python-for-zombies-brazilian-mooc.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python for Zombies: 5000 enrolled in the first Python Brazilian MOOC
Python for Zombies is the first free MOOC to learn programming with Python in Brazil. Our first edition had near to 5000 &amp;quot;zombies&amp;quot;. A spanish version is possible for next year. Additionally I have been taught programming in past five years at FATEC, a public university in Brazil, with decreasing rates of failure in the introduction to programming discipline. We have 100% class in labs, Coding Dojos to training and we use many funny examples to teach, like hacking Facebook friends photos. Besides the traditional university students we have, at FATEC, special classes for kids in a talent development program of the municipal government.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-11-02:pycon-uy-2013/python-for-zombies-brazilian-mooc.html</guid></item><item><title>import pybr12: experiencias de inclusión en la última PyCon Brazil</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2016/import-pybr12-experiencias-de-inclusion-en-la-ultima-pycon-brazil.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyconAR 2016 - Bahía Blanca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;import pybr12: experiencias de inclusión en la última PyCon Brazil por Fernando Masanori, Paola Katherine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience level: Principiante&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Descripción&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyLadies en el Brazil, como un de los fatores para tener 42% de mujeres speaker's, en la ultima PyCon Implementamos el Código de Conduta, como explicado en &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.coc-handbook.com/"&gt;https://www.coc-handbook.com/&lt;/a&gt; Acertos y errores, en la práctica, do ponto de vista de un miembro del time de respuesta. Explicación del Manifesto Pybr12: sticker con los principios de inclusión de la conferencia 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contexto de PyLadies en el Brazil: historico, localidades, desarrollo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descripcion particular de PyLadies San Pablo: hace un año de existencia apenas, yo he dado el primero taller, dados y peculiaridades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preliminares de la PyCon Brazil: el Forun Internacional del Software Libre (FISL) donde hube un track solo de mujeres speaker's organizado pelas PyLadies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;En FISL hubo una chica de doze años entre los speaker's, Larissa Oliva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Es la primera experiencia de crowfunding para cobrir los gastos de las chicas (translado, alojamiento), pues muchas eran estudiantes apenas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inicialmente no habia muchas submissiones de mujeres para la PyCon Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;En las listas internas de discussion de PyLadies se empeza un movimento de brainstorming, surgen muchas ideas para temas de posibles charlas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Se empezan las submissiones y una otra campaña de crowfunding, a que se suman tres empresas comos sponsors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;En la lista de discusión brasileña se llega a un consenso que no es suficiente tener un Código de Conduta, se decide implementarlo como explicado em &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.coc-handbook.com/"&gt;https://www.coc-handbook.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yo he participado en el time de respuesta, relato de los acertos y errores, en la condución del Código de Conduta. Fueron siete las ocorrências.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talleres para iniciantes junto con los sprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiencias compartidas de los organizadores de las PyCon's anterores (una forma de inclusión de los mayores).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicación del Manifesto Pybr12: sticker con los principios de inclusión de la conferencia 2016. Distribuido a todos los participantes. Manifesto abajo:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respetar a las personas. Las diferencias hacen mejor comunidad mejor. Sea paciente (con los demás, con el diferente, con principiantes). Todos somos diferentes. Todos somos maravillosos. (PyCon Japón). Abraze las causas que usted cree. Ayudar a quienes tienen dificultades. Proteger a las personas que están en necesidad. Personas - Tecnología.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django Girls en la PyCon: intercambio con Anitas, una iniciativa local que logro aumentar la diversidad de las chicas (hube participación de muchas chicas de humanas y biológicas).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ar.pycon.org/proposals/document/15/10467b62-28c9-4603-b3ae-6a299cd14835.pdf"&gt;http://ar.pycon.org/proposals/document/15/10467b62-28c9-4603-b3ae-6a299cd14835.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-25:pycon-ar-2016/import-pybr12-experiencias-de-inclusion-en-la-ultima-pycon-brazil.html</guid></item><item><title>Python For Zombies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2014/python-for-zombies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presented by: Fernando Masanori&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;15.000 enrolled in the first Brazilian MOOC to teach programming&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python for Zombies is the first MOOC (Massive Open Online Course) to teach programming in portuguese. Our first edition had 15.000 &amp;quot;zombies&amp;quot;. This course is different from traditional MOOCs (Edx, Coursera, etc). First is an initiative of the Brazilian Python community. Besides the difference of language, it is very &amp;quot;casual&amp;quot;, as I have little time, I recorded most of the videos on my trips between meetings, conferences or at mealtimes. This MOOC is &amp;quot;brazilian&amp;quot;, in a non traditional academic way. The size of the videos is far lower than the average traditional courses too. I will show you the most funny codes that I used in MOOC classes to teach programming: hacking basic modules and classes to obtain the &amp;quot;Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything&amp;quot;. All material is Creative Commons Share Alike. The MOOC is based in my experience to teach programming in past six years at FATEC, a public university in Brazil, with decreasing rates of failure in the introduction to programming discipline. We have 100% class in labs, Coding Dojos to training and tests in exercises. Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/python-for-zombies"&gt;http://bit.ly/python-for-zombies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-13:pycon-uk-2014/python-for-zombies.html</guid></item><item><title>import community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2016/import-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ten different PyCon's and three Django Girls in two year's: lessons on diversity that I learned. Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil, Italy, Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada, USA and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="abstract"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, in relation to other communities, is its effort to improve diversity. There is even a Diversity Statement at PSF: “We have created this diversity statement because we believe that a diverse Python community is stronger and more vibrant. A diverse community where people treat each other with respect has more potential contributors and more sources for ideas.” In last two years I was fortunate enough to take part in ten PyCon’s in eleven different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil, Italy, Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada, USA and Spain. Some were not national conferences, but were EuroPython or PyConUS. I was coach in three Django Girls at PyCon Namibia, Argentina and Brazil. I always took note of experiences on how to improve diversity, that could be useful and replicable in my local community and would like to share at PyCon Japan. There are other reports that I also would like to share, which are only beautiful personal stories of how Python reaches the most distant people and places you may never have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-21:pycon-japan-2016/import-community.html</guid></item><item><title>import community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/scipyla2016-import-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Fernando Masanori&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumo:
One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, in relation to other communities, is its effort to improve diversity. There is even a Diversity Statement at PSF: &amp;quot;We have created this diversity statement because we believe that a diverse Python community is stronger and more vibrant. A diverse community where people treat each other with respect has more potential contributors and more sources for ideas.&amp;quot; I was fortunate enough to take part in nine PyCon's in ten different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil, Italy, Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada and Spain. Some were not national conferences, but were EuroPython or PyConUS. I always took note of experiences on how to improve diversity, that could be useful and replicable in my local community and would like to share at SciPyLA. There are other reports that I also would like to share, which are only beautiful stories of how Python reaches the most distant people and places you may never have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materiais:
* &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pt.slideshare.net/fmasanori/import-community-62142823"&gt;http://pt.slideshare.net/fmasanori/import-community-62142823&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:scipyla-2016/scipyla2016-import-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Data Structures with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/data-structures-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fernando Masanori - Data Structures with Python
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
[Education Summit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Structures is traditionally a “bogeyman” discipline in Computer
Science courses and has a high degree of failure. In FATEC São José
dos Campos we are adopting a hybrid approach, with C and Python
languages. The failure rate decreased from 85% (2008) to 12% (2014).
The talk will be extensively illustrated with code in C and Python,
addressing the various concepts taught in this course: recursion,
linked lists, queues, stacks, sorting algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-05:europython-2015/data-structures-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>import community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/import-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, is its effort
to improve diversity. The authors will share experiences on diversity
obtained from ten different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil,
Italy, Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada and Spain. There are other
reports, that also we would like to share, which are only beautiful
stories of how Python reaches the most distant people and places you
may never have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest differences, in the Python community, in relation
to other communities, is its effort to improve diversity. There is
even a Diversity Statement at PSF: &amp;quot;We have created this diversity
statement because we believe that a diverse Python community is
stronger and more vibrant. A diverse community where people treat each
other with respect has more potential contributors and more sources
for ideas.&amp;quot; The authors will share experiences on diversity obtained
from ten different countries: Namibia, UK, Japan, Brazil, Italy,
Argentina, Uruguay, Germany, Canada and Spain. There are other reports
that we also would like to share, which are only beautiful stories of
how Python reaches the most distant people and places you may never
have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/import-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Python for Zombies: 15.000 enrolled in the first Brazil...</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/python-for-zombies-15000-enrolled-in-the-first.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiences of how we spread the Python community in Brazil with a non
english MOOC (Massive Open Online Course) to teach programming. Hacking
basic modules and classes to obtain the &amp;quot;Answer to the Ultimate Question
of Life, the Universe, and Everything&amp;quot;. A funny way to teach
programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/python-for-zombies-15000-enrolled-in-the-first.html</guid></item><item><title>Data Structures Discipline with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/data-structures-discipline-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Structures is traditionally a “bogeyman” discipline in Computer
Science courses and has a high degree of failure. In FATEC São José dos
Campos we are adopting a hybrid approach, with C and Python languages.
The failure rate decreased from 85% (2008) to 12% (2014). The talk will
be extensively illustrated with code in C and Python, addressing the
various concepts taught in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:pycon-italia-2015/data-structures-discipline-with-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Python, the next Brazilian generation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/python-the-next-brazilian-generation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python for Zombies is the first MOOC (Massive Open Online Course) in
portuguese. With a team made up of three folks and no budget, we have
reached 30.000 enrollments in one year and half. After having taken the
course, some former girl students even founded the first PyLadies groups
in Brazil, with great impact in diversity (RuPy Natal: 300+ 1/3 women,
Code Girl 2: 700+ 60% women). This MOOC also have a great impact in
Python community: I gave 40 talk’s and short courses in 2014!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fernando Masanori</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:pycon-italia-2015/python-the-next-brazilian-generation.html</guid></item></channel></rss>