<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Colin Gillespie</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Getting the Most Out of Git</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/getting-the-most-out-of-git.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you believe that Git will solve all of your data science worries? Instead, you've been plunged HEAD~1 first into merging (or is that rebasing?) chaos. Issues are ignored, branches are everywhere, main never works, and no one really knows who owns the repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry! There are ways to escape this pit of despair. Over the last few years, we've worked with many data science teams. During this time, we've spotted common patterns and also common pitfalls. While one size does not fit all, there are golden rules that should be followed. At the end of this talk, you'll understand the processes other data science teams implement to make Git work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Colin Gillespie</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/getting-the-most-out-of-git.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Give me the Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/give-me-the-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last 20+ years, I've been reading data into R. It all started with the humble scan() function. Then, I used fancy new-fangled file formats, such as parquet and arrow, before progressing onto trendy databases, such as duckdb, for analytics. Besides the fun you can have by messing around with new technologies, when should you consider the above formats? In this talk, I'll cover a variety of methods for importing data and highlight the good, the bad, and the annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Colin Gillespie</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/give-me-the-data.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>