<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The 3 energy saving tips for your data science ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/the-3-energy-saving-tips-for-your-data-science-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enabling AI is very energy-consuming. Nowadays, many companies turn
their attention toward productionizing machine learning models. However,
the energy efficiency of the models has not been considered as one of
the main quality requirements. In this talk, we outline some energy
efficiency guidelines that you can start using today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploying machine learning models into production can be very energy
costly. For instance, training and hyper-parameter tuning utilize quite
some hardware resources for quite long time intervals. Yet, most
companies do not consider energy efficiency metrics as one of the main
quality attributes of machine learning pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we walk you through some example machine learning
pipelines, which we use to show a couple of energy efficiency
approaches. We explore inefficiency sweet spots in the life cycle of the
models by looking at the utilization rates of the cloud resources.
Finally, we evaluate the effectiveness of our energy efficiency
approaches with regards to other efficiency metrics such as performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data scientists, machine learning engineers, and data engineers can
benefit from this talk by reusing the guidelines in similar use cases.
This talk aims to emphasize the importance of &amp;quot;energy efficiency by
design&amp;quot; in the data science field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fahimeh Alizadeh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-30:pydata-eindhoven-2019/the-3-energy-saving-tips-for-your-data-science-ecosystem.html</guid></item></channel></rss>