<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Agile used to be really cool</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2016/agile-used-to-be-really-cool.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agile software development used to be really cool back in the 00's.
The vision of old school waterfall projects, with months of work
before integrating and releasing software to users gives me the
creeps. But let's return to the present. I can hardly even recall
working in a non-agile project. I feel that most of the Agile
manifesto principles are in my DNA more than a thing to follow. If
you want to keep growing in this industry you might want to start
building on top of that. This presentation contains my experience
about aligning people, sharing a direction, and how servant
leadership works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wojtek Erbetowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-29:pycon-cz-2016/agile-used-to-be-really-cool.html</guid></item><item><title>Designing API for mobile apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2014/designing-api-for-mobile-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Designing API for mobile apps
Prelegent/Speaker: Wojtek Erbetowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide a fair user experience, mobile app’s performance must be well tuned. Loads of work are invested into designing screens to provide fast feedback to end user and make 3rd party services communication as invisible as possible. There is unfortunately a wall, that mobile devs cannot go through - making faster external calls, especially in difficult environment like poor connection quality. But we - backend developers - can minimize that pain, but only as a result of tight cooperation. Presentation contains a ton of knowledge about designing and developing mobile APIs and another ton of experience from the trenches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wojtek Erbetowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-19:pycon-pl-2014/designing-api-for-mobile-apps.html</guid></item><item><title>Good RESTful API documentation is executable</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2014/good-restful-api-documentation-is-executable.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Good RESTful API documentation is executable
Prelegent/Speaker: Wojtek Erbetowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you keep your REST API documented? Online description? Or maybe a spreadsheet/doc? Think about how does your consumer discover it. Poor one is pasting URLs to curl or POSTman, right? And he’s mad as hell, as documentation is out of sync with code as soon as it’s written. Not to mention submitting bugs looks like an email ping-pong. It’s not 2010 any more, you know? Let’s jump into cool tools that will improve your consumers’ life and save you some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wojtek Erbetowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-18:pycon-pl-2014/good-restful-api-documentation-is-executable.html</guid></item><item><title>Zaawansowane testowanie jednostkowe aplikacji Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2013/zaawansowane-testowanie-jednostkowe-aplikacji-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Zaawansowane testowanie jednostkowe aplikacji Django
Prelegent/Speaker: Wojtek Erbetowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Z tak piękną dokumentacją, jaką ma Django wydaje się być niemożliwym aby nie zrozumieć jakim prostym zadaniem jest pisanie testów. Niestety od zrozumienia jak one działają do umiejętności testowania złożonej aplikacji droga jeszcze bardzo długa, a tym gorzej dla nas, że także kręta, z urwiskami po obu stronach.
Na prezentacji dowiesz się rzeczy, których nie znajdziesz na StackOverflow, ani w tutorialach, doświadczeń zbieranych latami na różnych platformach i w różnych językach, wiedzy, którą zbiera się na dnie urwiska po solidnym upadku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2013/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wojtek Erbetowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-18:pycon-pl-2013/zaawansowane-testowanie-jednostkowe-aplikacji-django.html</guid></item></channel></rss>