<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Gajendra Deshpande</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_gajendra-deshpande.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Securing Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2021/securing-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-06-04:/djangocon-europe-2021/securing-django-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding and c) lack of awareness of secure first web …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding and c) lack of awareness of secure first web applications among developers. The vulnerable web applications put the data of the customers at greater risk and the compromised code can lead to problems beyond control. It is very important to develop secure web applications to protect customer data and code to mitigate the risk. In this talk, we will focus on two aspects. First, performing penetration testing on Django web applications to identify vulnerabilities and scanning for Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) Top 10 risks. Second, strategies and configuration settings for making the source code and Django applications secure. We will also discuss the Djangohunter tool to identify incorrectly configured Django applications that are exposing sensitive information.
Outline
1. Security aspects of Django web applications (03 minutes)
2. Penetration testing of Django web applications (07 Minutes)
3. Overview of OWASP Top 10 risks (07 Minutes)
4. Djangohunter tool demonstration (06 Minutes)
5. Strategies and configuration settings to make Django Application secure (07 Minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon Europe 2021"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="DjangoConEU"></category><category term="djangoconeu2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Securing Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/securing-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-23:/djangocon-us-2021/securing-django-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding and c) lack of awareness of secure first web …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding and c) lack of awareness of secure first web applications among developers. The vulnerable web applications put the data of the customers at greater risk and the compromised code can lead to problems beyond control. It is very important to develop secure web applications to protect customer data and code to mitigate the risk. In this talk, we will focus on two aspects. First, performing penetration testing on Django web applications to identify vulnerabilities and scanning for Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) Top 10 risks. Second, strategies and configuration settings for making the source code and Django applications secure. We will also discuss the Djangohunter tool to identify incorrectly configured Django applications that are exposing sensitive information.
Outline
1.      Security aspects of Django web applications (03 minutes)
2.      Penetration testing of Django web applications (07 Minutes)
3.      Overview of OWASP Top 10 risks (10 Minutes)
4.      Djangohunter tool demonstration (06 Minutes)
5.      Strategies and configuration settings to make Django Application secure (10 Minutes)
6.     Conclusion and Questions (04 Minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Security Best Practices for Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/security-best-practices-for-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-18:/djangocon-us-2022/security-best-practices-for-django-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security is of utmost importance to most applications in general and web applications in particular. Django being one of the most popular Python-based web frameworks, applications developed using Django are always on the radar of hackers who try to find the vulnerabilities in the Django application and exploit the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security is of utmost importance to most applications in general and web applications in particular. Django being one of the most popular Python-based web frameworks, applications developed using Django are always on the radar of hackers who try to find the vulnerabilities in the Django application and exploit the same for their benefit. Many times security is ignored or not well done due to a lack of awareness and the cost associated with it. But Security is too costly to be ignored. Although Django has many built-in security features, they are not sufficient to safeguard the application.  The talk begins with highlighting the importance of security and identifying security issues in Django applications using the Mozilla Observatory tool, then using the recommendations of the tool to secure them. Next, I will compare and contrast Mozilla's Web Security recommendations and Open Web Application Security Project(OWASP) Top 10 recommendations. Next, I will discuss built-in security features in Django. Finally, I will discuss the configuration settings and issues that may affect the secure deployment of Django applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline
1. Importance of Security with respect to Web applications (02 Minutes)
2. Identifying security issues using Mozilla Observatory (05 Minutes)
3. OWASP Top 10 issues and how to address them in Django (8 Minutes)
4. Built-in Security features in Django (7 Minutes)
5. Secure Deployment of Django applications (03 Minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Deceptive Security using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/deceptive-security-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/deceptive-security-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deceiving hackers to protect your resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are passing through an unknown street at midnight and you find that some anti-social elements are following you. To save yourself from them you start running and look for a safe place to hide. On the way, you will find a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deceiving hackers to protect your resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are passing through an unknown street at midnight and you find that some anti-social elements are following you. To save yourself from them you start running and look for a safe place to hide. On the way, you will find a good person and requests him to help you. He hides you in his place to protect you. When these anti-social elements visit a good person’s place and enquire about you, the good person misguides them and redirects them to some other place in order to protect you. This is exactly how deception works. In this analogy, YOU are the resources to be protected, anti-social elements are the hackers who want to gain access to the resources, and a good person is a deception technique that protects the resources from hackers by making them fall in the trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk begins with an introduction to deception technology, deception types, and methods, a deceptive security life cycle. In this talk, we will demonstrate the following deception tools implemented using python language:
•       WebTrap (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/IllusiveNetworks-Labs/WebTrap"&gt;https://github.com/IllusiveNetworks-Labs/WebTrap&lt;/a&gt;): is designed to create deceptive webpages to deceive and redirect attackers away from real websites. The deceptive webpages are generated by cloning real websites, specifically their login pages.
•       DemonHunter (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/RevengeComing/DemonHunter"&gt;https://github.com/RevengeComing/DemonHunter&lt;/a&gt;):  is a distributed low interaction honeypot with Agent/Master design
Finally, we will conclude the talk with how built a deception tool and demonstrate its working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we implemented a deception tool in python using machine learning:
We designed a deception tool in python language using PyBRAIN package to model and mitigate XPath injection attacks for web services. It is known that XML can be used to store the data and this data can be queried using XPath query language. XPath is a query language, it has injection issues similar to SQL. To handle this issue, we proposed a solution, which uses a count-based validation technique and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) modular neural networks to identify and classify atypical behavior in user input. Once the atypical user input is identified, the attacker is redirected to fake resources to protect the critical data. Our experiment resulted in over 90% accuracy in the classification of input vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline
1. Introduction to deception, Deception types, Deception technology applicable methods and Deception Life cycle(08 Minutes)
2. Demonstration of WebTrap deception tool(04 Minutes)
3. Demonstration of DemonHunter deception tool(04 Minutes)
4. Discussion of our deception tool and demonstration(06 Minutes)
5. Conclusion and Questions(03 Minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience
No experience level of Python is needed. In general, anyone can attend this talk and learn about applying deception techniques and machine learning to application security.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Beginners"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category><category term="Security"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Build Your First Cyber Forensic Application using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/build-your-first-cyber-forensic-application-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/build-your-first-cyber-forensic-application-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build Your First Cyber Forensic Application using Python
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Ni]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent study by CheckPoint Research has recorded over 1,50,000 cyber-attacks every week during the COVID-19 pandemic. There has been an increase of 30% in cyber-attacks compared to previous weeks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build Your First Cyber Forensic Application using Python
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Ni]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent study by CheckPoint Research has recorded over 1,50,000 cyber-attacks every week during the COVID-19 pandemic. There has been an increase of 30% in cyber-attacks compared to previous weeks. The pandemic has been the main reason for job loss and pay cuts of people and has led to an increase in cybercrimes. Examples of cyber-attacks include phishing, ransomware, fake news, fake medicine, extortion, and insider frauds. Cyber forensics is a field that deals with the investigation of digital crimes by analyzing, examining, identifying, and recovering digital evidence from electronic devices and producing them in the court of law. Python has a great collection of built-in modules for digital forensics tasks. The talk begins with an introduction to digital crimes, digital forensics, the process of investigation, and the collection of evidence. Next, I will cover the various python modules and built-in functions required to build your first cyber forensic application. The modules covered in the discussion are pyscreenshot, PIL, secrets, argparse, hashlib, os,csv, logging, time, sys, stat and NLTK. Finally, I will demonstrate using code walk through the sample cyber forensic application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline
1. Introduction to digital crimes, digital forensics, the process of investigation, and the collection of evidence. (03 Minutes)
2. Setting up Python for forensics application development (02 Minutes)
3. Built-in functions and modules for forensic tasks (05 Minutes)
4. Forensic Indexing and searching (03 Minutes)
5. Forensic Evidence extraction (03 Minutes)
6. Using Natural Language Tools in Forensics (05 Minutes)
7. Code walkthrough of sample forensic application (08 Minutes)
8. Conclusion and Next steps (01 Minutes)
9. Questions and Answers (05 Minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Fighting Money Laundering with Python and Open Source Software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/fighting-money-laundering-with-python-and-open-source-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/fighting-money-laundering-with-python-and-open-source-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — North Hall on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/fighting-money-laundering-with-python-and-open-source-software"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/fighting-money-laundering-with-python-and-open-source-software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk proposal, we will discuss how to detect the chain of fraudulent transactions and help the investigation agencies by providing useful insights to fight money laundering with the help of Python programming language and packages …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — North Hall on 2023-07-21]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/fighting-money-laundering-with-python-and-open-source-software"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/fighting-money-laundering-with-python-and-open-source-software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk proposal, we will discuss how to detect the chain of fraudulent transactions and help the investigation agencies by providing useful insights to fight money laundering with the help of Python programming language and packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Security considerations in Python Packaging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2022/security-considerations-in-python-packaging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-02-06:/pycascades-2022/security-considerations-in-python-packaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Popular programming language index websites (TIOBE index) and developer surveys (Stack Overflow) place Python as one of the fastest-growing programming languages. However, this popularity also puts in the target range of attackers. The attackers perform malicious dependency attacks and use misconfiguration tools to reveal confidential information. Jukka Ruohonen, Kalle …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Popular programming language index websites (TIOBE index) and developer surveys (Stack Overflow) place Python as one of the fastest-growing programming languages. However, this popularity also puts in the target range of attackers. The attackers perform malicious dependency attacks and use misconfiguration tools to reveal confidential information. Jukka Ruohonen, Kalle Hjerppe, and Kalle Rindell in their research paper “A Large-Scale Security-Oriented Static Analysis of Python Packages in PyPI” claimed that they scanned PyPI for security issues in Python packages and found the presence of at least one security issue in about 46% of the Python packages. In addition, security vulnerabilities can be present in the source code of the package. In this talk, we will address the security issues related to python packaging and possible solutions to make python packages secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Security Best Practices for Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/security-best-practices-for-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-18:/pycascades-2023/security-best-practices-for-django-applications.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django being one of the most popular Python-based web frameworks, applications developed using Django are always on the radar of hackers who try to find the vulnerabilities in the Django application and exploit the same for their benefit. This talk will discuss how to secure Django Web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Deceptive Security using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/deceptive-security-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/deceptive-security-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are passing through an unknown street at midnight and you find that some anti-social elements are following you. To save yourself from them you start running and look for a safe place to hide yourself. On the way …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are passing through an unknown street at midnight and you find that some anti-social elements are following you. To save yourself from them you start running and look for a safe place to hide yourself. On the way, you will find a good person and request the person to help you. The person hides you in the secure place to protect you. When these anti-social elements visit a good person’s place and enquire about you, the good person misguides them and redirects them to some other place in order to protect you. This is exactly how deception works. In this analogy, YOU are the resources to be protected, anti-social elements are the hackers who want to gain access to the resources, and a good person is a deception technique that protects the resources from hackers by making them fall in the trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How we implemented deception tool in python using machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;
We designed a deception tool in python language using PyBRAIN package to model and mitigate XPath injection attacks for web services. It is known that XML can be used to store the data and this data can be queried using XPath query language. XPath as a query language, it has injection issues similar to SQL. To handle this issue, we proposed a solution, which uses count-based validation technique and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) modular neural networks to identify and classify atypical behavior in user input. Once the atypical user input is identified, the attacker is redirected to fake resources to protect the critical data. Our experiment resulted in over 90% accuracy in classification of input vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep  4 13:20:00 2020 at Python 2&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2020"></category><category term="GajendraDeshpande"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConAU"></category><category term="PyConline"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Time Series Forecasting Techniques in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/time-series-forecasting-techniques-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/time-series-forecasting-techniques-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Gajendra Deshpande) Time series is one of the important as well as lesser-known fields of machine learning. In time series forecasting we analyze the time-dependent data for predicting long-term and seasonality trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Gajendra Deshpande) Time series is one of the important as well as lesser-known fields of machine learning. In time series forecasting we analyze the time-dependent data for predicting long-term and seasonality trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 14:15:00 2021 at Science, Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="GajendraDeshpande"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Investigating Digital Crimes using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2020/investigating-digital-crimes-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-03:/pycon-es-2020/investigating-digital-crimes-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gajendra Deshpande presents &amp;quot;Investigating Digital Crimes using Python&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the questions about the talk to the original speaker, please, use the following link:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://comunidad.es.python.org/t/investigating-digital-crimes-using-python/372"&gt;https://comunidad.es.python.org/t/investigating-digital-crimes-using-python/372&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
a recent study by the CheckPoint Research has recorded over 1,50,000 cyber-attacks every week during …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gajendra Deshpande presents &amp;quot;Investigating Digital Crimes using Python&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the questions about the talk to the original speaker, please, use the following link:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://comunidad.es.python.org/t/investigating-digital-crimes-using-python/372"&gt;https://comunidad.es.python.org/t/investigating-digital-crimes-using-python/372&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
a recent study by the CheckPoint Research has recorded over 1,50,000 cyber-attacks every week during the COVID-19 pandemic. There has been an increase of 30% in cyber-attacks compared to previous weeks. Cyber forensics is a field that deals with the investigation of digital crimes by analyzing, examining, identifying, and recovering digital evidence from electronic devices and producing them in the court of law. In this talk, we will learn to use Python for the investigation of digital crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---
La octava edición de la PyConES se celebra como un evento en línea y totalmente gratuito durante el día 3 de Octubre de 2020.
Web: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.es.pycon.org/"&gt;https://2020.es.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;
Agenda: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.es.pycon.org/index.html#agenda"&gt;https://2020.es.pycon.org/index.html#agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon ES 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Computation Techniques for Encrypted Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/computation-techniques-for-encrypted-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:/pycon-fr-2019/computation-techniques-for-encrypted-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The session begins with a discussion on homomorphic properties of cryptographic algorithms such as RSA, Elgamal, Paillier, Elliptic Curve and Gentry's Cryptosystems with demonstration. The session discusses the concept of recryption for secure computation. This session also discusses a case study on how machine learning technique can be applied …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The session begins with a discussion on homomorphic properties of cryptographic algorithms such as RSA, Elgamal, Paillier, Elliptic Curve and Gentry's Cryptosystems with demonstration. The session discusses the concept of recryption for secure computation. This session also discusses a case study on how machine learning technique can be applied on encrypted data for secure computation and protecting machine learning model. Finally the utility of homomorphic encryption for block chain will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon FR 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Computation Techniques for Encrypted Data using Python – PyCon Taiwan 2020</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2020/computation-techniques-for-encrypted-data-using-python-pycon-taiwan-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-taiwan-2020/computation-techniques-for-encrypted-data-using-python-pycon-taiwan-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R3 16:15–16:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session begins with a discussion on homomorphic properties of cryptographic algorithms such as RSA, Elgamal, Paillier, Elliptic Curve, and Gentry’s Cryptosystems with the demonstration. The session discusses techniques to reduce computational complexity. This session also discusses a case study on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1, R3 16:15–16:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session begins with a discussion on homomorphic properties of cryptographic algorithms such as RSA, Elgamal, Paillier, Elliptic Curve, and Gentry’s Cryptosystems with the demonstration. The session discusses techniques to reduce computational complexity. This session also discusses a case study on how machine learning techniques can be applied to encrypted data for secure computation and protecting the machine learning model. The talk will include the demonstration of the Python implementation of the RSA algorithm. To demonstrate the techniques to reduce complexity, we will perform multiplication over large random numbers using common * operator, multiplication using FFT, and Karatsuba algorithm. SciPy package has an in-built implementation for FFT. To demonstrate the implementation of secure machine learning model we used PyBRAIN and cryptography packages of python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Gajendra Deshpande holds a masters degree in Computer Science and Engineering and working as Assistant Professor at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, KLS Gogte Institute of Technology, Belagavi, Karnataka, India.  He has a teaching experience of 12 years and a Linux and Network Administration experience of one year. Under his mentor-ship teams have won Smart India Hackathon 2018 and Smart India Hackathon 2019. He is the Technical Director for Sestoauto Networks Pvt. Ltd. and Founder of Thingsvalley. His areas of Interest include Programming, Web Designing, Cyber Security, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Brain-Computer Interface, Internet of Things, and Virtual Reality. He has presented papers at NIT Goa, Scipy India 2017 IIT Bombay, JuliaCon 2018 London, Scipy India 2018 IIT Bombay, Scipy 2019 USA, and PyCon FR 2019, Bordeaux, France.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Build Your First Cyber Forensic Application using Python – Gajendra Deshpande (PyCon Taiwan 2021)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-taiwan-2021/build-your-first-cyber-forensic-application-using-python-gajendra-deshpande-pycon-taiwan-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-02:/pycon-taiwan-2021/build-your-first-cyber-forensic-application-using-python-gajendra-deshpande-pycon-taiwan-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1,  13:05-13:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber forensics is a field that deals with the investigation of digital crimes by analyzing, examining, identifying, and recovering digital evidence from electronic devices and producing them in the court of law. The talk begins with an introduction to digital forensics, the process …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1,  13:05-13:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber forensics is a field that deals with the investigation of digital crimes by analyzing, examining, identifying, and recovering digital evidence from electronic devices and producing them in the court of law. The talk begins with an introduction to digital forensics, the process of investigation, and the collection of evidence. Next, I will cover the various python modules and built-in functions required to build your first cyber forensic application. The modules covered in the discussion are pyscreenshot, Whoosh, PIL, hashlib, mutagen, pyPDF2, and pefile. Finally, I will demonstrate creating small cyber forensic applications using bulit-in modules and functions that are already to known to most of the Python programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides not uploaded by the speaker.
HackMD: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FByfYqeKGt"&gt;https://hackmd.io/&amp;#64;pycontw/2021/%2F%40pycontw%2FByfYqeKGt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Gajendra Deshpande holds a masters degree in Computer Science and Engineering and working as Assistant Professor at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, KLS Gogte Institute of Technology, Belagavi, Karnataka, India. He has a teaching experience of 12 years and a Linux and Network Administration experience of one year. Under his mentor-ship teams have won Smart India Hackathon 2018 and Smart India Hackathon 2019. He is the Technical Director for Sestoauto Networks Pvt. Ltd. and Founder of Thingsvalley. His areas of Interest include Programming, Web Designing, Cyber Security, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Brain-Computer Interface, Internet of Things, and Virtual Reality. He has presented papers at NIT Goa, Scipy India 2017 IIT Bombay, JuliaCon 2018 London, Scipy India 2018 IIT Bombay, Scipy 2019 USA, and PyCon FR 2019, Bordeaux, France.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Taiwan 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - Day 2 AM</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-2-am.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Weiss</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-2-am.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are a ~ 5 minutes long, on any topic of interest to other Python people. It doesn't have to be about something that you wrote, it can be something that you learned, or a technique you think other people will be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:45 - Jeff Weiss …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are a ~ 5 minutes long, on any topic of interest to other Python people. It doesn't have to be about something that you wrote, it can be something that you learned, or a technique you think other people will be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:45 - Jeff Weiss - Teaching Python for Community Outreach (Note: Video begins at ~2:40:00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;06:16 - Jessica David - How staying away from one word can change everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:59 - Roy m Mezan  - Biometric attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15:28 - Gajendra Deshpande - Security Considerations in Python Packaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:32 - Diamond Bishop - Scaling PyTorch Models in Prod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25:44 - Manabu Terada - Our Challeng to spread Python community w/ covid in Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30:59 - Jay Miller - DevRel: showing your company skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;36:29 - Jack Lee - Non-trivial applications of binary search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;41:11 - Henry Schreiner - Scikit-hep: developer pages a guide for modern package development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;46:44 - Chrisjrn - STOP RUNNING YOUR TESTS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Three Musketeers: Sherlock Holmes, Mathematics and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/three-musketeers-sherlock-holmes-mathematics-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/three-musketeers-sherlock-holmes-mathematics-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is a science and one of the most important discoveries of
the human race on earth. Math is everywhere and around us. It is in
nature, music, sports, economics, engineering, and so on. In our daily
life, we use mathematics knowingly and unknowingly. Many of us are
unaware …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is a science and one of the most important discoveries of
the human race on earth. Math is everywhere and around us. It is in
nature, music, sports, economics, engineering, and so on. In our daily
life, we use mathematics knowingly and unknowingly. Many of us are
unaware that forensic experts use mathematics to solve crime mysteries.
In this talk, we will explore how Sherlock Holmes, the famous fictional
detective character created by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle uses Mathematics
and Python programming language to solve crime mysteries. We will solve
simple crime puzzles using mathematics and python scripts. Finally, we
will solve a few complex hypothetical crime mysteries using advanced
python concepts. The participants will learn how to use the concepts of
mathematics such as statistics, probability, trigonometry, and graph
theory, and python and its packages such as SciPy, NumPy, and Matplotlib
to solve the crime puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Securing Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2021/securing-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-02:/pygotham-2021/securing-django-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web
applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons
including a) configuration settings of the web applications b) lack of
implementation of security best practices and secure coding and c) lack of
awareness of secure first web …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web
applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons
including a) configuration settings of the web applications b) lack of
implementation of security best practices and secure coding and c) lack of
awareness of secure first web applications among developers. The vulnerable
web applications put the data of the customers at greater risk and the
compromised code can lead to problems beyond control. It is very important
to develop secure web applications to protect customer data and code to
mitigate the risk. In this talk, we will focus on two aspects. First,
performing penetration testing on Django web applications to identify
vulnerabilities and scanning for Open Web Application Security Project
(OWASP) Top 10 risks. Second, strategies and configuration settings for
making the source code and Django applications secure. We will also discuss
the Djangohunter tool to identify incorrectly configured Django applications
that are exposing sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyGotham 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Education for Generation Z</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2020/python-in-education-for-generation-z.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-25:/pyohio-2020/python-in-education-for-generation-z.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The students who belong to Generation Z or post-millennials have access
to gadgets such as smartphones even before they go to school. This makes
them technology savvy and at the same time they get bored easily in
traditional classroom settings. It becomes necessary to use modern tools
and techniques …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The students who belong to Generation Z or post-millennials have access
to gadgets such as smartphones even before they go to school. This makes
them technology savvy and at the same time they get bored easily in
traditional classroom settings. It becomes necessary to use modern tools
and techniques in the classroom to engage students in activities. Also
governments are promoting “Bring Your Own Device (BYOD)” concept in
education which can be a boon to those who cannot afford a computer or
laptop. In this lightning talk I will introduce the QPython which can be
installed on smartphone to execute Python programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Securing Django Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/securing-django-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/securing-django-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications, b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding, and c) lack of awareness of secure first web …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django is the most popular Python-based web framework used for creating web applications. The web applications are vulnerable for various reasons including a) configuration settings of the web applications, b) lack of implementation of security best practices and secure coding, and c) lack of awareness of secure first web applications among developers. The vulnerable web applications put the data of the customers at greater risk and the compromised code can lead to problems beyond control. It is very important to develop secure web applications to protect customer data and code to mitigate the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will focus on two aspects. First, performing penetration testing on Django web applications to identify vulnerabilities and scanning for Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) Top 10 risks. Second, strategies and configuration settings for making the source code and Django applications secure. We will also discuss the Djangohunter tool to identify incorrectly configured Django applications that are exposing sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security aspects of Django web applications (03 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Penetration testing of Django web applications (07 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of OWASP Top 10 risks (10 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Djangohunter tool demonstration (06 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategies and configuration settings to make Django Application secure (10 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion and Questions (04 Minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks DAY 2 | SciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Pastor Muela</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-2-scipy-2023.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>