<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michael-a-alcorn.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>More than Words: Business Applications of Recurrent Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/more-than-words-business-applications-of-recurrent-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael A. Alcorn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/more-than-words-business-applications-of-recurrent-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recurrent neural networks have recently achieved spectacular results
in many different natural language processing tasks, but their utility
in more practical applications is largely undocumented. During this
talk, you’ll learn about how Red Hat is leveraging the power of
recurrent neural networks to make informed business decisions from
sequential customer data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recurrent neural networks have recently achieved spectacular results
in many different natural language processing tasks, but their utility
in more practical applications is largely undocumented. For companies
that follow a subscription business model, sequential data can often
be found in abundance, seemingly making recurrent neural networks a
perfect fit for many prediction tasks. Unfortunately, resources
describing how to leverage the power of recurrent neural networks in
non-language settings are generally lacking. At Red Hat, we’re using
recurrent neural networks to tackle a number of different business
goals, including predicting customer churn and prioritizing support
cases. During this talk, you’ll learn about Red Hat’s full deep
learning pipeline, from data collection (e.g., mining website logs on
Hadoop clusters and pulling data from SQL databases), to data
preprocessing (e.g., dimensionality reduction in scikit-learn), to
prediction. By the end, you’ll have the foundation necessary to begin
implementing your own recurrent neural network solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>