<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to bootstrap a startup using django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/how-to-bootstrap-a-startup-using-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] J Leidel -P Wassibauer - 3 JULY 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on our (Philipp Wassibauer and Jannis Leidel) experiences building
Gidsy.com this talk will give you valuable insight as to how your
infrastructure will evolve and how to set up the basic components
(Loadbalancer, Webservers, DB, Caching, Celery, CDN, …) of your site.
Outline: Basic project layout - How to handle different configurations
and package your project to make it easy to deploy and install. A basic
timeline of how your infrastructure needs will evolve - Starting from
the initial 1 server setup we will talk about how and when to scale out
your servers. Replicate production environments in development - We
developed a way to have all your services (Webserver, Celeryd, Solr,
Cache, Compass compiler, …) running using one management command.
Setting up Chef recipes to provision your servers. Dealing with cloud
based servers - Tips and tricks on how to manage your cloud based server
using tools like Instagrams ec2-ssh. Automating deploying to a bigger
infrastructure (5+ servers) - Once the infrastructure becomes larger the
deployments become more tedious. There are a few automation tools for
these scenarios like the Etsy Deployinator. Tips on performance - How to
find and remove performance bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">J Leidel</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-04:europython-2012/how-to-bootstrap-a-startup-using-django.html</guid></item></channel></rss>