<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Serverless SQL queries from Python with AWS Athena...or power to Data Scientists!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/serverless-sql-queries-from-python-with-aws-athenaor-power-to-data-scientists.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience&lt;/strong&gt; : beginner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt; The goal of this talk is to explain how Athena, a
serverless sql-like query service provided by Amazon’s AWS, combined
with a Python library called PyAthena, made it possible to store and
query as much data as needed with low costs, high performances and in a
Pythonesque way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt; We found ourselves in a sticky situation: for monitoring
and debugging reasons we had the need to store a large amount of data
(around 200 million rows), trying not to spend the entire year’s budget
but still managing to efficiently query the data in an interactive
setting. With such Big Data, we could not simply resort to Data Science
tools like Pandas and hope for the best. Our first idea was to just
shove it all in our Postgres DB: since both data and database were
stored on Amazon’s AWS infrastructure, all we had to do was to write
ad-hoc import and update queries. Sadly, our poor Postgres machine took
the hit, and was not able to respond to our requirements without greatly
increasing our costs. Then we found out about Athena: a serverless,
Presto-based, sql compliant database, that reads directly from S3
folders and creates a virtual table on which you can run sql queries.
Using Python’s Athena library (PyAthena) our query execution time
dropped from hours to seconds, we simplified the infrastructure and
decreased our costs, without the need to pay and maintain a dedicated
server. In this talk we will show why Athena was the right solution for
our use case and present its Python library with its functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;domenica 22 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniela Scardi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/serverless-sql-queries-from-python-with-aws-athenaor-power-to-data-scientists.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>aws</category><category>storage</category><category>cloud</category><category>sql</category></item></channel></rss>