<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_maciej-dziergwa.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>5 mistakes you will make building a Python Software House</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/5-mistakes-you-will-make-building-a-python-software-house.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maciej Dziergwa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pycon-uk-2016/5-mistakes-you-will-make-building-a-python-software-house.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maciej Dziergwa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005 I became keen on programming in Python, but at the time there were no job opportunities for Python developers in Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I decided to start my own Python Software House, and today I employ more than 200 people, including over 100 Python developers. Over 11 years of experience in company leadership allows me to see this career path from a wider perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize now, how easy it is to make wrong decisions, underestimate threats or undervalue opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will gladly share some lessons learnt from working with more than 100 clients, dozens of Python frameworks, and last but not least, a great number of talented developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Journey from Python Developer to Python Company Owner</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/the-journey-from-python-developer-to-python-company-owner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maciej Dziergwa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-28:europython-2016/the-journey-from-python-developer-to-python-company-owner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maciej Dziergwa - The Journey from Python Developer to Python Company Owner
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/the-journey-from-python-developer-to-python-company-owner"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/the-journey-from-python-developer-to-python-company-owner&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to indicate main keys to success, factors and features
that help a developer to find himself on an independent career path.
How to create employee-friendly work environment for Python developers?
Which business model gives a chance to attract and keep more than 100
Python enthusiast?
I will also gladly share some lessons learned working with dozens of
clients, dozens of Python frameworks, and lots, lots of great
developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago I became a big Python fan, but at the time there were no
jobs for Python developers in Poland. So, I decided to start my own
Python company. Today, ten years later, this company employs more than
100 Python Developers in four cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of Python enthusiasts in the world, many of them more
skilled than I was at that time, but clearly not anyone can become a
„Python Business Developer”. In this talk I would like to indicate
main keys to success, factors and features that help a developer to
find himself on an independent career path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to answear these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to create employee-friendly work environment for Python developers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which business model gives a chance to attract and keep more than 100
Python enthusiast?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also gladly share some lessons learned while working with
dozens of clients, dozens of Python frameworks, and lots, lots of
great developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to become an Agile company - case study</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/how-to-become-an-agile-company-case-study.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maciej Dziergwa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-23:europython-2014/how-to-become-an-agile-company-case-study.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The STX Next story has the classic arc of &amp;quot;zero to hero.&amp;quot; During the
last 9 years, STX Next has grown from a small business with a handful of
developers, to one of the biggest Python companies in Europe, and a
leading proponent of agile and scrum methodologies. We feel that now is
the best moment to share our experiences in implementing effective,
agile development processes in a company of nearly 100 developers.
Maciej Dziergwa will be discussing how he's grown his business, what
challenges there are today in python development, and how he plans to
take his company to the next level. Especially we want to spread our
ideas of building de-localized teams/frequently changing teams/teams
with young members that learn rapidly making synergy effect. Join us
during our Business Day on 23th July 2014! Remember that 2+2 can be much
more than 4...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>