<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Taming Pythons with ZooKeeper</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/taming-pythons-with-zookeeper.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concurrency is hard. Consistency in distributed systems is hard. And
then the whole thing should be highly-available and error resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not, there are good news: There exists an awesome tool called
ZooKeeper to help you with this. There even exists a plethora of Python
libraries for it, but how to know what to use and how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk you through ZooKeeper and how to use it with Python.
We’ll be focusing on what I think is the most prominient ZooKeeper
library out there for Python: Kazoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll see how to do things in ZooKeeper and how to implement them using
Kazoo. We’ll also peek in to the recipes Kazoo offers, and if we have
enough time, touch a real life application we’ve used Kazoo and
ZooKeeper to build at Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/taming-pythons-with-zookeeper.html</guid></item><item><title>PyConSE 2017 Opening</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/pyconse-2017-opening.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/pyconse-2017-opening.html</guid><category>opening</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Solid data structures in Python with logs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/keynote-solid-data-structures-in-python-with-logs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Keynote: Jyrki Pulliainen - Solid data structures in Python with logs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know the classic web application that has a database connected to it. Over time the app grows and we add more bells and whistles, like a search functionality via ElasticSearch. Soon we notice that we need a cache too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have a fairly complex application and a completely new set of problems like the cache invalidation, stale data, consistency issues etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I said that using logs would help you here? This talk looks into using Kafka via Python to build solid data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of the talk outline is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are log based data structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's Kafka and why is it amazing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Kafka via Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demo time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm a content engineer at the music streaming company Spotify. I've been using Python for professional and personal projects for over 10 years now. Over the course of years I've built open-source tools for Python and even contributed to the cpython itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been a part of creating both PyCon Finland and PyCon Sweden. I'm also organising the PySthlm meetups in Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/keynote-solid-data-structures-in-python-with-logs.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>How-To: Build a local Python community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/how-to-build-a-local-python-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jyrki Pulliainen - How-To: Build a local Python community
[EuroPython 2015]
[24 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you like visiting Python conferences like the EuroPython? Does it
make you to want something similar where you live too? This talk looks
into the effort, practical things and some good tips on how to
bootstrap your own Python community where you live!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already run a local Python community, join this talk to share
your views and give your comments to those interested in building
their first Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the talk you have a good idea of what it takes to run your local
Python community (spoiler: not much!) and how can you take it even further!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:europython-2015/how-to-build-a-local-python-community.html</guid></item><item><title>Spotify: Ask us anything</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/spotify-ask-us-anything.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] Jyrki Pulliainen - 4 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-05:europython-2012/spotify-ask-us-anything.html</guid></item><item><title>Spotify, pipelining your music</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/spotify-pipelining-your-music.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] Jyrki Pulliainen - 3 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s current catalog contains 15 million songs. Original storage of
audio and metadata is over 500 terabytes and we’re transcoding 500 000
new audio streams a day. At it’s best the system can make an album
playable just few minutes after it’s delivery. This talk is about
building the music pipeline, all the way from the labels, who deliver
music and metadata XML to our system, to the clients. Problems here are
the concurrency, massive amount of data, enriching the metadata to
provide better quality and to actually deliver 100 gigabytes of indexes
daily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-04:europython-2012/spotify-pipelining-your-music.html</guid></item><item><title>Packaging in packaging: dh-virtualenv</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/packaging-in-packaging-dh-virtualenv.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploying your software can become a tricky task, regardless of the
language. In the spirit of the Python conferences, every conference
needs at least one packaging talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about dh-virtualenv. It's a Python packaging tool aimed for
Debian-based systems and for deployment flows that already take
advantage of Debian packaging with Python virtualenvs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/spotify/dh-virtualenv"&gt;Dh-virtualenv&lt;/a&gt; is an open
source tool developed at Spotify. We use it to ease deploying our Python
software to production. We built dh-virtualenv as a tool that fits our
existing continuous integration flow with a dedicated sbuild server. As
we were already packaging software in Debian packages, the aim of
dh-virtualenv was to make transition to virtualenv based installations
as smooth as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk covers how you can use dh-virtualenv to help you deploy your
software to production, where you are already running a Debian-based
system, such as Ubuntu, and what are the advantages and disadvantages of
the approach over other existing and popular techniques. We will discuss
the deploying as a problem in general, look into building a
dh-vritualenv-backed package, and in the end, look into how
dh-virtualenv was actually made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goal is that after this presentation you know how to make your
Debian/Ubuntu deployments easier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/spotify/dh-virtualenv"&gt;dh-virtualenv&lt;/a&gt; if fully
open sourced, production tested software, licensed under GPLv2+ and
available in Debian testing and unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information of it is also available in our
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://labs.spotify.com/2013/10/10/packaging-in-your-packaging-dh-virtualenv/"&gt;blogpost&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction &amp;amp; overview (3min)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who am I?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why am I fiddling with Python packaging?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you get out of this talk?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different shortcomings of Python deployments (5min)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native system packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtualenv based installations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Containers, virtual machine images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dh-virtualenv (10 min)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is dh-virtualenv?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thought behind dh-virtualenv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advantages over others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements for your deployment flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short intro to packaging Sentry with dh-virtualenv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is it built? (10 min)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debian package building flow primer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How dh-virtualenv fits that flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it do build time and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jyrki Pulliainen</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/packaging-in-packaging-dh-virtualenv.html</guid></item></channel></rss>