<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Plénière n°3 / Keynote #3: The Role of 21st Century Technology in Protests</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/pleniere-ndeg3-keynote-3-the-role-of-21st-century-technology-in-protests.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since June 2019, Hong Kong shocked the world with massive protests. As protesters are mainly young, educated and technology-aware people, they are trying to use the new technology to outwit the government which also use AI and technology to control its people. Who got the upper hand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever think about using Tinder to look for a ‘date’ in the protest? Or using Uber to call for a free ride to drive you to safety?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the talk, we will cover the background of the protest, why it happened and how it is started. We will briefly talk about the politic environment of Hong Kong and what causes the protest 1: the fear of losing a “high degree of autonomy”
In the second part, which is the main part of the talk, we will cover how technology/ apps like Telegram, Tinder, Pokemon Go, Twitch, AirDrop, Bridgefy, Uber, etc were used in by the protesters and what
role they play in the protest. People use Telegram’s encryption to communicate without worrying leaking of identity; they use Tinder to spread the news about where and when to protest; They use Pokemon Go
to gather people 4; AirDrop to spread the message to the Chinese tourists; Bridgefy to communicate where internet is not available at crowded areas 3; Uber to let the protested know where there are
volunteer drivers to take you to safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third part, we will have a look at what technology the Chinese government may use to tighten its grip over Hong Kong. One of the front lines of the protest in the online activism 5, the Chinese
government has it’s own ‘50 cent army’ which is also known as ‘China bots’ who were paid to leave pro-CCP comments on social media. Which eventually cause Twitter and Facebook to shout down lots of accounts. Also, there are attacks cyberattacks, suspected to be related to the protest, towards Telegram and an online forum LiHKG which the protesters used to communicate. It is also suspected that the
government installed ‘smart’ lamppost which use facial detection to monitor the citizen of Hong Kong after protested found parts made by a Shanghai company which also made the surveillance cameras in mainland China 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for audients who are interested to know how our lives are changed by technology and how they could influence our society. By the end of the talk, audients will be more aware of what consequence new technology may bring us and be more thoughtful about the ethics behind the implementation of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:pycon-fr-2019/pleniere-ndeg3-keynote-3-the-role-of-21st-century-technology-in-protests.html</guid></item><item><title>Running An Open Source Project Like A Start Up</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2019/running-an-open-source-project-like-a-start-up.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Cheuk Ting Ho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago, I started an open source project - PicknMIx. It feels like running a start up if you are serious about it. Want to know my story? Want to check if you can do it as well? I will tell you. (Stickers not guaranteed though)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/9ARCJA"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/9ARCJA&lt;/a&gt;
Follow us on Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-09:pycon-de-2019/running-an-open-source-project-like-a-start-up.html</guid></item><item><title>Do we have a diversity problem in Python community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/do-we-have-a-diversity-problem-in-python-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python community cares about diversity. So do we still have a problem in, especially gender, diversity? We will look at some data and see if there’s a true problem, discuss what the problem may be and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-15:pycon-uk-2019/do-we-have-a-diversity-problem-in-python-community.html</guid></item><item><title>If Errol Street Could Talk</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2019/if-errol-street-could-talk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversity statement quoted as follows: &amp;quot;The Python Software Foundation and the global Python community welcome and encourage participation by everyone. Our community is based on mutual respect, tolerance, and encouragement, and we are working to help each other live up to these principles. We want our community to be more diverse: whoever you are, and whatever your background, we welcome you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversity, big deal! As an active members and event organisers (and also on the minority side of the gender) in the Python community, we have alway been concern by the question of: Do we truly have a problem in diversity? Especially, gender diversity. We would like to find out the truth, by data science, and see if we can find a clue why and how we can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will show the research others did regarding the representation of women in the R and Python communities [1]. Then, we will show the research that we did based on our experience and statistic. Including static analysis of the speakers diversity (regarding gender) at major PyCon and PyData conferences. Finally, as we all care about diversity and want improvements, we would like to find out the reason and what we can do about it. We would propose what we, the minorities and allies, could do against this seemingly unbalance situation and make the community better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for all that who cares about diversity in our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://reshamas.github.io/why-women-are-flourishing-in-r-community-but-lagging-in-python/"&gt;https://reshamas.github.io/why-women-are-flourishing-in-r-community-but-lagging-in-python/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-06-16:pylondinium-2019/if-errol-street-could-talk.html</guid></item><item><title>3 things about Chatbot (you don't have to learn it the hard way)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/3-things-about-chatbot-you-dont-have-to-learn-it-the-hard-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am telling you 3 things about Chatbot (so you don't have to learn it the hard way)
Cheuk Ting Ho
Audience level:
Intermediate
Description
Chatbot is cool! Now we can talk to our gadgets as if it’s a real human, right? It also makes you wonder when you chat with the “customer service” online, is that a real person or a robot on the other side? My boss wanted me to build a chatbot, and here’s 3 things that I discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:pydata-london-2019/3-things-about-chatbot-you-dont-have-to-learn-it-the-hard-way.html</guid></item><item><title>Deep Learning with Keras</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/deep-learning-with-keras.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computers are getting closer to speak like humans. But can we even make them speak in particular ways, like as Trump or Shakespeare? In this hands on talk we will see how this is possible with the latest deep learning techniques combined with word embeddings and other advanced NLP technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright belongs to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-09:pylondinium-2018/deep-learning-with-keras.html</guid></item><item><title>Case Study in Travel Business - Understanding agent connections using NetworkX</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-understanding-agent-connections-using-networkx.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network analysis is getting more and more attention in Business
Intelligence, people hope to get information out of the structure of an
organization or a communication network. In this talk, we use the hotel
room search requests from travel agents, including online public
website, B2C, B2B and B2B2C, to build a relational network among them.
By using this network as an example, we demonstrate how insights can be
extract by studying network properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of the talk, we will explain how the network is built
using NetworkX, an open-source python library that is designed for the
creation, manipulation, and study of the structure, dynamics, and
functions of complex networks. When 2 agents are making the same search
at the same time , a link ( or an “edge” in network analysts terms) is
made pointing form the initial searcher to the subsequent searcher.
Using a list of these searches, a directed graph is built. We will also
demonstrate how to pick the biggest connected component out form the
graph. In the second half, with the graphs created, we show how
different functions of NetworkX can be used to study the graphs. By
compare the graph properties of our graph to the other popular network
graphs, we can get the insight of how the network was created. Also by
studying the graphs, we can understand the behavior of the agents and
can even figure out which agents are acting as main hubs in the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people who are interested in network analysis and would
like to see how it can be used in a business case. Audiences with any
level of python experience can learn some basic concept of network
analysis work and how it can be applied to provide business insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-understanding-agent-connections-using-networkx.html</guid><category>Algorithms</category><category>Networks</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest And You Can Have Pythin In Your Language</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/hacktoberfest-and-you-can-have-pythin-in-your-language.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/hacktoberfest-and-you-can-have-pythin-in-your-language.html</guid><category>lightning talk</category></item><item><title>Time Series Analysis with Seasonal Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Case Study in Travel Business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For time series analysis, everyone’s talking about ARIMA or
Holt-Winters. But there’s other models which could also break down a
seasonal series into trend, seasonality and noise. We will use an open
source Python library called Seasonal to analyse B2B worldwide travel
data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-18:pycon-uk-2018/time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Fuzzy Matching - Smart Way of Finding Similar Names Using Fuzzywuzzy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/fuzzy-matching-smart-way-of-finding-similar-names-using-fuzzywuzzy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matching strings should be one of the first natural language processing
problem that human encounter since we start use computer to handle data.
Unlike numerical value which has an exact logic to compare them, it is
very hard to say how alike two strings are for a computer. One may
compare them character by character and have an idea of how many
characters in the pair of stings are the same. Unfortunately in most
application we need computer to perceive strings like we do and
therefore we have to use fuzzy matching. Fuzzy matching on names is
never straight forward though, the definition of how “difference” of two
names are really depends case by case. For example with restaurant
names, matching of words like “cafe” “bar” and “restaurant” are consider
less valuable then matching of some other less common words. Also, do we
consider company names that matches partly (like “Happy Unicorn company”
and Happy Unicorn co.”) are the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of the talk Levenshtein Distance, a measure of the
similarity between two strings, will be explained. Different functions
in Fuzzywuzzy like “partial &lt;em&gt;ratio” and “token&lt;/em&gt; sort_ratio” will also
be explored and compared for difference. It is very important to
understand our tool and choose the right one for our task. Then in the
second half, we will start tackling the example problem: matching
company names, we will show that besides using Fuzzywuzzy, we have to
also handle problem like finding and avoid matching of common words and
speeding up the matching process by grouping the names. By combining all
tricks and techniques that we demonstrate, we will also evaluate how
efficient this method is and the advantage of using this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people in all level of Python experience who would like
to learn a trick or two and would like to be able to solve similar
problems in the future. Theory of how the library works will be
explained and It is easy to be pick up even for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/fuzzy-matching-smart-way-of-finding-similar-names-using-fuzzywuzzy.html</guid></item><item><title>Launch Jupyter to the Cloud: an example of using Docker and Terraform</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-an-example-of-using-docker-and-terraform.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of reasons using a cloud service is favorable, but how to
make sure consistency between development and deployment? With Docker,
we can &amp;quot;ship&amp;quot; the project to different platforms in the same
environment. Going one step further we can also create the cloud
infrastructure as code with Terraform. As an example, we will deploy a
Jupyter notebook on Google Cloud Platform using both tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-07:pydata-berlin-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-an-example-of-using-docker-and-terraform.html</guid></item><item><title>Launch Jupyter to the Cloud with Docker and Terraform</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-with-docker-and-terraform.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launch Jupyter to the Cloud: an example of using Docker and Terraform&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will use a task: hiring a GPU on Google Cloud Platform to train neural network, as an example to show how an application can be deployed on a cloud platform with Docker and Terraform. The goal is to have Jupyter Notebook running in an environment with Tensorflow (GPU version) and other libraries installed on a Google Compute Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people with no experience in application deployment on cloud service but would benefit form computational reproducibility and cloud service, potentially data scientists/ analysts or tech practitioners who didn't have a software developing background. We will use an example that is simple but useful in data science to demonstrate basic usage of Docker and Terraform which would be beneficial to beginners who would like to simplify their work flow with those tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-05:pycon-israel-2018/launch-jupyter-to-the-cloud-with-docker-and-terraform.html</guid><category>jupyter</category><category>docker</category><category>terraform</category></item><item><title>Case Study in Travel Business - Time Series Analysis with Seasonal Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For time series analysis, everyone's talking about ARIMA or Holt-Winters. But there's other models which could also break down a seasonal series into trend, seasonality and noise. We will use an open source Python library called Seasonal to analyse B2B worldwide travel data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/case-study-in-travel-business-time-series-analysis-with-seasonal-data.html</guid></item></channel></rss>