<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Recursion for Beginners: A Beginner's Guide to Recursion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/recursion-for-beginners-a-beginners-guide-to-recursion.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between unintelligible algorithms and beautiful fractal artwork,
recursion has an intimidating reputation. But the underlying ideas
behind it are simple. This tutorial presents a quick intro of recursive
code, Python's features for handling recursion, and drawing fractals
with the turtle module. If you've ever thought &amp;quot;recursion is confusing&amp;quot;,
this tutorial is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-03:north-bay-python-2018/recursion-for-beginners-a-beginners-guide-to-recursion.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks Day 3 Round 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/lightning-talks-day-3-round-2.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amjith Ramanujam</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/lightning-talks-day-3-round-2.html</guid></item><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Tackling Recursion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2018/a-beginners-guide-to-tackling-recursion.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between unintelligible algorithms and beautiful fractal artwork,
recursion has an intimidating and even mystical reputation. But the
underlying ideas behind it are simple. In this tutorial we get a solid
foundation of recursive code, and run through several examples in the
interactive shell. If you've ever said or thought the words &amp;quot;recursion
is confusing&amp;quot;, this tutorial is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-28:pyohio-2018/a-beginners-guide-to-tackling-recursion.html</guid></item><item><title>Logging and Testing and Debugging, Oh My!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2017/logging-and-testing-and-debugging-oh-my.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Logging messages, unit tests, and using the debugger are best practices, but often left out of introductory programming tutorials. As a result, beginners come away with the idea that these time-saving features are somehow &amp;quot;advanced&amp;quot; or things to be learned later on. In this presentation, Al Sweigart dispels these notions by providing quickstart guides to Python's logging, doctest, and pdb modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logging messages, unit tests, and using the debugger are best practices, but often left out of introductory programming tutorials. As a result, beginners come away with the idea that these time-saving features are somehow &amp;quot;advanced&amp;quot; or things to be learned later on. In this presentation, Al Sweigart dispels these notions by providing quickstart guides to Python's logging, doctest, and pdb modules, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why beginners (incorrectly) avoid these programming best practices.
The &amp;quot;if you're doing this&amp;quot; signs that you aren't using these best practices.
The 4 lines of code you need from the logging module.
The 4 lines of code you need from the doctest module.
The 2 lines of code you need from the pdf module.
How much time you'll save, not spend, by using these not-so-advanced modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al Sweigart is the author of several programming books, including Automate the Boring Stuff with Python. He releases all of his books online for free under a Creative Commons license. He lives in San Francisco, and his cat weighs 12 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-13:pybay-2017/logging-and-testing-and-debugging-oh-my.html</guid></item><item><title>STDIO Game Jam</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2017/stdio-game-jam.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oakland's video game museum will host a hackathon to create small, complete game programs that beginners can read. These text-based games only use stdio, so they're easy for beginners to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-11:pybay-2017/stdio-game-jam.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>BayPIGgies April 2017 talk: Annual PyCon Preview</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/baypiggies-april-2017-talk-annual-pycon-preview.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Video courtesy of our meeting host, LinkedIn.
1. Automate AWS With Python - Moshe Zadka
AWS is one of the best-known cloud vendors. Using the Web UI is fine when starting out, but automating cloud operations is important. Boto3 provides a great Pythonic API to AWS, but using it correctly can be subtle.
The talk will cover how to automate AMI builds, building Cloud Formation Templates and automating S3 bucket management.
Speaker Bio
Moshe has been involved with Python since 1998, when he helped obsolete math-related modules. Since then, he made some contributions that were not just deleting code to core Python, and has been a contributor on the Twisted project since its inception.
Abstract
2. Yes, It's Time to Learn Regular Expressions - Al Sweigart
Regular expressions have a reputation as opaque and inscrutable. However, the basic concepts behind &amp;quot;regex&amp;quot; and text pattern recognition are simple to grasp. This talk is for any programmer who isn't familiar with Python's re module and its best practices. Stop putting it off, it's time to learn regular expressions!
Speaker Bio
Al Sweigart is a software developer and the author of Automate the Boring Stuff with Python, Invent Your Own Computer Games with Python, Making Games with Python &amp;amp; Pygame, and Hacking Secret Ciphers with Python. These books are freely available under a Creative Commons license at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://inventwithpython.com"&gt;http://inventwithpython.com&lt;/a&gt;.
Al enjoys haunting coffee shops, writing educational materials, cat whispering, and making useful software. He lives in San Francisco.
3. Type uWSGI; press enter; what happens? - Asheesh Laroia and Philip James
You're a pretty knowledgeable Python web application developer, but how does that web application get served to the world? For many of us, uWSGI is the magic that makes our application available, and in this talk we'll look at how uWSGI works with the OS and the networking stack to make the magic happen.
Speaker Bios
Asheesh Laroia
By day, Asheesh Laroia is a member of the technical staff at Sandstorm in Palo Alto. By night, he is volunteer President at OpenHatch, helping create workshops that teach students how to get involved in open source. His technical background touches machine learning, security, and linguistics. He helped start the Boston Python Workshop for women and their friends, has been teaching Python to newcomers since 2004, including at Noisebridge and the EFF, and has advised user groups on how to make their events more newcomer-friendly and gender-diverse.
Philip James
Philip James is a Software Engineer at Stripe, a Civic Technologist and a Director for the City of Alameda Democratic Club and the East Bay Young Democrats. In his free time he builds ContactOtter, a smart address book you can share.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Moshe Zadka</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-27:bay-piggies/baypiggies-april-2017-talk-annual-pycon-preview.html</guid></item><item><title>Yes, It's Time to Learn Regular Expressions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/yes-its-time-to-learn-regular-expressions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular expressions have a reputation as opaque and inscrutable.
However, the basic concepts behind &amp;quot;regex&amp;quot; and text pattern recognition
are simple to grasp. This talk is for any programmer who isn't familiar
with Python's re module and its best practices. Stop putting it off,
it's time to learn regular expressions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pycon-us-2017/yes-its-time-to-learn-regular-expressions.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks May 19th, 2017 Evening session</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/lightning-talks-may-19th-2017-evening-session.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks 2017-05-19 Evening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="12%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="23%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="65%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Start&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Speakers&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head" rowspan="2"&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;0:55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;Katy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emoji Archeology 101 - A lightning talk cover&lt;/strong&gt;
- A call to revolution against the Unicode emoji.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;5:55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Daniel Whitenack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking Over the Data World with Containerized&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;
- Using Kubernetes cluster with Pachyderm.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;11:20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Fang-Pen Lin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugbuzz - A modern web-based debugger for Python&lt;/strong&gt;
- Adding just a couple lines triggers a web based
debugger with basic functionality.  Uses PubNub.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;16:45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Kojo Idrissa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineering for Beginners&lt;/strong&gt;
- Focus on common tools like version control, in-code
documentation, testing &amp;amp; TDD, dependency management &amp;amp;
deployment, and finally OS stuff.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="8"&gt;21:50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="8"&gt;Cameron Dershem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Level Development:  What Python Should&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Learn From Rust&lt;/strong&gt;
- Please learn From Rust. Rust is the best community.
Devs are on chat and enforce good attitude; cool thank
you page; roadmap; 'how should this be taught' section
in RFCs; mentorship for starter maintainers; great
opensource book.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;26:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Al Sweigart&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Do PyCon&lt;/strong&gt;
- Skip talks and meet people; use shirt trick; don't
eat alone; Twitter is great for followup.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;31:53&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Myron Walker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faking Python Imports&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fake for modules and callables not available on test
environment. Use directory of local fakes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;35:12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Vince Salvino&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help Wanted: A PyPI Vulnerability DB&lt;/strong&gt;
- Like WPScan, it would be nice to a central DB and
tool for known PyPI security issues. Talk to me.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;37:50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Lev
Konstantinovskiy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same Content, Different Words&lt;/strong&gt;
- Is 'Ice cream' the same as 'Gelato' in different
reviews? Use Word Mover's Distance in GenSim to find
out.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;43:20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Mario&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Randomize Your Decisions&lt;/strong&gt;
- We spammed ourselves by having too many alerts, had
hacked users, bugs everywhere, bad SEO. Still, it was
worth making a website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;48:30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;Tim Head&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Optimization: Coffee&lt;/strong&gt;
- Tweak settings with Bayesian Optimization, easily.
Made scikit-optimize with simpler calls than scikit-
learn.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;53:35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;Meg Ray&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching Python to Children&lt;/strong&gt;
- Use both teacher pedagogy and developer technical
skills to train K-12 teachers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katie McLaughlin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-19:pycon-us-2017/lightning-talks-may-19th-2017-evening-session.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Automating Your Browser and Desktop Apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of data on the web and in your desktop apps, but accessing it can involve a lot of tedious typing and clicking. This talk is an introduction to the Selenium and PyAutoGUI modules, with live demos straight from the interactive shell. Al Sweigart explains web scraping techniques and programmatically controlling the keyboard and mouse to automate these tasks for you.
​
Abstract
The internet and personal computer are central tools in many jobs, including professions outside of engineering. This makes web scraping and GUI automation are relevant to not just developers and QA testers, but academics, organizers, and office workers. This talk is an introduction to Selenium and PyAutoGUI modules. and programatically controlling your browser and desktop applications from Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web scraping and GUI automation frameworks have an intimidating reputation for a steep learning curve. While they do have many sophisticated features, the basics that most folks will ever need can be covered in a single presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation has multiple live demos to showcase these modules straight from the interactive shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content from this talk is derived from Automate the Boring Stuff with Python, a beginner's Python book freely available under a Creative Commons license at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://automatetheboringstuff.com"&gt;https://automatetheboringstuff.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;
Al Sweigart is a software developer and the author of Automate the Boring Stuff with Python, Invent Your Own Computer Games with Python, Making Games with Python &amp;amp; Pygame, and Hacking Secret Ciphers with Python. These books are freely available under a Creative Commons license at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://inventwithpython.com"&gt;https://inventwithpython.com&lt;/a&gt;. Al enjoys haunting coffee shops, writing educational materials, cat whispering, and making useful software. He lives in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/al-sweigart-automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/al-sweigart-automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-21:pybay-2016/automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps.html</guid></item><item><title>Automating Your Browser and Desktop Apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2015/automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of data on the web and in your desktop apps, but accessing
it can involve a lot of tedious typing and clicking. In this talk Al
Sweigart explains web scraping techniques and programmatically
controlling the keyboard and mouse to automate these tasks for you.
Covers the Selenium and PyAutoGUI modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-01:pyohio-2015/automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Automating Your Browser and Desktop Apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps-by-al.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automating Your Browser and Desktop Apps by Al Sweigart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is an introduction to using the Requests, Beautiful Soup,
Selenium, and PyAutoGUI modules in order to automatically grab data from
the web or interact with desktop applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to download files and pages from the web How to use CSS selectors to
find content in a web page How to control a web browser from Python
using Selenium How to programmatically control the keyboard and mouse
The content from this talk is derived from Al Sweigart's book, Automate
the Boring Stuff with Python, which is freely available under a Creative
Commons license at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://automatetheboringstuff.com"&gt;http://automatetheboringstuff.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HHCL/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HHCL/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Al Sweigart</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-19:djangocon-us-2015/automating-your-browser-and-desktop-apps-by-al.html</guid></item></channel></rss>