<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Debugging Tips and Tricks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2016/debugging-tips-and-tricks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;발표자: Roy Hyunjin Han / rhh
슬라이드:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slides.com/invisibleroads/debugging-tips"&gt;https://slides.com/invisibleroads/debugging-tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roy Hyunjin Han</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-apac-2016/debugging-tips-and-tricks.html</guid></item><item><title>How Python is guiding infrastructure construction in Africa (#84)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/how-python-is-guiding-infrastructure-construction.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How Python is guiding infrastructure construction in Africa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Roy Hyunjin Han (InvisibleRoads)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whirlwind tour of the roles of different Python modules in the
architecture of a geospatial infrastructure planning system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used Python to transform an elaborate, multistep process for finding
and connecting households in villages into a single, streamlined
planning experience. I'll explain how Python's freely available
libraries empowered a small team of developers under a minimal budget
and timeframe. Now just imagine if we had to do the same thing with
Java.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roy Hyunjin Han</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/how-python-is-guiding-infrastructure-construction.html</guid><category>africa</category><category>casestudy</category><category>infrastructure</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Parallel Computing on an NVIDIA GPU using PyCUDA</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--introduction-to-parallel-computing-on.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Parallel Computing on an NVIDIA GPU using PyCUDA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Roy Hyunjin Han&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Andreas Klöckner's PyCUDA, you can harness the massively parallel
supercomputing power of your NVIDIA graphics card to crunch numerically
intensive scientific computing applications in a fraction of the runtime
it would take on a CPU and at a fraction of the development cost of C++.
We'll cover hardware architecture, API fundamentals and several examples
to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two approaches to parallelizing a computationally heavy
procedure: use a messaging queue such as AMQP to distribute tasks among
a networked cluster or increase the number of processors in a single
machine. This talk focuses on techniques for adapting mathematical code
to run on specialized multi-core graphic processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern graphic processors have hard-coded transistors for common vector
and matrix operations, making them ideal for general scientific
computing. However, the NVIDIA CUDA's unique design requires knowledge
of its hardware to adapt algorithms effectively. This talk covers basic
CUDA architecture, API functions and several examples to illustrate the
different kinds of problems that will benefit from parallelization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roy Hyunjin Han</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--introduction-to-parallel-computing-on.html</guid><category>nvidia</category><category>parallel</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>pycuda</category></item><item><title>34. CrossCompute is a web platform where users can run algorithms</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/34-crosscompute-is-a-web-platform-where-users-ca.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you developed a mathematical model or computational / visualization
algorithm? Your algorithm could be useful worldwide to people who face a
real- world problem but do not want to write code. Professionals in
industry, scientists in other fields or researchers in developing
countries can quickly apply your work to their domain with a web-based
cloud-computing platform like CrossCompute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CrossCompute is a site where you can run mathematical models and
algorithms submitted by researchers. If you are a researcher and you
submit your algorithm, you'll get paid each time it runs. We'll send you
a URL where users can run your model on their data as many times as they
want. More users mean more feedback that you can use to improve your
model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example: Suppose a mathematician in the US develops an
operations research model for placing schools in a community given the
locations of existing schools and households, and decides to charge ten
cents each time it runs. Then a business owner in Ghana runs the model
over the internet to place stores in his district, and saves money
because he didn't have to hire a consulting firm or buy a software
package. Meanwhile, the mathematician in the US uses the algorithm
revenue to fund research to improve the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is an exciting time to get involved in data analytics for your city
or local government. Governments need to prioritize limited resources
like emergency response firefighters, police officers and city
inspectors. I urge you to contact your local Mayor's office to learn
about the challenges they are facing. Then, create a tool to make their
life easier. You can send the tool to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:support&amp;#64;crosscompute.com"&gt;support&amp;#64;crosscompute.com&lt;/a&gt; where it
will join a growing collection of analytics for the public good. You
will get the credit for the algorithm, the revenue and users from around
the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roy Hyunjin Han</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-11:pycon-us-2012/34-crosscompute-is-a-web-platform-where-users-ca.html</guid></item></channel></rss>