<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Transfer learning for image recognition in healthcare industry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/transfer-learning-for-image-recognition-in-healthcare-industry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transfer learning is a powerful technique to boost the performance of a
deep learning model. However, the healthcare industry often has very
specific image data sets that are dissimilar to the large-scale data
sets used to pretrain the publicly available models. Therefore, are
there any benefits of applying transfer learning in healthcare? Come and
listen to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of transfer learning is to reuse features learned on a related
task to improve the performance of a model on a new task. The advantages
of transfer learning are well known: faster training, less labeled data
needed and higher accuracy of the final model. Therefore, the use of
pretrained models became a de facto standard in many practical
applications, among others in computer vision. This is all under the
assumption that the features learned on the source task are generic
enough to be reused on a target task. However, the healthcare industry
often has very specific data sets that are rather dissimilar to the
large-scale and publicly available data sets used to pretrain the
models. The goal of the presentation is to show if there are any
advantages of using pretrained models in such settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, we have designed a dedicated experiment in which we compare
the performance of various CNN architectures applied to different
medical imaging data sets, both public and private. We initialize the
models either randomly or with ImageNet pretrained parameters with
various settings. We also compare the results to the performance of a
small, custom designed CNN networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will have the following outline. First, the audience
will be introduced to the transfer learning and its variants. Later, the
design of the dedicated computational experiments will be presented,
followed by the results and conclusions. The latter will be compared to
the conclusions from the latest state of the art papers on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants will have a unique opportunity to learn about the
benefits and pitfalls of applying transfer learning to imaging data sets
that are much more specific than natural images from ImageNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background knowledge required to understand the presentation:
intermediate knowledge about machine learning, deep learning and CNNs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Kierzynka</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-12:pydata-warsaw-2019/transfer-learning-for-image-recognition-in-healthcare-industry.html</guid></item></channel></rss>