<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Developer to Manager</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/from-developer-to-manager.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Developer to Manager by Sean O'Connor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developers move along in their career, they are often encouraged to take on roles that involve more and more people management and less code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping towards management often can be a good move to make, but it is not one that should be taken lightly. If such a move is taken without a full appreciation for what it truly is (a career change), it can lead to woe and misery for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll follow one developer's journey from coding 40 hours/week to primarily managing humans. What worked well, what didn't work well, what was hard, and what was surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees of this talk should expect to walk away with a better idea of if they may be suited for management and if so, how they can successfully acclimate to their new role.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sean O'Connor</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:djangocon-us-2016/from-developer-to-manager.html</guid></item><item><title>A Tour of Large-Scale Data Analysis Tools in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/sarah-guido-sean-oconnor-a-tour-of-large-scale-data-analysis-tools-in-python-pycon-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Sarah Guido, Sean O'Connor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large-scale data analysis is complicated. There’s a limit to how much data you can analyze on a single box, but it is relatively inexpensive to get access to a large number of commodity servers. In this tutorial, you’ll learn how to leverage the power of distributed computing tools to do large-scale data analysis quickly and affordably using pure Python, Hadoop MapReduce, and Apache Spark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sarah Guido</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-09:pycon-us-2016/sarah-guido-sean-oconnor-a-tour-of-large-scale-data-analysis-tools-in-python-pycon-2016.html</guid></item><item><title>From Developer to Manager</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/sean-oconnor-from-developer-to-manager-pycon-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sean O'Connor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developers move along in their career, they will often be given the chance to move into management. This can be great, but it can also end in tears. In this talk we'll follow one developer's journey into management. Through that process we'll explore what one should think about before embarking on their own journey as well as some lessons for those who do decide to go down the management path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pycon2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides"&gt;https://github.com/PyCon/2016-slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sean O'Connor</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-31:pycon-us-2016/sean-oconnor-from-developer-to-manager-pycon-2016.html</guid></item><item><title>Failing With Grace</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2014/failing-with-grace.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges of building distributed systems is dealing
with failure. In this talk we'll cover a number of approaches and tools
to help you build systems that deal with failure as gracefully as
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sean O'Connor</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-09-16:pygotham-2014/failing-with-grace.html</guid></item><item><title>Domain Specific Frameworks - Why they rock and what can we do to get more of them</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--domain-specific-frameworks---why-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of some of the existing domain
specific frameworks (DSFs) in the Python/Django world, review some of
the common patterns used within them, and then explore some things which
can be done to make it easier for people to create and maintain DSFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a growing collection of tools such as Celery, ImageKit, and
Piston which fall into a weird but wonderful space between utility
libraries and full fledged applications. Much like Django, DSFs (domain
specific frameworks) provide more structure and have more opinion than
utility libraries, but remain focused on providing developer instead of
end-user level functionality. Unlike Django, DSFs focus on solving a
very specific set of specific problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of some of the existing DSFs in the
Python/Django world, review some of the common patterns used within
them, and then explore some things which can be done to make it easier
for people to create and maintain DSFs. Two of the DSFs to be discussed
include Celery and ImageKit. Some of the patterns to be reviewed include
registration, backends, and framework integration/independence. Finally,
the future facing discussion will explore possible tools to make DSF
building easier and steps general purpose frameworks (Django) can take
to ease integration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sean O'Connor</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-08:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--domain-specific-frameworks---why-.html</guid><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2010</category><category>domainspecificframeworks</category><category>dsf</category></item><item><title>How to make running a user group feel like cheating</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2010/djangoconeu-seanoconnor982flv.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sean O'Connor</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-05-24:djangocon-europe-2010/djangoconeu-seanoconnor982flv.html</guid></item></channel></rss>