<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rapid development &amp; integration of Real Time Communication in Websites</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2013/rapid-development-integration-of-real-time-communication-in-websites.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Online shopping or retail industry of the world is worth trillions of
dollars. Forrester research estimates that US online industry alone
will be worth $279 Billion by 2015!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Given the scenario, website customers have an ever-growing need of
communicating with customer service representatives in real time with
a live chat or media call. Businesses can not only view it as an
opportunity to act quickly and be flexible in delivering specific
product information to customers but also to prevent or recover from
service failures &amp;amp; convert leads to sales!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though critical, development teams have found it difficult to develop,
maintain and integrate instant chat or media calls in their websites.
Unavailability or shortage of ready-to-use frameworks has contributed to
longer development cycles and made the task seam out-of-reach. As a
result, real time communication in websites is often considered
‘good-to-have’ and doesn’t get the due importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses about development &amp;amp; integration of real-time
communication applications in websites. Audiences would get an
opportunity to appreciate the concept with the help of a working
prototype. The talk also suggests Python modules for getting the task
done in a rapid &amp;amp; customised way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chetan Giridhar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-08-31:pycon-india-2013/rapid-development-integration-of-real-time-communication-in-websites.html</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting memory mysteries of Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2013/dissecting-memory-mysteries-of-python-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Memory leak has been perennial problem for Python applications. This
causes application to behave erroneously with Memory error and very slow
operation. What is wrong with the application? How to find out the cause
and fix it? This is the motivation for this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64; Kiwi PyCon 2013 - Saturday, 07 Sep 2013 - Track 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a dynamically typed language. Applications leave task of
object memory management to Python VM. Python automatically manages
memory using reference counting and garbage collection. But, Python
memory manager may bloat the VM size, and sometimes it may consume
complete main memory. It causes applications to deliver low performance
and encounter unexpected memory errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk dissects the internals of CPython memory manager, its
limitations and negative impact on application behavior. We demonstrate
the problem of memory leaks by learning Python heap pattern, object
graphs and memory profiling. Next, we suggest solutions to reduce memory
footprints of applications, tools to diagnose and fix memory leaks and
lesson learned as best development practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/vishal-kanaujia-dissecting-memory-mysteries-of-python"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/vishal-kanaujia-dissecting-memory-mysteries-of-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chetan Giridhar</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-09-12:kiwi-pycon-2013/dissecting-memory-mysteries-of-python-0.html</guid></item><item><title>Rapid development of Unified Real-time communication for Websites</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2013/rapid-development-of-unified-real-time-communicat.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Development of real time communication channels like instant chat or
media calls has been difficult. Integrating it in a scalable and
responsive way for websites has been a bigger concern. This talk
describes how instant chat or media calls can be developed in a rapid
way with Python modules and demonstrates the concept with a working
prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64; Kiwi PyCon 2013 - Sunday, 08 Sep 2013 - Track 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online shopping or retail industry of the world is worth trillions of
dollars. Forrester research estimates that US online industry alone will
be worth $279 Billion by 2015!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the scenario, website customers have an ever-growing need of
communicating with customer service representatives in real time with a
live chat or media call. Businesses not only view it as an opportunity
to act quickly and be flexible in delivering specific product
information to customers but also to prevent or recover from service
failures &amp;amp; convert leads to sales!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though critical, development teams have found it difficult to develop,
maintain and integrate instant chat or call in their websites.
Scalability and responsiveness of these applications have been a measure
cause of anxiety. Unavailability or shortage of ready-to-use frameworks
has contributed to longer development cycles and made the task seam
out-of-reach. As a result, integration of real time communication in
websites is often considered 'good-to-have' and doesn't get the due
importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses first hand experiences of development &amp;amp; integration
of real-time communication applications in websites. Audiences would get
an opportunity to appreciate the concept with the help of a working
prototype. The talk also suggests Python modules foe getting the task
done in a rapid &amp;amp; customized way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/chetan-giridhar-rapid-development-of-unified-real-time-communication-for-websites"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/chetan-giridhar-rapid-development-of-unified-real-time-communication-for-websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chetan Giridhar</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-09-12:kiwi-pycon-2013/rapid-development-of-unified-real-time-communicat.html</guid></item></channel></rss>