<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jozef-van-eenbergen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Amanda: A New Generation of Distributed Services Framework</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/amanda-a-new-generation-of-distributed-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jozef van Eenbergen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/amanda-a-new-generation-of-distributed-services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help create award winning visual effects, MPC developed a distributed
service-oriented platform, Amanda. Amanda allows developers of any level
to write a service that is presented to users across 8 facilities
globally without them requiring any knowledge of building large
concurrent systems. It allows artists and developers across different
domains to work with clearly defined API's and gives the service
developer control over what and how data can and should be accessed. The
talk will cover how to set up such a platform from the ground up.
Starting at the service level building it out with additional modules
and technologies until the fully distributed system, covering topics
such as concurrency, componetisation and monitoring that allow the fine
tuning of setups depending on the type of work being undertaken and
changing business needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll start off with a quick overview of a movie production pipeline
which will set the stage for how Amanda provides artists with the tools
they need to develop and streamline the production process as well as
Amanda's crucial function as a robust framework for the support and
development teams. Going over some stats, up to 250.000 service calls a
minute during World War Z for example (for frame of reference this is
twice the average rate of stackoverflow.com), I'll highlight some of the
problems encountered with the 1st generation. Initially developed in
2007 and replaced last year it had several flaws in regards to
scalability, maintainability and future proofing. From there I'll
introduce the 2nd generation which is build on the principle of
componentisation and building blocks. Every part of the system needs to
be replaceable and this needs to be possible from the configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the presentation we will be stepping through the different
building blocks, how they have been set up, how they slot together and
how we monitor, trace and test the system from the ground up. Starting
at the lowest level with services we'll slowly step through the
different blocks necessary to build a fault tolerant, distributed and
scalable platform. We made sure that the platform is not tied into any
specific technology but allows the use of the best technologies
depending on the type of work being undertaken and changing business
needs and technological advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="service-development-and-testing"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Service development and testing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our development teams build applications for artists creating visual
effects through to management teams coordinating productions. A
service-based architecture was chosen to provide consistent interfaces
across the many different environments where this is required. We
provide an ecosystem where developers of any level can safely write a
service (a set of instructions regarding a specific topic) that are
presented to developers and technical artists globally. To write a
service the developer doesn't need any knowledge in regards to building
large concurrent systems. The service is implemented through a simple
Python API and the provided ecosystem allows services to exist in a
standalone manner. The service concept was separated from the platform
hosting it. This allows hosting in any application that provides a
standard container (a service provider). Extracting this allowed for
more rigorous and simple testing of services; it also allows developers
to provide fake versions of their services publicly against which client
code can be tested. The adage ʻeverything as a serviceʼ was applied to
the development of internal facilities. This includes our management
tools and the developer console, which presents the documentation of
services and methods available to developers through a web interface.
Infrastructure services were introduced to present an interface to
facilities provided to a regular service, for example databases,
configuration and centralized logging. Services can call other services
and, similarly to infrastructures, services can be replaced with
different services depending on the configuration. Services are exposed
to a service (or client as we will see later) via a service provider
just like in applications. Setting services up with the above patterns
allows developers to iterate quickly and to include services within
testing frameworks. It has also provided a standardized form across
projects allowing developers to support and add to unfamiliar code
easily. And last but not least it has given us full abstractions at all
levels, users of services do not need to know the code underneath the
hood be it at a service level or at an infrastructure level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="building-the-cluster"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Building the cluster&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than building a single system, the new architecture defines a set
of building blocks for constructing a distributed service platform.
These can provide adapters for best of breed third party tools or, where
necessary, custom implementations of functionality. Configuration is
used to determine the number and types of modules to use and the
parameters with which to initialize them. This allows the same platform
to be used for small instances at a developerʼs desk up to a production
environment of many nodes. The design enables improved components to be
swapped into the existing system whilst forming the basis for an
entirely new design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most practical applications require the service provider to handle
multiple requests at the same time. Amanda provides a set of
interchangeable concurrency modules. This allows the most appropriate
Python model for parallel processing to be chosen. For work involving
heavy I/O work we choose approaches that avoid waiting for the GIL, for
example multiple processes and greenlets/coroutines, whilst for CPU
bound work we can use threads which may prove more performant. Having
the option to choose between mechanisms is important since there is not
a solution that neatly fits all use cases. A pluggable concurrency
abstraction also allows integration of new libraries as they become
available. In future this might include the new asyncio (formerly Tulip)
core library for Python 3.3+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To benefit from concurrency, resource pooling, caching etc. we don't
always want to execute the service locally to the service provider.
Service proxies implement this behavior; they take the service, method
and arguments of a request as their input and return the result. The
proxy should be transparent to the service and service provider
components. By chaining proxies, complex routing schemes can be built or
analysis performed on the results returned. Some similarity can be drawn
with middle-ware in the Web Services Gateway Interface (WSGI)
specification. Communication between proxy and service provider is
served by the transport. This abstraction provides an asynchronous
interface to underlying technologies – Current implementations include
queue based AMQP, ontop of RabbitMQ, and ØMQ and more naïve
communications with standard UDP and TCP sockets. Most transports define
both client and server parts of the system – however some,
particularly HTTP-based transports, are designed to accept requests
directly from external clients. Requests from external applications
commonly use XMLRPC, JSONRPC or straight JSON. Transport implementations
can be interchanged without impacting other components of Amanda or
service developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In production, a request gateway implemented as a WSGI application
fronts the HTTP protocols. Using the standard web components NGINX and
μWSGI we can build a very scalable front end which internally uses the
service provider, proxy, transport pattern to offload the requests to a
backend. The gateway can also provide standard web facilities such as
template rendering (through the Jinja2 library1) for general web
clients. The gateway was a requirement as requests originate from
applications written in many languages including C++, Python, JavaScript
and domain specific languages such as mel. For us it was important that
the client used across all those languages was a proven standard and
lightweight. Most requests are served in near realtime (6ms round trip
times) and are presented to the client in a synchronous way so using a
frontend that supports a large number of HTTP like protocols allowed us
to keep the clients simple and present the platform to an extremely wide
variety of languages. Additionally, through the frontend, we can render
a web page and present that directly if the requests was made from a
browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final behavior of the platform is defined in configuration. This
allows the platform to be tuned to suit the work that a particular
service is performing (I/O vs CPU bound). It is important to remember
that every single component mentioned above be it the concurrency,
transport, proxies or frontend can be changed, removed, updated without
it impacting the service, the developer or any of the other components
that make up the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also important to mention that internally and externally everything is a
queue and presented as a queue. Going from the client to the frontend
there is a queue, from the frontend onto the backend there is a queue
etc. all the way down to a request being read of the transport and
stored inside a queue until a concurrency object is ready to handle the
request with the service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where we think our platform might take a different approach.
Rather than building the platform on top of a single great technology we
didn't want to limit ourselves and be able to use all the other great
technologies out there. There is no perfect solution for all problems
but allowing to fine tune the platform according to different problems.
The setup can now evolve in line with technological advancements and
changes to the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="maintenance-and-monitoring-5-mins"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Maintenance and Monitoring (5 mins)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will walk through how we are using the same setup with services,
service providers, proxies and transports to manage clusters around the
globe. Once again for our maintenance and monitoring we made sure
everything is done as a service so that if there is a better tool in the
future we could adopt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through leveraging the configuration management and remote execute
platform Salt, a new cluster can now be provisioned quickly. Management
is itself provided as a service. Through this system, the current state
is available and configuration changed across all servers globally. This
has reduced routine maintenance tasks from a half day to a five-minute
task, with less chance of human error. Monitoring and introspection are
provided, as a service, to aid in day-to-day support, tuning and to help
support analysis for future development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers of services can trace requests from when they enter the
system, producing a report of the sequence of methods being called, with
the supplied arguments. For each call the time spent to fulfill each
request is presented. Care was taken to minimize the impact of this on
return result of the request. Due to everything being a queue we can
collect the metrics after the result has been put back onto the
transport and send to the user and thus minimize the impact of this
collection on returning the result of the request This means that there
is no requirement to put the system into a debug mode in order to obtain
execution metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With logging being a service we can dynamically change the logging
configuration on a per service basis by making a request to the logging
service taking away the need of changing configuration and restarting
the service which often means a problem might have disappeared due to
the reset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="future-conclusion-1-min"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Future/Conclusion (1 min)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst developing the new generation of the platform there have been a
number of possible applications that have emerged. The way in which we
are able to scale the system would be suitable to run in a cloud
environment – especially with the improvements to management allowing
new nodes to be provisioned quickly. The ease of writing and integrating
new components would allow integration with infrastructure provided by
third-party cloud vendors. Other areas of interest include a smaller
version of the platform running locally on a userʼs workstation and
services for management of generic processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="main-technologies-and-libraries-currently-used"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main technologies and libraries currently used:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gevent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventlet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiprocessing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZeroMQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uwsgi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flask&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nginx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>