<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python for Text Analysis Kaggle Competition</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/python-for-text-analysis-kaggle-competition.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the recent Home Depot Search Relevance Kaggle competition
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/home-depot-product-search-relevance"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/c/home-depot-product-search-relevance&lt;/a&gt;) as an
example, this talk will give a general overview of a predictive
analytics project in python, specifically focusing on text analytics.
This talk will first give an introduction to Kaggle and this
competition in particular. To give an introduction to predictive
analytics, I will then show how to start designing &amp;quot;features&amp;quot; which
describe the similarity of two samples of text. Using a very simple
feature, the number of overlapping words, we can build our first
simple predictive model. Building on this base, we'll then explore
more advanced text mining techniques, such as term frequency matrices,
TF-IDF, Latent Semantic Analysis, and word2vec. Finally, we can see
how the final random forest model performs and what the most important
features were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've delivered this presentation in 30 minutes at a work event
already. I can tweak the talk to focus less on the introduction to
predictive analytics and more on the text analytics methods if that
would be a better fit for the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">John Savage</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-05:pycon-ireland-2016/python-for-text-analysis-kaggle-competition.html</guid></item></channel></rss>