<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Leksikov Sergey</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_leksikov-sergey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Practical usage of python ecosystem to build the AI ​​model to fight</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/practical-usage-of-python-ecosystem-to-build-the-ai-model-to-fight.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leksikov Sergey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/practical-usage-of-python-ecosystem-to-build-the-ai-model-to-fight.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use diverse python libraries such as Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, and TensorFlow from data processing to data visualization to fight the Covid-19 disease spread. Besides, by using the Deep Learning python-based framework TensorFlow we have built an Artificial Intelligence system to analyze and predict covid risk infection under various …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use diverse python libraries such as Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, and TensorFlow from data processing to data visualization to fight the Covid-19 disease spread. Besides, by using the Deep Learning python-based framework TensorFlow we have built an Artificial Intelligence system to analyze and predict covid risk infection under various circumstances. Artificial Intelligence is used for generating and interpolating from low-resolution to high-resolution data for various conditions of the experimental setup, particle distribution estimation, and risk infection prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Data Science"></category></entry><entry><title>Automating CLI commands execution with LLM and LangGraph</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2024/automating-cli-commands-execution-with-llm-and-langgraph.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leksikov Sergey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-10-26:/pycon-korea-2024/automating-cli-commands-execution-with-llm-and-langgraph.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full Title: Automating CLI commands execution with LLM and LangGraph: A new frontier in Python automation&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2024"></category></entry></feed>