<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Computer Vision: Creating a complex color polling project using Python, OpenCV and Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/computer-vision-creating-a-complex-color-polling-project-using-python-opencv-and-raspberry-pi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be talking about creating a computer vision classroom color poll
sheet recognition project using Python, OpenCV and raspberry Pi.
Specifically, looking at detecting color poll-sheets in a classroom of
about 50 - 150 students. Much like how one can poll an audience of
people using a clicker technology and show the results of the audience
with regards to a question asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience is anyone interested in computer vision, what computer
vision can do and achieve, as well as the hard work required to make
it all happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the talk the audience can have a glimpse into what it takes to
create a computer vision project, as well as the typical process and
algorithm one would follow in a simple task of creating a computer
vision project using python, opencv and raspberry pi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few aspects I will cover include:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer vision goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified overview of the algorithm used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going into a bit of detail where the challenges arise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example of the the project i worked on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results achieved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few global interesting projects around computer vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will end with a look into the python code involved and talk through
the results of the polling program, as well as any hard to detect areas
and how the system detects these. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Irikidzai Muchaneta</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-07:pycon-za-2016/computer-vision-creating-a-complex-color-polling-project-using-python-opencv-and-raspberry-pi.html</guid></item><item><title>Say Hello to the new wave of software bots...</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/say-hello-to-the-new-wave-of-software-bots.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, really, say &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; to them. The age of voice enabled interfaces
is already upon us with the rise of driverless cars, ubiquitous
technology and the Internet of Things(IoT), computers no longer need
to speak in code but they have learnt to speak the human language.
Google home is a voice-activated speaker powered by the google
assistant similar to other assistants namely Siri, Alexa and Cortana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will be looking at developing and deploying Actions
(Conversations) on the Google home assistant. This will be done by
creating an application (web hook) triggered by an action created in
API.AI using a python template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience is anyone interested in creating bots using API.AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone interested in adding customized actions to the google
assistant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone interested in learning about voice enabled actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific aspects I will cover include: - Reasons, voice enabled
interfacing is an interesting topic to follow - Simplified overview of
the steps to create custom &amp;quot;conversation actions&amp;quot; - Going into a bit of
detail where the challenges arise - Examples of cool projects out there
currently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will end with a look into creating your first simplified google
&amp;quot;conversational action&amp;quot; in hopefully less than 10 minutes once all the
prerequisite software is installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen...the software bots have risen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Irikidzai Muchaneta</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:pycon-za-2017/say-hello-to-the-new-wave-of-software-bots.html</guid></item></channel></rss>