<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jiri-benes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Reliability in distributed systems</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/reliability-in-distributed-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jiri Benes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/reliability-in-distributed-systems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is your system stable? Do you know what happens if any of your system’s
dependency will start failing? Do you even know what exactly each part
of your system does or did any time in the past? Or how fast you will
identify root of the problem in case your system goes down at 2am?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk focuses on distributed systems (microservices, APIs that
communicate with databases, memory, third party services, etc.),
monitoring, their failures and recovery in order to help you answer
yourself questions above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First part aims on importance of monitoring such systems on several
levels - monitoring of hardware, application monitoring, monitoring from
outside of the systems, detecting malfunctions based on anomalies within
system’s data flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second part presents several standard techniques for preventing system
failure in case of outage of dependency and technique how to recover
from inconsistent state after outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content of presentation is helpful and interesting for beginners and
intermediates. Senior developers and developers working on reliable
distributed systems should bear in mind content of this presentation and
master shown techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>