<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Package and distribute your Python code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2013/package-and-distribute-your-python-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, you've written your nifty, super-useful Python package. Now what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session intends to to teach the attendee everything about
packaging, documenting and distributing a Python package. Starting with
packaging basics, OS-specific packaging, specifying package
dependencies, including proper metadata, naming and versioning to
finally distributing the package on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150105080641/https://pypi.python.org/"&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt;,
at the end of the session the attendee's package will be easily
installable using tools like pip and easy_install. The talk will also
emphasize on including proper tests for the package. The modules
primarily used are distutils/distutils2 (2.x), packaging (3.x). The talk
will also feature an introduction to build-systems like
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150105080641/http://www.buildout.org/"&gt;Buildout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sanket Saurav</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-08-31:pycon-india-2013/package-and-distribute-your-python-code.html</guid></item><item><title>Django on Steroids -- Lessons from Scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pune-2017/django-on-steroids-lessons-from-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk summarizes my learnings (best practices and gotchas) by using
Django as the core application engine in a production application for
the past two years at DoSelect. I’ll discuss about the common, and
&lt;em&gt;not-so-common&lt;/em&gt; patterns you should take care of when you hit scale with
Django, complete with real- life scenarios. Topics include
(non-exhaustive) – production server configuration, best practices when
using Django as provider for an SPA (Single-page app), caching, query
optimization while using the ORM, gotchas while using async tasks, et
al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is intended for people who have a basic knowlegde of Python /
Django, know how web applications work in general. Key take-aways would
be things you can directly drop into your production Django application
for better performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-usual-suspects"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Usual Suspects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuning your web server configuration (using Nginx and Gunicorn as
example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caching whatever you can, but no more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to write Django ORM queries that scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When NOT to write Django ORM queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Async tasks while maintaining data consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-non-usual-suspects"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Non-usual Suspects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Django with an SPA front-end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scaling Postgres while scaling Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optmizing async task runners (more stuff to be added)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will include real-world code examples while illustating the
points above – explaining what we faced in production, and how we solved
it (and then realized that’s what we should have done in the first
place). I plan to have a bit longer Q&amp;amp;A session, due to the nature of
this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sanket Saurav</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-17:pycon-pune-2017/django-on-steroids-lessons-from-scale.html</guid></item></channel></rss>