<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stephen-j-turnbull.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Where we came from, what’s special about now, and where we might go</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/where-we-came-from-whats-special-about-now-and-where-we-might-go.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephen J Turnbull</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-13:pycon-ca-2016/where-we-came-from-whats-special-about-now-and-where-we-might-go.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on interviews with leading developers of Python and with Python,
we take a look at how the Python language specification and the
reference implementation are developed. The subcommunity of core
developers not only produces a great programming language that's fun to
use, but sets the tone for a vibrant, productive, and inclusive
community of user-developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="stephen-j-turnbull-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stephen J Turnbull Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Known as the Unwelome Guest on several channels because he professes the
Dismal Science of Economics, Steve nonetheless has found a ray of light
among the zero-profit theorems: open source software and the communities
that develop, support, and use it. He teaches in Japan, where he learned
the virtues of Unicode from living in an environment with 5 different
encodings (and many nonstandard variants) in use for the same language.
He was introduced to Python development during the discussion of PEP 263
(which appropriately enough allows you to be explicit about encoding of
Python programs), when he was turned into a newt by none other than GvR
for the sin of misusing the word &amp;quot;pythonic&amp;quot;. (It got better!) He mentors
in GSoC for Systers &amp;amp; GNU Mailman, and spends what's left of his free
time fighting DMARC to make the Internet safe for mailing lists again.
He's also been know to write Emacs Lisp (ssh! it's a dirty secret!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>