<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Kathy Keating</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kathy-keating.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Growth Mode Playbook for Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/the-growth-mode-playbook-for-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kathy Keating</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/the-growth-mode-playbook-for-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we want to survive and thrive in our roles as developers, there are skills beyond coding that will make us most effective in our roles. These skills are the ones that will help us get promoted, and be seen as highly valuable within our organizations. They are especially …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we want to survive and thrive in our roles as developers, there are skills beyond coding that will make us most effective in our roles. These skills are the ones that will help us get promoted, and be seen as highly valuable within our organizations. They are especially valuable to learn as the companies around use grow - really fast. In this talk, I’ll share my top 10 skills that I practice every day, and encourage my teams of developers to embrace, so that we can all thrive as we, and our companies grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>