<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python 103: Memory Model &amp; Best Practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/python-103-memory-model-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a growing crowd of Python users who don't consider themselves beginners anymore. However some users at this stage discover odd behavior that's hard to explain. Why doesn't code behave like it should? Why doesn't &amp;quot;correct&amp;quot; code execute correctly? We'll focus on Python's object &amp;amp; memory model, addressing these issues directly. Let's empower attendees to not create these bugs to begin with!
​
Abstract
In &amp;quot;Python 101,&amp;quot; you learned basic Python syntax. In &amp;quot;Python 102&amp;quot; (or equivalent in experience), you went further, exploring Python more deeply -- creating/using classes, decorators, files, other standard library or 3rd-party modules/packages -- and graduated from being purely a beginner. Because Python has been around the block for quite awhile now, there is a continuously growing number of &amp;quot;Python 103&amp;quot; programmers out there. Many are no longer new to the language, however, they have run into various issues, bugs, or odd behavior in their code that is difficult to explain. It's time to take a closer look. This is an interactive best practices talk, focusing on how Python objects, references, and the memory model work as well as thinking about performance. Knowing more about how the interpreter works under the covers, including the relationship between data objects and memory management, will make you a much more effective Python programmer, and the (main) goal with the knowledge imparted in this talk is to empower developers to not (inadvertently) create certain classes of bugs in their code to begin with! All you need to bring is the desire to learn more about the interpreter to take your Python skills to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;
Wesley J Chun is the author of the bestselling Core Python titles and the Python Fundamentals Live Lessons companion video. He is coauthor of Python Web Development with Django (withdjango.com), and has written for Linux Journal, CNET, and InformIT. Wesley is an architect and Developer Advocate at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/wesley-chun-python-103-memory-model-and-best-practices"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/wesley-chun-python-103-memory-model-and-best-practices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-20:pybay-2016/python-103-memory-model-best-practices.html</guid></item><item><title>What is Google App Engine?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google App Engine is a unique hosting platform that lets you build
applications and run them in Google's data centers using the massive
global infrastructure built to run the Internet's most powerful company.
App Engine offers a development environment that uses familiar
technologies (Java and Python) and provides a powerful and robust set of
APIs to users while maintaining security and independence from other
apps running in the cloud. It is always free to get started so you can
try it out with no risk, and if you need additional computing resources,
you can purchase additional computing resources beyond the free quota
limits. (If you enable billing and trust us with your credit card, we
will extend your free quotas even further; you won't get charged until
you exceed those &lt;em&gt;extended&lt;/em&gt; quotas.) Scale your application to millions
of users and pay only for what you use at competitive market pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we provide an update of the newest features found in
the most recent releases of the App Engine platform. We also share some
suggestions for best practices to existing App Engine developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners to the App Engine platform will be interested in the
introductory workshop which may be offered (see description below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google App Engine workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we'll give you a comprehensive introduction to the
platform in two/three components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-hour Introduction to Cloud computing and Google App Engine seminar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-hour App Engine hands-on workshop/codelab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first hour, we review Cloud Computing as an industry and where
Google App Engine fits into the picture. Specifically, we discuss App
Engine as a PaaS solution because of the inherent challenges of building
web and other applications. We'll outline the architecture of App
Engine, what it's major components are, introduce its features and APIs,
discuss the service and how it works (including information on the free
quotas), present some information about current users and usage,
including integration with Google Apps, and finally, give an overview of
its enterprise edition called Google App Engine for Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the approximately one-hour lecture, we'll show you how to create
applications that run on App Engine by building a simple but real web
application from the ground up via a hands-on coding laboratory.
Although based on the online tutorial, this codelab goes up and beyond
what's in the documentation: you will get a more detailed step-by-step
instructions to replicate that example as well as have the opportunity
to extend your application with some of the newer APIs that come with
App Engine. The codelab will cover the Users service, non-relational
Datastore, and Memcache APIs. Time-permitting, we'll also discuss some
of the newest features found in recent App Engine releases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html</guid><category>architecture</category><category>cloud</category><category>google</category><category>hosting</category><category>infrastructure</category><category>memcache</category><category>security</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Python 103: Mmmm... Understanding Python's Memory Model, Mutability, and Methods</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/python-103-mmmm-understanding-pythons-memory.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Python 101, you learned basic Python syntax, what its flow control
mechanisms and basic data types are and how they work. You learned how
to write functions and developed executable Python scripts that actually
work! You probably also learned how to create files, how to open, read
from or write to them, and close them. Perhaps you've even learned a
little bit of object- oriented programming, developed a couple of Python
classes, most with user- defined methods, and have no problems creating
instances to use in your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Python 102 (or equivalent in experience), you explored further, using
default values and variable arguments for functions, discovered how to
catch exceptions and write handlers for them… perhaps you've even
created your own exceptions. You have found some useful Python standard
library modules and using them actively in your own applications. You've
quite comfortable with OOP, creating classes and using instances
regularly in your programs. In fact, you've been coding Python for 6
months to a couple of years now. You're much more serious about Python
now because you're no longer a &amp;quot;beginner.&amp;quot; You've even taken notice at
the growing number of jobs requesting or requiring Python skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring Python developer, you are starting to be more aware of
the entire ecosystem around you, and think you may be ready for
&amp;quot;prime-time&amp;quot; and feel able to take on a full-time position as a Python
programmer. However, if you have experienced one or more of the below
questions or problems, this talk may be for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throughout this time, you've experienced strange bugs in your code.
In particular, you notice that things don't always behave the way you
expect and have spent a good amount of time debugging various parts
of your software that you thought were actually correct - you work
around them but are disturbed and don't have the time nor committment
to fully investigate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You've created classes and objects just fine but wish that you could
use some of Python's operators (like +, in, len(), etc.) with your
objects, which feel like they're &amp;quot;2nd-class&amp;quot; citizens compared to the
standard data types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you know what functional evaluation strategy means? Have you been
asked or considered whether Python is &amp;quot;call-by-value&amp;quot; or
&amp;quot;call-by-reference&amp;quot;? It is important to you, and can you clearly
explain your answer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does &amp;quot;mutability&amp;quot; mean? What is the difference between mutable
and immutable objects? Which Python objects are mutable and which
aren't?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you clearly explain both the output in the two code snippets
below, and even more importantly, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; the output is the way it is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SNIPPET A x = 42 y = x x += 1 print x print y&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SNIPPET B x = [1, 2, 3] y = x x[0] = 4 print x print y&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you seen odd behavior in container or collection objects like
lists or dictionaries? For example, you may have copied those types
of objects and discovered weird things happening to both the original
and the copy, or that you seen something not quite right if you loop
through it and remove items from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what Python 103 is for… to fill in all the missing gaps, to
answer all the questions (including those above) that do not seem to
have easy-to-find answers on Google, but only if you have the desire to
learn more about the interpreter to take your Python skills to the next
level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/python-103-mmmm-understanding-pythons-memory.html</guid><category>debugging</category><category>exceptions</category><category>memory</category><category>scripts</category></item><item><title>Using Python in Software for the Medical Industry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/using-python-in-software-for-the-medical-industry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The medical industry has long been dominated by custom software written
by manufacturers of medical equipment. With the widespread use of
lower-cost computing power and abundance of software developers using
cost-beneficial open source development tools, it is no surprise that
this is a rapidly- growing field in software engineering. In this talk,
I will describe some of my experiences using Python and other open
source tools, temporarily transitioning from the world of the web and
Internet development, jumping into the medical industry, an experience
much like being a fish out of water. The experiences of working in this
field, specifically developing software for use in clinical trials. We
describe the use of open source tools for such software development, the
required integration with closed-source software, and the documentation
rigor that is necessary in a field under the jurisdiction of the US Food
and Drug Administration (FDA). In particular, I'll describe direct
experience in building an application for the use of analyzing spinal
fractures and the various tools that make up the application suite,
whose primary development language was Python. We will also discuss the
particular role of the my employer at the time in the clinical trials
process and elaborate on the data flow that was necessary for all
medical applications developed at the firm, not just the one in
particular.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/using-python-in-software-for-the-medical-industry.html</guid><category>documentation</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Python 3: the Next Generation (is here already)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/python-3-the-next-generation-is-here-already-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is currently at a crossroads: Python 2 has taken it from a quiet
word- of-mouth language to primetime, with many companies around the
world using it and an ever-increasing global marketshare of the
programming world. But now comes Python 3, the first version of the
language that is not backwards compatible with previous releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? Are all my Python programs going to break? Will I
have to rewrite everything? How much time do I have? When is Python 2
going to be EOL'd? Is the language undergoing a complete rewrite and
will I even recognize it? What are the changes between Python 2 and 3
anyway? Also, the next generation is already here, as Python 3 is over
two years old now. What has been ported so far, and what is its current
status? Are migration plans or transition tools available? If I want to
start learning Python, should I do Python 2 or Python 3? Are all Python
2 books obsolete?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will attempt to answer all of these questions and more. Join us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OUTLINE/TOPICS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2 vs. Python 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Python 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backwards Compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generational Changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role of Remaining Python 2.x releases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transition &amp;amp; Migration Plans &amp;amp; Tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Futures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/python-3-the-next-generation-is-here-already-0.html</guid><category>learning</category><category>migration</category><category>python,</category></item><item><title>Writing Books using Python &amp; Open Source Software</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/writing-books-using-python-open-source-software.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 20 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of us are familiar with using open source tools to develop software
applications with, but instead of writing code, it is also possible to
create the manuscript of a book in very much the same way. These days,
authors have many choices in terms of the tools which are available to
aid them in writing a book. Gone are the times when the only option is
using a proprietary word processor, so why not try it using open source
tools? It's especially attractive to those who develop software using
open source tools as well those who are writing books about open source
tools. Both code and the written word are created in plain text files.
These files are easily archived using some version control system. They
can be shared easily via e-mail and can also be backed up in the same
manner. In the end, the final product is shipped to the customer: in the
case of software, it's distribution via CD or DVD, or perhaps a release
for installation on a server, and for a book, it's delivering a
manuscript to the publisher, perhaps in a format such as HTML or PDF®.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon some reflection, writing a book is, in many ways, similar to
writing an application: you create text or code which is saved to a file
(or files- typically one but could be more) file in some format,
proprietary or otherwise. Additions, changes, or deletions are made to
the file(s), which is then updated when the file is (re)saved. Backups
need to be made, some versioning may be required to keep track of
multiple files during the course of development, and finally, the
resulting file(s) have to be delivered, as described above. Because of
all the similarities described, we assert that it is possible to use a
development environment utilizing Python and other open source tools to
not only write application with, but also be able to create the entire
manuscript for a book as well! While this entire concept should not
really be mind-blowing, it does represent a trend seemingly growing in
popularity in the open source world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, we highlight the following requirements that are
necessary when creating a manuscript, especially with co-authors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versioning and Backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated Testing of Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML/PDF® Generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we highlight one particular case study, the development of
Addison Wesley's 2009 publication, &amp;quot;Python Web Development with Django&amp;quot;,
as well as provide some insight into other projects created using
similar tools. Open source software has radically affected how
applications are built today, and this phenomenon has the ability to
affect the book publishing world in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/writing-books-using-python-open-source-software.html</guid><category>cd</category><category>html</category><category>testing</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>PyCon 2009: Internet Programming with Python (Part 1 of 3)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--internet-programming-with-python--pa0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet Programming with Python (part 1 of 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Wesley J. Chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial introduces current Python programmers to 3-4 distinct
areas of Internet programming, each in self-contained (approximately)
1-hour lectures (unless otherwise noted) with a demonstration of code on
each lecture topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-02-17:pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--internet-programming-with-python--pa0.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2009</category><category>tutorial</category><category>webprogramming</category></item><item><title>PyCon 2009: Internet Programming with Python (Part 3 of 3)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--internet-programming-with-python--pa1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet Programming with Python (part 3 of 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Wesley J. Chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial introduces current Python programmers to 3-4 distinct
areas of Internet programming, each in self-contained (approximately)
1-hour lectures (unless otherwise noted) with a demonstration of code on
each lecture topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-02-17:pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--internet-programming-with-python--pa1.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2009</category><category>tutorial</category><category>webprogramming</category></item><item><title>PyCon 2009: Internet Programming with Python (Part 2 of 3)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--internet-programming-with-python--par.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet Programming with Python (part 2 of 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Wesley J. Chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial introduces current Python programmers to 3-4 distinct
areas of Internet programming, each in self-contained (approximately)
1-hour lectures (unless otherwise noted) with a demonstration of code on
each lecture topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-02-17:pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--internet-programming-with-python--par.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2009</category><category>tutorial</category><category>webprogramming</category></item><item><title>Python 3: The Next Generation (#48)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--python-3--the-next-generation---48.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3: The Next Generation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Wesley J. Chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about the evolution of Python. We will discuss Python 2 and
Python 3: what the compatibility issues are, what the main differences
are, and also talk about migration, Python 2.6, and other transition
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--python-3--the-next-generation---48.html</guid><category>2to3</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Writing Books using Python and Open Source Software (#40)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/writing-books-using-python-and-open-source-softwa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing Books using Python and Open Source Software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Mr. wesley j. chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, there are countless number of software applications and web
services that have been developed using free and open source software
(FOSS). Such tools have become so flexible, powerful, and universal,
that it should also be possible for authors to write manuscripts using
open source tools like Python in the same way that applications are
developed. In this talk, we present some case studies of this
phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/writing-books-using-python-and-open-source-softwa.html</guid><category>documentation</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>tools</category></item><item><title>Python 3: the next generation is here already</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/python-3-the-next-generation-is-here-already.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3: the next generation is here already&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by wesley chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about the evolution of Python. We will discuss Python 2 and
Python 3: what the compatibility issues are, what the main differences
are, and also talk about migration, Python 2.6/2.7, and other transition
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is currently at a crossroads: Python 2 has taken it from a quiet
word- of-mouth language to primetime, with many companies around the
world using it and an ever-increasing global marketshare of the
programming world. But now comes Python 3, the first version of the
language that is not backwards compatible with previous releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? Are all my Python programs going to break? Will I
have to rewrite everything? How much time do I have? When is Python 2
going to be EOL'd? Is the language undergoing a complete rewrite and
will I even recognize it? What are the changes between Python 2 and 3
anyway? Also, the next generation is already here, as Python 3 is over
two years old now. What has been ported so far, and what is its current
status? Are migration plans or transition tools available? If I want to
start learning Python, should I do Python 2 or Python 3? Are all Python
2 books obsolete?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will attempt to answer all of these questions and more. Join us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OUTLINE/TOPICS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2 vs. Python 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Python 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backwards Compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generational Changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role of Remaining Python 2.x releases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transition &amp;amp; Migration Plans &amp;amp; Tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Futures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/python-3-the-next-generation-is-here-already.html</guid><category>2to3</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>python2</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Running Django Apps on Google App Engine</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/running-django-apps-on-google-app-engine.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running Django Apps on Google App Engine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by wesley chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, Django users couldn't run apps unmodified on Google App
Engine. Some tools helped with integration but required you to change
your data models. Django-nonrel removes this requirement letting you run
native Django apps on App Engine with only config changes if you bear in
mind its restrictions like no JOINs. In this talk, we'll discuss
Django-nonrel &amp;amp; porting App Engine apps to Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, Django users could not get their apps to run unmodified on
Google App Engine, the cloud application-hosting platform. Older tools
like &amp;quot;the Helper&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;the Patch&amp;quot; required a change to the data models
as well as perhaps integrating additional tools into the application
source tree. The creators of the Patch realized how cumbersome this is
and created a replacement for all of these older tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django-nonrel allows users to run pure Django apps on App Engine with
only minor configuration changes. It basically enables Django's ORM to
operate on top of non-relational databases (in addition to preserving
its ability to support standard relational DBs), one of which is Google
App Engine's Datastore. (MongoDB is another.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means that current Django users can now use their existing
knowledge to write apps for App Engine as long as they keep App Engine
restrictions in mind, e.g., no JOINs. Projects written in this manner
will work without any modifications other than changing the
configuration settings. On the other side, App Engine developers now
have an alternative to the '&amp;quot;webapp&amp;quot; framework that comes with its SDK.
You can now leverage the power of a full web framework like Django and
still enjoy the flexibility and scalability of App Engine. In this talk,
we'll discuss Django-nonrel, and how to port App Engine apps from webapp
to pure Django to run on App Engine using Django-nonrel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/running-django-apps-on-google-app-engine.html</guid><category>django-nonrel</category><category>gae</category><category>googleappengine</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Sunday evening</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/sunday-evening-lightning-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday evening lightning talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=0m"&gt;00:00&lt;/a&gt; - Python 3 on your Atari Desktop - Jeffrey
Armstrong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=4m58s"&gt;04:58&lt;/a&gt; - Armstrong, Open Source News Platform - Joshua
Bonnett&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=9m34s"&gt;09:34&lt;/a&gt; - Metrics should be basic: xUnit for metrics -
Jeremy Dunck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=15m14s"&gt;15:14&lt;/a&gt; - The Answers - Luke Gotszling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=20m20s"&gt;20:20&lt;/a&gt; - Core Python: the next generation - Wesley
Chun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=25m15s"&gt;25:15&lt;/a&gt; - q.q - Ka-Ping Yee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=31m13s"&gt;31:10&lt;/a&gt; - Neckbeard: Because cloud deployment sucks -
Wes Winham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=36m54s"&gt;36:54&lt;/a&gt; - Abolishing the Traditional 9th to 12th Grade
Structure of High Schools - Eric Matthes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=41m43s"&gt;41:43&lt;/a&gt; - Python Anywhere - Henry Percival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=46m35s"&gt;46:35&lt;/a&gt; - RapydScript: Translating Python to JavaScript
- Charles Law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=52m47s"&gt;52:47&lt;/a&gt; - PyCon Australia 2013 - Christopher Neugebauer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OL3De8BAhME#t=53m44s"&gt;53:44&lt;/a&gt; - (py) Fore! - Christopher Neugebauer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeffrey Armstrong</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-17:pycon-us-2013/sunday-evening-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category><category>sprints</category></item></channel></rss>