<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tereza Iofciu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tereza-iofciu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/diversity-inclusion-in-the-python-community-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tereza Iofciu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/diversity-inclusion-in-the-python-community-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel - presented by Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Naomi Ceder, Nabanita Roy &amp;amp; Iqbal Abdullah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come meet some of the folks working on Diversity and Inclusion in the global Python Community!
Join the live panel discussion to hear about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel - presented by Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Naomi Ceder, Nabanita Roy &amp;amp; Iqbal Abdullah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come meet some of the folks working on Diversity and Inclusion in the global Python Community!
Join the live panel discussion to hear about the challenges and the work they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Marlene Mhangami, Nabanita Roy, Iqbal Abdullah, Tereza Iofciu. Chaired by Naomi Ceder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Why should we all be hyped about inclusive leadership?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/why-should-we-all-be-hyped-about-inclusive-leadership.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tereza Iofciu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/why-should-we-all-be-hyped-about-inclusive-leadership.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should we all be hyped about inclusive leadership? by Tereza Iofciu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/why-should-we-all-be-hyped-about-inclusive-leadership"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/why-should-we-all-be-hyped-about-inclusive-leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often associate the need for leadership skills with being in a management position. But...we start needing them a lot earlier in our career …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should we all be hyped about inclusive leadership? by Tereza Iofciu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/why-should-we-all-be-hyped-about-inclusive-leadership"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/why-should-we-all-be-hyped-about-inclusive-leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often associate the need for leadership skills with being in a management position. But...we start needing them a lot earlier in our career to succeed and have a positive impact. The diverse workspaces and communities are here to stay, though almost none of us have learned in school how to thrive in diversity. Nor how to be inclusive. We are all somewhere on a journey of inclusive leadership! In this talk we can find out how to asses where we are. And why we should approach inclusive leadership with a beginners mindset, try to do better, make mistakes, learn, repeat. And why we should all be hyped about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Meet &amp; Greet with PSF D&amp;I workgroup</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2022/meet-greet-with-psf-di-workgroup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tereza Iofciu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-02-06:/pycascades-2022/meet-greet-with-psf-di-workgroup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Débora Azevedo, Sayantika Banik, Georgi Ker) Python has become one of the most popular programming languages in the world, meaning that along with this growth the Python community has continued to expand, in every continent around the globe. While this growth has been exciting, it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Débora Azevedo, Sayantika Banik, Georgi Ker) Python has become one of the most popular programming languages in the world, meaning that along with this growth the Python community has continued to expand, in every continent around the globe. While this growth has been exciting, it has also brought new challenges and opportunities to improve our global community. Through this panel, we would like to address those challenges and understand our community better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Rethinking codes of conduct</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/rethinking-codes-of-conduct.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tereza Iofciu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/rethinking-codes-of-conduct.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Python Software Foundation Code of Conduct is turning 10 years old in 2023? It was voted in as they felt they were &amp;quot;unbalanced and not seeing the true spectrum of the greater community&amp;quot;. And thought that with time they could &amp;quot;advance towards a more …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Python Software Foundation Code of Conduct is turning 10 years old in 2023? It was voted in as they felt they were &amp;quot;unbalanced and not seeing the true spectrum of the greater community&amp;quot;. And thought that with time they could &amp;quot;advance towards a more diverse representation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that a big thing? Codes of conduct are an important part of any community, outlining the values of the community. They establish clear guidelines for acceptable behavior and help to create a safe and inclusive environment in the community. This can prevent discrimination and promote equal opportunities for all members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the role of code of conduct in communities, it's history in the PSF, and discuss strategies for rethinking what it means to have and enforce a Code of Conduct. We will look at the existing challenges that the Python communities face when implementing codes of conduct and talk about possible solutions. How does it look like when it works well and when it doesn't?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an essential part of any open source project, reflecting on these guidelines can help to ensure that the projects are successful and sustainable in the long term. Thinking back to Python, which also turns 20 in 2023: &amp;quot;Python got to where it is by being open, and it'll continue to prosper by remaining open&amp;quot;. It's important we continue this mission, after all, one of the things many people love about Python is the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2023"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Communication &amp; Contributing to Python Open Source</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/communication-contributing-to-python-open-source.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tereza Iofciu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-02:/pycon-korea-2022/communication-contributing-to-python-open-source.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Source Software work is not just about being a core contributor or a maintainer, it is also about lots of invisible work in the community. Most of this work requires lots of interactions. If the interactions are about OSS, these would be mostly in English, and although good …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Source Software work is not just about being a core contributor or a maintainer, it is also about lots of invisible work in the community. Most of this work requires lots of interactions. If the interactions are about OSS, these would be mostly in English, and although good communication skills are essential, they can also be gatekeeping sometimes. After describing the state of diversity in OSS and in Python I showing some thoughts about how we can build a better communication culture in the Python local and global communities. Why it is important to rethink Code of Conducts, what are the current problems with how people think of Code of Conducts. We can use these as a tool for building more inclusive Python communities. These are reflections stemming from my involvement over the past years in the Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Life / Social"></category></entry><entry><title>Acknowledging Women’s Contributions in the Python Community Through Podcast</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/acknowledging-womens-contributions-in-the-python-community-through-podcast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cheuk Ting Ho</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/acknowledging-womens-contributions-in-the-python-community-through-podcast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python community has been making efforts in improving the diversity
and representation among its members. There are examples of success
stories such as PyCon US Charlas, PyLadies, Djangonaut, and Django
Girls. Yet in the Python podcast community, women are still
underrepresented, making up only 17% of invited guests …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python community has been making efforts in improving the diversity
and representation among its members. There are examples of success
stories such as PyCon US Charlas, PyLadies, Djangonaut, and Django
Girls. Yet in the Python podcast community, women are still
underrepresented, making up only 17% of invited guests among the popular
podcast series. Being a guest in a podcast is a privilege, and an
opportunity to influence the Python community. There are many women and
underrepresented group members who have made impactful contributions to
the Python community globally, and they deserve the recognition and to
be heard by the rest of us. Disheartened by the lack of representation
by women on Python podcasts, and inspired by others who have shown us
how diversity in the community can be improved through intentionality,
we decided to start a podcast with a goal to highlight their voices so
that they could receive the recognition they deserve. In this talk,earn
about them, and about our podcast series. We’ll also share how you can
further help out cause in improving representation and diversity in the
Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="goal"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Goal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To raise awareness of the underrepresentation of certain groups,
especially women. To acknowledge the progress made by the Python
community and what can be done further to continue the improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="target-audience"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who cares about the diversity and inclusion progression in the
Python community. Community leaders who want to be allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Lessons Learned as a Product Manager in Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2019/lessons-learned-as-a-product-manager-in-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tereza Iofciu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-11:/pydata-berlin-2019/lessons-learned-as-a-product-manager-in-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tereza Iofciu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyData
The fun part about data science is that no two people really agree on the definition of the data scientist role. So how does the role of product manager in data science look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tereza Iofciu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyData
The fun part about data science is that no two people really agree on the definition of the data scientist role. So how does the role of product manager in data science look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/TS7TZF"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/TS7TZF&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2019"></category></entry></feed>