<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Xinrong Meng</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_xinrong-meng.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-08T17:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Scale Data Science by Pandas API on Spark</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2023/Scale_Data_Science_by_Pandas_API_on_Spark.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-08T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-08T17:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Xinrong Meng</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-08:/pybay-2023/Scale_Data_Science_by_Pandas_API_on_Spark.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Python has become the go-to language for data science, pandas has quickly evolved into a standard library in the field. However, one key drawback of pandas is its inability to linearly scale with increasing data volumes, primarily due to its reliance on single-machine processing. Pandas API on Spark …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Python has become the go-to language for data science, pandas has quickly evolved into a standard library in the field. However, one key drawback of pandas is its inability to linearly scale with increasing data volumes, primarily due to its reliance on single-machine processing. Pandas API on Spark addresses this issue, empowering users to handle vast datasets by leveraging Apache Spark while preserving the pandas APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce the Pandas API on Spark, explain how it enables the scaling of data science workloads, and explore the reasons behind its highly optimized performance. By the end of the session, you will have the knowledge to scale your existing data science workloads seamlessly using this powerful tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyBay 2023"></category></entry></feed>