<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using the SALib Library for Conducting Sensitivity Analyses of Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/using-the-salib-library-for-conducting-sensitivity-analyses-of-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sensitivity analysis should be a central part of the model
development process, yet software to actually perform the
best-practice approaches are seldom available. In this talk, there is
justification for the importance of sensitivity analysis,
step-by-step examples of how to use SALib and an outline of the
advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jdherman/SALib"&gt;SALib&lt;/a&gt; is an open source Python
library for conducting sensitivity analyses released under an MIT
license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll first justify the importance of sensitivity analysis,
give an step-by-step example of how to use the library, and outline the
advantages of using SALib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've packaged variance-based, elementary effects, and derivative based
approaches such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sobol Sensitivity Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Method of Morris, including groups and optimal trajectories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fourier Amplitude Sensitivity Test (FAST)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delta Moment-Independent Measure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivative-based Global Sensitivity Measure (DGSM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library is slowly gaining acceptance across academia as a package of
powerful tools from the literature to help identify key model inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensitivity analysis should be a central part of the model development
process, yet software to actually perform the best-practice approaches
are seldom available. As such, sensitivity analyses are often tagged on
at the last minute to a piece of work, and seldom are the most effective
techniques used. SALib solves all of this, by providing a simple API,
accessible from the command prompt or within python, to a range of
methods for coupled sample generation &amp;amp; analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library has been written so as to be independent from the model
being analysed by the library. It is written in a functional style, to
maintain clarity, using numpy almost throughout. While none of the
techniques are particularly computationally intensive, this is one of
the only open-source libraries which collect these techniques into one
cohesive library. As different approaches are applicable for different
kinds of models and types of data, the harmonised API allows users to
switch between the different techniques with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation is currently at a very early stage, with just a basic and
advanced readme available. However, there are use examples for each of
the methods and test functions to see the library in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing coverage is relatively good, particularly for the Morris Method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've recently released version v0.5 with an MIT license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;www.github.com/jdherman/SALib&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will Usher</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-20:pydata-london-2015/using-the-salib-library-for-conducting-sensitivity-analyses-of-models.html</guid></item></channel></rss>