<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_melanie-shimano.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How can Students Engage &amp; Improve Communities with Python?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/how-can-students-engage-improve-communities-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Melanie Shimano</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-16:pycon-uk-2018/how-can-students-engage-improve-communities-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applying open source technology outside of the classroom and into everyday life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My session will focus on how I’ve used Python, Raspberry Pi, and other
open source technology in classroom lessons in order to engage students
in civic tech and community-based solutions for community challenges.
Today, there are thousands of resources for hobbyists and educators to
incorporate inexpensive, open source technology into classroom lessons,
however, very few of these resources help students truly understand how
they can continue to use this technology in their everyday lives or in
developing solutions for everyday challenges. Over the past year and a
half, I’ve developed and taught a program of over 150 students in four
institutions in which students build and code open source “Food
Computers” (Raspberry Pi-controlled, hydroponic, indoor personal farms
designed at the MIT Media Lab) in order to learn how to design solutions
to urban food deserts in their neighborhoods. Students have designed and
begun to implement solutions surrounding nutrition, agriculture, and
technology education to elementary-age students, mobile “Food Computer”
grocery stores, monthly family cooking and nutrition classes at schools,
and school-wide sustainability lessons to engage high school students
with urban agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen how students transform and fully engage in computer science,
plant and food science, agriculture, and human-centered design lessons
over the course of each semester once they are able to personally relate
and take ownership of their lessons, and I would love to share lessons
learned and proposed curriculum guides for other educators to implement
similar lessons into their classrooms as well. By integrating real-world
challenges and solutions into classroom lesson plans, we can help
students best understand how they can leverage Python and other open
source tech to change the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>