<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Python Ecosystem for Data Science: A Guided Tour</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/the-python-ecosystem-for-data-science-a-guided-tour.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Staudt&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;C_L_Staudt)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an independent data scientist with a background in computer science, in-depth in algorithms, data analysis, high-performance computing and software engineering. My current interests include machine learning and data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pythonistas have access to an extensive collection of tools for data analysis. The space of tools is best understood as an ecosystem: Libraries build upon each other, and a good library fills an ecological niche by doing certain jobs well. This is a guided tour of the Python data science ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python Ecosystem for Data Science: A Guided Tour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is on its way to becoming the lingua franca of data science, and Pythonistas have access to an impressive and extensive collection of tools for data analysis. Here, a data scientist needs to see the forest for the trees: The space of tools is best understood as an ecosystem, where libraries build upon each other, and where a good library fills an ecological niche by doing certain jobs well. This talk is a guided tour of the Python data science ecosystem. More than a list of libraries, it aims to provide some structure, classing tools by type of data, size of data, and type of analysis. In our tour, we visit a number of areas, including working with tabular data (numpy, pandas, dask, ...) and graph data (e.g. networkx), statistics (e.g. statsmodels), machine learning (scikit-learn, ...), data visualization (matplotlib, seaborn, bokeh, ...). Aspiring data scientists, and everyone else working with data, should find this useful for selecting the right tools for their next data-driven project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Staudt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/the-python-ecosystem-for-data-science-a-guided-tour.html</guid><category>use-case</category><category>business</category><category>ai</category><category>analytics</category><category>data-science</category><category>python</category><category>machine learning</category></item></channel></rss>