<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sonal-kukreja.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Image Manipulation Detection using Neural Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/image-manipulation-detection-using-neural-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sonal Kukreja</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-04:pydata-delhi-2019/image-manipulation-detection-using-neural-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the present world of social networking, image manipulation is the
easiest and the scariest job! This requires an utter need of efficient
image manipulation detection techniques. Moving from the traditional
image manipulation detection techniques to the present scenario, CNN can
be the perfect deep learning model as the human visual cortex has the
ability to detect tampered areas in an image!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of social networking services like Facebook and
Instagram in the past few decades, the sharing of digital images has
substantially increased. Also, these images can be easily modified these
days by using easily available image processing softwares like Adobe
Photoshop. These modified images are used for fake news, mob incitement,
etc. Hence there is a crucial need for image authentication schemes that
can verify if the image is authentic or manipulated. Earlier, most of
the research in this direction has been done in pixel based, format
based, camera based, physics based and geometry based schemes. All these
schemes work upon the visual information of the image. Recently, CNN’s
came into picture that are inspired by visual cortex. It was analyzed
that it is possible for a human visual cortex to detect tampered areas
in an image. Thus CNN can be the perfect deep learning model for this
job! Content to be discussed: Traditional Image Manipulation Detection
Techniques Various datasets available for Image Manipulation Detection
Experimentation Learning Rich Features for Image Manipulation Detection
CNN based Image Manipulation Detection Techniques&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>