<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Guillaume Moigneu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_guillaume-moigneu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Sponsored Talk: Optimizing Django deployments with a Continuous Observability Strategy.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/sponsored-talk-optimizing-django-deployments-with-a-continuous-observability-strategy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillaume Moigneu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-18:/djangocon-us-2023/sponsored-talk-optimizing-django-deployments-with-a-continuous-observability-strategy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When applications fall short of performance expectations - they are consuming too much memory, response times increase, etc. - it can be tempting to increase the resources in the environment to respond. At the heart of the issue is application performance, and what's missing is a comprehensive strategy that connects production …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When applications fall short of performance expectations - they are consuming too much memory, response times increase, etc. - it can be tempting to increase the resources in the environment to respond. At the heart of the issue is application performance, and what's missing is a comprehensive strategy that connects production monitoring to tools that allow you to identify bottlenecks and enforce performance expectations (a performance budget) in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll attempt to show how using Blackfire.io in combination with Platform.sh as a deployment target makes it possible to not only create a Continuous Observability strategy across every application in your organization, but also how the pair makes it possible to make the environmental impact of web development a measurable and optimizable objective.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2023"></category></entry></feed>