<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sharing Your Side Projects Online (and Making Your Github the Best Résumé It Can Be)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/sharing-your-side-projects-online-and-making-your-github-the-best-resume-it-can-be.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's design makes it easy to create small programs to handle all
kinds of tasks. Tools like Github make it easy (and free!) to share
code with the world. However, code that solves a problem on your local
machine may not directly translate to solving the same problem for
someone else. This talk will provide basic practices and guidelines
for making your code usable and accessible to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python makes it easy to create small programs to handle all kinds of
tasks, and tools like Github make it easy and free to share code with
the world. However, simply adding a *.py to a Github repository (or
worse: a zip file on your personal website) doesn't mean other Python
programmers will be able to run and use your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I've written one-off scripts and small programs to automate
personal tasks and satisfy my curiosity. Until recently, I was never
comfortable sharing this code online. In this talk, I will share good
practices I've learned and developed for sharing my small projects
online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will include tips on writing reusable scripts, the basics of
Git and Github, the importance of READMEs and software licenses, and
creation of reproducible Python environments with Conda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides making your code more usable and accessible to others, the
tips in this talk will help you make your Github profile a valuable
component of your online résumé and open the door for others to
improve your programs through Github pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Timothy Hopper</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/sharing-your-side-projects-online-and-making-your-github-the-best-resume-it-can-be.html</guid></item></channel></rss>