<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_justina-petraityte.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building contextual AI assistants with OSS tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/building-contextual-ai-assistants-with-oss-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justina Petraityte</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-16:pybay-2019/building-contextual-ai-assistants-with-oss-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
AI assistants are getting a great deal of attention from the industry as well as the research. However, the majority of assistants built to this day are still developed using a state machine and a set of rules. That doesn’t scale in production. In this talk, you will learn how to build AI assistants that go beyond FAQ interactions using machine learning and open source tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
When built well, AI assistants provide great strategic business value and are fun to interact with. However, the majority of assistants built to this day are developed using just a set of rules and don’t go beyond simple FAQ interactions. This doesn’t scale in production and provides a rather disappointing user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interactive talk, we will challenge the usual approach of chatbot development by introducing machine learning-based methods for dialogue management. You will learn the fundamentals of conversational AI, as well as machine learning techniques behind natural language and dialogue management. Finally, you will learn the basics of using Rasa Stack – an open source ML-based framework which empowers developers to build contextual assistants in-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://t.ly/j93LV"&gt;https://t.ly/j93LV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Justina has a background in Econometrics and Data Analytics. Her curiosity for Data Science and human behaviour analytics has taken her to many places and industries – over the past three years she has been doing Data Science work across video gaming, fintech, insurance industries. Her interest in chatbots, natural language processing and open source has led her to Rasa, a Berlin-based conversational AI startup where she works as a Head of Developer Relations focusing on improving developer experience in using open source software for conversational AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Going Beyond “Sorry, I Didn’t Get That”: Building AI Assistants that Scale...</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2018/going-beyond-sorry-i-didnt-get-that-building-ai-assistants-that-scale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justina Petraitytė</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-17:pydata-new-york-city-2018/going-beyond-sorry-i-didnt-get-that-building-ai-assistants-that-scale.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Building your own conversational AI with open source tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/building-your-own-conversational-ai-with-open-source-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justina Petraitytė</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/building-your-own-conversational-ai-with-open-source-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conversational AI is far from being a solved problem, but you don’t need
to rely on third-party APIs to build great chat and voice apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will live-code a useful, engaging conversational AI bot
based entirely on machine learning. We’ll be using Rasa NLU &amp;amp; Rasa Core,
which are open source libraries for building machine learning-based
chatbots and voice assistants. We will teach our system how to hold
multi-turn conversations by creating some initial training data, and
then refine its behaviour by interacting with the system and providing
feedback. We will cover the fundamentals of conversational AI, including
the most important algorithms for intent classification, entity
extraction, and dialogue management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will attendees learn:&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Deprecating the state machine: building conversational AI with the Rasa stack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2018/deprecating-the-state-machine-building-conversational-ai-with-the-rasa-stack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justina Petraitytė</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-06:pydata-berlin-2018/deprecating-the-state-machine-building-conversational-ai-with-the-rasa-stack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rasa NLU &amp;amp; Rasa Core are the leading open source libraries for building
machine learning-based chatbots and voice assistants. In this
live-coding workshop you will learn the fundamentals of conversational
AI and how to build your own using the Rasa Stack.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>