<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Robert Jackson</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_robert-jackson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>PyDDA: A New Pythonic Package for Wind Retrievals</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/pydda-a-new-pythonic-package-for-wind-retrievals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Jackson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/scipy-2019/pydda-a-new-pythonic-package-for-wind-retrievals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDDA is a new community framework aimed at wind retrievals that depends only upon utilities in the SciPy ecosystem such as scipy, numpy, and dask. It can support retrievals of winds using information from weather radar networks constrained by high resolution forecast models over grids that cover thousands of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDDA is a new community framework aimed at wind retrievals that depends only upon utilities in the SciPy ecosystem such as scipy, numpy, and dask. It can support retrievals of winds using information from weather radar networks constrained by high resolution forecast models over grids that cover thousands of kilometers at kilometer-scale resolution. Unlike past wind retrieval packages, this package can be installed using anaconda for easy installation and, with a focus on ease of use can retrieve winds from gridded radar and model data with just a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Tobac: A Flexible Framework for Detection</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/tobac-a-flexible-framework-for-detection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Jackson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/tobac-a-flexible-framework-for-detection.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;tobac is a Python package to identify, track and analyze objects in different types of gridded datasets, such as model simulations, radar volume scans, and satellite images. tobac is a modular package that includes different algorithms for feature identification, tracking, and analyses. Analysis and visualization methods provide a convenient …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;tobac is a Python package to identify, track and analyze objects in different types of gridded datasets, such as model simulations, radar volume scans, and satellite images. tobac is a modular package that includes different algorithms for feature identification, tracking, and analyses. Analysis and visualization methods provide a convenient way to use and display the tracking results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A critical mass of users, contributors, and maintainers is critical for a successful community code. The project is currently extended (Version 1.5 and 2.0 ) by several contributors to include additional workflows and algorithms using the same structure, syntax, and data formats. Version 2.0 will merge the TINT into tobac, and add more features with Xarray capabilities. tobac will serve as a modular platform for performing Lagrangian analyses and evolve into a sustainable choice for tracking and analyzing atmospheric features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tobac.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;https://tobac.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tobac-project/tobac"&gt;https://github.com/tobac-project/tobac&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openradar/TINT"&gt;https://github.com/openradar/TINT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tobac-project/tobac-tutorials"&gt;https://github.com/tobac-project/tobac-tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roadmap:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tobac-project/tobac-roadmap"&gt;https://github.com/tobac-project/tobac-roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:
tobac &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-12-4551-2019"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-12-4551-2019&lt;/a&gt;
TINT &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.1175/jamc-d-20-0119.1"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/jamc-d-20-0119.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/g/tobac"&gt;https://groups.google.com/g/tobac&lt;/a&gt;
ask for slack channel invitation&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>