<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ekta-grover.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Experiments in data mining, entity disambiguation and how to think data-structures for designing beautiful algorithms</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2013/experiments-in-data-mining-entity-disambiguation-and-how-to-think-data-structures-for-designing-beautiful-algorithms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ekta Grover</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-09-01:pycon-india-2013/experiments-in-data-mining-entity-disambiguation-and-how-to-think-data-structures-for-designing-beautiful-algorithms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This session is for people who would like to move from pure play
analytics to heavy data lifting and data engineering applications. With
a background in Computer science and Quantitative economics, I blend
these two approaches to bring quick wins(and Fail cheaper) to solve some
of most interesting problems around us today- for fun and profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four problems I will discuss are around –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scoring your connections to find your net worth in LinkedIn [Data
structures, Algorithms , Data mining &amp;amp; Visualization]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building your custom distance metrics (with Graphs as base
data-structure) and finger keying – with applications for
hand-collected data-sets, susceptible to entirely different distance
metrics, than traditionally explored [Algorithms]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building relevant Job feeds in Linkedin (TF-IDF) and (possibly)
hacking around Job applications [Relevance Algorithms, Linguist
pre-processing &amp;amp; visualization]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing a custom batch aggregation platform - with competing
system goals [developing scoring metrics, concept of centrality &amp;amp;
formal constructs to measure recency]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Most of all you will learn the why and why not of things, that I will
keep coming back to as I discus the problems above. This I feel is the
most important differentiator between coding well and coding for
scale, and helps build a structured thought process to problem
solving.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;By the end of the session, you will have seen a blend of tools ranging
from Python (Algorithms &amp;amp; data mining &amp;amp; Graph Theory) , Python, R &amp;amp;
ink space (Graphical representation &amp;amp; visualization)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session will be heavy on algorithms, and thinking data structures,
so to make most of this, you need – a background/Interest in Computer
science and Quantitative vigor with some hands-on coding experience, and
a mind that wants to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>