<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Daniel Goldfarb</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creating Your Own Extensions for JupyterLab</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/creating-your-own-extensions-for-jupyterlab.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2A on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating Your Own Extensions for JupyterLab by Daniel Goldfarb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/creating-your-own-extensions-for-jupyterlab"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/creating-your-own-extensions-for-jupyterlab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wished for a feature in Jupyter Notebooks or JupyterLab that wasn't already there?  Or perhaps you've found yourself doing complex or repetitive tasks and realized that you, and others, could benefit from integrating those tasks into JupyterLab?  This is your chance to learn how to add that feature, or integrate that task, yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab enables you to work with Jupyter notebooks, text editors, terminals, and custom components in a flexible, integrated, and extensible manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk presents a practical tutorial about how to extend JupyterLab.  We focus on understanding the underlying extension support infrastructure, as we walk through a step-by-step example of creating an app in JupyterLab.  We will learn, among other things, how to launch that app from different places within JupyterLab, how to style our app, and how to pass parameters to our app to modify its behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attendees should have some familiarity with Jupyter Notebooks and/or JupyterLab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attendees must have solid experience with _any_ typical object-oriented programming language (i.e. a good understanding of classes, objects, and inheritance).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Goldfarb</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/creating-your-own-extensions-for-jupyterlab.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>Pandas for Fun and Profit: Using Pandas for Successful Investing. - Daniel Goldfarb - PyCon IL 2019</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2019/pandas-for-fun-and-profit-using-pandas-for-successful-investing-daniel-goldfarb-pycon-il-2019.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Goldfarb</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-06-04:/pycon-israel-2019/pandas-for-fun-and-profit-using-pandas-for-successful-investing-daniel-goldfarb-pycon-il-2019.html</guid><category>PyCon Israel 2019</category></item><item><title>Pandas for Fun and Profit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2019/pandas-for-fun-and-profit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this talk, I tell the story of how, as a new Python developer, I quickly learned enough Pandas to be able test some hypotheses about financial markets. I will demonstrate how I formulated the hypothesis, developed a test plan, gathered data, and tested the hypothesis. Along the way, attendees will see common Pandas techniques for cleaning, converting and reshaping the data, generating new derived data, finding patterns / correlations, and visualizing data. After attending this talk, you may choose to use Pandas to test your own hypotheses for fun (and maybe profit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience for this talk is any level Python developer with little to no experience with Pandas. Through this talk, attendees will learn what Pandas can do, and how it simplifies data analysis. Attendees will also learn how to apply a number of basic Pandas techniques for cleaning data, slicing data, setting and using indices, calculating new columns, merging data sets, generating statistics, and visualizing results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Goldfarb</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-06-16:/pylondinium-2019/pandas-for-fun-and-profit.html</guid><category>PyLondinium 2019</category></item></channel></rss>