<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dharhas-pothina.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building a User Maintainable Visualization Dashboard for the Large Synoptic Survey Telescope (LSST)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/building-a-user-maintainable-visualization-dashboard-for-the-large-synoptic-survey-telescope-lsst.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dharhas Pothina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/building-a-user-maintainable-visualization-dashboard-for-the-large-synoptic-survey-telescope-lsst.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2023, the Large Synoptic Survey Telescope (LSST) project will image the entire visible sky every few days for ten years. When in production the LSST will generate 15 Terabytes of data per night. Critical to the success of this project is ensuring the quality of the data processing pipeline. We will demonstrate the complex multi page data visualization dashboard used by scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="Visualization"></category><category term="dashboard"></category></entry><entry><title>EarthSim: Flexible Environmental Simulation Workflows Entirely Within Jupyter Notebooks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/earthsim-flexible-environmental-simulation-workflows-entirely-within-jupyter-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dharhas Pothina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-12:scipy-2018/earthsim-flexible-environmental-simulation-workflows-entirely-within-jupyter-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building environmental simulation workflows is typically a slow process
involving multiple proprietary desktop tools that do not interoperate
well. In this work, we demonstrate building flexible, lightweight
workflows entirely in Jupyter notebooks. We demonstrate these
capabilities through examples in hydrology and hydrodynamics using the
AdH and GSSHA simulators. The goal is to provide a set of tools that can
easily be reconfigured and repurposed as needed to rapidly solve
specific emerging issues. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pyviz.github.io/EarthSim/"&gt;https://pyviz.github.io/EarthSim/&lt;/a&gt;) As part of
this work, extensive improvements were made to several general-purpose
open source packages, including support for annotating and editing plots
and maps in Bokeh and HoloViews, rendering large triangular meshes and
regridding large raster data in HoloViews, GeoViews, and Datashader, and
widget libraries for Param. In addition, two new open source projects
are being released for triangular mesh generation and environmental data
access.Presenter(s): Speaker: Dharhas Pothina, U.S. Army Engineer
Research and Development Center Speaker: James A. Bednar, Solutions
Architect, Anaconda, Inc. Speaker: Scott Christensen, U.S. Army Engineer
Research and Development Center Speaker: Kevin Winters, U.S. Army
Engineer Research and Development Center Speaker: Christopher Ball,
Anaconda, Inc. Speaker: Gregory Brener, Anaconda Inc. Speaker: Philipp
Rudiger, Software Engineer, Anaconda, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>