<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_eliza-chang.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The PlaceIQ Location Based Analytic Platform</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/the-placeiq-location-based-analytic-platform.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eliza Chang</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/the-placeiq-location-based-analytic-platform.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PlaceIQ's patented platform analyzes half a trillion diverse data points
about location, time, and real-world behavior to define human audiences
and allow businesses to understand consumers at scale. It ingests large
volumes of mobile activity data and geographic data, calling for
creative use machine learning techniques to enable the high-fidelity
abstractions insightful to businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The surge in mobile device adoption and the subsequent abundance of
time-stamped location data have given rise to possibilities and interest
in understanding movement-based human behavior. The PlaceIQ analytic
platform is a large-scale data analysis system that addresses this
demand, providing a large-scale, flexible, and reliable platform created
around the concepts of location and audience. The platform's data
processing piece ingests large volumes of mobile activity data daily and
overlays them onto geospatial data. These data include: the
discretization of the U.S. into 1 billion 100 meter by 100 m tiles; more
than 400,000 proprietary polygons delineating the shapes of properties
and businesses; business listings and census data; and terabytes of
mobile activity data. We discuss here the methodologies - namely DBSCAN
clustering and kd-trees - used to de-dupe disparate geodata sources and
evaluate the quality of noisy activity data at scale. The resulting
overlays of people, places, and time create high-fidelity abstractions
and manipulations insightful to businesses, particularly in the mobile
advertising domain.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>