<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_chris-kees.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Parallel Computational Methods and Simulation for Coastal and Hydraulic Applications Using the Proteus Toolkit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/parallel-computational-methods-and-simulation-for.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Kees</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/parallel-computational-methods-and-simulation-for.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="Geophysics Mini-Symposia"></category></entry><entry><title>Reproducible, Relocatable, Customizable Builds and Packaging with HashDist Part1</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/reproducible-relocatable-customizable-builds-an.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andy Terrel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/reproducible-relocatable-customizable-builds-an.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces HashDist, a critical component of the scientific
software development workflow. HashDist enables highly customizable,
source-driven, and reproducible builds for scientific software stacks.
HashDist builds can be made relocatable, allowing the easy
redistribution of binaries on all three major operating systems as well
as cloud and supercomputing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing scientific software is a continuous balance between not
reinventing the wheel and getting fragile codes to interoperate with one
another. Binary software distributions such as Anaconda provide a robust
starting point for many scientific software packages, but this solution
alone is insufficient for many scientific software developers. HashDist
provides a critical component of the development workflow, enabling
highly customizable, source-driven, and reproducible builds for
scientific software stacks, available from both the IPython Notebook and
the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, the Coastal and Hydraulics Laboratory at the US
Army Engineer Research and Development Center has funded the development
of HashDist in collaboration with Simula Research Laboratories and the
University of Texas at Austin. HashDist is motivated by a functional
approach to package build management, and features intelligent caching
of sources and builds, parametrized build specifications, and the
ability to interoperate with system compilers and packages. HashDist
enables the easy specification of &amp;quot;software stacks&amp;quot;, which allow both
the novice user to install a default environment and the advanced user
to configure every aspect of their build in a modular fashion. As an
advanced feature, HashDist builds can be made relocatable, allowing the
easy redistribution of binaries on all three major operating systems as
well as cloud, and supercomputing platforms. As a final benefit, all
HashDist builds are reproducible, with a build hash specifying exactly
how each component of the software stack was installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will feature an introduction to the problem of packaging
Python-based scientific software, a discussion of the basic tools
available to scientific Python developers, and a detailed discussion and
demonstration of the HashDist package build manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HashDist documentation is available from:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hashdist.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://hashdist.readthedocs.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt; HashDist is currently hosted
at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/hashdist/hashdist"&gt;https://github.com/hashdist/hashdist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="packaging"></category><category term="reproducible research"></category></entry></feed>