<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ivett Ördög</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ivett-ordog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>What transitioning from male to female taught me about leadership</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/what-transitioning-from-male-to-female-taught-me-about-leadership.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivett Ördög</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/what-transitioning-from-male-to-female-taught-me-about-leadership.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - What transitioning from male to female taught me about leadership - presented by Ivett Ördög&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been struggling with gender dysphoria (a debilitating sense of disconnect from the gender assigned to someone at birth) for decades, but it took me until not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - What transitioning from male to female taught me about leadership - presented by Ivett Ördög&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been struggling with gender dysphoria (a debilitating sense of disconnect from the gender assigned to someone at birth) for decades, but it took me until not so long ago to realize what it was, and how it could be treated. Nothing has been the same since. Transitioning and the events leading up to it changed my life, and the experiences I had during my transition changed me as a person, and as a leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for me to open up about this period in my life, not just because it comes with tremendous vulnerability, not just because it’s very personal, but also because it has been the hardest few months in my life. The decisions I faced were far more consequential and way harder to grapple than any decisions I had to make as a leader or any time during my professional career. However I feel that other people — people who will never go through anything like I did — can learn from my story a lot exactly because it has been a very unusual and difficult problem to solve.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>How to sell a big refactor or rewrite to the business?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/how-to-sell-a-big-refactor-or-rewrite-to-the-business.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivett Ördög</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/how-to-sell-a-big-refactor-or-rewrite-to-the-business.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to sell a big refactor or rewrite to the business? by Ivett Ördög&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-sell-a-big-refactor-or-rewrite-to-the-business"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-sell-a-big-refactor-or-rewrite-to-the-business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of software development, dealing with legacy code is often a necessary evil, especially for successful, fast-growing companies. The design …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to sell a big refactor or rewrite to the business? by Ivett Ördög&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-sell-a-big-refactor-or-rewrite-to-the-business"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-sell-a-big-refactor-or-rewrite-to-the-business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of software development, dealing with legacy code is often a necessary evil, especially for successful, fast-growing companies. The design stamina hypothesis suggests that legacy code is a sign of success, not failure. But how do we tackle this challenge smartly? This talk delves into the often-misunderstood realm of large-scale refactoring and rewrites, presenting a nuanced approach that contrasts with the traditional 'never rewrite' dogma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll delve into real-world case studies where companies have successfully navigated their technical debt, uncovering crucial insights. Specifically, we will identify two key properties of these successful rewrites that can make or break your efforts. Understanding these properties enables us to strategically manage technical debt without losing our competitive edge. This session is not just a theoretical discussion but a practical guide, concluding with a decision-making quadrant to help determine the most effective approach for your team's refactor or rewrite projects. Whether you're leading a team through growth or coaching developers on best practices, this talk will equip you with a deeper understanding and actionable insights into one of the most critical aspects of software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry></feed>