<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Vadim Nelidov</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vadim-nelidov.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series: Techniques, Tools and Tricks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/anomaly-detection-in-time-series-techniques-tools-and-tricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vadim Nelidov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/anomaly-detection-in-time-series-techniques-tools-and-tricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From sensor data to epidemic outbreaks, particle dynamics to environmental monitoring, much of crucial real world data has temporal nature. Fundamental challenges facing data specialist dealing with time series include not only predicting the future values, but also determining when these values are alarming. Standard anomaly detection algorithms and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From sensor data to epidemic outbreaks, particle dynamics to environmental monitoring, much of crucial real world data has temporal nature. Fundamental challenges facing data specialist dealing with time series include not only predicting the future values, but also determining when these values are alarming. Standard anomaly detection algorithms and common rule-based heuristics often fall short in addressing this problem effectively. In this talk, we will closely examine this domain, exploring its unique characteristics and challenges. You will learn to apply some of the most promising techniques for detecting time series anomalies as well as relevant scientific Python tools that can help you with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Common issues with Time Series data and how to solve them</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/common-issues-with-time-series-data-and-how-to-solve-them.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vadim Nelidov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/common-issues-with-time-series-data-and-how-to-solve-them.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time-series data is all around us: from logistics to digital marketing, from pricing to stock markets. It's hard to imagine a modern business that has no time series data to forecast. However, mastering such forecasting is not an easy task. For this talk, together with other domain experts, I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time-series data is all around us: from logistics to digital marketing, from pricing to stock markets. It's hard to imagine a modern business that has no time series data to forecast. However, mastering such forecasting is not an easy task. For this talk, together with other domain experts, I have collected a list of common time series issues that data professionals commonly run into. After this talk, you will learn to identify, understand, and resolve such issues. This will include stabilising divergent time series, organising delayed / irregular data, handling missing values without anomaly propagation,
and reducing the impact of noise and outliers on your forecasting models.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category><category term="Time Series"></category></entry></feed>