<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Avanindra Kumar Pandeya</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_avanindra-kumar-pandeya.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>FastAPI and Celery - Building Reliable Web Applications with TDD</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/fastapi-and-celery-building-reliable-web-applications-with-tdd.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Avanindra Kumar Pandeya</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/fastapi-and-celery-building-reliable-web-applications-with-tdd.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to use the FastAPI web framework and Celery task queue to build reliable and scalable web applications in a test-driven manner. We will start by setting up a testing environment and writing unit tests for the core functionality of our application. Next …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to use the FastAPI web framework and Celery task queue to build reliable and scalable web applications in a test-driven manner. We will start by setting up a testing environment and writing unit tests for the core functionality of our application. Next, we will use FastAPI to create an api to perform some long-running task. Finally, we will then see how Celery can help us offload long-running tasks and improve the performance of our application.
By the end of this talk, attendees will have a strong understanding of TDD and how to apply it to your FastAPI and Celery projects, and you will be able to write tests that ensure the reliability and maintainability of your code.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2023"></category></entry></feed>