<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - David Rigaudie</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Automating Vulnerability Detection at Scale with CHOPCHOP</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/automating-vulnerability-detection-at-scale-with-chopchop.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of vulnerabilities are getting disclosed each week and the number of CVE has just been exploding during the last few years. When a new vulnerability comes out, the usual questions from the management are : &amp;quot;Are we impacted? If so, how many servers are vulnerable to X?&amp;quot;. During this presentation, we will release &amp;quot;ChopChop&amp;quot;, an internal tool we built aimed at solving problematics around vulnerability detection/regression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chopchop aims at providing a fully-featured scanner allowing you :
- to easily scan your servers
- integrate new plugins (aka new vulnerability checks) without pain.
- get pragmatic results in term of security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created this tool back in 2017 at Michelin integrating popular checks (eg. non-interpreted .htpasswd, .git folder accessible in the webroot, wildcard in crossdomain.xml, ...) and is now, one of our go-to tool, also integrated inside our CI/CD pipeline in order to tackle security in its whole.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Amar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:/pycon-fr-2019/automating-vulnerability-detection-at-scale-with-chopchop.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2019</category></item><item><title>Une application versionnée automatiquement</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2024/une-application-versionnee-automatiquement.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cette présentation mettra en oeuvre l'utilisation de la librairie python-semantic-release dans un projet python. C'est un package qui permet de mettre à jour la version de votre application en fonction de la structure des messages de commit (encore une raison de bien écrire vos commits). Ce fonctionnement repose sur SemVer et la convention Angular.&amp;nbsp;On va voir les concepts et du code bien sûr !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus que je vais évoquer sera connecté à une CI Gitlab pour automatiser tout cela au maximum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pas d'inquiétude si la stack technique n'est pas celle que vous utilisez car cette convention peut être implémenté dans d'autre langage, nous allons voir les principes qui se cachent derrière&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Rigaudie</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-11-03:/pycon-fr-2024/une-application-versionnee-automatiquement.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2024</category></item></channel></rss>