<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Booking.com serves Deep Learning model predictions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/how-bookingcom-serves-deep-learning-model-predictions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With so many machine learning frameworks and libraries available,
writing a model isn’t a bottleneck anymore while putting your models
in production is still a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how we deploy the python deep learning
models in production at Booking.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning model training in Docker containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated retraining of models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment of models using Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving model predictions in containerized environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimising serving predictions for latency and throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sahil Dua</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:europython-2017/how-bookingcom-serves-deep-learning-model-predictions.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Pandas. Introduction to the open source data analysis and manipulation library</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/fosdem-2017/introduction-to-pandas-introduction-to-the-open-source-data-analysis-and-manipulation-library.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will be based on open source data manipulation and analysis python library – Pandas. It will mainly focus on exploring the most commonly used features of the library like – integrated indexing using DataFrame objects, slicing and subsetting of large data sets, merging, joining and size mutability of data structures, hierarchical axis indexing to work with high-dimensional data in a lower-dimensional data, flexible reshaping and pivoting of data sets etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sahil Dua</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-05:fosdem-2017/introduction-to-pandas-introduction-to-the-open-source-data-analysis-and-manipulation-library.html</guid></item><item><title>Manipulating and analysing multi-dimensional data with Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2016/manipulating-and-analysing-multi-dimensional-data-with-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will be based on open source data manipulation and analysis python library – Pandas. It will mainly focus on exploring the most commonly used features of the library like – integrated indexing using DataFrame objects, slicing and subsetting of large data sets, merging, joining and size mutability of data structures, hierarchical axis indexing to work with high-dimensional data in a lower-dimensional data, flexible reshaping and pivoting of data sets etc. Basically, this talk will give you an overview of the most useful features of this library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sahil Dua</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-30:pycon-de-2016/manipulating-and-analysing-multi-dimensional-data-with-pandas.html</guid></item></channel></rss>