<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_caitlin-rivers.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Epipy: Visualization of Emerging Zoonoses Through Temporal Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/epipy-visualization-of-emerging-zoonoses-through.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Caitlin Rivers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/epipy-visualization-of-emerging-zoonoses-through.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We introduce two new plots for visualizing infectious disease outbreaks.
Case tree plots depict the emergence and growth of clusters of zoonotic
disease over time. Checkerboard plots also represent temporal case
clusters, but do not construct transmission trees. These plots visualize
outbreak dynamics and allow for analyses like case fatality risk
stratified by generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present two new visualizations, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cmrivers/epipy/blob/master/figs/example_casetree.png"&gt;case tree
plots&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cmrivers/epipy/blob/master/figs/test_checkerboard.png"&gt;checkerboard&lt;/a&gt;
plots, for visualizing emerging zoonoses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoonoses represent an estimated 58% of all human infectious diseases,
and 73% of emerging infectious diseases. Recent examples of zoonotic
outbreaks include H1N1, SARS and Middle East Respiratory Syndrome, which
have caused thousands of deaths combined. The current toolkit for
visualizing data from these emerging diseases is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case tree and checkerboard plots were developed to address that gap. The
visualizations are best suited for diseases like SARS for which there
are a limited number of cases, with data available on human to human
transmission. They a) allow for easy estimation of epidemiological
parameters like basic reproduction number b) indicate the frequency of
introductory events, e.g. spillovers in the case of zoonoses c)
represent patterns of case attributes like patient sex both by
generation and over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case tree plots depict the emergence and growth of clusters of disease
over time. Each case is represented by a colored node. Nodes that share
an epidemiological link are connected by an edge. The color of the node
varies based on the node attribute; it could represent patient sex,
health status (e.g. alive, dead), or any other categorical attribute.
Node placement along the x-axis corresponds with the date of illness
onset for the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second visualization, the checkerboard plot, was developed to
complement case tree plots. They can be used in conjunction with case
tree plots, or in situations where representing a hypothetical network
structure is inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plots are available in the open source package epipy, which is
available on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cmrivers/epipy"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. Detailed
documentation and examples are also
&lt;a class="reference external" href="cmrivers.github.io/epipy"&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to these
visualizations, epipy includes functions for common epidemiology
calculations like odds ratio and relative risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="epipy"></category><category term="vis"></category></entry></feed>