<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Axel Donath</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_axel-donath.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Pylira: Deconvolution of Images in the Presence of Poisson Noise</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/pylira-deconvolution-of-images-in-the-presence-of-poisson-noise.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Axel Donath</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/pylira-deconvolution-of-images-in-the-presence-of-poisson-noise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The result of any physical and astronomical imaging observation is degraded by both the limited angular resolution of the camera or telescope and measurement noise. By using deconvolution methods the original signal can be partly restored, however this process is especially challenging in the presence of Poisson noise. We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The result of any physical and astronomical imaging observation is degraded by both the limited angular resolution of the camera or telescope and measurement noise. By using deconvolution methods the original signal can be partly restored, however this process is especially challenging in the presence of Poisson noise. We compare existing deconvolution algorithms in the Python ecosystem and compare their performance in the low signal to noise regime against improved methods implemented in a dedicated new Python package called Pylira.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Gammapy: a Python Package for Gamma-Ray Astronomy Version v1.0</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/gammapy-a-python-package-for-gamma-ray-astronomy-version-v10.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Axel Donath</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/gammapy-a-python-package-for-gamma-ray-astronomy-version-v10.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this contribution we will present the first stable version v1.0 of Gammapy, an openly developed Python package for gamma-ray astronomy. Gammapy provides methods for the analysis of astronomical gamma-ray data, such as measurement of spectra, images and light curves. By relying on standardized data formats and a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this contribution we will present the first stable version v1.0 of Gammapy, an openly developed Python package for gamma-ray astronomy. Gammapy provides methods for the analysis of astronomical gamma-ray data, such as measurement of spectra, images and light curves. By relying on standardized data formats and a joint likelihood framework, it allows astronomers to combine data from multiple instruments and constrain underlying astrophysical emission processes across large parts of the electromagnetic spectrum. Finally we will share lessons learned during the journey towards version v1.0 for an openly developed scientific Python package.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks DAY 3 | SciPy 2023</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Axel Donath</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/lightning-talks-day-3-scipy-2023.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are 5-minute talks on any topic of interest for the SciPy community. We encourage spontaneous and prepared talks from everyone, but we can’t guarantee spots. Sign ups are at the NumFOCUS booth during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2023"></category></entry></feed>