<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A primer to write a conversational chatbot</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2017/a-primer-to-write-a-conversational-chatbot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wonder of complicated could be to write a 'working' conversational chatbot engine using an opensource project? Maybe integrated with Facebook Messenger ? Well, this presentation, will guide you to develop a simple bot, with a sprinkle of AI and all in your hands, ready to be consumed and to learn how your bot could solve problems and make more awesome your life&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Vollero</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-13:pycon-israel-2017/a-primer-to-write-a-conversational-chatbot.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to app development with OpenStack SDK</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2016/introduction-to-app-development-with-openstack-sdk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever thought about what it takes to write a scalable cloud application using an OpenStack SDK? My talk is aiming to introduce the audience to the 'magicness' of the OpenStack SDK to develop applications that could use effectively all the features exposed. This talk is a way to evangelize people to use the proper tools and getting in touch with what's already out there instead to rewrite everything from scratch or reinvent the wheel. At the end of the talk the audience will see and 'touch' how easy is to write from scratch an application and make use of it, immediately using for example the trystack environment. Since the talk time is 30 minutes, there will be a template on github from what to start and at the end the working apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/francesco-vollerol.pdf"&gt;http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/francesco-vollerol.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Vollero</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-09:pycon-israel-2016/introduction-to-app-development-with-openstack-sdk.html</guid></item></channel></rss>