<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>If It Weighs the Same as a Duck: Detecting Fraud with Python and Machine Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/if-it-weighs-the-same-as-a-duck-detecting-fraud-with-python-and-machine-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stripe's system for preventing fraudulent payments utilizes a mix of
machine learning and data analysis. This talk will describe some
technical challenges we’ve faced in building it. In particular, I
will discuss how we’ve used (and occasionally written) various Python
packages as part of a broader ecosystem to address data processing,
feature engineering, and model evaluation problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stripe's system for preventing fraudulent payments utilizes a mix of
machine learning and data analysis. Over the last few years, it has
evolved from a collection of manually assembled ad-hoc rules to an
ensemble of machine- learned models based on historical data from across
the entire Stripe network. This talk will describe some of the technical
challenges we've faced in building and scaling it. In particular I will
discuss how we've used (and occasionally written) various Python
packages as part of a broader ecosystem to address data processing,
feature engineering, and model evaluation problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use scikit-learn to train a majority of our models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use luigi to manage long-running feature generation jobs and model
training scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use pandas to debug models and features that generate systematic
false positives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We wrote topmodel to evaluate model performance on both production
and backtested data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Wang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-20:pydata-london-2015/if-it-weighs-the-same-as-a-duck-detecting-fraud-with-python-and-machine-learning.html</guid></item></channel></rss>