<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_yury-kasimov.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Machine Learning on big data in security applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/machine-learning-on-big-data-in-security-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yury Kasimov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:pydata-warsaw-2019/machine-learning-on-big-data-in-security-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we describe how Python in combination with Apache Spark
helps Avast to fight bad guys. We demonstrate different use cases how we
apply machine learning to a wide range of security applications from
anomaly detection on time series to clustering of malicious files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avast is dedicated to creating a world that provides safety and privacy
for all. Every month we stop over 1.5 billion attacks and analyze 30
million new executable files. Robust big data pipelines are crucial for
us to ensure the safety of our customers. We use Apache Spark and
machine learning frameworks, including TensorFlow, in different areas
such as network security and malware detection and classification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the presentation, we describe our cluster
environment and talk about how we analyze, cluster, and build
classification models for malicious files. Clustering by itself is
widely used for different security applications, and Spark enables us
with a fast way of conducting our experiments. The pipeline is useful
for the research on new algorithms and the evaluation of the production
ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part, we show the application of anomaly detection on time
series. As an antivirus company, we receive thousands of different
incident reports daily. We help malware experts to analyze threats by
notifying them about sudden changes. We will walk you through our
streaming application with parallel training and serving of multiple
TensorFlow models.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>