<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Pranjal Biyani</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Synergize AI and Domain Expertise - Explainability Check with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/synergize-ai-and-domain-expertise-explainability-check-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Synergize AI and Domain Expertise - Explainability Check with Python - presented by Pranjal Biyani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will go through the Why? How? and What? of Model Explainability to build consistent, robust and trustworthy models. We explore the inability of complex models to deliver meaningful insights, cause-effect relationships and inter-connected effects within data and how explainers can empower decision makers with more than just predictions. We evaluate an intuitive game-theory based algorithm, SHAP, with a working implementation in Python. We will also pin-point intersections necessary with domain experts with 2 practical industry applications to facilitate further exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pranjal Biyani</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/synergize-ai-and-domain-expertise-explainability-check-with-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Solving Multi-Objective Constrained Optimisation Problems using Pymoo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/solving-multi-objective-constrained-optimisation-problems-using-pymoo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — North Hall on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/solving-multi-objective-constrained-optimisation-problems-using-pymoo"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/solving-multi-objective-constrained-optimisation-problems-using-pymoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pymoo is an open source python framework with state-of-the-art optimisation and post performance analysis capabilities. It provides an object oriented interface to solve constrained Single/Multi-Objective optimisation problems with a catalog of algorithms, customisations and post-optimisation evaluation functionalities. With additional features like Visualisation of optimal pareto-fronts, decision making, parallelization and customised sampling, Pymoo promises to be highly valuable for scalable optimisation solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pranjal Biyani</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/solving-multi-objective-constrained-optimisation-problems-using-pymoo.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item><item><title>Unlocking Mixture of Experts : From 1 Know-it-all to group of Jedi Masters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/unlocking-mixture-of-experts-from-1-know-it-all-to-group-of-jedi-masters.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlocking Mixture of Experts : From 1 Know-it-all to group of Jedi Masters by Pranjal Biyani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/unlocking-mixture-of-experts-from-1-know-it-all-to-group-of-jedi-masters"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/unlocking-mixture-of-experts-from-1-know-it-all-to-group-of-jedi-masters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer this : In critical domains like Healthcare would you prefer a Jack-of-all-trades OR one Yoda, the master?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me on an exhilarating journey as we delve deep into the Mixture of Experts (MoE) technique which is a practical and intuitive next-step to elevate predictive powers of generalised know-it-all models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A powerful approach to solve a variety of ML tasks, MoE operates on the principle of Divide and Conquer with some less obvious limitations, pros, and cons. You’ll go through a captivating exploration of insights, intuitive reasoning, solid mathematical underpinnings, and a treasure trove of interesting examples!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll kick off by surveying the landscape, from ensemble models to stacked estimators, gradually ascending towards the pinnacle of MoE. Along the way, we'll explore challenges, alternative routes, and the crucial art of knowing when to wield the MoE magic—AND when to hold back. Brace yourselves for a business-oriented finale, where we discuss metrics around cost, latency, and throughput for MoE models. And fear not! We'll wrap up with an array of resources equipping you to dive headfirst into pre-trained MoE models, fine-tune them, or even forge your own from scratch. May the force of Experts be with you !&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pranjal Biyani</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/unlocking-mixture-of-experts-from-1-know-it-all-to-group-of-jedi-masters.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>