<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Cha Kyung-mook</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_cha-kyung-mook.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Learn FastAPI with pseudocode</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/learn-fastapi-with-pseudocode.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cha Kyung-mook</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/learn-fastapi-with-pseudocode.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am very interested in how my team can learn and grow sustainably, and I am exploring and experimenting with various methods. The experiments are designed and executed with a focus on: - Feedback - Narrowing the scope of what you don’t know about the learning target and gradually expanding …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am very interested in how my team can learn and grow sustainably, and I am exploring and experimenting with various methods. The experiments are designed and executed with a focus on: - Feedback - Narrowing the scope of what you don’t know about the learning target and gradually expanding it - Mutual coaching - Taking notes within the scope of what you understand and connecting notes FastAPI is an asynchronous web framework that is receiving a lot of attention and growing rapidly. I am developing a project using FastAPI, and as I learn and use FastAPI, I find it useful as a tool for the learning method I am refining. On the other hand, since FastAPI is a new tool compared to other web frameworks, it is rare for new colleagues to have experience with FastAPI when joining the team. Therefore, onboarding FastAPI is a major task for the team. This presentation introduces the content of learning FastAPI based on my experience of efficiently and effectively onboarding new colleagues when they have not used FastAPI or are not familiar with it. I will explain what the learning method I am refining is and in what context FastAPI is a useful learning tool for that learning method.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Python Library"></category></entry></feed>