<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Hannes Mühleisen</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>In-Process Analytical Data Management with DuckDB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talks introduces DuckDB, an in-process analytical data management system that is deeply integrated into the R ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuckDB is an in-process analytical data management system. DuckDB supports complex SQL queries, has no external dependencies, and is deeply integrated into the R ecosystem. For example, DuckDB can run SQL queries directly on R data frames without any data transfer. DuckDB uses state-of-the-art query processing techniques like vectorised execution and automatic parallelism. DuckDB is out-of-core capable, meaning that it is possible to process datasets far bigger than main memory. DuckDB is free and open source software under the MIT license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will describe the user values of DuckDB, and how it can be used to improve their day-to-day lives through automatic parallelisation, efficient operators, and out-of-core operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://duckdb.org"&gt;https://duckdb.org&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://duckdb.org/docs/api/r.html"&gt;https://duckdb.org/docs/api/r.html&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/duckdb/duckdb-r"&gt;https://github.com/duckdb/duckdb-r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hannes Mühleisen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Data Wrangling [for Python or R] Like a Boss With DuckDB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/data-wrangling-for-python-or-r-like-a-boss-with-duckdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data wrangling is the thorny hedge that higher powers have placed in front of the enjoyable task of actually analyzing or visualizing data. Common struggles come from importing data from ill-mannered CSV files, the tedious task of orchestrating efficient data transformation, or the inevitable management of changes to tables. Data wrangling is rife with questionable ad-hoc solutions, which can sometimes even make things worse. The design rationale of DuckDB is to support the task of data wrangling by bringing the best of decades of data management research and best practices to the world of interactive data analysis in R or Python. For example, DuckDB has one of the world's most advanced CSV readers, native support for Parquet files and Arrow structures, an efficient parallel vectorized query processing engine, and support for efficient atomic updates to tables. All of this is wrapped up in a zero-dependency package available in a programming language near you for free. In my talk, I will discuss the above as well as the design rationale of DuckDB, which was designed and built in collaboration with the Data Science community in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hannes Mühleisen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/data-wrangling-for-python-or-r-like-a-boss-with-duckdb.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item><item><title>In Process Analytical Data Management with DuckDB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DuckDB is a novel analytical data management system. DuckDB supports complex queries, has no external dependencies, and is deeply integrated into the Python ecosystem. Because DuckDB runs in the same process, no serialization or socket communication has to occur, making data transfer virtually instantaneous. For example, DuckDB can directly query Pandas data frames faster than Pandas itself. In our talk, we will describe the user values of DuckDB, and how it can be used to improve their day-to-day lives through automatic parallelization, efficient operators and out-of-core operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Monahan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/in-process-analytical-data-management-with-duckdb.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item></channel></rss>