<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Improving Your Documentation: A talk for developers who want to write stuff good</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/improving-your-documentation-a-talk-for-developers-who-want-to-write-stuff-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You're part of a team of developers on a small open source project.  You don't have the luxury of dedicated technical writers, but you know that clear, comprehensive, and easy to use documentation is important for your users to get the most from your project.  How do you achieve that?  Never fear - I'm here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk Charelle will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why people are reading your documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some simple points about English you may have forgotten from school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ways to make your docs clear, easy to follow and frustration free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to test your documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various markup languages, tools and features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your documentation is important: It's the authority on how your project works, and high quality docs shows that you care about your users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charelle Collett</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-06:pycon-au-2017/improving-your-documentation-a-talk-for-developers-who-want-to-write-stuff-good.html</guid></item><item><title>The Importance of Design: maybe the users aren't wrong?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/the-importance-of-design-maybe-the-users-arent-wrong.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Educating users on how something works is hard.  What if you don't have to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usability design isn't just about the UI. Making your software, docs, products, and systems intuitive to use reduces frustration, support requirements, makes them safer and more secure (no more weird workarounds). 'Human error' can often be avoided by designing around what users actually do, rather than educating them on how things are supposed to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will be covering Don Norman's design principles, and how you can (and should!) apply them to everything, including software, documentation, error messages and even doors. Have you ever felt stupid pushing on a 'pull' door? Maybe it wasn't your fault!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charelle Collett</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/the-importance-of-design-maybe-the-users-arent-wrong.html</guid></item></channel></rss>