<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_katharine-jarmul.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data Science meets Data Protection: Keeping your data secure while learning from it.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/data-science-meets-data-protection-keeping-your-data-secure-while-learning-from-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Dewes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/data-science-meets-data-protection-keeping-your-data-secure-while-learning-from-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will discuss anonymization and pseudonymization techniques that you
can apply to your data to keep it secure and comply with the law(s)
while still being able to gain useful insights from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will show concrete Python implementations of various techniques and
use example data sets to show how applying pseudonymization and
anonymization will affect our ability to do machine learning / data
science.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Business &amp; Start-Ups"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Data Science"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to object detection</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2018/introduction-to-object-detection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-01:pycon-apac-2018/introduction-to-object-detection.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, models based on Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) have revolutionized the entire field of computer vision. Problems like image classification can now be considered solved, and it is easy to construct implementations with any modern Deep Learning framework using fine tuning with pre-trained weights on datasets such as ImageNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how and why these techniques work, getting an understanding of the intuitive aspects of what the networks are actually doing. Moreover, this intuition will enable us to understand how to jump from image classification to the more complex problem of object detection, explaining the workings of the Faster R-CNN algorithm in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also speak about an open source Python object detection toolkit based on TensorFlow called Luminoth, going over the motivation behind it and showing how it can be integrated to your application.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>DAGs &amp; Dask: How &amp; When to Accelerate Your Data Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2016/dags-dask-how-when-to-accelerate-your-data-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-29:pycon-cz-2016/dags-dask-how-when-to-accelerate-your-data-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the audience to the Dask library for data
analysis, focusing on when Dask is useful (and when you might be
better off simply using SQL or Pandas). We will cover how to build
and analyze directed acyclic graphs using Dask and how to easily set
up a cluster running Dask for your data wrangling needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Data Wrangling with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2016/introduction-to-data-wrangling-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-29:pycon-cz-2016/introduction-to-data-wrangling-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Become a data wrangler with Python! This talk will introduce you to
the core concepts of data analysis with Python. We’ll cover libraries
that allow you to easily clean and set up your initial dataset,
importing data from all different file types and standards. We’ll
introduce some basic libraries to help with statistics and analysis
and then cover how to document and explore your findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s assumed you have a working understanding of Python and its data
types and structures, and that you’ve used and understand Python for
basic scripting. It’s also assumed you haven’t done much in terms of
data analysis, and you’d like to learn more. If this is you, welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ethics in Machine Learning Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advances in AI are happening at a tremendous pace, and especially Machine Learning systems are hastily deployed in settings that span as wide as social media, search engines, advertising, military use, and legal systems. At first sight results are often promising, but more and more &amp;quot;outliers&amp;quot; are becoming visible as well. Systemic bias in culture, language, or business practices often become intensified: From the Tay-chatbot turning racist, to both Google and Flickr classifying images of African-Americans as &amp;quot;monkeys&amp;quot;, to discrimination and sexism encoded in language models used for everything from translation, to court sentencing decision. Luckily, initiatives that address some of these concerns is happening through more interpretable models, new privacy regulations, novel privacy-preserving learning algorithms, and researchers and engineers standing up for more just and transparent machine learning models and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel aims to debate these themes with speakers, and the audience, and go beyond the usual &amp;quot;AI hype&amp;quot; and discuss both the amazing progress, as well as the setbacks, in making societies better, more humane, and ready for the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the panel will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roelof Pieters, Panel Host, Co-founder at creative.ai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marek Rosa, CEO/CTO at GoodAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Françoise Provencher, Data Team Lead at Shopify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hendrik Heuer, Researcher at Institute for Information Management (ifib) at the University of Bremen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andreas Dewes, Founder at 7scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katharine Jarmul, Founder at kjamistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to Q&amp;amp;A: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw"&gt;https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw&lt;/a&gt; (Second pyvideo tab)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="panel"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>If Ethics is not None</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/if-ethics-is-not-none.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-12:europython-2017/if-ethics-is-not-none.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The history of computing, as it's often covered in textbooks or
talks, remains primarily focused on a series of hardware
advancements, architectures, operating systems and software. In this
talk, we will instead explore the history of ethics in computing,
touching on the early days of computers in warfare and science,
leading up to ethical issues today such as Artificial Intelligence
and privacy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Building Data Pipelines with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/building-data-pipelines-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-11:pycon-sk-2017/building-data-pipelines-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manging data at a company of any size can be a pain. Data pipelines and other automation workflows can help! In this talk, we'll cover how to determine if a task or data process is a good candidate for automation and review some likely frameworks you can use to do so: like Spotify's Luigi and Airbnb's Airflow. The talk will also cover potential issues in automation and how to best validate proper data processing with your new pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ethical Machine Learning: Creating Fair Models in an Unjust World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2017/ethical-machine-learning-creating-fair-models-in-an-unjust-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pydata-amsterdam-2017/ethical-machine-learning-creating-fair-models-in-an-unjust-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increased use of machine learning (both simple and advanced) to make decisions that impact business and at times, our culture and our lives, is simply a fact of our current world. Determining ways to make accountable, fair and ethical decisions when using AI or machine learning is a subject of much debate and current research. Join the conversation and explore how we can help build a more just&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to cover the current research in training and producing ethical and fair machine learning models. Based on many papers released in the past year, we can see we have a massive problem when it comes to AI and machine learning algorithms and models which make (often accurate) biased decisions based on race, location and gender. As machine learning researchers, data engineers and scientists, our decisions in choosing accuracy over ethics (or the opposite) can impact our lives, our research but also the world. This talk will provide questions and (some) answers about how to fight prejudicial training and work to create less prejudiced models in a biased world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I Hate You, NLP... ;)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/i-hate-you-nlp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/i-hate-you-nlp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an era of almost-unlimited textual data, accurate sentiment
analysis can be the key for determining if our products, services and
communities are delighting or aggravating others. We'll take a look at
the sentiment analysis landscape in Python: touching on simple
libraries and approaches to try as well as more complex systems based
on machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="overview"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to introduce the audience to the wide array of tools
available in Python focused on sentiment analysis. It will cover basic
semantic mapping, emoticon mapping as well as some of the more recent
developments in applying neural networks, machine learning and deep
learning to natural language processing. Participants will also learn
some of the pitfalls of the different approaches and see some hands-on
code for sentiment analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="outline"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Outline&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NLP: then and now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Emotions Are Hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TextBlob (&amp;amp; other available libraries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bag of Words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naive Bayes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preprocessing with word2vec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metamind &amp;amp; RNLN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimus &amp;amp; CNN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live Demo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Holy D@t*! How to Deal with Imperfect, Unclean Datasets</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2016/katharine-jarmul-holy-dt-how-to-deal-with-imperfect-unclean-datasets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-31:pydata-london-2016/katharine-jarmul-holy-dt-how-to-deal-with-imperfect-unclean-datasets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered what sort of sick person created the datasets you work with? Sadly, we can't answer that question directly, but we can aim to handle messy data problems. From the non-significant or null datasets, to unclean and unclear string data, to difficult formats like PDFs, we'll take a closer look at how to best work with imperfect data and what questions you can answer given your datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover how to handle and manage working with unclean and imperfect datasets. We'll cover several issues and suggestions as well as some code examples for managing that messy data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Noble Quest against Messy Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with null data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insignificant data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messy strings Regex Fuzzy Match&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XML / HTML Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to go from here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1G-lgHKTdrqeeJhcvVmd7C9gOIfTRe429zhBN6lmKKzA/"&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1G-lgHKTdrqeeJhcvVmd7C9gOIfTRe429zhBN6lmKKzA/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Data wrangling with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/katherine-jarmul-data-wrangling-with-python-at.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-10:djangocon-europe-2015/katherine-jarmul-data-wrangling-with-python-at.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Y'all Wanna Scrape with Us? Content Ain't a Thing : Web Scraping With Our Favorite Python Libraries</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--y--39-all-wanna-scrape-with-us--c.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-05:djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--y--39-all-wanna-scrape-with-us--c.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Y'all Wanna Scrape with Us? Content Ain't a Thing: Web Scraping With Our
Favorite Python Libraries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Katharine Jarmul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love or hate them, the top python scraping libraries have some hidden
gems and tricks that you can use to enhance, update and diversify your
Django models. This talk will teach you more advanced techniques to
aggregate content from RSS feeds, Twitter, Tumblr and normal old web
sites for your Django projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2011"></category><category term="lxml"></category><category term="scraping"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Python for Programmers: A Project-Based Tutorial</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/python-for-programmers-a-project-based-tutorial.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexandra Strong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-13:pycon-us-2013/python-for-programmers-a-project-based-tutorial.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you a Python-curious programmer? Learn by writing your first
project! You'll build a complete quiz creation web application. We will
cover topics from data structures and classes, to debugging and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the day of the workshop, you will need to have Python 2.7,
CherryPy, IPython, and Jinja2 installed. Alternatively, you may arrive
at the venue an hour early to receive assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Web (and data!) Scraping with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/introduction-to-web-and-data-scraping-with-pyt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-12:pycon-us-2014/introduction-to-web-and-data-scraping-with-pyt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to scrape the web (and / or organized data sets and
APIs) for content? This tutorial will give you the building blocks (and
code) to begin your own scraping adventures. We will review basic data
scraping, API usage, form submission as well as how to scrape pesky bits
like Javascript-usage for DOM manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Scraping Showdown: A performance and accuracy review</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/python-scraping-showdown-a-performance-and-accur.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katharine Jarmul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-12:pycon-us-2014/python-scraping-showdown-a-performance-and-accur.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how python web-scraping libraries compare in terms of
speed and accuracy? I'll review lxml, html5lib, BeautifulSoup and scrapy
with a series of sites evaluating how quickly they can parse pages and
how accurately they can find data, particularly pieces of data that
render after DOM loading and other pesky bits like hidden form data,
internationalized data and mobile-compliant sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>