<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jakub-nowacki.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to manage data-related projects and not fail (too often)?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/how-to-manage-data-related-projects-and-not-fail-too-often.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Nowacki</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:pydata-warsaw-2019/how-to-manage-data-related-projects-and-not-fail-too-often.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up to 85% of data-related projects fail. Most of that is due to ill
management of these projects, and no one-size-fits-all solution (not
even agile), can solve the problem. I want to share what I learned so
far: from experience but also from good books and articles, start and
promote a wider discussion on the data-related project and people
management, and how we can help ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on estimates between 60% and 85% of Big Data projects fail; we
see similar numbers for AI/ML projects. Why is that? Have you ever been
on a good- looking project that didn't deliver or was abruptly closed? A
lot of that has to do with management, and if you think product based on
software development was hard, data-related projects are even harder. In
this talk I will combine my experience of being a part of or running
teams in a few data-related projects, spanning from big data engineering
to machine learning engineering in organization of a different size. I
will tell you about my successes and failures, how I feel the
data-related projects are perceived by the business and what can we do
about this. The ideas and experience are backed by a number of books,
articles and methods circulating around in the community. You will learn
not only what you can do as a manager, but also as a team member. Also,
that Agile is good, but is also not one-size-fits-all solution, and what
is better to pass. By no means I feel as a know-it-all person in
management, I just want to share what I learned so far, start and
promote a wider discussion on the data-related project and people
management, and how we can help ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>