<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Azure Machine Learning: Predict Who Survives the Titanic</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/azure-machine-learning-predict-who-survives-the-titanic.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Azure Machine Learning: Predict Who Survives the Titanic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in doing machine learning in the cloud? In this demo, Jennifer Marsman will set the stage with some information on the different types of machine learning (clustering, classification, regression, and anomaly detection) supported by Azure Machine Learning and when to use each. Then, for the majority of the session, she’ll demonstrate using Azure Machine Learning to build a model which predicts survival of individuals on the Titanic (one of the challenges on the Kaggle website). She'll talk through how she analyzes the given data and why she chooses to drop or modify certain data, so you will see the entire process from data import to data cleaning to building, training, testing, and deploying a model. You’ll leave with practical knowledge on how to get started and build your own predictive models using Azure Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Marsman is a Principal Software Development Engineer in Microsoft’s Developer Experience group, where she educates developers on Microsoft’s new technologies with a focus on data science, machine learning, and artificial intelligence. Jennifer blogs at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jennifer"&gt;http://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jennifer&lt;/a&gt; and tweets at &amp;#64;jennifermarsman.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jennifer Marsman</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:pydata-meetups/azure-machine-learning-predict-who-survives-the-titanic.html</guid></item></channel></rss>