<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jennifer Rondeau</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jennifer-rondeau.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Back to the Future: What Can Documentarians Learn From The Past?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2015/back-to-the-future-what-can-documentarians-learn-from-the-past.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Rondeau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-31:/write-the-docs-europe-2015/back-to-the-future-what-can-documentarians-learn-from-the-past.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world of software development rightly demands an emphasis on the new
and the innovative -- on doing things differently from how they’ve been
done. The assumption is that newer is (almost) always better. But if we
look only to the present and the future, we risk reinventing the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world of software development rightly demands an emphasis on the new
and the innovative -- on doing things differently from how they’ve been
done. The assumption is that newer is (almost) always better. But if we
look only to the present and the future, we risk reinventing the wheel,
failing to understand that we are all built on tradition, failing to
learn everything that we could from the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk shows how documentarians can find inspiration in the past,
build on it, and move forward. It tells some of these stories, and shows
what they meant in historical context:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pre-history and dawn of software documentation -- how technical
writers were hired, how they worked, what they made, the challenges
they faced, and how their solutions continue to inform the work we do
today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The much longer history of teaching engineers to write documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efforts to make technical writing into an independent profession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Europe 2015"></category></entry><entry><title>Docs as Code: The Missing Manual</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-europe-2016/docs-as-code-the-missing-manual.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Margaret Eker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:/write-the-docs-europe-2016/docs-as-code-the-missing-manual.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treating docs as code, an approach that more and more teams and
companies are moving toward, involves more than putting the two together
in a repo. We discuss some of the details that often get lost in as dev
and docs learn to work together in new ways. Because …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treating docs as code, an approach that more and more teams and
companies are moving toward, involves more than putting the two together
in a repo. We discuss some of the details that often get lost in as dev
and docs learn to work together in new ways. Because if all we do is put
doc files next to code files in source control, or use parts of the same
workflow for code and docs, we're still isolating docs as a separate
sort of responsibility, free from the obligations of systematic review
and testing without which code would never be accepted into production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some missing parts of this newer approach to documentation workflow that
we'll discuss include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outlining a documentation lifecycle that describes how material moves
from initial draft to final production, to help people unfamiliar
with documentation development understand better how to efficiently
manage documentation review and testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping GitHub workflow clearly to documentation workflow. This can
help writers and editors understand better just how to use GitHub
effectively, and equally important how it can help other contributors
(notably programmers) understand the parts of the writer workflow
that can be lost when docs move next to code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating an information architecture. Words need structure to provide
meaning, usability, and discoverability. A strong content
architecture provides logical places for adding new content,
especially for doc projects at scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing and enforcing a style guide: terminology, voice, tone.
These things make the difference between words that users might
understand, and documentation that can truly assist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewing and line/copy editing. Because you wouldn't do any less for
code, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Europe 2016"></category></entry></feed>