<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Flourishing FLOSS: Making Your Project Successful</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/flourishing-floss-making-your-project-successful.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You maintain an Open Source project with great code? Yet your project isn’t succeeding in the ways you want? Maybe you’re struggling with funding or documentation? Or you just can’t find new contributors and you’re drowning in issues and pull requests?
Open Source is made up of many components and we are often better-trained in methods for writing good code, than in methods for succeeding in the other dimensions we want our project to grow.
In this talk we’ll explore the different components of an Open Source project and how they work together. After this talk you’ll be well-equipped with a ideas and strategies for growing, cultivating, and nourishing your Open Source project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your project to succeed, all of its non-code components must be well-maintained. What are these different components and what methods can we learn to maintain them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build real relationships with your sponsors and determine ways how both sides can benefit from this relationship, don’t just ask people for money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a good communication system with your contributors: Keep them informed, listen to their feedback and input, make them feel heard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank the people who worked on ticket triage or marketing, not just those who wrote code, in your release notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it easy for new contributors to get started: Write and maintain good documentation, answer questions in a friendly and timely manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market and evangelize in the right places and at the right time: Give conference talks, organize sprints, keep your project’s Twitter account active, always curate new and interesting content on your blog or website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement a Code of Conduct and enforce it if needed: Make your project a safe space to contribute for everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these methods and a half-dozen others, you’ll handle beautifully all the components your project needs to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/flourishing-floss-making-your-project-successful.html</guid></item><item><title>Be(come) a Mentor! Help Others Succeed!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/become-a-mentor-help-others-succeed.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of us are lifelong learners. Especially in technology there is
always something new to learn so we are always experts in one and
beginners in another field. In order to learn, make progress, and
succeed, it’s really helpful to have a mentor. But it’s equally
important to learn how to be a good mentor to others. All of us started
out as beginners and if it wasn’t for the help of others, who shared
their knowledge with us, lent a hand, and guided us, we probably
wouldn’t be where we are today. Let’s start giving back! Let’s help
others succeed! Mentorship can be super fun and rewarding, you will
learn a ton by helping others, and you don’t need to be an expert in
order to mentor someone. In my talk we’ll explore what a mentor is and
why you should become a mentor. I’ll also give you mentorship advice and
tips and we’ll learn about the Do’s and Don’ts of mentorship. Finally,
I’ll present some concrete ways you can help as a mentor and which
projects you can get involved in. PS: There will be Star Wars involved ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction - Who am I? What is this talk about? (2 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a mentor? (3 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why you should be(come) a mentor (3 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to be a good mentor - Mentorship tips (9 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concrete ways you can help as a mentor&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What projects to get involved in (5 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion (3 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A (5 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/become-a-mentor-help-others-succeed.html</guid></item><item><title>Be(come) a mentor! Help others succeed!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/become-a-mentor-help-others-succeed.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is always something new to learn in technology. We are always
experts in one and beginners in another field. In order to learn
successfully it’s important to have a mentor but it’s equally
important to learn how to be a good mentor. In my talk we’ll explore
what a mentor is, why we should all be(come) mentors, tips and tricks
of mentorship, and concrete ways you can get involved as a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of us are lifelong learners. Especially in technology there is
always something new to learn so we are always experts in one and
beginners in another field. In order to learn, make progress, and
succeed, it’s really helpful to have a mentor. But it’s equally
important to learn how to be a good mentor to others. All of us
started out as beginners and if it wasn’t for the help of others, who
shared their knowledge with us, lent a hand, and guided us, we
probably wouldn’t be where we are today. Let’s start giving back!
Let’s help others succeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentorship can be super fun and rewarding, you will learn a ton by
helping others, and you don't need to be an expert in order to mentor
someone. In my talk we’ll explore what a mentor is and why you should
become a mentor. I’ll also give you mentorship advice and tips and
we’ll learn about the Do’s and Don’ts of mentorship. Finally, I’ll
present some concrete ways you can help as a mentor and which
projects you can get involved in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-09:pycon-cz-2017/become-a-mentor-help-others-succeed.html</guid></item><item><title>All about community panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion about the efforts to have open, and sustainable communities (in economic, physical and emotional sense) and how this reflects on individuals&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Russell Keith-Magee</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</guid></item><item><title>Django Tales and how the Django community can change lives.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2015/django-tales-and-how-the-django-community-can-change-lives.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Django and Python communities can change lives and have changed many lives including my own. I’ve been running the Your Django Story interview series on the Django Girls blog for over a year now. So far I featured 70 amazing women who work with Django. In my talk, I will present our interview series and share 8 Django Tales, stories of 8 inspiring women whose lives were changed by learning Python and Django and becoming involved in the Python and Django communities. I will also share what you can do to help Django Girls grow even more.
If you’d love to hear inspiring Django Tales, this is the right talk for you :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-24:pycon-ireland-2015/django-tales-and-how-the-django-community-can-change-lives.html</guid></item><item><title>Rub-a-dub rubber duck: don’t be afraid to debug!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scenario: You run into a bug, break your code-then you have to
figure out how to fix it. Do you want to learn what to do when your code
doesn’t work? How a rubber duck can help? This talk is for you! I’ll
present debugging strategies, how to prevent frustration, how to become
a more confident debugger, and where/how to get help. Breaking things is
the first step to learning how to fix them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="anna-ossowski-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anna Ossowski Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna is currently looking for a new people-focused role in tech. She is
a former director of the Python Software Foundation, PyCon Open
Spaces-Chair, DjangoCon US Communications Chair, and group leader of the
PyLadies Remote group. In her free time she loves speaking at
conferences and mentoring future speakers. Anna is very passionate about
diversity and community outreach and wants to encourage more women to
learn programming because it's awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</guid></item><item><title>Rub-A-Dub Rubber Duck: Don't be Afraid to Debug!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/djangocon-us-2016-rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug-by-anna-ossowski.json.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US 2016 - Rub-A-Dub Rubber Duck: Don't be Afraid to Debug! by Anna Ossowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone of us knows this scenario, it's part of the daily life of a programmer: You build something and it doesn’t work. You run into a bug, you find a problem, you break your code - and then you have to figure out how to fix it again. This can take 5 minutes, several hours, sometimes even several days. Sometimes you get really frustrated and are about to give up but when you finally find the solution it's the greatest feeling in the world. Do you want to learn how to proceed when your code doesn’t work? Do you want to learn how you can become a better problem solver? Do you want to learn how a rubber duck can help you? Then this talk is for you :) In this talk I will present strategies on how to proceed when you run into a bug or other coding problems. I will also talk about what you can do in order to prevent frustration and how you can learn to be more confident when encountering bugs. My goal is to show that bugs are nothing to be scared of, that you can fix (almost) everything and shouldn’t be afraid of breaking things, and that debugging can be easier than you think it might be if you approach it the right way. Breaking things is the first step to learning how to fix them! This talk is inspired by a blog post I wrote a while ago, which you can find here().&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction - Who am I? What is this talk about? (2 minutes)
What is a bug?/What is debugging? (5 minutes)
Why breaking things is great - Don’t be afraid to break things (3 minutes)
Why a rubber duck? - Debugging strategies (10 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading error messages the right way
How Google can help
Rubber ducks, hypothesis, testing different approaches/solutions
Reproducing bugs
Breaking your code down into smaller pieces
Drawing diagrams of code/writing pseudocode
Reading documentation
Debugging tools like the django-debug toolbar
What to do when frustration kicks in (3 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where/how to get help (2 minutes)
Q&amp;amp;A (5 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-10:djangocon-us-2016/djangocon-us-2016-rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug-by-anna-ossowski.json.html</guid></item><item><title>Flourishing FLOSS: Making Your Project Successful</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2017/flourishing-floss-making-your-project-successful.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US 2017 - Flourishing FLOSS: Making Your Project Successful by Anna Ossowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You maintain an Open Source project with great code? Yet your project isn’t succeeding in the ways you want? Maybe you’re struggling with funding or documentation? Or you just can’t find new contributors and you’re drowning in issues and pull requests? Open Source is made up of many components and we are often better-trained in methods for writing good code, than in methods for succeeding in the other dimensions we want our project to grow. In this talk we’ll explore the different components of an Open Source project and how they work together. After this talk you’ll be well-equipped with a ideas and strategies for growing, cultivating, and nourishing your Open Source project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your project to succeed, all of its non-code components must be well-maintained. What are these different components and what methods can we learn to maintain them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build real relationships with your sponsors and determine ways how both sides can benefit from this relationship, don’t just ask people for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establish a good communication system with your contributors: Keep them informed, listen to their feedback and input, make them feel heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank the people who worked on ticket triage or marketing, not just those who wrote code, in your release notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it easy for new contributors to get started: Write and maintain good documentation, answer questions in a friendly and timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market and evangelize in the right places and at the right time: Give conference talks, organize sprints, keep your project’s Twitter account active, always curate new and interesting content on your blog or website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement a Code of Conduct and enforce it if needed: Make your project a safe space to contribute for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these methods and a half-dozen others, you’ll handle beautifully all the components your project needs to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/flourishing-floss-making-your-project-successful/"&gt;https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/flourishing-floss-making-your-project-successful/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-14:djangocon-us-2017/flourishing-floss-making-your-project-successful.html</guid></item><item><title>Rub-a-Dub Rubber Duck: Don’t Be Afraid to Debug!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/1"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug-by-anna-ossowski/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Django Tales: How Django and Its Community Can Change Lives</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/django-tales-how-django-and-its-community-can-by.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django Tales: How Django and Its Community Can Change Lives by Anna
Ossowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I came for the framework but I stayed for the community.“ Many people
make this statement when asked &amp;quot;Why Django?“. The Django community can
change lives and has changed many lives, including my own. I’d like to
share Django Tales with you, stories of inspiring women whose lives were
changed by learning Django and becoming involved in the community. But
what is it that makes the Django community so special and awesome? What
do we all love about Django and its community? There is no doubt that
the Django community is great but we’re not done yet! There are things
we can improve. So what can we do better? And how can you help improve
our community? How can you help people become part of our community? If
you’re curious about the answers to those questions and would love to
hear inspiring Django Tales, then this is the right talk for you :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things I will talk about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Your Django Story“ interview series on the Django Girls blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Django Stories?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Django can change lives: Stories of awesome whose lives were changed
by learning Django&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s awesome about the Django community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re not done yet! What can we do better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you help people become part of the community/make our community
better?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-18:djangocon-us-2015/django-tales-how-django-and-its-community-can-by.html</guid></item></channel></rss>