<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jens-bruno-wittek.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>reticulate: R interface to Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/reticulate-r-interface-to-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jens Bruno Wittek</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/reticulate-r-interface-to-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and R are the preferred languages for data science. In 2018,
RStudio introduced its package reticulate and clearly demonstrates that
it favours to join forces. Both languages have strengths and weaknesses.
Tools to combine the strengths will enable easier collaboration in
projects and more possibilities to succeed. Using Python from R gives R
users wider access to functions and makes it easier for Python beginners
to just run scripts and being able to collaborate in Python projects.
The talk will show the possibilities of reticulate: The main part starts
with demonstrating the Python interpreter within R. It will show how to
source Python scripts as well as install and import modules. Then it
will deal with the most important types of Python objects, how they are
represented in R and how to further manipulate them. Thereby, a special
focus is on using Python for data science. In addition, it will be
presented how Conda environments can be created and used from R. A
further application will be the creation of reports with Markdown and
LaTeX where R and Python can be used within one document and share
objects. A last topic is about showing the possibilities for easier
development in RStudio (help regarding Python functions, auto
completion).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Visualisation"></category></entry></feed>