<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Georgi Ker</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Meet &amp; Greet with PSF D&amp;I workgroup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2022/meet-greet-with-psf-di-workgroup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Débora Azevedo, Sayantika Banik, Georgi Ker) Python has become one of the most popular programming languages in the world, meaning that along with this growth the Python community has continued to expand, in every continent around the globe. While this growth has been exciting, it has also brought new challenges and opportunities to improve our global community. Through this panel, we would like to address those challenges and understand our community better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tereza Iofciu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-02-06:/pycascades-2022/meet-greet-with-psf-di-workgroup.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2022</category></item><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion Workgroup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/diversity-inclusion-workgroup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion Workgroup Panel
Georgi Ker, Lorena Mesa, Anthony Shaw, Reuven Lerner&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Georgi Ker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/diversity-inclusion-workgroup.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>Keynote</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - Day 2 PM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-2-pm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are a ~ 5 minutes long, on any topic of interest to other Python people. It doesn't have to be about something that you wrote, it can be something that you learned, or a technique you think other people will be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:35 - Christian Maureia Fredes - Python en Espanol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05:35 - Mario Munoz - My First Pycon: Reflections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:20 - Georgi Ker - Open source is a walk in the park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14:30 - Bence Nagy - Lint your code, repo, playlist, and fashion sense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19:49 - Mark Shannon - Help us speed up Python with benchmarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23:35 - Larry Hastings - Correlate your data with Correlate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;27:39 - Rich Taggart - The importance of effective concise communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35:38 - William Woodruff - Securing your PyPI account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40:18 - Alexa Lindberg - Generating recipes w/ GPT-2 &amp;amp; Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:53 - Srinivas Bontula - Managing transitive dependencies for Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50:25 - Adrian - When to rewrite in rust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Maureia Fredes</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/lightning-talks-day-2-pm.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Diversity and Inclusion Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/diversity-and-inclusion-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity and Inclusion Panel&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Débora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/diversity-and-inclusion-panel.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Acknowledging Women’s Contributions in the Python Community Through Podcast</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/acknowledging-womens-contributions-in-the-python-community-through-podcast.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python community has been making efforts in improving the diversity
and representation among its members. There are examples of success
stories such as PyCon US Charlas, PyLadies, Djangonaut, and Django
Girls. Yet in the Python podcast community, women are still
underrepresented, making up only 17% of invited guests among the popular
podcast series. Being a guest in a podcast is a privilege, and an
opportunity to influence the Python community. There are many women and
underrepresented group members who have made impactful contributions to
the Python community globally, and they deserve the recognition and to
be heard by the rest of us. Disheartened by the lack of representation
by women on Python podcasts, and inspired by others who have shown us
how diversity in the community can be improved through intentionality,
we decided to start a podcast with a goal to highlight their voices so
that they could receive the recognition they deserve. In this talk,earn
about them, and about our podcast series. We’ll also share how you can
further help out cause in improving representation and diversity in the
Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="goal"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Goal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To raise awareness of the underrepresentation of certain groups,
especially women. To acknowledge the progress made by the Python
community and what can be done further to continue the improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="target-audience"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who cares about the diversity and inclusion progression in the
Python community. Community leaders who want to be allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ting Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/acknowledging-womens-contributions-in-the-python-community-through-podcast.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>