<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_david-nunez.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python to build a data privacy layer for decentralized applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2018/using-python-to-build-a-data-privacy-layer-for-decentralized-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Núñez</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-07:pycon-es-2018/using-python-to-build-a-data-privacy-layer-for-decentralized-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll go through our project called NuCypher, a network to empower privacy and data confidentiality in decentralized systems based on the use of advanced cryptographic techniques. In particular, we use &amp;quot;proxy re-encryption&amp;quot;, a special type of cryptosystem that allows to delegate decryption rights of encrypted information. Nodes in our network provide a cryptographically-enforced access control service that allows users to securely share information with others, but in such a way that nodes are completely oblivious to the data that is encrypted: at no point nodes can read anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll cover how Python has enabled the vast majority of our implementation, from constructing a low-level library for elliptic curve arithmetic on top of cryptography.io, to interacting with the Ethereum blockchain with py-geth and web3.py. Finally, you'll see a practical example of the use of pyUmbral, our cryptographic library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/nucypher/pyUmbral"&gt;https://github.com/nucypher/pyUmbral&lt;/a&gt;), and a live demo of how to share data securely with the NuCypher network.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="nucypher"></category></entry></feed>