<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Encouraging new programmers - the Open Tech School model</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2013/encouraging-new-programmers-the-open-tech-schoo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As programmers we should encourage new people to take up our craft.
Coding skills can benefit a lot of people who aren't inclined to call
themselves programmers. In this talk I'll explain why I think this is
important, introduce the free volunteer organisation Open Tech School,
and describe some of the things we've found that work and why we've
embraced Python for our beginner workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64; Kiwi PyCon 2013 - Sunday, 08 Sep 2013 - Track 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python community may be one of the most welcoming programming
communities, but even the experience of learning Python can be daunting
for an outsider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Tech School (OTS) - &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opentechschool.org/"&gt;http://www.opentechschool.org/&lt;/a&gt; - is one of many
organisations aiming to introduce people to programming. Our motto: &amp;quot;We
organize tech workshops. Hands-on, awesome, and free.&amp;quot; All content is
published online under open licenses, and OTS workshops are run by
volunteers at no cost to participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like arithmetic skills are useful for people with no interest in
becoming professional accountants, coding skills can be useful for
people with no interest in becoming professional programmers. Many
people are faced with menial computer-based tasks in their daily lives.
Most could be greatly eased with the help of some programming. Not to
mention that programming can be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll explain why I think introducing outsiders to
programming skills is important, and why I think every professional
programmer has a reason to benefit from this. I'll also go into some of
the details of how OTS workshops function, and the reasons I think most
OTS beginner workshops use Python. Finally I'll show how you could go
about starting OTS in your local community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/angus-gratton-encouraging-new-programmers-the-open-tech-school-model"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/angus-gratton-encouraging-new-programmers-the-open-tech-school-model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Angus Gratton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-09-12:kiwi-pycon-2013/encouraging-new-programmers-the-open-tech-schoo.html</guid></item></channel></rss>