<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aj-bowen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Getting started with Kubernetes and container orchestration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/getting-started-with-kubernetes-and-container-orchestration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jérôme Petazzoni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-01:pycon-us-2019/getting-started-with-kubernetes-and-container-orchestration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You've started to &amp;quot;containerize&amp;quot; your applications by writing a
Dockerfile or two, and now you want to run your containers in a cluster.
But Kubernetes is quite different from Docker: the smallest unit of
deployment is not a container, but a &lt;em&gt;pod&lt;/em&gt;; pods are accessed through
specialized load balancers called &lt;em&gt;services&lt;/em&gt;; there are &lt;em&gt;labels&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;selectors&lt;/em&gt; everywhere; and everything is created by expressing desired
state with YAML, lots of YAML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this hands-on tutorial, we will learn about Kubernetes and its key
concepts, both in theory (we will become familiar with all the things
evoked in the previous paragraph) and in practice (we will know how to
use them to deploy and scale our applications).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes has the reputation of being a complex system with a steep
learning curve. We will see that it is, indeed, a complex system, but
that it is possible to tame its most essential features in just a few
hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploy and scale containers with Docker native, open source orchestration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/deploy-and-scale-containers-with-docker-native-open-source-orchestration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jerome Petazzoni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-18:pycon-us-2017/deploy-and-scale-containers-with-docker-native-open-source-orchestration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploy your own cluster! Use it to &amp;quot;build, ship, and run&amp;quot; containerized
applications! Learn how to implement logging, metrics, stateful
services, and more! Learn the True Way of DevOps! Alright, we can't
promise anything about the True Way of DevOps, but everything else will
definitely be in this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will run a demo app featuring Python components and see some best
practices to &amp;quot;Dockerize&amp;quot; Python code and Flask in particular; but the
tutorial also includes other languages and frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come with your laptop! You don't need to install anything before the
workshop, as long as you have a web browser and a SSH client. Each
student will have their own private cluster during the tutorial, to get
immediately applicable first-hand experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>