<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Tidjani Dia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Wagtail Live: bringing a live blogging tool to the Django ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/wagtail-live-bringing-a-live-blogging-tool-to-the-django-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;People want their news as fast as possible. Increasingly, large news organisations are using 'live blogging' techniques to bring breaking stories to the public as they happen - this could be goals in a soccer match, or the unfolding events of an election night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a student on the Google Summer of Code programme, I'm bringing a tool like this into the Django ecosystem. I've been working on Wagtail Live, a project to help reporters submit text, images and videos from lightweight tools like Slack, Telegram and WhatsApp, directly into a CMS that updates the content for its audience in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show you how to use Wagtail Live to build a live blog in your own app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, we will give a better overview of what a live blog is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will then explain how Wagtail Live makes live blogging happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last, we will go through the steps of building a live blog with Wagtail Live and Slack from A to Z.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tidjani Dia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-23:/djangocon-us-2021/wagtail-live-bringing-a-live-blogging-tool-to-the-django-ecosystem.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>Wagtail Live: Bringing a live blogging tool to the Django ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/wagtail-live-bringing-a-live-blogging-tool-to-the-django-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear about the Google Summer of Code 'Wagtail Live' project and experience. Wagtail Live enables reporters to instantly publish to a live blog by submitting messages via apps like Telegram and Slack. The audience can read the posts right away as the live blog page instantly updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tidjani Dia</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/wagtail-live-bringing-a-live-blogging-tool-to-the-django-ecosystem.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>