<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Cynthia Ukawu</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Pandas to PySpark</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-virginia-2025/from-pandas-to-pyspark.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tired of waiting for massive datasets to load on your local machine? In this beginner-friendly tutorial, we’ll explore how to scale your data analysis skills from pandas to PySpark using a real-world anime dataset. We’ll walk through the basics of distributed computing, discuss why Spark was created, and demonstrate the benefits of working with PySpark for big data tasks—including reading, cleaning, and transforming millions of records with ease. By the end of this workshop, you’ll understand how PySpark harnesses cluster computing to handle large-scale data and you’ll be comfortable applying these techniques to your own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participant Requirements:
- A laptop (any OS) with an internet connection
- A Google account (to access Colab notebooks and slides)
- Familiarity with Python and pandas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the link to the Google Colab to follow along 👇🏾
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1fi0cTQ1NIE5kDEH0ynp2sqDuVeiBJJWU?usp=sharing"&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1fi0cTQ1NIE5kDEH0ynp2sqDuVeiBJJWU?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides 👇🏾
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/11JIih1VzLxTJ9O6PeGzqD_e8vumTZQmw/view?usp=sharing"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/11JIih1VzLxTJ9O6PeGzqD_e8vumTZQmw/view?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cynthia Ukawu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-18:/pydata-virginia-2025/from-pandas-to-pyspark.html</guid><category>PyData Virginia 2025</category></item><item><title>Detecting Road Conditions from Space Using PyTorch, Public Data, and Free Satellite Imagery</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/detecting-road-conditions-from-space-using-pytorch-public-data-and-free-satellite-imagery.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monitoring the health of city streets and roadways is expensive,
time-consuming, and often reactive. But what if we could automate part
of that process using satellite imagery and Python?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll walk through a real-world project that combines
transfer learning, PyTorch, and publicly available datasets to classify
road segment conditions (good, fair, poor) from aerial imagery. You'll
learn how to work with messy real-world geospatial data, fine-tune a
deep learning model using only a small training set (~2,000 examples),
and overcome common challenges like blurry imagery, inconsistent labels,
and overfitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session is practical and code-driven, aimed at data scientists and
analysts working in mobility analytics, urban development, or
infrastructure who want to apply machine perception techniques in their
work. By the end, you’ll walk away with a reusable workflow for
analyzing and predicting urban infrastructure quality — all using free
tools and open data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cynthia Ukawu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-26:/pyohio-2025/detecting-road-conditions-from-space-using-pytorch-public-data-and-free-satellite-imagery.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2025</category></item><item><title>Advanced Tracking with Kalman Filters and Stone Soup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2024/advanced-tracking-with-kalman-filters-and-stone-soup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced Tracking with Kalman Filters and Stone Soup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to implement sophisticated tracking solutions in Python with Kalman filters and the Stone Soup framework. This demo aims to enhance your data analytics and machine learning skills by showcasing an implementation of a tracking algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Cynthia Ukawu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a backend software engineer for a tech company in Washington, DC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cynthia Ukawu</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-04-21:/pytexas-2024/advanced-tracking-with-kalman-filters-and-stone-soup.html</guid><category>PyTexas 2024</category></item></channel></rss>