<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_florian-wahl.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building Industry 4.0 logistics applications with MicroPython and ESP32 MCUs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/building-industry-40-logistics-applications-with-micropython-and-esp32-mcus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Florian Wahl</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/building-industry-40-logistics-applications-with-micropython-and-esp32-mcus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this session, we will report about a forklift hailing application
we built using MicroPython and the ESP32-based prototyping hardware
M5Stack.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In a production facility, machine operators can hail a forklift using
an ESP32 device running MicroPython. The device sends a request to a
forklift dispatcher software, written in Python. The request is queued
and subsequently, the next available forklift is notified and sent to
the machine. Each forklift is also fitted with an ESP32 device. In
this project, the prototyping hardware M5Stack was used. It features
an ESP32 micro controller with Bluetooth, WIFI, GPIO, three buttons,
and a display.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will learn how MicroPython and prototyping hardware can be
used to scale from an idea on the developers desk to a working system in
a rough Industry 4.0 production environment. The talk will recap our
journey with MicroPython, the lessons learned, and the pitfalls to
avoid. Furthermore, the tooling setup will be introduced, including our
M5Stack GUI-simulator to mock the M5Stack display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central dispatch server is built using Python and deployed in a
Docker container. Messages are exchanged using MQTT, a popular IoT
message protocol. The talk will conclude with a live demonstration of
the forklift hailing system. Attendees should be comfortable with the
Python syntax but are not expected to have any MicroPython, MQTT, Docker
or domain knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials can be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitlab.com/fwahl/europython2019"&gt;https://gitlab.com/fwahl/europython2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Cross-Platform-Development"></category><category term="DIY"></category><category term="Hardware/IoT"></category><category term="Internet of Things (IoT)"></category><category term="MicroPython"></category></entry></feed>