<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_matt-hall.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Striplog Wrangling 1D Subsurface Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/striplog-wrangling-1d-subsurface-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matt Hall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-09:scipy-2015/striplog-wrangling-1d-subsurface-data.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>The Road to Modelr: Building a Commercial Web Application on an Open Source Foundation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/the-road-to-modelr-building-a-commercial-web-app.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matt Hall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-10:scipy-2014/the-road-to-modelr-building-a-commercial-web-app.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lessons learned along the bumpy road from Python noob to an open source
geophysics web application, with a commercial web service front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software for applied geoscientists in the petroleum industry is usually
expensive, hard to use, Windows or Linux only, and slow to evolve.
Furthermore, it is almost always stridently proprietary and therefore
black-box. Open source software is rare. There are few developers
working outside of seismic processing and enterprise database
development, and consequently there is very little in the web and mobile
domain. Reconciling a commitment to open source with a desire to earn a
good living is one of the great conundrums of software engineering. We
have chosen a hybrid approach of open core (like OpendTect, which has
proprietary add-ons) and software-as-a-service (like WordPress.org vs
WordPress.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-back-end"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Open source back-end&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our open core is a Python web app for producing synthetic seismic
models, in much the same way that the now-deprecated &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/chart/image/"&gt;Google Image
Charts API&lt;/a&gt; used to work:
the user provides a URL, which contains all the relevant data, and a
JPEG image generated by matplotlib is returned. Along with the image, we
return some computed data about the model, such as the elastic
properties of the rocks involved. The mode of the tool is described by
&amp;quot;scripts&amp;quot;, which for now reside on the server, but which we plan to
allow users to provide as part of the API. Scripts have various
parameters, such as the P-wave and S-wave velocities, and the bulk
density of the rocks in the model, and it is these parameters that make
up most of the data in the API call. Other parameters include the type
and frequency of wavelet to use, and the computation method for the
reflectivity (for example the Zoeppritz equations, or the Aki013Richards
approximation). The app has no user interface to speak of, only a web
API. It is licensed under the Apache 2 license and can be found &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/agile-geoscience/modelr"&gt;on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. We are running
an instance of our app on a &amp;quot;T1.micro&amp;quot; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/"&gt;Amazon EC2
instance&lt;/a&gt; running Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="proprietary-front-end"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Proprietary front-end&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commercial, proprietary front end is a Python web app that lives in
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/appengine/"&gt;Google App Engine&lt;/a&gt;
walled garden. This app, which uses the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://getbootstrap.com/"&gt;Twitter Bootstrap
framework&lt;/a&gt;, is serving at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.modelr.io/"&gt;modelr.io&lt;/a&gt; and provides a user object in
which a geoscientist can save rocks and scenarios consisting of a script
and all its parameters. We chose App Engine for its strong
infrastructure, good track record, and the easy availability of tools
like the datastore, memcache, login, and so on. We also host support
channels and materials through this front end, which has a very
lightweight &amp;quot;demo&amp;quot; mode, and otherwise requires a $9/month subscription
to use, handled by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://stripe.com/ca"&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;. This necessitated
serving both the front and back ends over HTTPS, something we wanted to
do anyway, because of industry mistrust of the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things we picked up along the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We started with a strong need of our own, so had clear milestones
from day 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We left the project alone for months, but good documentation and
GitHub meant this was not a problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinting with a professional developer at the start meant less
thrashing later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cloud landscape is exciting, but it's easy to be distracted by
all the APIs. Keeping it simple is a constant struggle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing through Xeno's paradox to get to a live, public-facing app
took stamina and focus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's nothing like having other users to get you to up your coding
game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that by telling this story of the early days of a commercial
scientific web application, built by a bunch of consulting scientists in
Nova Scotia, not a tech startup in San Francisco, we can speed others
along the path to creating a rich ecosystem of new geoscience tools and
web APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>