<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Rajkumar Venkatesan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rajkumar-venkatesan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Building AI-First Organizations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-virginia-2025/building-ai-first-organizations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rajkumar Venkatesan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-18:/pydata-virginia-2025/building-ai-first-organizations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As businesses strive to become AI-first, the pivotal role of AI practitioners extends beyond technical implementation to encompass strategic stewardship. This transition necessitates a profound understanding of organizational goals, data governance, and ethical considerations. By aligning AI initiatives with business objectives, fostering cross-functional collaboration, and addressing challenges such as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As businesses strive to become AI-first, the pivotal role of AI practitioners extends beyond technical implementation to encompass strategic stewardship. This transition necessitates a profound understanding of organizational goals, data governance, and ethical considerations. By aligning AI initiatives with business objectives, fostering cross-functional collaboration, and addressing challenges such as data privacy and employee adaptation, AI professionals can drive effective transformation. This keynote explores the essential competencies and approaches required for AI practitioners to lead their organizations successfully into an AI-centric future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Virginia 2025"></category><category term="keynote"></category></entry></feed>