<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - GOSSELIN</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_gosselin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to Build great Applications for Business Users in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/how-to-build-great-applications-for-business-users-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>GOSSELIN</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-01:/pycon-korea-2022/how-to-build-great-applications-for-business-users-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning your Data/AI algorithms into full web apps in no time with Taipy In the Python open-source eco-system, many packages are available that cater to: - the building of great algorithms - the visualization of data - back-end functions despite this, over 85% of Data Science Pilots remain pilots and do …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning your Data/AI algorithms into full web apps in no time with Taipy In the Python open-source eco-system, many packages are available that cater to: - the building of great algorithms - the visualization of data - back-end functions despite this, over 85% of Data Science Pilots remain pilots and do not make it to the production stage. With Taipy, Data Scientists/Python Developers will be able to build great pilots as well as stunning production-ready applications for end-users. Taipy provides two independent modules: Taipy GUI and Taipy Core. In this talk, we will demonstrate how: Taipy GUI goes way beyond the capabilities of the standard graphical stack. Taipy Core is simpler yet more powerful than the standard Python back-end stack.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="Python Library"></category></entry></feed>