<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_abhipray-sahoo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Snakes in Sheets</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/snakes-in-sheets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abhipray Sahoo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-05:pytexas-2014/snakes-in-sheets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Excel continues to be popular across many industries where
data analysis is fundamental to success. It marries powerful
organization and presentation functionality to sift through large
datasets. However, the default scripting language for Excel, VBA, is
often cumbersome to use. Python is maturing as a quantitative scripting
language with a growing scientific community around it, so it makes
great sense to marry Excel’s user interface with Python’s extensive data
acquisition and analysis libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces you to Pyinex, an open source project to embed a
Python interpreter within an Excel addin. It directly exposes Python
user defined functions as Excel worksheet functions, allows users to
call arbitrary Python code from within Excel, and provides an
interactive Python session all from within the same process space.
Pyinex brings to Excel all the goodies of Python—data analysis using
SciPy, NumPy, Pandas and more; integration with databases, web services,
and other network resources; rapid function prototyping; extensive
library support; and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will demonstrate the capabilities of Pyinex and give an
overview of how it works internally. The aim is to present the tool for
both end-users and developers to inspire the audience thinking of new
use cases and spark conversation on how to further improve the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>