<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Lauri Apple</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lauri-apple.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Telling a Great Story on GitHub</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-prague-2017/telling-a-great-story-on-github.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lauri Apple</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-11:/write-the-docs-prague-2017/telling-a-great-story-on-github.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a former journalist, I tend to think in terms of storytelling. As an
open source evangelist, I invite you to do the same. What you share on
GitHub tells a story about you, your development practices, and your
openness to others in the open source community. If you're …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a former journalist, I tend to think in terms of storytelling. As an
open source evangelist, I invite you to do the same. What you share on
GitHub tells a story about you, your development practices, and your
openness to others in the open source community. If you're motivated to
gain users, contributors, and positive feedback about your projects,
then building a compelling, coherent narrative is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, I'll share insights gained from curating Zalando's
GitHub repository so we can tell a better story. I'll describe how we've
used GitHub and other tools to create guidelines and processes that
bring sanity to our storytelling. And I'll talk about how focusing on
higher-quality docs has helped us to instill a stronger product mindset
in our development teams. Writing a README, for example, offers an
opportunity to tell the world why a project exists, how it works (and
why), what makes it unique, and how it might evolve over time. I'll
discuss how this process not only empowers developers, but also those of
us who are technical writers and storytellers—offering several real-life
examples to (hopefully) inspire you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 400+ projects of widely differing quality, reliability and
maintenance levels, we've winnowed our OSS offerings at Zalando to make
our highest- quality work more discoverable and user-friendly. If your
organization is facing GitHub-bloat challenges, looking for ways to
manage your repos more effectively, or wondering how better docs can
help your OSS efforts succeed, you might find some help here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Write the Docs Prague 2017"></category></entry></feed>