<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Wu-Jung Lee</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_wu-jung-lee.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Echopype: Enhancing the Interoperability and Scalability of Ocean Sonar Data Processing for Biological Information</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/echopype-enhancing-the-interoperability-and-scalability-of-ocean-sonar-data-processing-for-biological-information.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wu-Jung Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/scipy-2019/echopype-enhancing-the-interoperability-and-scalability-of-ocean-sonar-data-processing-for-biological-information.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instrumentation advancements in the last decade have produced a deluge of ocean sonar data. These data provide opportunities to study the marine ecosystems at unprecedented spatial and temporal scales. However, to date, these data remain significantly under-utilized, mainly due to the lack of data interoperability and scalable analysis workflow …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instrumentation advancements in the last decade have produced a deluge of ocean sonar data. These data provide opportunities to study the marine ecosystems at unprecedented spatial and temporal scales. However, to date, these data remain significantly under-utilized, mainly due to the lack of data interoperability and scalable analysis workflow. We address these challenges by developing an open-source Python package, echopype, which defines an interoperable netCDF file format and leverages the power of Xarray and Dask for explicit and efficient sonar data analysis in the Jupyter environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Echostack: A scalable open-source software suite for echosounder data processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/echostack-a-scalable-open-source-software-suite-for-echosounder-data-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wu-Jung Lee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/echostack-a-scalable-open-source-software-suite-for-echosounder-data-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water column sonar data collected by echosounders are essential for fisheries and marine ecosystem research, enabling the detection, classification, and quantification of fish and zooplankton from many different ocean observing platforms. However, the broad usage of these data has been hindered by the lack of modular software tools that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water column sonar data collected by echosounders are essential for fisheries and marine ecosystem research, enabling the detection, classification, and quantification of fish and zooplankton from many different ocean observing platforms. However, the broad usage of these data has been hindered by the lack of modular software tools that allow flexible composition of data processing workflows that incorporate powerful analytical tools in the scientific Python ecosystem. We address this gap by developing Echostack, a suite of open-source Python software packages that leverage existing distributed computing and cloud-interfacing libraries to support intuitive and scalable data access, processing, and interpretation. These tools can be used individually or orchestrated together, which we demonstrate in example use cases for a fisheries acoustic-trawl survey.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>