<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Automated report writing using data from a relational database</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/automated-report-writing-using-data-from-a-relational-database.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of the Development Consent Order submission for large infrastructure (Highways scheme), a book of reference needs to be submitted. The user previously needed to export spreadsheets from a database and populate the document manually. We have automated this process on a jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dani Papamaximou</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-15:pycon-uk-2019/automated-report-writing-using-data-from-a-relational-database.html</guid></item><item><title>Surface Wave Propagation Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/surface-wave-propagation-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Python to Takle Engineering Problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rayleigh waves are a type of surface wave that can be generated from a
number of sources such as earthquakes, construction activities, and
transient train loading. When considering transient train loads,
Rayleigh Waves cause displacements of the track and the material below
it when the train speed approaches the Rayleigh Wave Velocity of the
soil, resulting in excessive vibration. Therefore, a stiff layer under
the rail track needs to be constructed to accommodate the increased
speed. The shear velocity occurring from existing seismic tests is used
as an input alongside the in-situ soil properties to calculate the
Rayleigh wave dispersion curve-Rayleigh wave velocity over frequency.
This data is used in strategic decision making to identify the thickness
of the competent layer while maximising the speed and minimising the
volume of the imported competent material. This presentation aims to
highlight the data analysis challenges in geotechnical engineering,
where python is not predominantly used for data analysis. The
implementation of numpy to tackle the equations for calculating the
Rayleigh wave dispersion curve followed by the implementation of pandas
to create dataframes that are agile and easy to manipulate will be
discussed initially. As we have to analyse data from many datapoints, it
is essential that we create an agile form of database, or an
input-output procedure which remains constant. Data querying can then be
conducted in a way such that engineers without programming knowledge can
extract information-provided that the right question is asked. The
importance of the ‘right question’ in database querying will be
highlighted as there is a need to ensure clear communication between the
developer and other engineering disciplines. The use of jupyter to
create a user interface for such data analysis will be demonstrated.
Finally, the lessons learnt from communicating the querying/calculative
limitations to third parties will be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dani Papamaximou</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-16:pycon-uk-2018/surface-wave-propagation-analysis.html</guid></item></channel></rss>