<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_maurits-kaptein.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Keynote: Personalization, Bandits, and Causal inference</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/keynote-personalization-bandits-and-causal-inference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maurits Kaptein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-30:pydata-eindhoven-2019/keynote-personalization-bandits-and-causal-inference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk Maurits will introduce the problem of personalization and
discuss some its peculiarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over ten years Maurits has been exploring different statistical methods
to efficiently learn “what to do to whom”. His work has been applied
various fields such as marketing (who should we target with our
retention campaigns?) and healthcare (which type of treatment has the
best expected outcome for the current patient?). In this talk Maurits
will introduce the problem of personalization and discuss some its
peculiarities. Maurits will focus on two contemporary challenges: First,
how should we — if we are lucky enough to be able to — setup experiments
to learn “what to do to whom” through sequential experimentation?
Second, how can we learn, based on already existing data, what we should
do to whom in the future? This talk will cover some of the intuitions
behind effective sequential learning and offline policy evaluation, and
will highlight a number of tools and software packages developed by
member of Maurits’ lab that enable you to get started right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lab website: www.nth-iteration.com&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>