<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Predicting flight compensation - a case study</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/predicting-flight-compensation-a-case-study.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under EU law, airplane passengers have the right to be compensated if
their flight is sufficiently delayed. GIVT helps passengers file such
claims. Every claim needs to be verified as there are various conditions
that can invalidate it: extreme weather, strikes, bird hit, etc. In this
talk, I will describe a machine learning system which replaces manual
verification of claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk describes the process of implementing a machine learning model
in production. I will talk about various problems that we encountered
and how we solved them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will describe the problem: verification if the airline should
compensate the passenger for the flight. This depends on many factors,
some of which are easy to define (is the flight delayed more than 180
minutes? is the airline from EU?) and some are not (is the weather bad
enough to invalidate the claim? is there a strike?). Of course, with
perfect data, those questions would be very easy, but in practice we do
not have the luxury of working with ideal data. For example, the weather
reports are not available in real time and we know they are available
for the airports, not the whole route of the flight. I will tell you
what data we had and what features we extracted from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I will briefly describe the algorithms we used and why,
unsurprisingly, we ended up using GBM. After the model was ready, we ran
it in parallel to manual verification for several weeks so the
predictions of the model could be compared to human work. One important
aspect of running the model in production is explaining the model
decisions to the verification team (and end users). I will talk about
techniques that can be used to 'explain' the model's decision, for
example, SHAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main value of my talk will be practical lessons for solving a real
business problem with machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Witkowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:pydata-warsaw-2019/predicting-flight-compensation-a-case-study.html</guid></item></channel></rss>