<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Greg Michaelson</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AutoML as it should have always been</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/automl-as-it-should-have-always-been.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When AutoML was popularised during the 2010s, there was a great hope that the citizen data scientist would take over machine learning and that business analysts everywhere would soon be building thousands of advanced AI-based solutions, ushering in the age of AI in business. Not only did that not happen, but even the name “AutoML” has become sullied along with the myth of the citizen data scientist. In this talk, Greg will discuss the launch of a brand new open source project that promises to deliver AutoML as it should have been: open, flexible, code-based, and targeted at the only people generating value from machine learning — data science experts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Greg Michaelson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/automl-as-it-should-have-always-been.html</guid><category>JupyterCon 2023</category></item><item><title>How data science shortened the COVID-19 pandemic by 2 months</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-virginia-2025/how-data-science-shortened-the-covid-19-pandemic-by-2-months.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When every day counted during the COVID-19 pandemic, data science became an essential catalyst in accelerating the path to widespread vaccination. This talk delves into the data-driven strategies that enabled the U.S. government’s vaccine trials to move faster, cutting crucial weeks—6 to 8, by our estimates—off the timeline to deployment. Through sophisticated geospatial modeling, we identified and swiftly mobilized trial recruitment efforts in emerging hot zones, ensuring that each candidate pool was both numerically sufficient and demographically representative. Attendees will discover how advanced analytics, predictive modeling, and interdisciplinary collaboration converged to target the right communities at the right time, ultimately expediting vaccine availability. This behind-the-scenes look at rapid-response data science highlights not just the technical innovations, but the decisive cultural and operational shifts that turned real-time insights into life-saving action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Greg Michaelson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-18:/pydata-virginia-2025/how-data-science-shortened-the-covid-19-pandemic-by-2-months.html</guid><category>PyData Virginia 2025</category></item></channel></rss>