<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Dmitry Vinnik</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modern Web Testing: Going Beyond Selenium</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2021/modern-web-testing-going-beyond-selenium.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is safe to say that Selenium WebDriver is the number one testing tool for many software engineers across the globe. However, as the tech world has been growing rapidly, so has the testing industry. More and more UI testing frameworks besides Selenium are gaining popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new test frameworks are especially appealing to its users because of the promise to solve speed, maintenance, development and other concerns of WebDriver implementations. These new, non-Selenium frameworks emphasize Rapid Test Development practices, and it has been resonating with the development community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we dive into test solutions evolved from Selenium like Protractor, and talk about non-Selenium frameworks like TestCafe and Cypress.io. We discuss why these new tools are gaining popularity and continue to disrupt the traditional testing standards of Selenium WebDriver. More importantly, we address how to get started and what mistakes to avoid when first implementing TestCafe or Cypress.io in your team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dmitry Vinnik</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-23:/djangocon-us-2021/modern-web-testing-going-beyond-selenium.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2021</category></item><item><title>The 10,000 Steps of Open Source Project Health</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/the-10000-steps-of-open-source-project-health.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human health is complex - it’s not something we can buy; it’s something we have to earn! This exact approach goes for open source projects and their communities. A truly dedicated and loyal fanbase cannot be bought; it has to be nurtured. But what do we mean when we call a community and the open source project &amp;quot;healthy&amp;quot;? This question is what we are trying to answer at Facebook!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will look at the approach that Facebook Open Source team takes to measure the current state of Facebook open source projects, and how we use these metrics to prioritize and to direct our DevRel focus. Ultimately, we aim to show how by looking at information about your open source communities, your team can concentrate on the quality of the projects instead of only the quantity of repositories that you make public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dmitry Vinnik</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-23:/python-web-conf-2022/the-10000-steps-of-open-source-project-health.html</guid><category>Python Web Conf 2022</category><category>PythonWebConf</category><category>PythonWebConf2022</category></item></channel></rss>