<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Israel Blancas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_israel-blancas.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Autoinstrumentation Adventures: enhancing Python apps with OpenTelemetry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/autoinstrumentation-adventures-enhancing-python-apps-with-opentelemetry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Israel Blancas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/autoinstrumentation-adventures-enhancing-python-apps-with-opentelemetry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoinstrumentation Adventures: enhancing Python apps with OpenTelemetry by Israel Blancas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/autoinstrumentation-adventures-enhancing-python-apps-with-opentelemetry"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/autoinstrumentation-adventures-enhancing-python-apps-with-opentelemetry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow Python enthusiasts! Are you ready to dive into the exciting world of application observability without getting your hands too dirty with complex instrumentation? If …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoinstrumentation Adventures: enhancing Python apps with OpenTelemetry by Israel Blancas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/autoinstrumentation-adventures-enhancing-python-apps-with-opentelemetry"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/autoinstrumentation-adventures-enhancing-python-apps-with-opentelemetry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow Python enthusiasts! Are you ready to dive into the exciting world of application observability without getting your hands too dirty with complex instrumentation? If that sounds like a journey you'd be interested in, then you're in for a treat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observability is that magical window into the inner workings of our applications, allowing us to understand what's happening under the hood, troubleshoot issues, and ensure everything is running smoothly. However, achieving this level of insight can sometimes feel like a daunting task. That's where OpenTelemetry comes into play, simplifying the entire process and making it accessible to everyone, not just the observability wizards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our session, we'll start with the basics: what OpenTelemetry is and the problems it aims to solve (and those it doesn't). We'll demystify the concept of instrumentation—the process of embedding observability into your applications—and show you how OpenTelemetry makes this not only possible but painless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart of our talk will be focused on autoinstrumentation, a magical feature of OpenTelemetry that automates the task of adding observability to your Python projects. Imagine being able to get detailed insights into your application's performance and behavior without having to manually instrument every nook and cranny. Sounds like a dream, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because we believe in learning by doing, we'll walk you through a small but mighty demo. You'll see firsthand how effortlessly you can implement OpenTelemetry in your own Python applications, turning the daunting into the doable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>GitHubCity: una biblioteca para conocer tu comunidad</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2016/githubcity-una-biblioteca-para-conocer-tu-comunidad.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Israel Blancas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:/pycon-es-2016/githubcity-una-biblioteca-para-conocer-tu-comunidad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHubCity es una biblioteca escrita en Python creada para conocer cómo es tu comunidad de desarrolladores de software libre. Mediante peticiones a la API Rest de GitHub, se extraen datos de los usuarios, siendo filtrados por una ubicación. Podrás saber quienes son los usuarios que pertenecen a tu misma …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHubCity es una biblioteca escrita en Python creada para conocer cómo es tu comunidad de desarrolladores de software libre. Mediante peticiones a la API Rest de GitHub, se extraen datos de los usuarios, siendo filtrados por una ubicación. Podrás saber quienes son los usuarios que pertenecen a tu misma ciudad, clasificarlos según varios métodos... ¡Ven a ver cómo funciona y cómo sacarle partido para atraer a nuevos desarrolladores a tus eventos! Durante la charla se espera que se aporten nuevas ideas para mejorarla y algunas nuevas funcionalidades que puedan ser útiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2016.es.pycon.org/"&gt;http://2016.es.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon ES 2016"></category></entry></feed>