<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Irit Katriel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CPython Developer Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/cpython-developer-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - CPython Developer Panel - presented by Łukasz Langa, Pablo Galindo Salgado, Mark Shannon, Steve Dower, Irit Katriel, Batuhan Taskaya &amp;amp; Ken Jin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come meet the folks who make the Python programming language!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A panel discussion of core Python developers will take place on Wednesday at 2pm. Hear what's on their mind, what they're working on and what the future holds for Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Pablo Galindo Salgado, Steve Dower, Batuhan Taskaya, Ken Jin, Irit Katriel and Dr.Mark &amp;quot;&amp;quot;HotPy&amp;quot;&amp;quot; Shannon. Chaired by the esteemed Łukasz &amp;quot;&amp;quot;Any color you like so long as it's black&amp;quot;&amp;quot; Langa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Łukasz Langa</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/cpython-developer-panel.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Exception Groups and except*</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2022/exception-groups-and-except.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python 3.11 introduces new features that make it possible to raise and handle multiple unrelated exceptions. This talk briefly covers what they do and how they work, and answers a frequently asked question: why we needed to add new language syntax to handle exception groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.11 introduces new features that make it possible to raise and handle multiple unrelated exceptions at the same time (see PEP 654). This talk, given by one of the authors of PEP 654, will describe how they work and some of the design decisions we made while developing these features. In particular, why we needed to add the new syntax except* to handle exception groups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Irit Katriel</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-16:/pycon-uk-2022/exception-groups-and-except.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2022</category></item><item><title>CPython's Compilation Pipeline</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/cpythons-compilation-pipeline.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, CPython's compiler was refactored. In
version 3.13, we will have access from Python scripts to more of the
compilation stages: Instead of the old 4-stage pipeline (source --&amp;gt;
tokens --&amp;gt; AST --&amp;gt; code object), we will have a more refined pipeline
(source --&amp;gt; tokens --&amp;gt; AST --&amp;gt; optimized AST --&amp;gt; pseudo bytecode --&amp;gt;
optimized pseudo bytecode --&amp;gt; bytecode --&amp;gt; code object).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk describes the new compilation pipeline of CPython 3.13 and the
possibilities that it creates for CPython users, maintainers and
educators. It presents Codoscope, a new vizualization tool that displays
CPython's process of translating Python source code into an executable
code object.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Irit Katriel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/cpythons-compilation-pipeline.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>