<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_guilherme-chapiewski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Small acts make great revolutions: crafting Python and Open Source communities in Rio de Janeiro (#78)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/small-acts-make-great-revolutions-crafting-pytho.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guilherme Chapiewski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/small-acts-make-great-revolutions-crafting-pytho.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Small acts make great revolutions: crafting Python and Open Source
communities in Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Guilherme Chapiewski; Henrique Bastos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we are Python lovers, we at PythOnRio (Python's Rio de
Janeiro users group) strongly believe in differences. Programming
languages and technologies are not religions. Why do we have to compete
against each other when we can take advantage of diversity by sharing
our knowledge and learning to use the best tools for each job? By
promoting this thinking we are gathering people from many different open
source communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's our main recipe for the success of initiatives like Coding Dojo
Rio, PythOnCampus, Dev in Rio, #horaextra and many other social meetings
where we have gathered some of the smartest people in Rio's software
development community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this philosophy, Rio de Janeiro communities are growing and
starting to jell - they are becoming so strongly knit that the whole is
greater than the sum of the parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we would like to share not only our &amp;quot;methods&amp;quot; and
&amp;quot;formulas&amp;quot;, but the values and experiences that are leading us to build
a strong and active community while having lots of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="pythonrio"></category></entry></feed>