<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Commenting code — beyond common wisdom</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2019/commenting-code-beyond-common-wisdom.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Stefan Schwarzer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyConDE
Good code comments are important for software maintenance. This talk
goes beyond the common wisdom you find in most books and online and
explains when this common wisdom falls short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/SUC9VW"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/SUC9VW&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Schwarzer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-10:pycon-de-2019/commenting-code-beyond-common-wisdom.html</guid></item><item><title>Concurrency in Python - concepts, frameworks and best practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/concurrency-in-python-concepts-frameworks-and-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you run in situations where concurrent execution could speed up
your Python code? Are you using a GUI toolkit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk gives you the background to use concurrency in your code
without shooting yourself in the foot - which is quite easy if you don't
understand how concurrent execution differs from linear execution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation starts with explaining some concepts like concurrency,
parallelism, resources, atomic operations, race conditions and
deadlocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we discuss the commonly-used approaches to concurrency:
multithreading with the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;threading&lt;/tt&gt; module, multiprocessing with the
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;multiprocessing&lt;/tt&gt; module, and event loops (which include the
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;asyncio&lt;/tt&gt; framework). Each of these approaches has its typical use
cases, which are explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can implement concurrency on a number of abstraction levels. The
lowest level consists of primitives like locks, events, semaphores and
so on. A higher abstraction level is using queues, typically with worker
threads or processes. Even higher abstraction levels are active objects
(hiding primitives or queues behind an API; this includes &amp;quot;actors&amp;quot; if
you heard of them), the thread and process pools in
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;concurrent.futures&lt;/tt&gt; and the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;asyncio&lt;/tt&gt; framework. Finally, you can
&amp;quot;outsource&amp;quot; concurrency by leaving it to a message broker, which is a
distinct process that receives and distributes messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk closes with some tips and best practices, mainly:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Schwarzer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/concurrency-in-python-concepts-frameworks-and-best-practices.html</guid><category>Parallel Programming</category><category>Programming</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Support Python 2 and 3 with the same code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/support-python-2-and-3-with-the-same-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your library supports only Python 2, - but your users keep nagging you
about Python 3 support?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Python 3 gets adopted more and more, users ask for Python 3 support
in existing libraries for Python 2. Although there are several
approaches, this talk focuses on using the very same code for a Python 2
and a Python 3 version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk discusses the main problems when supporting Python 3 and best
practices to apply for compatibility with Python 2 and 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your library supports only Python 2, - but your users keep nagging you
about Python 3 support?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Python 3 gets adopted more and more, users ask for Python 3 support
in existing libraries for Python 2. This talk mentions some approaches
for giving users a Python 3 version, but will quickly focus on using the
very same code for a Python 2 and a Python 3 version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is much easier if you require Python 2.6 and up, and yet a bit
easier if you require Python 3.3 as the minimum Python 3 version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk discusses main problems when supporting Python 3 (some are
easily solved):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;print&lt;/tt&gt; is a function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Python APIs return iterators that used to return lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's now a clear distinction between bytes and unicode (text)
strings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files are opened as text by default, requiring an encoding to apply
on reading and writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk also explains some best practices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with a good automatic test coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deal with many automatic conversions with a one-time 2to3 run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about how your library should handle bytes and unicode strings.
(Rule of thumb: Decode bytes as early as possible; encode unicode
text as late as possible.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should you break compatibility with your existing Python 2 API? (Yes,
if there's no other way to design a sane API for Python 2 and 3. If
you do it, raise the first part of the version number.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to keep code that's different for Python 2 and 3 minimal. Put
code that needs to be different for Python 2 and 3 into a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;compat&lt;/tt&gt;
module. Or use third-party libraries like &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;six&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;future&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the talk will mention some helpful resources on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Schwarzer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/support-python-2-and-3-with-the-same-code.html</guid></item><item><title>Debugging mit Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/debugging-mit-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manche Fehler in Python-Programmen lassen sich mit Print-Anweisungen
aufdecken, in komplizierteren Fällen ist aber ein Debugger gefragt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortrag behandelt Grundlagen für die Fehlersuche in
Python-Programmen. Zunächst soll es - für die einfachen Fälle - um
Print-Anweisungen gehen. Danach kommt die Verwendung des mit Python
gelieferten Debuggers pdb. Dazu werden Grundbegriffe wie Programmzeiger
und Breakpoint erklärt und gezeigt, wie man die Befehle des Debuggers
für die Fehlersuche benutzt (zum Beispiel Setzen von Breakpoints,
schrittweise Ausführung ohne und mit Funktionsaufrufen sowie natürlich
die Untersuchung von Objekten).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ich kann den Vortrag wahlweise als 55- oder 25-Minuten-Version halten.
Im ersten Fall würde ich auch noch auf andere Debugger wie pudb, pdb++
und WinPdb eingehen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Schwarzer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-31:pycon-de-2012/debugging-mit-python.html</guid><category>breakpoint</category><category>debugger</category><category>debugging</category><category>fehler</category><category>fehlersuche</category><category>print</category><category>programmzeiger</category><category>unterbrechungspunkt</category></item><item><title>Nebenläufige Programme mit Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/nebenlaufige-programme-mit-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In diesem Vortrag soll es um Grundlagen nebenläufiger Programme gehen,
wie sie mit den Modulen threading und multiprocessing möglich sind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zuerst wird erklärt, in welchen Fällen Nebenläufigkeit sinnvoll ist.
Danach wird auf die grundsätzlichen Probleme nebenläufiger Programme
eingegangen, insbesondere Änderungen an gemeinsam genutzten Ressourcen
(zum Beispiel Dateien oder auch &amp;quot;nur&amp;quot; Objekte im Speicher) durch mehrere
Threads oder Prozesse. Schließlich wird gezeigt, wie man solche
Ressourcen-Zugriffe durch Locks oder Queues entschärfen kann.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Schwarzer</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-30:pycon-de-2012/nebenlaufige-programme-mit-python.html</guid><category>deadlock</category><category>gil</category><category>multiprocessing</category><category>nebenläufigkeit</category><category>queue</category><category>threading</category></item></channel></rss>