<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Faking It - The Art of Testing Using Verified Fakes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/faking-it-the-art-of-testing-using-verified-fakes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Richard Wall - Faking It - The Art of Testing Using Verified Fakes
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever worried that your tests aren't as good because they're
running against a fake or mock instead of the real thing?
Verified fakes solve this problem.
Verified fakes allow for simplified testing using fakes while still
providing the assurance that code tested using a fake implementation
will behave the same way when used with a real implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will begin with a case-study, demonstrating what it means to
write a &amp;quot;verified fake&amp;quot; implementation of a public API.
I will show how to write tests that verify a fake implementation of a
well defined API
and I will show how those same tests can be re-used to verify and test
real implementations of the same API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will end with a proposal that more libraries should include
verified fakes.
I will show, with real-world examples, how verified fakes can be used
by integrators
and discuss how they are superior to ad-hoc, unverified, mocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the talk I will refer to various real world, Open Source
examples. Including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flocker's Pluggable &amp;quot;Block Device Backend&amp;quot; [1]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This API allows Flocker to manipulate file systems on OpenStack
Cinder Blocks and AWS EBS devices.
It also makes it easy for third parties to implement their own
Flocker block device backends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliot's Memory Logger - and its use in testing and verifying logged messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibCloud's DummyNodeDriver - and its limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boto - as an example of a library that could benefit from a verified, introspectable fake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker-py - as an example of a library for which we have written a verified fake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be at least 5 minutes for discussion at the end of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Flocker is an Open Source Docker orchestration system written in Python by ClusterHQ&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Richard Wall</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-02:europython-2015/faking-it-the-art-of-testing-using-verified-fakes.html</guid></item><item><title>Twisted Names: DNS Building Blocks for Python Programmers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/twisted-names-dns-building-blocks-for-python-pro.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will report on my efforts to update the DNS components of
Twisted and discuss some of the things I've learned along the way. I'll
demonstrate the EDNS0, DNSSEC and DANE client support which I have been
working on and show how these new Twisted Names components can be glued
together to build novel DNS servers and clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twisted is an event-driven networking engine written in Python and
licensed under the open source MIT license. It is a platform for
developing internet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My talk will consist of four main sections. Given the 30 minute time
constraint, I may shorten or drop the two introductory parts in favour
of the narrative and demonstration of interesting new APIs and code
examples in the final two parts. My experience of delivering a similar
talk at PyconUK 2013 is that those are the parts that will most interest
the audience and prompt most audience questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my proposed sections with rough time allocations and
descriptions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="introducing-twisted-names-0-5"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Introducing Twisted Names (0-5)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twisted includes a comprehensive set of DNS components, collectively
known as Twisted Names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twistedmatrix.com/trac/wiki/TwistedNames"&gt;https://twistedmatrix.com/trac/wiki/TwistedNames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will begin the talk with a quick introduction to Twisted Names and its
capabilities, including one or two simple code examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="introducing-my-project-0-5"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Introducing My Project (0-5)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With generous funding from The NLnet Foundation I am adding EDNS(0) and
DNSSEC client support in Twisted Names, including full DNSSEC
verification and DANE support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk I will quickly summarise the steps taken and lessons learned
in securing that funding, and hope to encourage the audience to seek
funding to support there own pet OSS projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-s-new-in-twisted-names-project-progress-report-10"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What's New in Twisted Names / Project Progress Report (10)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project plan is divided into the following broad milestones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EDNS(0)&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OPT record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended Message object with additional EDNS(0) items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EDNS Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RRSET handling&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical Form and Order of Resource Records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receiving RRSETs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNSSEC&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New DNSSEC Records and Lookup Methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security-aware Non-validating Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DANE&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A twistd dns authoritative server capable of loading and serving
TLSA records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Twisted web client Agent wrapper which performs TLSA lookup and
verification of a server certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A HostnameClientEndpoint which performs TLSA lookup and
verification of a server certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A command line tool for debugging TLSA records and for verifying a
certificate file against a domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A TLSA Record class for encoding and decoding TLSA bytes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A TLSA lookup method which accepts port, protocol and hostname and
constructs a suitable TLSA domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk I will quickly outline these goals, report on my progress so
far, and show running code examples to demonstrate the new APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="future-developments-5"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Future Developments (5)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of my project is to lay foundations that will eventually allow
end-to-end DNSSEC verification in all the core Twisted networking
components, including Twisted Conch (SSH), Mail (SMTP, POP3),
Perspective Broker (RPC), Web (HTTP, XML-RPC, SOAP), Words (XMPP, IRC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally I hope that this foundation work will encourage the
development of end-to-end DNSSEC verification in many of the Open Source
and commercial projects built on top of Twisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will end the talk by outlining these exciting possibilities, and
demonstrate some code examples that illustrate these possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="q-a-5-10"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Q &amp;amp; A (5-10)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm determined to leave at least five minutes at the end for audience
questions. At PyconUK 2013 I was frustrated because I ran out of time
and ended up answering questions outside the lecture theatre; questions
which would have been interesting to the whole audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Richard Wall</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-25:europython-2014/twisted-names-dns-building-blocks-for-python-pro.html</guid></item></channel></rss>