<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ethan-rosenthal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Time series for scikit-learn people</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/time-series-for-scikit-learn-people.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ethan Rosenthal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-04:pydata-new-york-city-2019/time-series-for-scikit-learn-people.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will frame the topic of time series forecasting in the language of machine learning. This framing will be used to introduce the skits library which provides a scikit-learn-compatible API for fitting and forecasting time series models using supervised machine learning. Finally, a real-world deployment of skits involving thousands of forecasts per hour will be demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Model Remodeling with Modern Deep Learning Frameworks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/model-remodeling-with-modern-deep-learning-frameworks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ethan Rosenthal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/model-remodeling-with-modern-deep-learning-frameworks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While modern deep learning frameworks have revolutionized the ability for non-experts to train deep learning models, they have also democratized a host of other innovations which extend beyond the niche of deep learning. In this talk, I will explore some models and domains that are not commonly thought of as “machine learning” problems and show how PyTorch allows one to build more complex and scalable models than ever before. This represents an opportunity to revisit existing models, which I will do by showing how to implement them with PyTorch and integrate them into the rest of the PyData ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Diving into the deep end of clothing styles</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2017/diving-into-the-deep-end-of-clothing-styles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ethan Rosenthal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-27:pydata-new-york-city-2017/diving-into-the-deep-end-of-clothing-styles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recently resorted to deep learning-based methods for understanding the styles of our clothing at Dia&amp;amp;Co, but only after a journey through failed models and approaches. I will discuss lessons learned from this journey as well as the successful, deep learning-based approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>