<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sorawit Saengkyongam</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sorawit-saengkyongam.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Learning Joint Nonlinear Effects from Single-variable Interventions in the Presence</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/learning-joint-nonlinear-effects-from-single-variable-interventions-in-the-presence.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sorawit Saengkyongam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/learning-joint-nonlinear-effects-from-single-variable-interventions-in-the-presence.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Learning Joint Nonlinear Effects from Single-variable Interventions in the Presence of Hidden Confounders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorawit  Saengkyongam (University College London)*; Ricardo Silva (University College London)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose an approach to estimate the effect of multiple simultaneous interventions in the presence of hidden confounders. To overcome the problem of hidden confounding, we …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Learning Joint Nonlinear Effects from Single-variable Interventions in the Presence of Hidden Confounders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorawit  Saengkyongam (University College London)*; Ricardo Silva (University College London)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose an approach to estimate the effect of multiple simultaneous interventions in the presence of hidden confounders. To overcome the problem of hidden confounding, we consider the setting where we have access to not only the observational data but also sets of single-variable interventions in which each of the treatment variables is intervened on separately. We prove identifiability under the assumption that the data is generated from a nonlinear continuous structural causal model with additive Gaussian noise. In addition, we propose a simple parameter estimation method by pooling all the data from different regimes and jointly maximizing the combined likelihood. We also conduct comprehensive experiments to verify the identifiability result as well as to compare the performance of our approach against a baseline on both synthetic and real-world data.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>