<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_marcin-kowiel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to numerically represent semi-structured log data for anomaly detection?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/how-to-numerically-represent-semi-structured-log-data-for-anomaly-detection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marcin Kowiel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-12:pydata-warsaw-2019/how-to-numerically-represent-semi-structured-log-data-for-anomaly-detection.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representation of text data from semi-structured log records is a
challenging problem that is crucial for the quality of anomaly detection
engines. In the presentation, I will show a pipeline to create vector
embeddings and normalization rules on semi-structured, text data that
could be used in anomaly detection problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semi-structured data such as server logs or system activity metadata is
key to detect cybersecurity threats or security breaches. At F-Secure,
we apply a variety of machine learning methods to detect anomalies in
the stream of semi- structured text-based events to protect our
customers. However, many advanced techniques require a numerical
representation of text data (file paths, program names, command line
arguments, registry records). The most popular methods (one-hot-encoding
and simple embeddings) do not capture the specific context and semantics
of log data. Typically, when processing the log data, the vocabulary is
much bigger than in natural languages. Moreover, we need to identify and
normalize randomly generated paths, temporary files, software versions
or command-line arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present a pipeline to create vector embeddings and normalization
rules on semi-structured data using the popular natural language
processing (NLP) Word2Vec model. At the end I will show a simple anomaly
detection engine that uses the embeddings to find potentially malicious
activity. If you are interested in cybersecurity, NLP or log processing
you should find it appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>