<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_damien-george.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Writing fast and efficient MicroPython</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/writing-fast-and-efficient-micropython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damien George</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-24:pycon-au-2018/writing-fast-and-efficient-micropython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MicroPython is an implementation of Python designed to run on microcontrollers and embedded systems. These devices don't have many resources (CPU, RAM) and so it's important to write efficient scripts. This talk shows how to make the most of your resources in MicroPython, and has some fun demos!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using MicroPython in the wild</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/using-micropython-in-the-wild.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damien George</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-04:pycon-au-2017/using-micropython-in-the-wild.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MicroPython is a complete reimplementation of Python that runs on small devices like microcontrollers.  It enables users to build cool stuff - like Internet of Things devices - by combining their existing Python knowledge with a little bit of hands-on hardware hacking.  In this talk I will start with a brief overview of MicroPython, how it works, how you can try it out, and how you can use it.  I will then discuss some of the technical advances in the MicroPython software that have occurred over the past 12 months.  Finally, I will talk about some of the things MicroPython is being used for, from robotics to IoT.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Micro Python - shrinking Python down to run on a microcontroller</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2014/micro-python-shrinking-python-down-to-run-on-a-microcontroller.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damien George</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-14:pycon-uk-2014/micro-python-shrinking-python-down-to-run-on-a-microcontroller.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presented by: Damien George&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micro Python is a rewrite of the Python language that uses minimal RAM and which is optimised to run on a microcontroller (basically a very small computer). I will outline the architecture of Micro Python, explain how it minimises RAM usage, and discuss its benefits and use in the embedded electronics world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="MicroPython"></category></entry><entry><title>MicroPython: a journey from Kickstarter to Space</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/micropython-a-journey-from-kickstarter-to-space.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damien George</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-13:pycon-au-2016/micropython-a-journey-from-kickstarter-to-space.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damien George
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/199/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/199/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
MicroPython is a lean and efficient reimplementation of Python 3 with a
reduced standard library, and brings the awesomeness of Python to computing
devices with few resources, such as microcontrollers.  In this talk I will
detail my journey in building MicroPython and the various projects that it
has been used in and the people who are using it.  I will talk about running
a successful Kickstarter campaign (actually two of them!), circuit board
manufacturing, working with the European Space Agency, working with the BBC
on the micro:bit project, and the challenges of managing and funding
open-source software.  There will also be some live demos!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="MicroPython"></category></entry><entry><title>Scripting the Internet of Things</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/scripting-the-internet-of-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Damien George</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:pycon-au-2016/scripting-the-internet-of-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A big part of the Internet of Things are the end nodes, such as sensors, that are controlled by microcontrollers or other small computing devices. These devices are getting more and more sophisticated and it can be beneficial to program them with a scripting language instead of a low-level language like C. Such scripting languages need to be implemented specifically to fit and run on a microcontroller and in this talk I will discuss a few of them: Python, Lua, JavaScript and Ruby. I will talk in detail about MicroPython, a lean and efficient reimplementation of Python 3 with a reduced standard library, that runs on microcontrollers and can be used to build Internet-of-Things devices. There will be plenty of time in the talk for questions and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Internet-of-Things"></category><category term="MicroPython"></category></entry></feed>