<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_heather-shapiro.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>There's a Sign for That!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2017/theres-a-sign-for-that.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Heather Shapiro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-27:pydata-new-york-city-2017/theres-a-sign-for-that.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how to be more visually accessible to those around you? American Sign Language (ASL) is the main form of communication for many deaf Americans, yet it is not widely known in the hearing community. Learn how to convert your speech to text and then to sign to be more inclusive!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>There's a sign for that!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2017/theres-a-sign-for-that.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Heather Shapiro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-07:pygotham-2017/theres-a-sign-for-that.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how to be more visually accessible to those around you? American Sign Language (ASL) is the main form of communication for many deaf Americans, yet it is not widely known in the hearing community. Learn how to convert your speech to text and then to sign to be more inclusive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain how to use Speech to Text APIs in Python in order to record audio, convert it to text, and match it to a similar gif to show the phrase!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>An end to boring data with visualizations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/an-end-to-boring-data-with-visualizations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Heather Shapiro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/an-end-to-boring-data-with-visualizations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put the days of trying to decipher meaning from boring spreadsheets
behind you. Visualize data to give greater and immediate meaning to all
those numbers with Python. Explore the variety of options available for
data visualization in Python using different libraries and understand
which ones excel for what type of task. Create maps, statistical graphs
and more detailed or interactive visualization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="heather-shapiro-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Heather Shapiro Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heather Shapiro is a Technical Evangelist in Microsoft's Developer
Experience group, where she educates developers on Microsoft's new
technologies. In this role, Heather works closely with students and
developer communities across the North East to understand the newest
technologies and architectures. Prior to becoming a Technical
Evangelist, Heather completed her undergraduate degree at Duke
University and graduated in the Class of 2015. She received Bachelors of
Science in Computer Science and Statistical Science, and completed an
Honors Thesis about employing Bayesian Approaches to Understanding Music
Popularity. Heather blogs at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://microheather.com"&gt;http://microheather.com&lt;/a&gt; and tweets at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/microheather"&gt;http://twitter.com/microheather&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>An End to Boring Data with Visualizations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/an-end-to-boring-data-with-visualizations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Heather Shapiro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/an-end-to-boring-data-with-visualizations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put the days of trying to decipher meaning from boring spreadsheets behind you. Visualize data to give greater and immediate meaning to all those numbers with Python. Explore the variety of options available for data visualization in Python using different libraries and understand which ones excel for what type of task. Create maps, statistical graphs and more detailed or interactive visualizations that can also be used on the web, ideal to take that blog post to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>