<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trio: Async concurrency for mere mortals</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/trio-async-concurrency-for-mere-mortals.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concurrent programs are super useful: think of web apps juggling lots of
simultaneous downloads and websocket connections, chat bots tracking
multiple concurrent conversations, or web spiders fetching pages in
parallel. But &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; concurrent programs is complicated, intimidating
to newcomers, and often challenging even for experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it have to be? Python is famous for being simple and
straightforward; can Python make concurrent programming simple and
straightforward too? I think so. By carefully analyzing usability
pitfalls in other libraries, and taking advantage of new Python 3
features, I’ve come up with a new set of primitives that make it
dramatically easier to write correct concurrent programs, and
implemented them in a new library called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://trio.readthedocs.io"&gt;Trio&lt;/a&gt;. In this talk, I’ll
describe these primitives, and demonstrate how to use them to implement
a basic algorithm for speeding up TCP connections. Compared to the best
previous Python implementation, our version turns out to be easier to
understand, more correct, and dramatically shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk assumes basic familiarity with Python, but does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; require
any prior experience with concurrency, async/await, or networking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathaniel J. Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/trio-async-concurrency-for-mere-mortals.html</guid><category>trio</category><category>async</category><category>concurrency</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - 2016-05-31PM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-05-31pm.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Garson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-01:pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-05-31pm.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item></channel></rss>