<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Camelot 101</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/camelot-101.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] J Dierckx A Cuni - 4 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Pizza Napoli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Camelot , as seen on EuroPython 2010 and 2011 is a framework for
developing desktop database applications at warp speed. It is to desktop
applications what Django is to web applications. Some see it as a
replacement for MS Access, but its tight integration with SQLAlchemy
enables a vast amount of more advanced features and possibilities. This
tutorial style course will enable you to get started with your own
Camelot project. We will tackle the hurdles met when going through the
lifecycle of a desktop application First Example : We start our little
Camelot project, have a look at the concepts and terminology used within
Camelot. We go through the different parts of the application and look
at the possibilities to customize them. Declarative Models and Views :
Then we move on by defining a relational model and use introspection
together with a declarative definition of our view to generate table and
form views. We look at the various options that can be used to create
and reuse form and table definitions. Actions and Reports : Next we’ll
dive into the details of actions the user can trigger, we discuss and
experiment with the standard actions Camelot offers. One of those
actions can be the generation of a nicely formatted Word document.
Advanced Model Definition : Once an application grows, more advanced
model definition is needed. We will try out some advanced features of
SQLAlchemy and see how they interact with the graphical interface. Fine
tuning of the GUI : Here we have a look at how Qt’s model-view-delegate
framework works and how it is used by Camelot. This will enable us to
fully customize the graphical interface to our needs. Deployment and
Users : The last step of the development process is getting the
application to the users. We will discuss the deployment options and
list the things to be aware of when submitting an application to its
users. Q &amp;amp; A : Throw all Camelot questions you have in the group and try
to resolve them together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">A Cuni</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-05:europython-2012/camelot-101.html</guid></item></channel></rss>