<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Learning from the mistakes that even big projects make</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/learning-from-the-mistakes-that-even-big-projects-make.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, I've worked on a large Open Source project in python. It kind of got out of hand -- 1000s of developers and millions of lines of code. Yet despite being well resourced, we made the same mistakes that those tiny scripts you whip up to solve a small problem make. Come learn from our fail.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Still</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-24:pycon-au-2018/learning-from-the-mistakes-that-even-big-projects-make.html</guid></item><item><title>What is OpenStack? by Michael Still</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/what-is-openstack-by-michael-still.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is one of the biggest python projects ever, and is hiring
plenty of interesting python people to work on Open Source, which is
cool. Yet, many people tell me that they don't really understand what
OpenStack is. Let's fix that once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 minutes isn't a long time, so what I'll provide is an overview of the
various components of OpenStack and how they tie together. We'll cover
what bits might be of interest to your average python hacker, as well as
the general problems we're trying to solve. I secretly hope this will
enthuse people to come and hack on OpenStack, but its also cool if
audience members walk away from the talk deciding that OpenStack is not
of interest to them -- so long as they now understand vaguely what
OpenStack is, then we're cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll also try and cover how the OpenStack Foundation and code governance
model works, but it might require talking really fast. We shall see!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Still</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-07:pycon-au-2014/what-is-openstack-by-michael-still.html</guid></item></channel></rss>