<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jacob-schreiber.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>apricot: Submodular Selection for Data Summarization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/apricot-submodular-selection-for-data-summarization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacob Schreiber</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/apricot-submodular-selection-for-data-summarization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submodular selection can be used to reduce a complex data set down to a representative subset. This subset can then be used to train machine learning models with high efficiency and resulting accuracy. In this talk we will introduce apricot, a Python package for submodular selection, and show examples of its usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>pomegranate Fast and Flexible Probabilistic Modeling in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/pomegranate-fast-and-flexible-probabilistic-modeling-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacob Schreiber</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:scipy-2017/pomegranate-fast-and-flexible-probabilistic-modeling-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pomegranate is a python package that extends the ideas behind scikit-learn to probabilistic models such as mixtures, Bayesian networks, and hidden Markov models. pomegranate is built to be modular by separating out the probability distributions from the models themselves, allowing both arbitrary distributions to be used for any model, and making the modeling of different features with different distributions a breeze. pomegranate was built with large quantities of data in mind, supporting both an out-of-core API for when your data doesn't fit in memory, built-in multi-threaded parallelism made possibly by releasing the GIL, and most recently GPU support for large Gaussian models. This talk will be an overview of the most important features behind pomegranate and motivate the concept of probabilistic modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pomegranate"></category></entry><entry><title>Rambutan - A Python Package for Predicting 3D Genome Architecture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/rambutan-a-python-package-for-predicting-3d-genome-architecture.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacob Schreiber</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:scipy-2017/rambutan-a-python-package-for-predicting-3d-genome-architecture.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, Hi-C has been used to probe the 3D chromatin architecture of multiple organisms and cell types. A computational method for predicting pairwise contacts without the need to run a Hi-C experiment would be invaluable in understanding the role that 3D chromatin architecture plays in genome biology. In this talk I will describe Rambutan, a Python package that uses a deep convolutional neural network to predict Hi-C contacts at 1 kb resolution using nucleotide sequence and DNaseI assay signal as inputs. I will explain the area of chromatin architecture briefly, how Rambutan fits in with other methods in the field, validate this model using both traditional accuracy metrics and at biological tasks, and show how one can use Rambutan simply in their own work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Pomegranate: fast and flexible probabilistic models in python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/pomegranate-fast-and-flexible-probabilistic-models-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacob Schreiber</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-26:pydata-chicago-2016/pomegranate-fast-and-flexible-probabilistic-models-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/secret/cxZTghInOlIeOs"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/secret/cxZTghInOlIeOs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pomegranate is a python module for probabilistic modelling focusing on both ease of use and speed, beating out competitors, including scikit-learn, in benchmarks. In this talk I will describe how to use pomegranate to simply create sophisticated hidden Markov models, Bayesian Networks, General Mixture Models (and more!) and benchmark their implementations to other python packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="models"></category></entry></feed>