<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Isabel Zimmerman</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_isabel-zimmerman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Thanks, I Made It with Quartodoc</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/thanks-i-made-it-with-quartodoc.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Isabel Zimmerman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/thanks-i-made-it-with-quartodoc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Python package developers create documentation, they typically must choose between mostly auto-generated docs or writing all the docs by hand. This is problematic since effective documentation has a mix of function references, high-level context, examples, and other content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quartodoc is a new documentation system that automatically generates Python …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Python package developers create documentation, they typically must choose between mostly auto-generated docs or writing all the docs by hand. This is problematic since effective documentation has a mix of function references, high-level context, examples, and other content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quartodoc is a new documentation system that automatically generates Python function references within Quarto websites. This talk will discuss pkgdown's success in the R ecosystem and how those wins can be replicated in Python with quartodoc examples. Listeners will walk away knowing more about what makes documentation delightful (or painful), when to use quartodoc, and how to use this tool to make docs for a Python package.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Introducing Positron, a new data science IDE</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/introducing-positron-a-new-data-science-ide.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Julia Silge</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/introducing-positron-a-new-data-science-ide.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Positron is a next-generation data science IDE that is newly available to the community for early beta testing. This new IDE is an extensible tool built to facilitate exploratory data analysis, reproducible authoring, and publishing data artifacts. Positron currently supports these data workflows in either or both Python and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Positron is a next-generation data science IDE that is newly available to the community for early beta testing. This new IDE is an extensible tool built to facilitate exploratory data analysis, reproducible authoring, and publishing data artifacts. Positron currently supports these data workflows in either or both Python and R and is designed with a forward-looking architecture that can support other data science languages in the future. In this session, learn from the team-building Positron about how and why it is designed the way it is, what will feel familiar or new coming from other IDEs, and whether it might be a good fit for your own work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>