<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alistair-miles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Parameter Estimation Using the Python Package pymcmcstat</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/parameter-estimation-using-the-python-package-pymcmcstat.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alistair Miles</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/parameter-estimation-using-the-python-package-pymcmcstat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metropolis algorithms have greatly expanded our ability to estimate parameter distributions. In this talk we introduce pymcmcstat [Miles, 2018], which utilizes the Delayed Rejection Adaptive Metropolis (DRAM) algorithm [Haario et al., 2006, Haario et al., 2001] to perform Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) simulations. The user interface provides a straight forward environment for experienced and new Python users to quickly compare their models with data. Furthermore, the package provides a wide variety of diagnostic tools for visualizing uncertainty propagation. This package has been utilized in a wide array of scientific and engineering problems, including radiation source localization and constitutive model development of smart material systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Zarr: Scalable Storage of Tensor Data for Use in Parallel and Distributed Computing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/zarr-scalable-storage-of-tensor-data-for-use-in-parallel-and-distributed-computing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alistair Miles</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/zarr-scalable-storage-of-tensor-data-for-use-in-parallel-and-distributed-computing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many scientific problems involve computing over large N-dimensional typed arrays of data, and reading or writing data is often the major bottleneck limiting speed or scalability. The Zarr project is developing a simple, scalable approach to storage of such data in a way that is compatible with a range of approaches to distributed and parallel computing. We describe the Zarr protocol and data storage format, and the current state of implementations for various programming languages including Python. We also describe current uses of Zarr in malaria genomics, the Human Cell Atlas, and the Pangeo project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>