<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_katerina-falk.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Science with the world’s biggest lasers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/science-with-the-worlds-biggest-lasers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kateřina Falk</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-09:pycon-cz-2017/science-with-the-worlds-biggest-lasers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laser is possibly the most important invention of the 20th century
with applications spanning across all human activities from medicine,
telecommunications, information technology or entertainment to
manufacturing, defense, energy production or fundamental science
research in astrophysics or cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give you a brief overview of how lasers work, their
applications and future developments. It will also provide a tour of
the world’s biggest laser facilities and the new laser center ELI
Beamlines currently constructed on the outskirts of Prague that will
soon harbor the most powerful laser beam in the world. A brief
outline of the most recent research in particle acceleration and
ultra-fast x-ray and particle diagnostics by Katerina Falk will also
be given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kateřina works as a scientist specializing in plasma physics with a
special focus dense plasmas relevant to fusion technology and
laboratory astrophysics. She earned her degrees at Imperial College
London and the University of Oxford, before moving to New Mexico,
USA, where she joined a research group at Los Alamos National
Laboratory. She has worked on the biggest laser systems on the planet
before joining the scientific team at ELI Beamlines, Czech Academy of
Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>