<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jon-riehl.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Lightning Talks - Wednesday</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/lightning-talks-wednesday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jake Vanderplas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/lightning-talks-wednesday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SciPy Sparse Graphs, Jake Vanderplas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animation for Traits and Chaco, Corran Webster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pynthantics, Jon Roland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State of the Numba, Jon Riehl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pipe-o-matic call, Walker Hale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Command ND-Array, Frédéric Bastien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category><category term="Plenary"></category></entry><entry><title>Numba Python bytecode to LLVM translator</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/numba-python-bytecode-to-llvm-translator.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jon Riehl</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/numba-python-bytecode-to-llvm-translator.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numba is a Python bytecode to LLVM translator that allows creation of
fast, machine code from Python functions. The Low Level Virtual Machine
(LLVM) project is rapidly becoming a hardware-industry standard for the
intermediate representation (IR) of compiled codes. Numba's high-level
translator to the LLVM IR provides Python the ability to take advantage
of the machine code generated by the hardware manufacturers
contributions to LLVM. Numba translates a Python function comprised of a
subset of Python syntax to machine code using simple type inference and
the creation of multiple machine-code versions. In this talk, I will
describe the design of Numba, illustrate its applications to multiple
domains and discuss the enhancements to NumPy and SciPy that can benefit
from this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hpc"></category></entry><entry><title>Scientific Knowledge Management with Web of Trails</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/scientific-knowledge-management-with-web-of-trail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jon Riehl</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/scientific-knowledge-management-with-web-of-trail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you hate repeating yourself? Want to know when your publication is
repeating someone else? The Web of Trails project is a solution to
knowledge management that empowers users to quickly find repetition of
key phrases. Using syntactic indexing, as opposed to lexical techniques,
this approach is capable of representing the literature using less space
while providing high value results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web of Trails (WOT) is an open source project that uses context-free
grammars (CFG's) as the basic building block for search. Current search
technology relies upon the presence of words on a page, sometimes
augmented with statistical correlations among words. Even with these
restrictions, maintenance of an index requires storage much greater than
the input size (a polynomial function of it). CFG's have been used for
decades in compilation and language tools, and more recently in data
compression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary advantage of this CFG approach, based upon the Sequitur
algorithm, is that it indexes content in linear-space, not
polynomial-space. The secondary advantage is that combined with research
in inference, grammars can express human concepts and connections rather
than just correlations. This project uses grammar and syntactic analysis
to replace lexical and word-based approaches to the problem of searching
collections of digital artifacts. Benchmarking in web content indexing
will be shown relative to popular alternatives such Apache Lucene and
Amazon Cloud Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to implementing content indexing with Sequitur, this project
will enable domain-specific extensions of WOT. Once complete, we will
research novel techniques for generalizing the grammars inferred by
Sequitur. As this fundamental research develops, it will inform later
framework development and increase search precision. This is a big leap
in the state of the art, as text artifacts are no longer represented as
bags of words, but as bags on non-terminals in a growing and adapting
grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>