<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A/B Testing in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/ab-testing-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python development has had a great emergence in development of
statistical packages, algorithms, and implementations. However, with the
development and ease of practicing statistics &amp;amp; algorithms, there are
still some rules and constraints one must follow to obtain quality
solutions. And that is especially true with AB Testing, a statistical
procedure to provide data- driven insights in uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be a breakout Session on frequentist AB Testing in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll explore the jungle of application and statistical methodology and
practice with examples of Click Through Rates, the early metrics of
choice for AB Testing in production. That being said, compared to your
last statistics course you may have taken in the past, there are still
some rules and constraints one must follow to obtain quality solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raul Maldonado</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/ab-testing-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>AB Testing in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/ab-testing-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Python development has had a great emergence in development of statistical packages, algorithms, and implementations. However, with the development and ease of practicing statistics &amp;amp; algorithms, there are still some rules and constraints one must follow to obtain quality solutions. And that is especially true with AB Testing, a statistical procedure to provide data-driven insights in uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Data Analyst residing in San Francisco, CA. Specialize in SQL Python, BI, and other related responsibilities. Additionally, Raul spends his time creating technical side-projects and volunteering in the intersection of Data and Technology/Coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raul Maldonado</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-16:pybay-2019/ab-testing-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks Day 3 Round 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/lightning-talks-day-3-round-2.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amjith Ramanujam</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/lightning-talks-day-3-round-2.html</guid></item></channel></rss>