<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Nik Kantar</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title># TODO: Add Comments: 5 Tips for _Winning_ at Code Comments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/todo-add-comments-5-tips-for-_winning_-at-code-comments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk covers five unexpected pieces of advice for writing better
code comments. From an editor change to some sound writing advice, it
takes a brief journey into a few habits of successful commenters.
Disclaimer: opinions ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation often gets paid lip service, and code comments almost
always suffer the most. And yet they're often that last-moment savior
during archeological expeditions into depths no longer known, unearthing
obscure bugs or just trying to understand the foundation upon which to
build something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, we're all human, and thus oh so very fallible. And so we fall prey
to habits which make the situation worse over time, usually little by
little. We try to be heroes, but end up the very villains we bemoan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Okay, how can I do better?&amp;quot; you ask. In this talk we'll cover five
simple things you can do to hack yourself into writing better comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nik Kantar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-27:/pyohio-2019/todo-add-comments-5-tips-for-_winning_-at-code-comments.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2019</category></item><item><title>Sunday Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/sunday-lightning-talks.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kat Passen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-27:/pyohio-2019/sunday-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2019</category></item><item><title>Adafruit Circuit Playground Express as an “On Air” Light</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2023/adafruit-circuit-playground-express-as-an-on-air-light.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The swag bags for PyCon 2019 included an Adafruit Circuit Playground
Express, a lovely little circuit board with many inputs and outputs,
and—crucially for us—the ability to run Python. With the power of Python
and a few other bits of software, it’s possible to turn one into your
personal “On Air” light. This talk will walk the viewer through the
steps required to accomplish this, and reference related resources for
the sake of inspiration. There will be pretty lights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nik Kantar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-12-16:/pyohio-2023/adafruit-circuit-playground-express-as-an-on-air-light.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2023</category></item></channel></rss>