<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ville-tuulos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Pushing the limits of Python ML infra at Netflix</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/pushing-the-limits-of-python-ml-infra-at-netflix.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ville Tuulos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-17:pybay-2019/pushing-the-limits-of-python-ml-infra-at-netflix.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
We will share our experiences on building Metaflow, a Python library that is used at Netflix to build and operate hundreds of machine learning applications. This talk is for you if you want to learn how to develop systems for big data and ML in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Metaflow is a Python library that empowers data scientists to prototype, build, deploy, and operate end-to-end machine learning solutions. We started building Metaflow at Netflix to provide a solid foundation for hundreds of internal ML use cases, from classical statistical analysis to large-scale applications of deep learning. Metaflow is designed with a human-centric mindset: instead of reinventing the wheel for large-scale computing or machine learning, we integrate existing solutions into a delightfully consistent and easy-to-use package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk focuses on the internals of Metaflow; it will highlight lessons that we have learned in building a Python library that needs to be robust, performant, and flexible enough to solve a large set of complex real-world business problems related to machine learning. We will share our learnings around optimizing the performance of Python, in particular, related to concurrency. We will also talk about the complexities of dependency management, the overall architecture of the library and the cloud-based compute and storage systems it relies on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Ravi is an engineer on the ML Infrastructure team at Netflix. He has been building large scale systems focusing on performance, simplified user journeys and intuitive APIs in MLI and previously in Search Indexing at Google (6 years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>TrailDB tutorial Store and process billions of events efficiently</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-san-francisco-2016/traildb-tutorial-store-and-process-billions-of-events-efficiently.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ville Tuulos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-24:pydata-san-francisco-2016/traildb-tutorial-store-and-process-billions-of-events-efficiently.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData SF 2016
Ville Tuulos | TrailDB tutorial Store and process billions of events efficiently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TrailDB is an efficient library for storing and querying series of events. It shines at compressing a large number of discrete events in a small space - often small enough to allow processing on a single server. TrailDB is implemented in C and it comes with Python bindings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hands-on tutorial that gets you started with TrailDB. Bring your own data or play with a public data set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is TrailDB?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TrailDB is designed to be a core building block for systems that need to store and process a large number of discrete events, organized by a primary key. It is complementary to existing relational and time-series databases and key-value stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes TrailDB different is immutability: Immutable data enables deeper compression, scalability, and architectural decisions, which would not be feasible with existing databases. This is especially true for cloud environments with object stores like Amazon S3 that are a perfect match for compressed, immutable files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer productivity is another main motivation of TrailDB. Individual files are easy to manipulate using standard filesystem tools. The easily portable C library has only a few easily available dependencies, making it easily deployable. The API is clean and minimal by design. Language bindings are provided for Python, Go, Haskell, R, and D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TrailDB is a perfect match for use cases that involve detecting patterns over time, such as web/mobile analytics, anomaly detection, and various machine learning models. Since 2014, AdRoll has used TrailDB to store and query over 20 trillion events that power a number of products at AdRoll. TrailDB was open-sourced in May 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>