<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Heinrich Peters</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_heinrich-peters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>An Integrated Toolkit for Collaborative Machine Learning Model Development</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/an-integrated-toolkit-for-collaborative-machine-learning-model-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Heinrich Peters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/an-integrated-toolkit-for-collaborative-machine-learning-model-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Model Share AI (AIMS) is an easy-to-use Python library designed to streamline collaborative ML model development, model provenance tracking, and model deployment, as well as a host of other functions aiming to maximize the real-world impact of ML research. AIMS features collaborative project spaces, allowing users to analyze and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Model Share AI (AIMS) is an easy-to-use Python library designed to streamline collaborative ML model development, model provenance tracking, and model deployment, as well as a host of other functions aiming to maximize the real-world impact of ML research. AIMS features collaborative project spaces, allowing users to analyze and compare their models in a standardized fashion. Model performance and various model metadata are automatically captured to facilitate provenance tracking and allow users to learn from and build on previous submissions. Additionally, AIMS allows users to deploy ML models built in Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow Keras, PyTorch, and ONNX into live REST APIs and automatically generated web apps with minimal code. The ability to deploy models with minimal effort and to make them accessible to non-technical end-users through web apps has the potential to make ML research more applicable to real-world challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>