<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Brian Ziebart</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brian-ziebart.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Adversarial Learning for 3D Matching</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/adversarial-learning-for-3d-matching.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wei Xing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/adversarial-learning-for-3d-matching.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Adversarial Learning for 3D Matching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wei Xing (University of Illinois at Chicago)*; Brian Ziebart (UIC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structured prediction of objects in spaces that are inherently difficult to search or compactly characterize is a particularly challenging task. For example, though bipartite matchings in two dimensions can be tractably optimized and learned …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Adversarial Learning for 3D Matching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wei Xing (University of Illinois at Chicago)*; Brian Ziebart (UIC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structured prediction of objects in spaces that are inherently difficult to search or compactly characterize is a particularly challenging task. For example, though bipartite matchings in two dimensions can be tractably optimized and learned, the higher-dimensional generalization—3D matchings—are NP-hard to optimally obtain and the set of potential solutions cannot be compactly characterized. Though approximation is therefore necessary, prevalent structured prediction methods inherit the weaknesses they possess in the two-dimensional setting either suffering from inconsistency or intractability—even when the approximations are sufficient. In this paper, we explore extending an adversarial approach to learning bipartite matchings that avoids these weaknesses to the three dimensional setting. We assess the benefits compared to margin-based methods on a three-frame tracking problem.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>