<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Melanie Arbor</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keynote: Come on in, the Water’s Fine: Making Python More Approachable</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/keynote-come-on-in-the-waters-fine-making-python-more-approachable.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has grown to be the largest programming language in the world; that’s one big pool. But like all things tech there are too many things that keep folx out of the water, and lots of ways we can get them diving into the deep end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk shares the perspectives of two developers who benefitted from a community that was welcoming, supportive, and awesome. They’ll share the advice they did and DIDN'T receive; stories from along the way; and how those of us already floating can make room for all the new people wanting to join in on the fun. Grab your floaties, kids—let’s jump in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melanie Arbor</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-17:/djangocon-us-2022/keynote-come-on-in-the-waters-fine-making-python-more-approachable.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2022</category></item><item><title>Cakeprehensions: A Recipe for Success with Comprehensions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2025/cakeprehensions-a-recipe-for-success-with-comprehensions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Melanie Arbor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/E7L3BV"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/E7L3BV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you seen Python’s comprehensions but found them odd and intimidating? You’re not alone! Whether you’re just starting out with Python, or you’ve been using it for a long time, I wouldn’t blame you for steering clear of the strange “this for this in that” syntax. But fear not; I will rescue you with cake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll walk through for loops, and how comprehensions are their tasty cousins. We'll talk about the various comprehensions we have at our disposal, including dictionary comprehensions, and comprehensions with conditionals. And then, like a towering 3-tiered cake, we'll try our hand at nested comprehensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will arm you with a mental anchor to fall back on every time you write a comprehension, regardless of how simple or complex. Over time—if you use this recipe enough—you won’t even need to crack open the cookbook. We will ask…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we want? Cake!
When do we want it? As we loop over this iterable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll leave hungry for those confusing-looking Python treats… and cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Apr 26 15:15:00 2025 at Reis River Ranch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Melanie Arbor</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-26:/north-bay-python-2025/cakeprehensions-a-recipe-for-success-with-comprehensions.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2025</category></item></channel></rss>