<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brian-curtin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python 3 and the Road Ahead</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2014/python-3-and-the-road-ahead.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-06-03:pycon-russia-2014/python-3-and-the-road-ahead.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn where we're at with Python 3, where we're going, and how we'll get there.
The talk will include a recap of Python 3 discussions from the Python Language Summit as well as some of the ideas that came out of it.
There's a lot of talk around the community about what to do, and there are some plans to move forward. Find out what the future holds for Python 2.7 and the rest of the Python 3 series.
You'll also find out about some great resources to help your own projects along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Set it, and forget it! Auto Scale on Rackspace</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/chipy/set-it-and-forget-it-auto-scale-on-rackspace.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-09-12:chipy/set-it-and-forget-it-auto-scale-on-rackspace.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rackspace is rolling out a new service to allow your cloud to scale on
its own, called Auto Scale. Built on Monitoring, Auto Scale allows you
to grow or shrink your fleet of resources as demand changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pyrax, a Python package for working with OpenStack-based clouds like
Rackspace's, just released Auto Scale and Monitoring support with
version 1.5.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll show how you can use pyrax to deploy servers and automatically add
or remove them based on their usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python 3.3.0 Release</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/chipy/python-330-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-11:chipy/python-330-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brian will cover the September 29th release of Python 3 (3.3.0)
including some highly technical details and importing information for
the casual users. He will go over some of the particular Window's stuff
while leaving the talk's focus on an assortment of cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Development of Python and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--the-development-of-python-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--the-development-of-python-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Development of Python and You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Curtin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an inside look at what it takes to work on CPython, from getting
setup with the source and navigating the bug tracker, to the best
practices for having your work accepted. We'll find, categorize, and fix
an issue in Python to get you started. This talk is ideal for those who
are new to open source projects or are interested in the Python
development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People from all backgrounds, users of all platforms, and developers of
all levels are necessary in the development of Python. From writing code
to documentation, it takes all kinds of people to make an impact. If
you've used Python, we need you, and what better place to get involved
than at PyCon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010 saw a rise in the number of contributors to CPython, and the PSF
stepped in to support the efforts of those wanting to get involved. Are
you up for the challenge? This talk dives right into what it takes to
get involved, covering the who, what, where, when, and why of Python
development, going through the whole process live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference is over, stick around with the CPython crew and
hack away!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="coredev"></category><category term="cpython"></category><category term="development"></category><category term="gettinginvolved"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry><entry><title>1. PSF Sprints - Supporting the community one sprint at at time</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/1-psf-sprints-supporting-the-community-one-spr.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-11:pycon-us-2012/1-psf-sprints-supporting-the-community-one-spr.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Formed in 2010, the PSF Sprints committee set out to support local
communities getting together to make great software by funding their
sprints with up to $300 USD. No matter the project, the PSF wants to
help you contribute to the Python ecosystem. Come see what we're doing,
how we're doing it, who we've supported, and see how you can take part
as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PSF Sprint committee offers up to $300 USD to groups that organize
sprint efforts on open source projects in the Python world. From working
on Python itself, to the vast array of projects in the community, we
take great interest in keeping you interested. We're also interested in
buying you dinner, providing a place to work at, and buying t-shirts or
other goodies for sprint attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Committee Goals&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fund existing sprint groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get new groups interested in sprinting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate interest in contribution to Python projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertise sprint events, including those at conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have fun, learn, and contribute with other community members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How We Operate&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive applications, vote, advertise, reimburse after event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Past Sponsorships&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;packaging, Genshi, matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upcoming Sponsorships&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon (will update closer to conference)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How To Receive Funding&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to apply, how to be reimbursed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What's New in Python on Windows</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/whats-new-in-python-on-windows.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-11:pycon-us-2012/whats-new-in-python-on-windows.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With nearly 1.5 million downloads per month, the CPython installers for
Windows account for a huge amount of the traffic through python.org, and
they're the most common way for Windows users to obtain Python. Take a
look at what's going on with Python on Windows and see what the road
ahead looks like for Python 3.3.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What is the Python Software Foundation?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/what-is-the-python-software-foundation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-16:pycon-us-2013/what-is-the-python-software-foundation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To a lot of people, the Python Software Foundation is a black box. After
years of being on the outside of the box, a few years on the inside have
given a good look at what this foundation is and why it matters. Come
see what the PSF is about, what it's doing, and what you can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry></feed>