<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Brainwaves for Hackers 2.0</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/brainwaves-for-hackers-20.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andreas Klostermann - Brainwaves for Hackers 2.0
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a sequel to &amp;quot;Brainwaves for Hackers&amp;quot; and illustrates some
experiments you can do with a Neurosky Mindwave headset, a bluetooth
enabled EEG device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll also talk some more about how to integrate the device with the IPython&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notebook for real time viewing and how to use the Mindwave with the
Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Klostermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-07:europython-2015/brainwaves-for-hackers-20.html</guid></item><item><title>Brainwaves for Hackers 3.0</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/brainwaves-for-hackers-30.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andreas Klostermann - Brainwaves for Hackers 3.0
[EuroPython 2016]
[20 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/brainwaves-for-hackers-3"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/brainwaves-for-hackers-3&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about using our &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; skills to explore the
&lt;strong&gt;secrets of our brains&lt;/strong&gt;.   Using the Neurosky Mindwave as a
bluetooth connected EEG device, I'll talk about new experiments I have
performed inside the Jupyter notebook, for example &amp;quot;Evoked Response
Potentials&amp;quot; and more about &amp;quot;Neuro Feedback&amp;quot; training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electroencephalography &lt;strong&gt;(EEG)&lt;/strong&gt; measures potential waves originating
within the brain. Billions of brain cells fire  inside your brain,
each sending out a minuscule wave. The summed potential waves can be
measured, even with quite cheap and &lt;strong&gt;portable devices&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the third major version of this talk, I'll talk briefly about
the Neurosky Mindwave and the Muse headset. I have also developed more
interactive Jupyter experiments, which I'll demonstrate in the talk.
For example &lt;strong&gt;Evoked Response Potentials (ERP)&lt;/strong&gt; can be demonstrated
with relatively simple means. Also I'll talk some more about
experiments with &lt;strong&gt;Neuro Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Klostermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/brainwaves-for-hackers-30.html</guid></item><item><title>Brain Waves for Hackers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/brain-waves-for-hackers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the Neurosky Mindwave headset we can read brain waves via
bluetooth. In this talk I will present ways to interface with this
device and to analyze their data, mostly from the perspective of a
Python hacker, and not so much from the perspective of academic research
or the development of production-ready software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will convey the basic scientific and technical background, keeping in
mind the non-medical audience, and touch on several practical
applications, especially Neurofeedback and its use for personal mental
training and potential therapeutic uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audience can expect to walk away with a basic knowledge of EEG
analysis, Neurofeedback and how to start experimenting with these
devices on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new class of cheap consumer EEG devices allows ordinary hackers and
even high school students a glimpse into the human brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present how to use the &amp;quot;Neurosky Mindwave&amp;quot; headset with
python software, and lay out the basic scientific and technical
background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mindwave Mobile is a device that can be easily talked to using
bluetooth, and it talks a binary protocol which is specifically designed
to be useful without much computing power in the receiving device or
advanced knowledge of signal processing. In fact, an Arduino with a few
lines of code is perfectly capable of parsing some of the byte stream
and reacting to the mental state of the user, while fully-featured
python software can do advanced analysis using PyEEG and Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same hardware module and protocol is used in the Nekomimi headset
(mind-controlled cat ears for cosplay) and some Boardgames (MindFlex).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A python library for interfacing with the headset is presented and will
be demonstrated on stage. Mostly kivy applications will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I will present some data analysis you can perform with pandas and
scipy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurofeedback is a type of mental exercise where a computer uses the EEG
data to direct the user towards certain mental states. In the easiest
configuration a program would display a bar with the &amp;quot;concentration&amp;quot;
level, and the user would learn how to tilt this bar upwards. In more
complicated setups a game could react favorably towards states like
relaxation or concentration. Using Gamification, Neurofeedback can
provide a more engaging experience for children or adults, than other
techniques with similar goals, like mindfulness meditation, and the more
immediate feedback should enhance the effectiveness of mental training,
though that has not been investigated scientifically yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurofeedback has been shown to be effective (albeit not recommended as
sole treatment) in Patients with Attention Deficit Hyperactivity
Disorder (ADHD), Epilepsy and Dementia. Some background about these
conditions and applications of Neurofeedback to them will be given. The
first use of Neurofeedback was done in Cats, during early experiments
with EEG electrodes in the 60ies. Cats where conditioned to exhibit
certain wave patterns, and later, due to a coincidence, the researchers
noticed that the conditioned cats where more resistant to
epilepsy-inducing medications. The effect has since been reproduced in
humans, in cases where medications did not work sufficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ample hints on not to treat any of this information as medical advice
will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to promote Neurofeedback as a useful mental
training and to encourage development of applications around
Neurofeedback and the analysis of EEG data, from the perspective of a
python hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a similar talk at PyConDe 2013 in Cologne. The new talk will be
in English, show some improvements on the software, and more advanced
demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Klostermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-22:europython-2014/brain-waves-for-hackers.html</guid></item><item><title>Gehirnwellen für Hacker</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/gehirnwellen-fur-hacker.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag beschreibt das Neurosky Mindwave Headset, wie man es mit
Python von einem Linuxsystem aus ansteuert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimale biophysikalische Grundlagen zu Gehirnströmen werden erklärt um
ein Gefühl für Fähigkeiten und Grenzen dieses Systems zu vermitteln.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es werden Anwendungen im Neurofeedback vorgestellt, wie sie zum Beispiel
gegen das Aufmerksamkeitsdefizit-/Hyperaktivitätsstörungssyndrom (ADHS)
als unterstützende Maßnahme eingesetzt werden könnten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zum Thema Brain Computer Interfaces stelle ich vor was mit diesem
Headset funktioniert und was nicht.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Klostermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-17:pycon-de-2013/gehirnwellen-fur-hacker.html</guid><category>biology</category><category>brain computer interfaces</category><category>eeg</category><category>medicine</category><category>neurofeedback</category><category>raspberry pi</category></item></channel></rss>