<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Python to make learning Python better</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2019/using-python-to-make-learning-python-better.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As programmers one of the biggest super-powers we have is to improve the world by making new tools, automating work and making the tedious easy. As educators we know that things like personalised learning, scaffolding, and feedback really help our students. But doing all that can be challenging! We don’t have the tools, and it’s really tedious. Hang on!? Isn’t that our super-power?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’ll explore how we can use our super-powers as programmers (and as educators) to improve our own practice. I’ll talk about how we can help develop deeper understanding in our students, and use tools (that we build) to do it! Programming isn’t just for “app developers” it’s something that everyone can use, so let’s demonstrate that by using it ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2019.pycon-au.org/talks/using-python-to-make-learning-python-better"&gt;https://2019.pycon-au.org/talks/using-python-to-make-learning-python-better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Aug  2 09:15:00 2019 at C3.4 &amp;amp; C3.5&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Taylor</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-02:pycon-au-2019/using-python-to-make-learning-python-better.html</guid></item><item><title>Running Python on your brain computer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/running-python-on-your-brain-computer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading and predicting what code will do is a fundamental coding skill. But when students read code are they executing it on their brain computer? Or do they only read the words?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore learning to read and trace code, misconceptions and how to build a really good brain computer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Taylor</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-24:pycon-au-2018/running-python-on-your-brain-computer.html</guid></item></channel></rss>