<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building a Django Community in Africa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2019/building-a-django-community-in-africa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fast spread of Django in Africa through some initiatives such as Django Girls and Python Conferences has gained popularity especially in the West of Africa. Pushing the agenda of creating an active community will go a long way to promote the use of Django and strengthen the relationship between Django developers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-21:/djangocon-europe-2019/building-a-django-community-in-africa.html</guid><category>DjangoCon Europe 2019</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Finding Purpose in Open Source Through Community Building.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/keynote-finding-purpose-in-open-source-through-community-building.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I had little enthusiasm for Computers and Mathematics and I found it difficult to navigate these areas in school. However, after my first encounter as a mentee at a Django Girls event held in Accra, Ghana, I saw the value of Open Source Software and Community and was challenged to encourage the participation of more women. This challenge evolved into a bigger one which involved bringing together more Africans, to share ideas, collaborate, and find their career paths, while also inspiring the next generation of contributors. My efforts in strategic team building, projects, and communities like Django Girls and PyCon Africa helped us reach these goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will share my journey of how I was challenged to contribute to open source by bringing others into it, and how it has helped me develop resilience and a growth mindset. I will discuss how I discovered the benefits of open source, overcame the challenges of contributing, became strategic about community building, embraced discomfort, and ultimately found a sense of purpose and fulfillment in my contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through my experience, I aim to encourage others to keep welcoming new people, particularly those from underrepresented groups, to participate in open source. Show them the various ways that open source can help them improve the world and fulfill their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/djangocon-us-2023/keynote-finding-purpose-in-open-source-through-community-building.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/diversity-inclusion-panel.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Debora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-18:/pycon-us-2024/diversity-inclusion-panel.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Starting my career, the Open Source way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-starting-my-career-the-open-source-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote in English&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/keynote-starting-my-career-the-open-source-way.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Begin with the End in Mind: Why Your Community Work Matters</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/keynote-begin-with-the-end-in-mind-why-your-community-work-matters.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the world of open source, community work often begins with passion,
but to make it sustainable and impactful, we must begin with the end in
mind. In this keynote, I will reflect on my journey from contributing to
Django Girls to leading PyLadies Ghana and building inclusive tech
communities across Africa. Drawing lessons from open source leadership,
cultural identity, and personal growth, we will explore what it truly
means to build communities that outlast us. This talk challenges
attendees to rethink community involvement not just as volunteering, but
as systems-building, infused with purpose, clarity, and intention.
Through storytelling, reflection, and real-world examples, we will
experience how every contribution can create ripple effects of
confidence, leadership, and global impact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-26:/pyohio-2025/keynote-begin-with-the-end-in-mind-why-your-community-work-matters.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2025</category></item></channel></rss>