<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Conversational AI with Rasa Core &amp; NLU</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2018/conversational-ai-with-rasa-core-nlu.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rasa NLU &amp;amp; Rasa Core are open source libraries for building machine learning-based chatbots and voice assistants. In this live-coding workshop you will learn the fundamentals of conversational AI and how to build your own using these open source libraries. In this workshop we will live-code a useful, engaging conversational AI bot based entirely on machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Bocklisch</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-26:pydata-amsterdam-2018/conversational-ai-with-rasa-core-nlu.html</guid></item><item><title>Conversational AI: Building clever chatbots</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/conversational-ai-building-clever-chatbots.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most chatbots and voice skills are based on a state machine and too many if/else statements. Tom will show you how to move past that and build flexible, robust experiences using machine learning throughout the stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversational software is everywhere: messaging apps have opened up APIs to bot developers and millions of consumers now own voice controlled speakers. But the tools and frameworks for building these systems are still immature. Tom will talk about Rasa, an open source machine learning framework for building conversational software. The talk will cover the algorithms Rasa uses to build flexible and robust voice and text systems, the trade offs in using supervised versus reinforcement learning, and whether it's really such a good idea to generate text with LSTMs. Outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Components : NLU , DM , integration , NLG
Overview of available tools and frameworks
Describe how Rasa does NLU
Motivation &amp;amp; a chatbot leading to state machine hell
How Rasa does dialogue management.
How to advance a bots capabilities - closing the loop and data collection.
Current research topics and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tom Bocklisch</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/conversational-ai-building-clever-chatbots.html</guid></item></channel></rss>