<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dom-weldon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Dash : applications web de visualisation de données interactives sans Javascript</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2019/dash-applications-web-de-visualisation-de-donnees-interactives-sans-javascript.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dom Weldon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-02:pycon-fr-2019/dash-applications-web-de-visualisation-de-donnees-interactives-sans-javascript.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aujourd’hui, on ne veut plus simplement produire un rapport PDF pour son projet de data science ou d'apprentissage automatique. De plus en plus, les utilisateurs souhaitent des outils interactifs permettant d'explorer des données avec des visualisations et des graphiques interactifs. Ces outils étant exécutés dans un navigateur web, soit il faut embaucher un spécialiste front end  qui respire le Javascript dans son équipe soit il faut que les data scientists  apprennent les technologies web. Ces alternatives ne sont pas pratiques et sont coûteuses. L’alternative se nomme Dash !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash, une bibliothèque de Plotly, peut résoudre le dilemme ainsi: les scientifiques de données peuvent faire les sites interactifs utilisant uniquement le Python et une connaissance minimale du HTML, et absolument aucun JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À decisionLab, une société de conseil en modélisation mathématique du centre du Londres, nous avons adopté Dash pour créer des interfaces pour nos POCs et les premiers alphas de nos projets. Bien que nous ne fassions pas officiellement partie du projet Dash, en l’utilisant quotidiennement, à travers de nombreux projets, nous avons acquis de nombreuses connaissances. Nous aimerions les partager ainsi que des conseils et des bonnes pratiques. Puis obtenir vos retours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cette conférence donnera un aperçu de Dash, de son fonctionnement et de son utilité, avant de présenter certains problèmes pouvant survenir lorsque les data scientists  sont laissés à eux-mêmes pour créer des applications Web, et que les ingénieurs informatiques doivent travailler avec l'écosystème pydata. Nous identifierons aussi certaines des limites de Dash, et discuterons de la façon de prendre la décision d'arrêter d'utiliser Dash pour commencer à créer une application Web complète.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dash: Interactive Data Visualization Web Apps with no Javascript</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2019/dash-interactive-data-visualization-web-apps-with-no-javascript.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dom Weldon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-10:pydata-berlin-2019/dash-interactive-data-visualization-web-apps-with-no-javascript.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dom Weldon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track:PyData
Interactive web pages and visualizations with no JavaScript? What could go wrong? What you can, can't, should and probably shouldn't do with plotly/Dash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2019 conference.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.de"&gt;https://pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/program/R7PELL"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/program/R7PELL&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter:  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dash Interactive Data Visualization Web Apps with no Javascript</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/dash-interactive-data-visualization-web-apps-with-no-javascript.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dom Weldon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-15:pycon-uk-2019/dash-interactive-data-visualization-web-apps-with-no-javascript.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the team that makes Plotly, Dash is a library for producing interactive web apps with Python. This talk introduces Dash and will discuss how it may fit into your team!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dash: Interactive Data Visualization Web Apps with no Javascript</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/dash-interactive-data-visualization-web-apps-with-no-javascript.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dom Weldon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/dash-interactive-data-visualization-web-apps-with-no-javascript.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your data science or machine learning project probably won't just
produce a written report. Instead, projects are increasingly expected to
produce interactive tools to allow end-users to explore data and results
with rich, interactive visualizations. Inevitably, this will be done in
a web browser, meaning you'll need to add a quantitatively trained web
developer to your team, or have your data scientists spend time learning
HTML, Javascript and CSS. Dash, a project by the team that makes Plotly,
solves some of these problems by allowing data scientists to build rich
and interactive websites in pure python, with minimal knowledge of HTML
and absolutely no Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At decisionLab, a London-based data science consultancy producing
decision tools, we've embraced Dash to produce proof-of-concept models
for our projects in alpha. Although we're not officially connected to
the plotly/Dash project, by using the library daily across many
projects, we've learned many lessons and what we feel are best practises
we'd like to share, and hear feedback on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give an overview of Dash, how it works and what it can be
used for, before outlining some of the common problems that emerge when
data scientists are let loose to produce web applications, and web
developers have to work with the pydata ecosystem. The talk also covers
effective working practises to start producing cool interactive
statistical web applications, fast. We'll also identify some of the
pitfalls of Dash, and how and when to make the decision to stop using
Dash and start building a proper web application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://domweldon-europython-2019-dash.s3.eu"&gt;http://domweldon-europython-2019-dash.s3.eu&lt;/a&gt;-
west-2.amazonaws.com/index.html&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="JavaScript"></category><category term="Visualization"></category><category term="Web"></category><category term="Web Servers and MicroFWs"></category></entry><entry><title>Oxidizing MyPy: Why I decided to learn Rust and use it with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-estonia-2019/oxidizing-mypy-why-i-decided-to-learn-rust-and-use-it-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dom Weldon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-03:pycon-estonia-2019/oxidizing-mypy-why-i-decided-to-learn-rust-and-use-it-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dom is a Principal Software Engineer at decisionLab, a mathematical modelling consultancy based in central London. After studying natural sciences at the University of Cambridge, and pursuing a PhD in Computational Geography at King's College London, he now heads a team specialising in building production tools out of mathematical models. Dom loves all things code, and is most recently exploring the world of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get tickets for PyCon Estonia 2020 - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bit.ly/pycon2020"&gt;https://bit.ly/pycon2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is nearing 3 decades in existence (yes, kinda hard to believe). Where do we go from here? We have the same question, hence PyCon 2019 will be a peek into the future of Python. Come, hang out with an inspired crowd, have rich, direct conversations and who knows, maybe you’ll even find an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycon.ee"&gt;https://pycon.ee&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConEstonia"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConEstonia&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/vaba-lava/pycon-estonia-2019/318811955508926/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/vaba-lava/pycon-estonia-2019/318811955508926/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>