<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_deborah-diller-harris.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-27T11:15:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Feature Engineering: An Apprentice’s Guide to the “Dark Art” of Machine Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/feature-engineering-an-apprentices-guide-to-the-dark-art-of-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-27T11:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T11:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Deborah Diller Harris</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-27:pyohio-2019/feature-engineering-an-apprentices-guide-to-the-dark-art-of-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is feature engineering considered the &amp;quot;dark art&amp;quot; of machine
learning? Transforming raw data into a form that your machine learning
algorithm can utilize seems mysterious and downright frightening! Bring
your wizard hat and join me as this machine learning apprentice shares
her personal book of feature engineering incantations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is feature engineering and why do we need it? When is it applied?
Is it an art or a science? Find out the answers to these questions and
more as we explore different methods of feature engineering with
practical examples provided. There are three main methods of feature
engineering: adjusting raw features, combining raw features and
decomposing raw features into usable subsets. We will use datasets to
illustrate binning, encoding, binaries, summing, differencing, feature
scaling, extraction, and the manipulation of date/time features.
Finally, we will explore the performance of a machine learning model
before and after feature engineering is applied. As a postscript,
current automated feature engineering tools for Python will be
introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>