<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Abraham Coiman</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_abraham-coiman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Wildfire Modeling in Yosemite National Park</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/wildfire-modeling-in-yosemite-national-park.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abraham Coiman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/wildfire-modeling-in-yosemite-national-park.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wildfire Modeling in Yosemite National Park
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Abraham Coiman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will show you the use of GRASS GIS (Geographic Resources Analysis Support System - Geographical Information System) and other geospatial Python libraries within a Jupyter Notebook to simulate wildfire …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wildfire Modeling in Yosemite National Park
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Abraham Coiman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will show you the use of GRASS GIS (Geographic Resources Analysis Support System - Geographical Information System) and other geospatial Python libraries within a Jupyter Notebook to simulate wildfire spread in Yosemite National Park California USA.  We will also show you a straightforward workflow to obtain and save input geospatial data for wildfire simulation using Google Earth Engine (GEE) Python API, GeoPandas, and geemap (a Python package for interactive mapping with GEE). GRASS GIS commands are generally run into bash shells, thus in this talk, we will demonstrate how we run GRASS GIS commands from Jupyter notebook to model wildfire behavior and display the resulting maps. We expect the audience has a basic understanding of GIS, Remote Sensing, and Python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry></feed>