<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Process Mining in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/process-mining-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk (/workshop) we introduce the field of process mining as
well as the PM4Py library, i.e., a python library implementing process
mining algorithms. Process mining is a collection of tools, techniques,
methods etc. aimed at analyzing operational process data, stored during
the execution of (business) processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The execution of business processes, in modern organizations, is often
supported by different information systems. Clearly, the better one
understands its core processes, the easier to steer the process towards
an increased overall process performance. In order to gain a detailed
understanding of the execution of a process, i.e., in terms of its
performance and conformance, different techniques and methods
originating from the process mining domain are typically used.
Essentially, process mining techniques aim to distill actionable
knowledge and insights of a process, on the basis of historical
execution data. For example, process discovery algorithms are able to
translate the captured even data into a process model, e.g., into a BPMN
model. Furthermore, conformance checking algorithms allow us to compute,
in an exact manner, whether or not the execution of the process, i.e.,
as captured in the data, is in line with a reference model.
Additionally, heaps of techniques exist that allow us to compute
insights in the performance of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past twenty years, process mining has remained a relatively
unknown, scientific, endeavor. However, recently, there has been a keen
interest from industry in this technology as well. This is best
illustrated by the German process mining company Celonis, recently
valued over 1 billion dollars of net worth. Furthermore, the 1st
international conference on process mining (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://icpmconference.org"&gt;https://icpmconference.org&lt;/a&gt;),
held in June 2019, attracted a total number of 20 sponsors from industry
(mainly process mining vendors) and a total of 400 participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the vast increase in commercial/industrial interest, the amount
of open-source tools supporting process mining techniques has, until
recently, been very little. For years, ProM (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://promtools.org"&gt;http://promtools.org&lt;/a&gt;) and
Apromore (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://apromore.org/"&gt;https://apromore.org/&lt;/a&gt;) have been the de-facto leading
open-source process mining solutions. However, these tools are primarily
designed to be used by end-users, i.e., they provide a front-end and are
not easily integrated in other software solutions. Only recently,
solutions in R, i.e., bupaR (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.bupar.net/"&gt;https://www.bupar.net/&lt;/a&gt;) and Python, i.e.,
PM4Py (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pm4py.fit.fraunhofer.de"&gt;https://pm4py.fit.fraunhofer.de&lt;/a&gt;), have been developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we present the main idea of process mining, i.e., going
from captured event data process insights, and, we briefly show an
example in python. In case of a possible workshop, we will elaborate
more on the algorithmic details of one (of the many) state-of-the-art
process mining algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastiaan J. van Zelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-30:pydata-eindhoven-2019/process-mining-in-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>