<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Next-Gen railway asset management with computer vision at ProRail</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/next-gen-railway-asset-management-with-computer-vision-at-prorail.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With computer vision we’re able to localize assets and determine their
condition. In this talk we will dive into the details of convolutional
neural networks and we’ll show how they help ProRail maintain 7000 km of
railway track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProRail manages and maintains over 7000 km of railway track. In order to
prevent and solve delays, accurate knowledge about the location and
state of the various assets is required. Special camera-equipped trains
cover the entire railway track twice a year, providing over 50 million
images of the railway. Using computer vision, these images can be used
to both localize assets and determine their condition. This technology
is currently being put into production at ProRail, where the focus is
first on the localization of important assets and next on quantifying
their state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will dive into how computer vision is applied at
ProRail. First, we will discuss the convolutional neural network that we
use in order to detect our main asset of interest: the insulation joint.
We will elaborate on the specific choices we made and the tools we used
during the implementation. However, a simple cnn might not cut it for us
when trying to distinguish between 28 slightly different assets. In the
second part of our talk we’ll touch on more advanced techniques such as
transfer learning, and compare them on the use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prior knowledge is required for this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jasper Derikx</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-30:pydata-eindhoven-2019/next-gen-railway-asset-management-with-computer-vision-at-prorail.html</guid></item></channel></rss>