<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kyle-kastner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Trends in Deep Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2013/trends-in-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Kastner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-08-16:pytexas-2013/trends-in-deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk gives a brief history of deep learning architectures, moving into modern trends and research in the field. Key points of discussion are neural activation functions, weight optimization strategies, techniques for hyper-parameter selection, and example architectures for different problem sets. We finish with a few notable examples of &amp;quot;web scale&amp;quot; deep learning at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on (briefly) sklearn, Theano, pylearn2, theanets, and hyperopt.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Deep Learning Tips from the Road</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/deep-learning-tips-from-the-road.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Kastner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/deep-learning-tips-from-the-road.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning with Scikit Learn - Part I</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-i.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning with Scikit Learn - Part II</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Mueller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-08:scipy-2015/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-part-ii.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>What Can I Do With "Deep Learning"?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/what-can-i-do-with-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Kastner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-15:pygotham-2015/what-can-i-do-with-deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Deep learning&amp;quot; is a recent rebranding and mixing of old and new methods
in neural networks, graphical modeling, and optimization. We will
discuss the applications of these approaches, how these methods are
different than others for machine learning, and what recent advances in
the field mean for people trying to solve problems in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Neural Networks for Computer Vision</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2014/neural-networks-for-computer-vision.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Kastner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-22:euroscipy-2014/neural-networks-for-computer-vision.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neural networks with many layers are known as &amp;quot;deep&amp;quot; neural networks.
While the phrase &amp;quot;deep learning&amp;quot; to describe deep neural networks is
new, the ideas behind these networks have been around for many years.
Deep neural networks attempt to learn concise, hierarchical
representations of complex data, and recent advances in research have
made it much easier to use these networks on many tasks, including
computer vision. Due to massive increases in compute power, available
data, and algorithmic techniques, neural networks have greatly improved
the state of the art for many aspects of computer vision including
object recognition and localization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two key Python packages (pylearn2 and theano) enable machine learning
researchers easily develop new architectures and algorithms for neural
networks which utilize GPU processing. This specialized hardware
improves the computational feasibility of big neural networks, and GPU
programming was a key driver (along with the development of a technique
called dropout) in the resurgence of neural networks for machine
learning tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing networks trained on extremely large compute farms as
&amp;quot;black-box&amp;quot; preprocessing, a consumer grade desktop or laptop can
approach state of the art results using standard machine learning
techniques such as logistic regression and support vector machines
(SVM). This idea has serious potential in the embedded/FPGA/ASIC space
as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The python interface to pylearn2 will be heavily discussed, while also
using the preprocessing features of scikit-learn for data preparation.
There will also be discussion of the recent advances for pre-trained
neural networks as preprocessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk, I hope you will understand what &amp;quot;deep learning&amp;quot;
really means, how to apply these techniques to image data using Python,
and how these techniques will shape the future of machine learning
research and its applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning 101</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/machine-learning-101.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kyle Kastner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-11:pycon-us-2015/machine-learning-101.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is a crucial part of modern software development.
Libraries like pandas, scikit-learn, gensim, and Theano help developers
build projects that were previously impossible, and these applications
empower our users and can make fundamental improvements in daily life.
This talk will show you the why, what, and how of machine learning in
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>