<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Bilge Yucel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EuroPython 2024 — Lightning talks Thursday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/europython-2024-lightning-talks-thursday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks Thursday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/lightning-talks-thursday"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/lightning-talks-thursday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Thursdays's lightning talks. Short talks about everything by everyone. Hosted by Velda Kiara and Angel Ramboi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;00:00 &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Thursday's Lightning Talks&lt;/em&gt;
00:31 &lt;em&gt;Community Conference / Events Announcements &amp;amp; Celebration!&lt;/em&gt;
17:55 &lt;em&gt;What to expect at the social event&lt;/em&gt; — Moisés Guimarães
24:50 &lt;em&gt;AutoQuizzer: Can you beat an LLM in a pub quiz?&lt;/em&gt; — Bilge Yucel
29:38 &lt;em&gt;Launching Crawlee for Python: Special beta version for EuroPython&lt;/em&gt; — Saurav Jain
32:33 &lt;em&gt;Should Python adopt CalVer? 🗓&lt;/em&gt; — Hugo van Kemenade
37:30 &lt;em&gt;F**k it&lt;/em&gt; — Sébastien Crocquevieille
40:28 &lt;em&gt;Work on sqrt(3) and Pitagora's Theorem&lt;/em&gt; — Riccardo Polli
44:24 &lt;em&gt;Present-ception: A presentation about presentations&lt;/em&gt; — Siddharth Gupta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Moisés Guimarães</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/europython-2024-lightning-talks-thursday.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Build Your First LLM-based Application with Haystack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/build-your-first-llm-based-application-with-haystack.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP) is advancing at an unprecedented pace, with new large language models (LLMs) emerging almost daily. These models, coupled with innovative ideas, revolutionize how we build applications. However, for software developers, entering the field of NLP can be overwhelming because of all new NLP concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haystack is an open-source Python framework designed to empower developers in building LLM applications using the latest language models and state-of-the-art NLP approaches by providing all the tools you need. Haystack's composable pipeline system and LLM-based building components open up a world of possibilities, enabling generative question answering, document retrieval, chatbots, and much more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll begin with a high-level overview of key NLP concepts, including vector databases, document preprocessing, word embeddings, LLMs, and prompting. This will lay the groundwork for understanding the core concepts required to develop applications powered by LLMs. Once we've explored these fundamental concepts, we’ll combine them together to create a generative question-answering application tailored for custom documents using Haystack. By end of this talk, you'll have a solid grasp of NLP basics and learn how to use it for your needs in your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bilge Yücel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/build-your-first-llm-based-application-with-haystack.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item></channel></rss>