<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jessica-jahnke.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-02T10:30:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building a Community for Girls with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/building-a-community-for-girls-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-02T10:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-02T10:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neha Gupta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-02:pycon-us-2019/building-a-community-for-girls-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We teach Python to 5th-12th grade girls, aiming to build community,
build self-confidence, and help bridge the gender gap in tech. This talk
offers solutions to common challenges in motivating students and
community organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will share methods to increase student engagement and aid the
transition to Python. We used “Unplugged” activities that complement
programming fundamentals, “block-based” logic in Scratch, and the
drag-to-text Python platform in Codesters. We will also share examples
of leading discussions that build girls’ curiosity about technology
fields, including learning about role models of top women in the
industry, and learning about emerging areas in technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, organizing clubs for students from diverse backgrounds,
with varying technical educations, can involve bridging gaps and
encouraging community involvement. We’ll discuss methods of reaching
families and local communities, such as open presentations,
celebrations, and share some do's and don'ts from our experiences. We’ll
also share ways to encourage participants to develop communication
skills about their technical work and teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women’s rights and community activism are gathering national attention,
and we believe that anyone can effectively run an ongoing coding club to
positively impact girls' education in their communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry></feed>