<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python-based data science to understand knowledge discovery and expertise: A science perspective</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/chipy/python-based-data-science-to-understand-knowledge-discovery-and-expertise-a-science-perspective.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All kinds of businesses are using data science and machine learning to understand themselves, lowering costs, engineering better products, and improving customer experiences. Similarly, we use data science to improve science itself, understanding how scientific topics are discovered and modeling institutional expertise. In our work, we use a combination of Python-powered big data analytics and web-based tools to achieve this goal, including pyspark (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://spark.apache.org"&gt;http://spark.apache.org&lt;/a&gt;), scikit-learn (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://http://scikit-learn.org"&gt;http://http://scikit-learn.org&lt;/a&gt;), Django (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;https://www.djangoproject.com/&lt;/a&gt;), Celery (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.celeryproject.org/"&gt;http://www.celeryproject.org/&lt;/a&gt;), and or-tools (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/optimization"&gt;https://developers.google.com/optimization&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will present the infrastructure behind Scholarfy, a recommender system for massive scientific conferences (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scholarfy.net"&gt;http://www.scholarfy.net&lt;/a&gt;). We will also present a machine learning approach to automatically match expert scientific reviewers to research proposals (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pr.scienceofscience.org"&gt;http://pr.scienceofscience.org&lt;/a&gt;). Finally, we will present the work behind our award-winning visualization, World’s Science Map (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://map.scienceofscience.org"&gt;http://map.scienceofscience.org&lt;/a&gt;), where we modeled the institutional expertise, collaboration network, and funding of all institutions in the world. At the end of our talk, we will argue that Python-powered data science can improve not only businesses but also science, making it more agile and accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel E. Acuna</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-10:chipy/python-based-data-science-to-understand-knowledge-discovery-and-expertise-a-science-perspective.html</guid></item></channel></rss>