<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nick Terrel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nick-terrel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Atomistic uncertainty driven data generation in ANI neural network potentials</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/atomistic-uncertainty-driven-data-generation-in-ani-neural-network-potentials.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nick Terrel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/atomistic-uncertainty-driven-data-generation-in-ani-neural-network-potentials.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using machine learning to predict chemical properties and behavior is an important complement to traditional approaches to computation and simulation in chemistry. The ANAKIN-ME (ANI) methodology has been shown to produce generalized and transferable neural network potentials, trained on density functional theory (DFT) molecular energies, at a greatly reduced …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using machine learning to predict chemical properties and behavior is an important complement to traditional approaches to computation and simulation in chemistry. The ANAKIN-ME (ANI) methodology has been shown to produce generalized and transferable neural network potentials, trained on density functional theory (DFT) molecular energies, at a greatly reduced computational cost. The work presented here details an approach to generating new data in an active learning scheme in order to improve predictions in the regions of chemical space with high predictive uncertainty at the atom level.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>