<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lorna-brightmore.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Making great tasting dog food with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/making-great-tasting-dog-food-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorna Brightmore</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-16:pycon-uk-2018/making-great-tasting-dog-food-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How we are using social network analysis to understand palatability in dog food recipes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a data scientist working for a tailor made dog food company, and in
this session I’ll explain how we are applying ideas in social network
analysis to understand and improve the overall taste and palatability of
our dry dog food recipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding what makes dog food delicious is a difficult problem to
solve, and as the intended consumers of our food are dogs, this presents
some obvious limitations to the methods available to approach this
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am taking a fairly unique and data led approach to this, using ideas
in social network analysis to visualise our dog food recipes and find
ingredients (or combinations of ingredients) common in recipes where we
know that the dog didn’t like the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll tell the story of how this project evolved, and how
we’ve been using the Python library NetworkX to help us create some
really insightful visualisations of our data. Along the way I’ll cover
some of the great things about this library, as well as some of the
pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Survival Analysis to understand customer retention</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2018/using-survival-analysis-to-understand-customer-retention.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorna Brightmore</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-29:pydata-london-2018/using-survival-analysis-to-understand-customer-retention.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show how we use techniques in Survival Analysis and
Machine Learning to predict the time a customer (and their dog) will
keep ordering and enjoying our products. I'll also show how this is an
important part of understanding the Lifetime Value of a customer, which
is arguably the most important metric in any subscription business&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>