<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jie Shen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jie-shen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>One-Bit Compressed Sensing via One-Shot Hard Thresholding</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/one-bit-compressed-sensing-via-one-shot-hard-thresholding.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jie Shen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/one-bit-compressed-sensing-via-one-shot-hard-thresholding.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;One-Bit Compressed Sensing via One-Shot Hard Thresholding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jie Shen (Stevens Institute of Technology)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper concerns the problem of 1-bit compressed sensing, where the goal is to estimate a sparse signal from a few of its binary measurements. We study a non-convex sparsity-constrained program and present a novel and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;One-Bit Compressed Sensing via One-Shot Hard Thresholding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jie Shen (Stevens Institute of Technology)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper concerns the problem of 1-bit compressed sensing, where the goal is to estimate a sparse signal from a few of its binary measurements. We study a non-convex sparsity-constrained program and present a novel and concise analysis that moves away from the widely used notion of Gaussian width. We show that with high probability a simple algorithm is guaranteed to produce an accurate approximation to the normalized signal of interest under the L2-metric. On top of that, we establish an ensemble of new results that address norm estimation, support recovery, and model misspecification. On the computational side, it is shown that the non-convex program can be solved via one-step hard thresholding which is dramatically efficient in terms of time complexity and memory footprint. On the statistical side, it is shown that our estimator enjoys a near-optimal error rate under standard conditions. The theoretical results are further substantiated by numerical experiments.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2020"></category></entry></feed>