<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_emily-morehouse-valcarcel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python Steering Council Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/python-steering-council-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Everitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-17:pybay-2019/python-steering-council-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Elected as prescribed in PEP 8017, the Python Steering Council is a 5-person committee that assumes a mandate to maintain the quality and stability of the Python language and CPython interpreter, improve the contributor experience, formalize and maintain a relationship between the Python core team and the PSF, establish decision making processes for Python Enhancement Proposals, seek consensus among contributors and the Python core team, and resolve decisions and disputes in decision making among the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will be moderated by , Paul Everitt (Python Software Foundation), to introduce a discussion with members of the community. Barry Warsaw (Steering Council), Łukasz Langa (3.8 Release Manager), Emily Morehouse (Core Dev), Benjamin Peterson (2.7 Release Manager)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Barry Warsaw: Barry Warsaw is a Sr. Staff Engineer with LinkedIn, working on the Python Foundation team. He has been a core Python developer since the first workshop at NIST in 1994. As the first non-Dutch contributor, he's been dubbed Python's Terry Gilliam. In 2009, he became the FLUFL (Friendly Language Uncle For Life) via the humorous PEP 401. Today, he is one of 5 members of the Python Steering Council, helping to provide leadership for the future of Python.Barry has served as Python Release Manager, Jython project leader, and GNU Mailman project leader. He served as co-chair of the Pycon Language Summit for 4 years. He currently mentors new contributors on their journeys to becoming core developers. Outside of Python, Barry is a semi-pro bass player, and studies tai chi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Peterson: Creator of six (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/six"&gt;http://pypi.python.org/pypi/six&lt;/a&gt;), a Python 2 and 3 compatibility library. Release manager for Python 2.6 and 2.7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Morehouse: Emily Morehouse-Valcarcel is the Director of Engineering at Cuttlesoft, a digital product agency focused on creating beautifully designed software. Her passion is driven by a blend of empathy, strategy, curiosity, and human-centered design. She's a Python Core Developer, avid OSS contributor, and constant learner focused on building tools to automate the mundane and shed light on the complexity of the human experience. Emily holds degrees in Computer Science, Criminology, and Theatre from Florida State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lukasz Langa: ambv on Github. Python core developer, Python 3.8 release manager, creator of Black, pianist, dad. Likes analog modular synthesizers, immersive single-player role playing games (Fallout, Elder Scrolls), and single malt Scotch whisky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Everitt: Paul is the PyCharm Developer Advocate at JetBrains. Before that, Paul was a co-founder of Zope Corporation, taking the first open source application server through $14M of funding. Paul has bootstrapped both the Python Software Foundation and the Plone Foundation. Paul was an officer in the US Navy, starting www.navy.mil in 1993.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>My Path to Becoming a Python Core Developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/my-path-to-becoming-a-python-core-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emily Morehouse Valcarcel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-16:pybay-2019/my-path-to-becoming-a-python-core-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Python Core Developers help shape and build the language we love. But what do core developers actually do, and how do you become one? Hear the story of how I went from an aspiring Core Developer to implementing one of the most controversial changes to the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Introduction
Forgotten Knowledge
What is a Python Core Developer?
Realities of the process
Timeline of my path and PEP 572
Challenges of Contributing and OSS
If this is so hard and often thankless, then WHY do we do it??
Fostering welcoming communities
Why diversity matters
What does Python really need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://t.ly/O28Ke"&gt;https://t.ly/O28Ke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Emily Morehouse-Valcarcel is the Director of Engineering at Cuttlesoft, a digital product agency focused on creating beautifully designed software. Her passion is driven by a blend of empathy, strategy, curiosity, and human-centered design. She's a Python Core Developer, avid OSS contributor, and constant learner focused on building tools to automate the mundane and shed light on the complexity of the human experience. Emily holds degrees in Computer Science, Criminology, and Theatre from Florida State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Keynote: My Path to Becoming a Python Core Developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2019/keynote-my-path-to-becoming-a-python-core-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emily Morehouse-Valcarcel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-13:pytexas-2019/keynote-my-path-to-becoming-a-python-core-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>The AST and Me</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/the-ast-and-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emily Morehouse-Valcarcel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/the-ast-and-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get under the hood and learn about Python's beloved Abstract Syntax Tree. Ever wonder how Python code is run? Overheard people arguing about whether Python is interpreted or compiled? In this talk, we will delve into the lifecycle of a piece of Python code in order to understand the role that Python's Abstract Syntax Tree plays in shaping the runtime of your code. Utilizing your newfound knowledge of Python's AST, you'll get a taste of how you probably already rely on ASTs and how they can be used to build awesome tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ast"></category><category term="abstract syntax tree"></category></entry><entry><title>The AST and Me</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2018/the-ast-and-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Emily Morehouse-Valcarcel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-01-22:pycascades-2018/the-ast-and-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get under the hood and learn about Python's beloved Abstract Syntax Tree. We'll discuss the AST's role in Python's compilation process, how it affects Bytecode, and how you can use it's optimizations to improve your code's speed at runtime. Write better code!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ast"></category></entry></feed>