<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Astropy Beyond Astronomy: Infrastructure of an Open Source Ecosystem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/astropy-beyond-astronomy-infrastructure-of-an-open-source-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Astropy Project is a community effort to develop a common core package and to foster an ecosystem of interoperable astronomy packages. In addition to these domain specific libraries we also maintain a suite of infrastructure packages. This infrastructure can be easily utilized to cover the needs of most scientific Python projects. Sharing the tools we developed for maintenance, testing, documenting, and general upkeep of the most essential parts of our project maximizes the impact of the software engineering expertise and resources within the whole ecosystem to ensure that others can benefit from the efforts of the core Astropy team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Robitaille</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/astropy-beyond-astronomy-infrastructure-of-an-open-source-ecosystem.html</guid></item><item><title>Multi Dimensional Linked Data Exploration with Glue</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/multi-dimensional-linked-data-exploration-with-glue.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have developed an open-source multi-disciplinary Python package named glue (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://glueviz.org"&gt;http://glueviz.org&lt;/a&gt;) that allows users to explore relationships within and across related datasets, making it easy for them to create multi-dimensional linked visualizations of datasets, select subsets of data interactively or programmatically in 1, 2, or 3 dimensions, and to see those selections propagate live across all open visualizations of the data (e.g., graphs, maps, diagnostics charts, etc.). In this talk, I will present both the desktop and the new Jupyter-based versions of glue, along with plugins that can be used to extend glue for different disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Robitaille</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:scipy-2019/multi-dimensional-linked-data-exploration-with-glue.html</guid></item><item><title>Multi-dimensional Linked Data Exploration with Glue (Tutorial)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/multi-dimensional-linked-data-exploration-with-glue-tutorial.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have developed an open-source multi-disciplinary Python package named glue (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://glueviz.org"&gt;http://glueviz.org&lt;/a&gt;) that allows users to explore relationships within and across related datasets, making it easy for them to create multi-dimensional linked visualizations of datasets, select subsets of data interactively or programmatically in 1, 2, or 3 dimensions, and to see those selections propagate live across all open visualizations of the data (e.g., graphs, maps, diagnostics charts, etc.). In this tutorial, participants will learn how to use and customize the desktop and Jupyter version of glue, using example data as well as their own data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Robitaille</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:scipy-2019/multi-dimensional-linked-data-exploration-with-glue-tutorial.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Astropy - Herding Snakes or Astronomers: which is more difficult?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/astropy-herding-snakes-or-astronomers-which-is.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers and users of astronomical software have long bemoaned the
absence of shared efforts in the field. While there are well known, free
software tools available for astronomy, most have been developed by
large institutions, and the past few decades have seen comparatively
little progress in fostering a community-based set of software tools.
There is hope that is changing now. The continuing growth of Python in
astronomy has led to an increasing awareness of needless duplication of
efforts within the community and the need to make existing packages work
better with each other; such discussions came to a head on the astropy
email list in the spring of 2011 leading to formation of the astropy
project. The first coordination meeting was held in the fall of 2011,
and significant progress has been made in setting up a community
repository of core astronomical packages. We will describe the general
goals of astropy and the progress that has been made to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erik Tollerud</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/astropy-herding-snakes-or-astronomers-which-is.html</guid><category>Astronomy Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Astropy, growing a community-based software system for astronomy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/astropy-growing-a-community-based-software-syste-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astropy is a community-based software project to coordinate the
development of libraries and applications for astronomy. We will report
on progress that has been made with astropy since the last scipy
conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authors: Droettboom, Michael, STScI; Robitaille, Thomas, Max Planck
Institute; Tollerud, Erik, Yale Universit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: Astronomy and Astrophysics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astropy is a community-based software project to coordinate the
development of libraries and applications for astronomy. We will report
on progress that has been made with astropy since the last scipy
conference. The past year has seen much growth in the number and quality
of the core libraries in astropy and a public release. We will highlight
the new capabilities available, and outline the development plans for
the upcoming year. Finally we discuss the strategies for advertising its
capabilities and growing the documentation and tutorials available for
users and developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erik Tollerud</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-01:scipy-2013/astropy-growing-a-community-based-software-syste-0.html</guid><category>astronomy</category><category>astrophysics</category><category>astropy</category></item><item><title>Astropy and astronomical tools Part I</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/astropy-and-astronomical-tools-part-i.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introductory session will start with an overview of the astropy
project and the goals of the tutorial, followed by the basics on
accessing astronomical data and the associated attributes of such data,
including the units and coordinates. Also covered is how to use the new
and powerful quantities facility, which allows physical quantities to be
explicitly bound to the units they are defined in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of astropy (15 minutes) [Greenfield]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Import astropy, demonstrate that tools are present and
echo simple examples given. (15 minutes: allowing for typical
start-up problems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Units/quantities (15 minutes) [Droettboom]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Solve problems using standard units; define new unit;
use unit equivalencies; define blackbody function using
quantities/units (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tables (20 minutes) [Aldcroft]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: read in provided table files and apply requested table
manipulations (20 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessing and updating data&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FITS (30 minutes) [Bray]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Open supplied data files; manipulate header
information; manipulate data; write results; update and append
to existing file (30 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ascii tables (15 minutes) [Aldcroft]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Open supplied ascii files, modify and convert into
csv files (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coordinates (sky/time) (15 minutes) [Robitaille]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises: solve coordinate/time conversion problems; read in
various string representations for coordinates/times; print
alternate string representations (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erik Bray</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/astropy-and-astronomical-tools-part-i.html</guid><category>astropy</category></item><item><title>WCSAxes: A Framework for Plotting Astronomical and Geospatial Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/wcsaxes-a-framework-for-plotting-astronomical-an.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will present WCSAxes, a new framework for plotting astronomical data
that seamlessly handles the plotting of ticks, tick labels, and grid
lines for arbitrary coordinate systems and projections. While originally
written for with astronomical data, it can be used for any kind of map
provided that the projection and coordinate system can be represented by
a pixel-to-world transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astronomical data (whether images on the sky, or other data) are
typically stored with information about their corresponding projection
(Gnomonic, Mercator, Conical, Aitoff, and &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; more) and coordinate
system (Equatorial, Galactic, Ecliptic, and so on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/astrofrog/wcsaxes"&gt;WCSAxes&lt;/a&gt;, a new
framework for plotting such astronomical data, developed as part of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.astropy.org"&gt;Astropy&lt;/a&gt; project. WCSAxes consists primarily
of a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.matplotlib.org"&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/a&gt; Axes sub-class that
seamlessly handles the plotting of ticks, tick labels, and grid lines
for arbitrary coordinate systems and projections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, the following plot was produced with WCSAxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Galactic center as seen by the Chandra X-ray observatory" src="http://www.mpia.de/~robitaille/chandra_avm_small.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The Galactic Center as seen by Chandra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image Credit: NASA/CXC/UMass/D. Wang et al. -
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chandra.harvard.edu/photo/2009/gcenter/"&gt;http://chandra.harvard.edu/photo/2009/gcenter/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it is a sub-class of the Matplotlib Axes class, all the default
Matplotlib methods such as plot, scatter, imshow, contour, as well as
patches, lines, collections, and so on are supported, and WCSAxes - in
combination with Matplotlib's ability to accept arbitrary
transformations - makes it very easy to define whether the plotting
should apply to pixel coordinates, or a world coordinate system related
to the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WCSAxes has been designed as a framework that can be easily used in
other Python tools, and it is planned for inclusion in
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.glueviz.org"&gt;Glue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aplpy.github.io"&gt;APLpy&lt;/a&gt;,
and other astronomical tools. While originally written for Astronomical
images, it should be easily extendable to any kind of map (such as
Earth-based geospatial data) provided that the projection and coordinate
system can be represented by a pixel-to-world transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Robitaille</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/wcsaxes-a-framework-for-plotting-astronomical-an.html</guid><category>astronomy</category><category>gis</category></item></channel></rss>