<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brian-thorne.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Privacy Preserving Record Linkage</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/privacy-preserving-record-linkage.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Thorne</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-24:pycon-au-2018/privacy-preserving-record-linkage.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Record linkage is essential for organizations to collaborate and carry out joint analysis. Instead of trusting someone with lots of personally identifiable information like name/address we can learn the entity matching in a privacy preserving way. Let's talk about a Python implementation of that!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Brian Thorne - Computer Vision</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/brian-thorne---computer-vision.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Thorne</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/brian-thorne---computer-vision.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Thorne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An introduction to computer vision in Python, from the general concept
to its implementation with some current open-source libraries (opencv,
scipy, pygame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of my presentation is an introduction to computer vision
(CV) and image processing in Python. I will aim to show what is possible
with current libraries, demonstrate their usability, explore their
limitations, and cover elements of best coding practice. Firstly, I will
briefly present the basics, such as video grabbing, image processing and
computer vision algorithms. I will illustrate my presentation with the
Python bindings to the opencv library and show different examples such
as displaying a video image, some filtering algorithms (dilation,
gaussian blur), and how to implement facial recognition. I will describe
after how related tasks can be achieved with other Python tools such as
scipy and pygame. I will show how these three libraries can be used in
conjunction to perform video capturing, image processing and user
interfacing. Finally, I will introduce my basic Python computer vision
framework, which is aimed at inexperienced users, and demonstrate it on
the XO laptop, the inexpensive low-powered sub-notebook distributed as
part of the One Laptop Per Child (OLPC) initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Sound and video are poor. Slides are hard to read.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="kiwipycon"></category><category term="kiwipycon2009"></category><category term="olpc"></category><category term="pygame"></category><category term="scipy"></category><category term="vision"></category></entry><entry><title>Blind Analytics - getting insight from data without seeing the data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2015/blind-analytics-getting-insight-from-data-witho.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Thorne</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-06:kiwi-pycon-2015/blind-analytics-getting-insight-from-data-witho.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will start with an overview of current methods of privacy
preserving computation including homomorphic encryption, secret sharing,
and differential privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will explore current uses of privacy preserving computation, in
fields such as government, finance, telecommunications and IoT. We will
look at the technological and social barriers to wider adoption then
gaze into the crystal ball to see where the future might take us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude we will explore one technique (partially homomorphic
encryption) with a motivating medical example. A high level overview of
the open source library &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;python-paillier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; will be given along with a
few code samples showing how easy (some) privacy preserving analytics
can be to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>