<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_kamila-stepniowska.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How can you use Open Source materials to learn Python &amp; data science?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/how-can-you-use-open-source-materials-to-learn-python-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kamila Stepniowska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/how-can-you-use-open-source-materials-to-learn-python-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is very often recommended as the language of choice in a
programming education. I can see at least two cases when it’s a thing: -
introduction to programming - regardless an age and any previous
educational experience, - data science - it’s just a standard… and
actually both - you can teach a future data scientists starting by
teaching Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk, I would like to briefly present you what Open Source
Python educational materials do we have there and how those are and can
be used to teach Python and data science. PyLadies, Django Girls, Django
Carrots, Python Software Foundation creates many very available
materials. From the data science side, you have Open Source materials
created by kaggle, Minerva, Github repos, and many other organizations
and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk you will learn: - where to find an Open Source Python
and data science tutorials and educational materials - how does the
Python community can support your learning process - why learning data
science with Python is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also interested in learning your educational experience with an Open
Source materials and Python community supporting your learning
experience. If you would like to share a link or your educational story,
please feel free to send me an email on &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:kamila&amp;#64;stepniowski.com"&gt;kamila&amp;#64;stepniowski.com&lt;/a&gt;. If I
will find it interesting for the audience and if you will give me your
permission to share it, I might use it in the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>