<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_josh-bartlett.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Neatly Twisted</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2012/neatly-twisted.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Bartlett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-08-22:pycon-au-2012/neatly-twisted.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many Python circles, Twisted is the recommended framework for all
networking and multitasking applications. Twisted provides a powerful,
extensible event-driven framework with built-in support for many network
protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many Python circles, Twisted is the recommended framework for all
networking and multitasking applications. Twisted provides a powerful,
extensible event-driven framework with built-in support for many network
protocols. But without due care, Twisted’s event-driven features can
result in code that’s a nightmare to read and maintain. In this
presentation, I will review the basics of Twisted, and show some of the
features which make Twisted such a popular framework. I’ll share my
experiences debugging and maintaining mission-critical Twisted
applications, discuss some of the pitfalls to avoid when coding with
Twisted, and present tips and tricks for debugging Twisted code and
writing Twisted code that’s a pleasure to read and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="twisted"></category></entry><entry><title>What in the World is Asyncio? by Josh Bartlett</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/what-in-the-world-is-asyncio-by-josh-bartlett.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Bartlett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-09:pycon-au-2014/what-in-the-world-is-asyncio-by-josh-bartlett.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python 3.4 standard library contains a new module called &amp;quot;asyncio&amp;quot;
(formerly &amp;quot;tulip&amp;quot;), which allows you to write single-threaded
asynchronous code based on PEP 3156. This presentation will begin with
an outline of what asyncio provides and how to use it, highlighting the
kinds of use cases that it was designed for. The presentation will then
go through a number of example use cases and within the context of these
use cases, will compare asyncio with Twisted, one of the existing
libraries for asynchronous programming. Finally, the presentation will
touch on the question of interoperability between asyncio and libraries
like Twisted, Pyramid and gevent.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Tales from Managing an Open Source Python Game</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/tales-from-managing-an-open-source-python-game.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Josh Bartlett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:pycon-au-2015/tales-from-managing-an-open-source-python-game.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, a rag-tag bunch of computer camp leaders decided to
create a game that would teach kids teamwork and strategy, and which the
kids could feel a part of. In those days, the presenter was a young
dreamer with time on his hands, and he chose to spearhead the project.
Was this folly? You be the judge. The game was Trosnoth. It is developed
in Python, using Pygame and Twisted. In this presentation, Josh will
tell the story of Trosnoth, and share some of the many lessons, both
social and technical, which he learnt while managing the project. Maybe
you’ve considered writing a game in Python. Maybe you’re not sure how
Open Source projects really work. Maybe you’re an experienced project
manager who wants to laugh at some of the mistakes Josh made. Or maybe
you just enjoy hearing Josh tell stories. Whoever you are, there’s bound
to be something in this presentation for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>