<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Idea to Product: Customer Profiling in Apache Zeppelin with PySpark</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2018/from-idea-to-product-customer-profiling-in-apache-zeppelin-with-pyspark.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zeppelin is a web based notebook which enables interactive data
analytics on big data. Data can easily be ingested from a variety of
databases and analysis can be performed in Python and Pyspark.
Visualisations can be built and displayed together with the code, using
Zeppelin’s built in tool Helium, or Python specific tools such as
Matplotlib and Bokeh. The web based interface facilitates easy sharing
of results, and collaboration on projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing in Zeppelin has changed the way we approach model
development. We are able to take a project from an idea to a product all
within one tool using the following process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with an idea. Write some notes in a Zeppelin notebook
describing how we would like the idea implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly start fleshing out the idea, with real code, until the
solution is built. This is great to demo, as the code is in bite size
chunks, and visualisations can be added directly in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the code into production. It can be scheduled it to run directly
in Zeppelin with a cron scheduler, or from a tool such as Nifi.
Interactive visualisations can be embedded in a web-based frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at data scientists, particularly those working with
big data. We will demonstrate how we have built a catalogue of
subscriber attributes based on customer mobile usage and purchase
behavior using Zeppelin and Pyspark. These attributes can be used to
profile subscribers, and are the starting point for indivisualised
customer engagement. Anyone who attends this talk will get an
introduction to Zeppelin and Pyspark and an overview of what can be
achieved with these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sarah Sprich</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-11:pycon-za-2018/from-idea-to-product-customer-profiling-in-apache-zeppelin-with-pyspark.html</guid></item></channel></rss>