<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rachel-willmer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>23 Years Without A Proper Job</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/23-years-without-a-proper-job.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rachel Willmer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-24:djangocon-europe-2018/23-years-without-a-proper-job.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered about being your own boss? Then this talk is for you. Good experience, bad experience: I’ve had some of both as a startup founder and freelancer in the 23 years after I left my last salaried job. Let me share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you love your job or hate it, at some time you’ve probably wondered what it would be like to work for your self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’re working on a sideproject and wonder how you could make some money from it? Or maybe you have the idea for the next Facebook or Uber?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a coder in today’s world of work is to have amazing opportunities to design the business life you want. You can work remotely; you can write books, or teach, or consult, with anyone anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can have a crazy idea on Friday and have it running by Monday. Design your architecture to use cloud computing, so your tiny team can scale up your huge ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or keep it small, and just earn some extra money with a Wordpress plugin, or a training course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 23 years since I last had a ‘real job’ and a regular income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I survived creating and running a company through the madness of the dotcom years. I made money from sideprojects, that I had started just for fun and for learning. I have freelanced without needing to use an agency to find the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to my stories and learn from my mistakes and successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Willmer&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Real-Time Data with Django</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/real-time-data-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rachel Willmer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-27:pyconweb-2017/real-time-data-with-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For several years, Rachel Willmer has been searching for the perfect real-time data solution for her Django-based website, Luzme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two most recent candidates under the microscope are Google Firebase (a paid service) and the new Django Channels (free and open source).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel shares her experiences of both and compares the relative advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Channels and Real-Time Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/django-channels-and-real-time-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rachel Willmer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-11:pycon-sk-2017/django-channels-and-real-time-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rachel is a entrepreneur and full-stack developer who enjoys developing complicated distributed software. She first joined the Internet in 1986 and has since has worked on CAD, networking, cryptography, digital cash, ebooks and price comparison products. Rachel is the founder of Luzme, the world's best ebook price comparison website, which sends price alerts on your watchlist. Originally built with Django/Python, this now includes a new front-end stack based on AngularJS/Firebase. As the founder of Intertrader in 1995, Rachel created a dotcom company aiming to create the world's first digital cash exchange. After surviving 8 years of dotcom boom-and-bust, and after successfully selling the concept to major customers like Mastercard, CREST and Bank of Scotland, she eventually learnt that being 20 years ahead of the market was not necessarily a Good Thing and closed the company. She then worked with Ben Laurie on the OpenPGP::API open source cryptography library, moving on the BBC where she worked on one of the world's top 10 largest CouchDB installations. Rachel is active in the technology and startups communities, with a particular interest in new technologies and companies. She studied Engineering Science at the University of Durham. She lives in Edinburgh, Scotland and is learning to play jazz upright bass.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>20 years without a 'proper job'</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/20-years-without-a-proper-job.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rachel Willmer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-28:europython-2016/20-years-without-a-proper-job.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rachel Willmer - 20 years without a 'proper job'
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keynote-20-years-without-a-proper-job"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keynote-20-years-without-a-proper-job&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how you could be your own boss? or how you
could make money from your side project? or build the next Facebook or
Uber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a coder in today's world of work is to have amazing
opportunities to design the business life you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've enjoyed the last 20 years without a 'real job', as company
founder, freelancer and side-project-hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I am bootstrapping my current company to profitability. Listen to
my stories and learn from my mistakes and successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how you could be your own boss? If so, then
this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you're working on a sideproject and wonder how you could make
some money from it? Or maybe you have the idea for the next Facebook
or Uber?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a coder in today's world of work is to have amazing
opportunities to design the business life you want. You can work
remotely; you can write books, or teach, or consult, with anyone
anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can have a crazy idea on Friday and have it running by Monday.
Design your architecture to use cloud computing, so your tiny team can
scale up your huge ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or keep it small, and just earn some extra money with a Wordpress
plugin, or a training course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 21 years since I last had a 'real job' and a regular income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I survived creating and running a company through the madness of the
dotcom years.  I made money from sideprojects, that I had started just
for fun and for learning.  I have freelanced without needing to use an
agency to find the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I'm bootstrapping my current business to profitability. Listen
to my stories and learn from my mistakes and successes.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>