<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Hubert Halun</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hubert-halun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Art of R Packages: Forging Community with Hex Stickers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/art-of-r-packages-forging-community-with-hex-stickers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hubert Halun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/art-of-r-packages-forging-community-with-hex-stickers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hex logotypes in the R community are not just for show. They represent identity, unity, and the collaborative nature of open-source projects. This talk will explore how these stickers blend design and visual storytelling, turning R packages into symbols of community. I'll cover the hex sticker creation process, from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hex logotypes in the R community are not just for show. They represent identity, unity, and the collaborative nature of open-source projects. This talk will explore how these stickers blend design and visual storytelling, turning R packages into symbols of community. I'll cover the hex sticker creation process, from idea to design, and their impact on brand recognition and user pride. Using examples from the Tidyverse, Rhinoverse, Nest, and others, I'll highlight how hex stickers unite the R community. The aim is to show how mixing design with data science in creating R packages can build a strong community, highlighting the importance of both looks and usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>