<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_wojciech-rzasa.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>From HTTP to Kafka-based microservices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/from-http-to-kafka-based-microservices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wojciech Rząsa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/from-http-to-kafka-based-microservices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTTP or asynchronous communication in microservices? This question is
frequently repeated and discussed. Obviously, HTTP-based communication
is easier for developers and architects. Even if your developers have no
prior experience with microservices, they will probably understand how
to implement an HTTP service well. While asynchronous communication has
a lot of advantages that allow to design and implement really robust
microservices system, they also bring new challenges not so obvious for
people who didn’t have a chance to work with such an environment before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In FLYR we mostly have HTTP-based Inter Process Communication (IPC) in
our infrastructure. At some point, we realized that to provide the
functionality required by our product we needed something more flexible
and more… asynchronous. We designed and implemented a Python library to
facilitate switching to asynchronous IPC, supporting one- or two-way or
even single- request – multi-response communication. An important thing
in the design process was to provide developers having HTTP experience a
tool that would ease the process of switching to asynchronous
communication. Consequently, to switch an HTTP server-side endpoint to
asynchronous IPC is a straightforward task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We selected Kafka for our message broker, not surprisingly by comparing
its performance reports with our very rough, but no less demanding
performance requirements. But we also took care to hide the details of
the broker logic from developers. Yes, we don’t use all Kafka
capabilities, if you need e.g. Kafka Streams, you will have to use
another solution. But we can decide what capabilities are used in our
microservices and how we can make changes in the way our services
communicate in a single place. There are also hooks, Kubernetes health
checks and more with a lot of flexibility available out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to opensource our library. At the moment of writing it
‘opensourcing’ is still a work in progress and we didn’t have sufficient
time to do it due to strict time constraints we have on delivering
functionality to our customers, but we hope to be able to do it soon. In
this talk I would like to describe how we solved particularly important
problems, what solutions we developed, how we use them and what problems
still need to be addressed by developers. In other words, I would like
to describe you the journey we made from HTTP to Kafka-based
microservices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Communication"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category></entry></feed>