<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_casey-schroeder.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>To Catch a Cheat</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2016/to-catch-a-cheat.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Casey Schroeder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-07:depy-2016/to-catch-a-cheat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are various game theoretic models of cheating. I give results from simulations of various models of cheating-in-game-play collected from my own open source python code (MIT). These results are extended to a &amp;quot;society at large&amp;quot; model of the result of cheating-at-game-play. I discuss some overt and less overt counter-measures to cheating-at-game-play in the context of online test taking.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Use of Web Games to Train Data Analysts</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/depy-2015/the-use-of-web-games-to-train-data-analysts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Casey Schroeder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:depy-2015/the-use-of-web-games-to-train-data-analysts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been recent work on the taxonomy of games which are based, one
way or another, on real world data. Typically these games help people
learn that data or how to cope with it. The traditional examples are
simulation games (flight, driving, etc.), while other games incorporate
data in such a way that it is beneficial to learn the real world data in
the game play (trivia). These types of data-games commonly have a domain
specific focus. We intend to explore the possibility of interactive
games which help people to learn data analysis, in general, implementing
some such games in python using web2py.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>