<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 16:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Is This Your Card? Computer Vision for Playing Card Recognition</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2019/is-this-your-card-computer-vision-for-playing-card-recognition.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision aims to teach computers to interact with the visual
world. It has applications navigation, automated inspection, assisting
the visually impaired, and so much more. In this talk, I will explain
and demonstrate how you can use Computer Vision to locate and identify a
playing card in a live video feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Pick a card, any card,&amp;quot; the magician prompts you fanning out a deck of
cards. You select a card, note its value, and hand it back to the
magician. They do some sleight of hand, make the card disappear into the
deck, and then make it reappear. You confirm that it is, indeed, your
original card. The magician moves on and you get to go back to enjoying
your dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the real magic? Is it in the magician's ability to make a card
reappear? Or, is it something that many of us take for granted each and
every day? In the very instant you glance at a card, you're able to take
in details without even thinking about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision aims to teach computers to interact with the visual
world. It has applications in navigation, automated inspection, medical
image process, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the field of Computer Vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate how to manipulate a webcam video feed and pre-process the
video to perform Canny Edge Detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use these edges to isolate a playing card image and, eventually,
identify which playing card is being shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prior knowledge of Computer Vision or Machine Learning is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steve Crow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-28:pyohio-2019/is-this-your-card-computer-vision-for-playing-card-recognition.html</guid></item></channel></rss>