<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Can you keep a secret?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/can-you-keep-a-secret.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been guilty of hard-coding secrets at some point. It’s just a
quick hack, and you’ll definitely go back and tidy it up later. But then you
forget, and it’s all too easy to &lt;cite&gt;git push&lt;/cite&gt; your API keys to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This easy to make mistake could end up [costing you thousands of
dollars](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dev.to/juanmanuelramallo/i-was-billed-for-14k-usd-on"&gt;https://dev.to/juanmanuelramallo/i-was-billed-for-14k-usd-on&lt;/a&gt;-
amazon-web-services-17fn), and with the [median time to discovery for a
secret key leaked to GitHub being 20 seconds](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.ndss"&gt;https://www.ndss&lt;/a&gt;-
symposium.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ndss2019_04B-3_Meli_paper.pdf) you
could end up compromised before you have a chance to correct your error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll look at techniques that you can use personally and
within your development teams to properly store, share, and manage your
secrets, as easily as possible without disrupting your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/can-you-keep-a-secret.html</guid></item><item><title>When your wetware has too many threads - Tips from an ADHDer on how to improve your focus</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Somewhere between 5% and 12% of adults have ADHD. Even if you do not
have the disorder yourself you probably work, live or know someone who
does. But the world is not designed for people with ADHD, so to be
successful I’ve had to develop techniques to keep my concentration and
procrastination in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll briefly look at what ADHD is and how it impairs not
only concentration but also executive function. Then we’ll explore how
changes in the workplace can benefit not just those with ADHD, but
anyone whose work requires creativity or extended periods of focus.
Next, we’ll look at some persistent myths about productivity, and what
you can do personally to increase your concentration and output without
burning out. Then I’ll present some techniques you can rollout within
your team to remove distractions while improving the quality of
communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</guid></item><item><title>When the __future__ becomes the present; Dropping Python 2 support in a commercial client</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/when-the-__future__-becomes-the-present-dropping-python-2-support-in-a-commercial-client.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nexmo recently decided to refactor our Python client library to be
Python 3-only. Learn why we made this decision, the advantages (and
disadvantages) that come along with it, and how we’re monitoring and
helping our users with the migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Python 3.4, Python has jumped forward, adding many features that
are not available in Python 2.7. Maintaining Python 2 compatibility
means either avoiding these new language features or using backport
libraries that provide an approximation. Neither provided the best
experience for our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll also discuss how we support users of our legacy
library, the benefits that the new library offers, and our experience of
developing a customer-facing Python library with the latest Python
language and core library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/when-the-__future__-becomes-the-present-dropping-python-2-support-in-a-commercial-client.html</guid></item><item><title>When your wetware has too many threads - Tips from an ADHDer on how to improve your focus</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My brain is different. The regions involved in concentration, impulse
control, inhibition, and motor activity are smaller than usual; Like
somewhere between 5% and 12% of adults I have ADHD. Even if you do not
have the disorder yourself you probably work, live or know someone who
does. But the world is not designed for people with ADHD, so to be
successful I’ve had to develop techniques to keep my concentration and
procrastination in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;What is ADHD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;How can we change our workspaces to help focus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Being more productive without burning out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Communicating as a team without interrupting flow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is not just for those people with ADHD, although they will
benefit as well. It is for anyone whose job requires long bouts of
focus or “flow”. The primary audience of the talk will be
programmers, but it will also benefit team leads, product managers,
and technical writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no specialist knowledge required to understand this talk. I
do give a brief overview of the start of what ADHD is to establish
context, but the talk focuses on productivity, not psychiatry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope people will leave with ideas about how they can make their
workplace, their team and themselves more productive, less stressed
and distracted, and ultimately more happy in their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 20 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 16:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</guid><category>process</category><category>wetware</category><category>mental health</category><category>productivity</category></item><item><title>When your wetware has too many threads - Tips from an ADHDer on how to improve your focus</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My brain is different. The regions involved in concentration, impulse
control, and inhibition are smaller than usual; Like somewhere between
5% and 12% of adults I have ADHD. Even if you do not have the disorder
yourself you probably work, live or know someone who does. But the world
is not designed for people with ADHD, so to be successful I’ve had to
develop techniques to keep my concentration and procrastination in
check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll briefly look at what ADHD is and how it impairs not
only concentration but also executive function. Then we’ll explore how
changes in the workplace can benefit not just those with ADHD, but
anyone whose work requires creativity or extended periods of focus.
Next, we’ll look at some persistent myths about productivity, and what
you can do personally to increase your concentration and output without
burning out. Then I’ll present some techniques you can rollout within
your team to remove distractions while improving the quality of
communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/when-your-wetware-has-too-many-threads-tips-from-an-adhder-on-how-to-improve-your-focus.html</guid><category>ADHD</category><category>PyCon SK</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Hello to the World in 8 Web Frameworks (micro, batteries included &amp; async)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/hello-to-the-world-in-8-web-frameworks-micro-batteries-included-async.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us for a Phileas Fogg inspired whirlwind tour of eight Python web
frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Had he programmed? It was likely, for no one seemed to know web
frameworks more familiarly; there was no framework so obscure that he
did not appear to have an intimate acquaintance with it. He must have
developed in everything, at least in the spirit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start with the current crop of microframeworks, showing how to
achieve the same task in each, before progressing to “Batteries
included” and the more specialised async frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For developers who perhaps have only used a single framework, this talk
gives them an opportunity to get out and explore the world (of web
frameworks) and broaden their horizons, with plenty of Jules Verne
inspired fun along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:europython-2018/hello-to-the-world-in-8-web-frameworks-micro-batteries-included-async.html</guid></item><item><title>Hello to the World in 8 Web Frameworks (Micro, Batteries Included &amp; Async)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2018/hello-to-the-world-in-8-web-frameworks-micro-batteries-included-async.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Phileas Fogg inspired tour of 8 frameworks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Had he programmed? It was likely, for no one seemed to know web frameworks more familiarly; there was no framework so obscure that he did not appear to have an intimate acquaintance with it. He must have developed in everything, at least in the spirit.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-26:pycon-au-2018/hello-to-the-world-in-8-web-frameworks-micro-batteries-included-async.html</guid></item><item><title>Django and the testing pyramid</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/django-and-the-testing-pyramid.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Model mommy lettuce factory boy expects gherkin behave. Travis mock splinter nose phantom hypothesis!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most developers recognise the importance of testing in building maintainable software, but the sheer volume of tools and approaches can be bewildering and sometimes make it sound like you're talking a different language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll look at the testing pyramid. We'll discuss how approaching our testing in layers can increase developer productivity by reducing the time taken to run our test suites. We'll look at the importance of different testing types including integration and acceptance testing. Finally we'll introduce some tools and packages you can use to make writing good tests easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end you'll be able to talk TDD and BDD like a native!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/django-and-the-testing-pyramid.html</guid></item><item><title>Effortless real time apps in Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/aaron-bassett-effortless-real-time-apps-in-django.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aaron Bassett</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-15:djangocon-europe-2015/aaron-bassett-effortless-real-time-apps-in-django.html</guid></item></channel></rss>