<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_muriel-green.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Bespoke communication devices for kids with autism built with Django and Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/bespoke-communication-devices-for-kids-with-autism-built-with-django-and-raspberry-pi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Muriel Green</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-17:djangocon-us-2018/bespoke-communication-devices-for-kids-with-autism-built-with-django-and-raspberry-pi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will detail my experience building an Augmentative Alternative
Communication (AAC) device for my son who has autism. I had to perform
some troubleshooting to get Django to harmonize with the Raspbian OS and
touchscreen drivers, but the result is easily replicable using the
instructions I will cover from my project documentation on the Hackaday
website bit.ly/TalkerHackaday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to give this talk to inspire other developers to try their hand
at building bespoke assistive devices. Commercially available medical
assistive devices are expensive partly because they try to be everything
to everybody. What if instead, we made products that do one thing for
one specific user very well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline shows what I will cover in my talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a need and fill it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django on Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface prototyping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gesture recognition for touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom enclosures with NO 3D printing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone needs to become an inventor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people who are curious about running Django in an
embedded system (development server as the production environment).
People who are interested in Debian Linux will also find this talk
interesting. I would love to reach the autism community and people who
want to build assistive technology. To get the most out of this talk,
attendees should have a basic knowledge of how to perform a command line
Django installation and what a raspberry pi is.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>