<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_felipe-lema.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>ALGES: Geostatistics and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/alges-geostatistics-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felipe Lema</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/alges-geostatistics-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ALGES is a laboratory that develops tools applied to geostatistics.
We've been using python for a while and it has brought us very good
results. Its ease-of- use and portability allow us to rapidly offer
practical solutions to problems. Along with a brief introduction to the
laboratory, we cover two particular projects we are currently working
on. One project is an application for multivariate geostatistic
analysis. Most available applications provide analysis for a single
variable at a time and either obviate how variables can relate between
one another or make it really difficult to consider any relationship.
Our proposal provides both an interface that's both easy to use for
primers and fine tuning for experienced users. The other presented
project covers a problem in geological modeling and resource estimation.
Commonly, when modeling geological volumes, continuity in data is
assumed. This is not often true, as there are different kinds of faults
that break this continuity. This is very hard to incorporate when
modeling. We propose a solution to restore the original continuous
volume for better modeling as well as restitution to the real distorted
volume, all this providing a better estimation. Both projects have lots
of heavy computations and no shortage of input data. We take this as a
challenge to build fast processing solutions, so we take advantage of
both the easiness of a python interface and the speed of C/C++ code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Geophysics Mini-Symposia"></category></entry></feed>