<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_dhananjay-sathe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>We're building Skynet and it loves Python!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2013/were-building-skynet-and-it-loves-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dhananjay Sathe</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-08-31:pycon-india-2013/were-building-skynet-and-it-loves-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of Driverless cars, autonomous self learning robots, robots with
minds in the cloud. In common terms think of Trinity downloading the
routine to fly apache in The Matrix. Until now prohibitive costs,
architectural limitations , complex network setups and configurations
and limitations of computing resources have hampered some really cool
stuff in Robotics, Rapyuta attempts to solve these very issues. Off late
we have completely revamped it and added a ton of exciting new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RoboEarth is one of the top projects in the EU funded by the FP7
framework with members including ETH Zurich, Tu Munich, Tu Eindhoven and
others and is fully available in Open Source. It draws from the strong
base and standards of ROS (www.ros.org) to bring the best of modern
robotics algorithms and software to the average developers and uses some
exciting new tech like lxc and websockets, yet is simple to use and
configure on almost any platform from EC2, Google Compute Engine,
Rackspace or even commodity hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a general purpose talk to introduce you to Rapyuta, briefly
touch on how we built it (twisted devs would love this), how you can
easily use and configure it and what it does for you. I will also try to
showcase some breakthrough real world application demos that were
presented at ROSCON '13 at Stuttgart, that would get the geeks in us
excited. There will also be some interesting pointers of how you could
use it , extend it and get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>