<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Rodrigo Silva Ferreira</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rodrigo-silva-ferreira.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Un Enfoque Pythonico para Minería de Textos de Historias de Trabajo Arduo, Migración y Resiliencia</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2025/un-enfoque-pythonico-para-mineria-de-textos-de-historias-de-trabajo-arduo-migracion-y-resiliencia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Silva Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-17:/pycon-us-2025/un-enfoque-pythonico-para-mineria-de-textos-de-historias-de-trabajo-arduo-migracion-y-resiliencia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entre 1942 y 1964, el Programa Bracero llevó a más de 4.5 millones de trabajadores mexicanos a los Estados Unidos para hacer frente a la escasez de mano de obra. Sin embargo, las experiencias personales de estos trabajadores a menudo permanecen en la sombra, aunque sus relatos capturan …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entre 1942 y 1964, el Programa Bracero llevó a más de 4.5 millones de trabajadores mexicanos a los Estados Unidos para hacer frente a la escasez de mano de obra. Sin embargo, las experiencias personales de estos trabajadores a menudo permanecen en la sombra, aunque sus relatos capturan historias de trabajo incansable, migración, discriminación y resiliencia. Honrar estas narrativas requiere no solo un reconocimiento histórico, sino también un método para descubrir y analizar sistemáticamente sus relatos matizados. Aprovechando la minería de texto y el procesamiento de lenguaje natural mediante bibliotecas de Python como beautiful soup, Sentence Transformers y BERTopic, esta charla tiene como objetivo destacar los temas, luchas y resiliencia que definen las experiencias de braceros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esta sesión explorará cómo estas bibliotecas de Python pueden utilizarse para realizar un análisis sistemático de grandes cuerpos de texto, revelando temas recurrentes y el sentimiento en historias orales y entrevistas. Profundizaremos en técnicas basadas en código para el modelado de temas, la extracción de palabras clave y el análisis de sentimiento que dan vida a las historias de los Braceros. Al examinar cómo Python puede facilitar la comprensión del lenguaje del trabajo, la migración y las dificultades, esta charla demostrará cómo la ciencia de datos puede desempeñar un papel en la valoración de narrativas culturales e históricas. Al hacerlo, esta presentación también busca mostrar el potencial de Python para unir los campos de las humanidades digitales, la etnografía y la tecnología, allanando el camino hacia una mayor comprensión y reconocimiento de las voces subrepresentadas en la historia compartida de trabajo y migración entre México y Estados Unidos.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Signal Processing in Electrochemistry with Python: Applications to the US Opioids Crisis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2024/signal-processing-in-electrochemistry-with-python-applications-to-the-us-opioids-crisis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Silva Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-28:/pyohio-2024/signal-processing-in-electrochemistry-with-python-applications-to-the-us-opioids-crisis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 195 daily deaths due to synthetic opioids overdose in
2021, the US have been facing an unprecedented opioids crisis. Fentanyl
and its analogues have been a major source of concern, due to their high
levels of addiction, fast-acting mechanisms, and detection challenges.
Fast, effective, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 195 daily deaths due to synthetic opioids overdose in
2021, the US have been facing an unprecedented opioids crisis. Fentanyl
and its analogues have been a major source of concern, due to their high
levels of addiction, fast-acting mechanisms, and detection challenges.
Fast, effective, and accurate identification and quantification of
fentanyl, its analogues, and metabolites are essential to help prevent
overdose-related incidents and to enable agile medical response.
Although electrochemical sensors represent a promising technology for
selectively detecting opioids at low concentrations, analyzing and
processing the data remains one of the major challenges. To tackle this
challenge, certain Python libraries, such as &lt;em&gt;scipy.signal&lt;/em&gt;, could be
useful in processing signals with high levels of noise and interference
from other substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on specific examples of how such libraries could
help enable filtering, Fourier transformation, and wavelet analysis of
electrochemical data. As examples, code snippets and outputs will be
shown to demonstrate how Python can help improve the quality and
usability of electrochemical data. Additionally, this talk will show how
data processing can further benefit from hyper parameter optimization
techniques, enabled by libraries like &lt;em&gt;hyperopt&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ray-tune&lt;/em&gt;. By
doing so, my hope is to demonstrate how Python could be extremely useful
in helping address problems at the intersection of statistics, public
health, and public policy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>From Fortran to Python: A Conversation Across Generations of Scientific Computing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/from-fortran-to-python-a-conversation-across-generations-of-scientific-computing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Silva Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-27:/pyohio-2025/from-fortran-to-python-a-conversation-across-generations-of-scientific-computing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What was it like to write scientific code before personal computers,
IDEs, or instant feedback loops? In this talk, a mother and son — one
who programmed in &lt;em&gt;Fortran&lt;/em&gt; using punch cards and one who writes
&lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; today in modern IDEs — reflect on how programming practices,
tools, and mindsets have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What was it like to write scientific code before personal computers,
IDEs, or instant feedback loops? In this talk, a mother and son — one
who programmed in &lt;em&gt;Fortran&lt;/em&gt; using punch cards and one who writes
&lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; today in modern IDEs — reflect on how programming practices,
tools, and mindsets have evolved across generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through personal stories and a short demo of a scientific simulation, we
compare the experience of coding the same computational model decades
apart. This talk is less about syntax and more about what has changed
(and what hasn’t) in how we approach problem-solving, debugging, and
scientific thinking in code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you're a veteran programmer or just getting started, join us for
a thoughtful, engaging, and intergenerational exploration of scientific
computing — from punch cards to &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; notebooks and modern IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2025"></category></entry><entry><title>Signal Processing in Electrochemistry: Application to the US Opioid Crisis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2025/signal-processing-in-electrochemistry-application-to-the-us-opioid-crisis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rodrigo Silva Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-12:/pytexas-2025/signal-processing-in-electrochemistry-application-to-the-us-opioid-crisis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 195 daily deaths due to synthetic opioids overdose in 2021, the US have been facing an unprecedented opioids crisis. Fentanyl and its analogues have been a major source of concern, due to their high levels of addiction, fast-acting mechanisms, and detection challenges. Fast, effective, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an average of 195 daily deaths due to synthetic opioids overdose in 2021, the US have been facing an unprecedented opioids crisis. Fentanyl and its analogues have been a major source of concern, due to their high levels of addiction, fast-acting mechanisms, and detection challenges. Fast, effective, and accurate identification and quantification of fentanyl, its analogues, and metabolites are essential to help prevent overdose-related incidents and to enable agile medical response. Although electrochemical sensors represent a promising technology for selectively detecting opioids at low concentrations, analyzing and processing the data remains one of the major challenges. To tackle this challenge, certain Python libraries, such as scipy.signal, could be useful in processing signals with high levels of noise and interference from other substances. This talk will focus on specific examples of how such libraries could help enable filtering, Fourier transformation, and wavelet analysis of electrochemical data. As examples, code snippets and outputs will be shown to demonstrate how Python can help improve the quality and usability of electrochemical data. Additionally, this talk will show how data processing can further benefit from hyper parameter optimization techniques, enabled by libraries like hyperopt and ray-tune. By doing so, my hope is to demonstrate how Python could be extremely useful in helping address problems at the intersection of statistics, public health, and public policy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2025"></category></entry></feed>