<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mx Chiin-Rui Tan</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Investigating Environmental issues with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2023/investigating-environmental-issues-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earth's sustainability is on the brink. However, with today's information wars this situation isn't universally accepted. This talk democratises citizen environmental investigation by applying Python to selected Green issues. By separating facts from fiction humanity can be better informed to safeguard our existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existential threats to humanity as a result of decades of damage inflicted to the planet are already in motion. From the first climate refugees in 2014, to escalating public health crises of air pollution and food insecurity around the world, Earth becomes less inhabitable every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet concern isn't as widespread as is warranted. Many parties profit from unsustainable practices, and therefore have motive to obfuscate the long-term harmful consequences. In today's post-truth world, exacerbated by generative AI and other mis-used tech, public opinion is the battleground between multiple opposing influences, only to the detriment of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to better equip citizens to bypass/counter the deliberate informational noise and investigate environmental issues themselves, being more empowered to come to their own conclusions about the actual state of our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A selection of scientific workflows, using open-source Python and publicly available resources, will be presented, each delving into a topical environmental issue to produce actionable insight. Designed to be accessible and reproducible by tech literate citizens without domain expertise, the audience will takeaway transferable Python skills for undertaking similar scientific computing exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's democratise Python's potential for citizen access to discovery of environmental facts, so that humanity can be better informed to better influence the safeguarding of our planet, and ultimately our existence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mx Chiin-Rui Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-23:/pycon-uk-2023/investigating-environmental-issues-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon UK 2023</category></item><item><title>Exploring Eco topics with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/exploring-eco-topics-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Deforestation to Wildlife Trade to Carbon Polluters, learn how to
use Python to explore current Eco topics!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Earth's sustainability edges ever closer to tipping point, it has
never been more important for us inhabitants to be aware of the impact
we have on the environment, and the deteriorating state of our planet.
This tutorial will democratize access to practical Python skills for the
relevant sciences, applying these skills to pressing Eco issues, and
ultimately empower non-subject experts with working proficiency of
relevant open-source tools for discovering more facts about our natural
world, at a time when disinformation is rife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Python takeaways: intro to and/or application of numpy, pandas,
matplotlib, networkx, geopandas, xarray, and rioxarray.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format: interactive computer lab, with attendees working hands-on
through pre-prepared Jupyter Notebook content at a group pace led by
the instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience: no prior Eco/Scientific domain knowledge or experience with
the Python packages being taught required, but attendees must have
basic Python programming proficiency and ability to set-up access to
JupyterLab with the required mainstream dependencies (as per
instructions provided in advance).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mx Chiin-Rui Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/exploring-eco-topics-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>