<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_christophe-poulain.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>CodaLab: A New Service for Data Exchange, Code Execution, Benchmarks &amp; Reproducible Research</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/codalab-a-new-service-for-data-exchange-code-ex.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christophe Poulain</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/codalab-a-new-service-for-data-exchange-code-ex.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn, Share and Collaborate with CodaLab -- A new open source platform
which lets communities create and explore experiments together and
engage in benchmarking and competitions to enable true reproducibility
and advance the state of the art in data-driven research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CodaLab is a web-based open source platform that allows researchers to
share and browse code, data, and create experiments in a truly
reproducible manner. CodaLab focuses on accomplishing the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as a data repository for data sets including large scale data
sets that could only be hosted in a cloud computing environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as an algorithm repository that researchers can use in their
experimentation, to teach and learn from others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host the execution of experiments as worksheets, sometimes referred
to as &amp;quot;executable papers&amp;quot;, which are annotated scientific documents
that combine textual process descriptions with live data sets and
functioning code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable the creation of benchmarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodaLab is a community-driven effort led by Percy Liang from Stanford
University who built the precursor of CodaLab, namely, MLComp. From a
development viewpoint CodaLab supports both the Linux and Windows
communities with code in GitHub and Python as one of the main language
used to support the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At SciPi, we invite the community to participate in CodaLab by creating
experiments as executable papers and by sharing them with the rest of
the community at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://codalab.org"&gt;http://codalab.org&lt;/a&gt;. These worksheets or &amp;quot;executable
papers&amp;quot; can then be freely reproduced, appended, and otherwise modified
to improve productivity and accelerate the pace of discovery and
learning among data-driven scientific professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>