<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Bence Arató</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_bence-arato.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Python Data Visualization Landscape in 2020</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/the-python-data-visualization-landscape-in-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bence Arató</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/the-python-data-visualization-landscape-in-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python offers many different data visualization libraries, and the sheer number of alternatives  can be daunting to newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to introduce the most important visualization libraries, covering Matplotlib, Plotly, Bokeh and Altair, among others. It also provides a summary of the quickly developing dashboarding solutions, including Dash …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python offers many different data visualization libraries, and the sheer number of alternatives  can be daunting to newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to introduce the most important visualization libraries, covering Matplotlib, Plotly, Bokeh and Altair, among others. It also provides a summary of the quickly developing dashboarding solutions, including Dash, Panel and Voila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of talk is not just to provide a simple list of libraries, but also to highlight the main characteristics and inspirations for each, and summarize the recent developments as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed to people who have some basic experience working with data in Python and would like to get a better understanding of the data visualization tool landscape.  Some existing knowledge of pandas DataFrames is beneficial for understanding the examples, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Analytics"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Visualization"></category></entry></feed>