<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_godfrey-akpojotor.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-02T11:30:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Adopting QPython in smartphones for teaching/learning computational science and engineering</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/adopting-qpython-in-smartphones-for-teachinglearning-computational-science-and-engineering.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-02T11:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-02T11:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Godfrey Akpojotor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-02:pycon-us-2019/adopting-qpython-in-smartphones-for-teachinglearning-computational-science-and-engineering.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been teaching undergraduate computational physics for more than a
decade in my university. Adopting Python as our programming language has
really helped because of its unique qualities which made it easily
accessible and easy to teach/learn. However, providing enough computing
devices to the increasing number of students has been a serious
challenge. This is even more frustrating when one require to involve
online classroom submission/evaluation of assignments. I have overcome
this challenge by adopting QPython in smartphones which are rapidly
penetrating Africa. With a built-in math library and possibility to
install Numpy, QPython in smartphones has made the teaching/learning to
more students more efficient especially as they can now engage in
learning programming anywhere, anytime and anyhow. The success made me
extend it to one of our current projects under the Python African
Computational Science and Engineering Tour (PACSETPro) on teaching
Python to students, new beginners as well as expert programmers in
science and engineering (S &amp;amp; E). In this talk, I gave a captivating
account on how to use QPython to teach computational approaches in S &amp;amp; E
in a manner that advancing to normal computing systems is
straightforward. Highly excited by the success so far, our outlook is
having both Matplotlib and QVPython in smartphones. This will be a boon
for teaching/learning computational approaches anywhere, anytime and
anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Challenges and Prospects of the Python African Computational Science and Engineering Tour Project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/challenges-and-prospects-of-the-python-african-co.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Godfrey Akpojotor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/challenges-and-prospects-of-the-python-african-co.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer and computer based activities have pervaded our
teaching/learning process as well as research so much so that the 21st
century academic activities in science and engineering (S &amp;amp; E) cannot be
fully engaged without some level of computation. An important choice of
a programming language especially in a developing country is the ease to
learn it and its accessibility. Python's unique features and the
possibility that any user connected to the internet can download the
entire packages into any platform, install it and immediately begin to
use it makes it a preferred environment for introducing students and new
beginners to elegant and all purpose programming. Therefore in Africa,
the Python African Tour project has been launched and I am coordinating
its use in computational Science and Engineering (S &amp;amp; E) code-named
Python African Computational Science and Engineering Tour (PACSET).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry></feed>