<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jose Haro Peralta</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jose-haro-peralta.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Documentation-driven development for Python web APIs</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/documentation-driven-development-for-python-web-apis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jose Haro Peralta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/documentation-driven-development-for-python-web-apis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documentation-driven development for Python web APIs
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Jose Haro Peralta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation shows how we can use documentation-driven development to minimise the risk of API integration failures. APIs are the gateways that connect our web applications to the world. Microservices rely on them …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documentation-driven development for Python web APIs
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Jose Haro Peralta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation shows how we can use documentation-driven development to minimise the risk of API integration failures. APIs are the gateways that connect our web applications to the world. Microservices rely on them to work together, and frontend applications use them to connect to our backend. Despite their importance, API integration failures are a daily occurrence. There’re many reasons for this, but a common factor is the lack of API documentation, or the use of bad API documentation.
Often, API documentation comes in unstructured formats or in JSON examples, instead of standard formats such as OpenAPI or Schema Definition Language. When we don’t use standards to document our APIs, we give up the whole ecosystem of frameworks and tools built around those standards. Such tools and frameworks are designed to make our lives easier when managing the lifecycle of our APIs.
In documentation-driven development, we write the API specification first, and then we implement the API server and the client against the specification. I’ll show how we can use mock servers to test the client while the backend is being developed, and tools like Dredd and schemathesis to validate the backend implementation. I’ll show how we can use these tools in a CI server to validate our code before it’s released. This approach doesn’t eliminate completely the risk of API integration failures, but it helps to minimise it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Zero Trust APIs with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/zero-trust-apis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jose Haro Peralta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/zero-trust-apis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero Trust APIs with Python by Jose Haro Peralta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/zero-trust-apis-with-python"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/zero-trust-apis-with-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it take to deliver a properly secured API? When we think about API security, we first think of authentication and authorization. But there’s more …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — South Hall 2A on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero Trust APIs with Python by Jose Haro Peralta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/zero-trust-apis-with-python"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/zero-trust-apis-with-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it take to deliver a properly secured API? When we think about API security, we first think of authentication and authorization. But there’s more to it. API security also includes protecting against SQL Injection attacks, Mass Assignment, Excessive Data Exposure, Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRS), and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APIs are now the main attack vector on the Internet, and we gotta do something about it. Thankfully, Python boasts excellent libraries for API development, like FastAPI, the Django REST Framework, APIFlask, and more. When used properly, these libraries help us deliver secure APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll present a model of Zero Trust Security for APIs that applies robust data validation and sanitization across all data flows to help us deliver secure APIs. You’ll learn how your API design and implementation choices impact API security and how to discover and tackle vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll walk through practical examples of SQL injection, mass assignment, big payload attacks, pagination attacks, and more. We’ll see how URL parameters and request payloads can become attack vectors when they’re not properly configured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll also learn how to use tools like schemathesis and Spectral to automate and scale the process of detecting vulnerabilities in your APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you’ll be aware of the most important threats to our APIs and you’ll know how to discover and address them effectively. You’ll also get familiar with the concepts of API Security by Design, Shift-Left API Security, and Zero Trust APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Delivering successful API integrations with documentation driven development</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2021/delivering-successful-api-integrations-with-documentation-driven-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jose Haro Peralta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-19:/pycon-india-2021/delivering-successful-api-integrations-with-documentation-driven-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyCon India 2021 Online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India is the largest gathering of Pythonistas in India for the Python programming language.
The 13th edition of PyCon India took place online from 17th Sept to 20th Sept 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk Detail: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals/delivering-successful-api-integrations-with-documentation-driven-development~dwpmM/"&gt;https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyCon India 2021 Online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India is the largest gathering of Pythonistas in India for the Python programming language.
The 13th edition of PyCon India took place online from 17th Sept to 20th Sept 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk Detail: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals/delivering-successful-api-integrations-with-documentation-driven-development~dwpmM/"&gt;https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2021/proposals/delivering-successful-api-integrations-with-documentation-driven-development~dwpmM/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to subscribe to the PyCon India channel: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;
Follow PyCon India on Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconindia"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconindia&lt;/a&gt;
Follow PyCon India on Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/PyConIndia/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/PyConIndia/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon India 2021"></category><category term="PyConIndia"></category><category term="PyConIndia2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Fundamentals of API security with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/fundamentals-of-api-security-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jose Haro Peralta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/fundamentals-of-api-security-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you’ll dive into the fundamentals of API security for
Python applications. You’ll learn best practices and patterns for API
authentication and authorization and for API security by design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll go through the OWASP top 10 API vulnerabilities. We’ll see
practical examples of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you’ll dive into the fundamentals of API security for
Python applications. You’ll learn best practices and patterns for API
authentication and authorization and for API security by design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll go through the OWASP top 10 API vulnerabilities. We’ll see
practical examples of how they occur, including examples from real-world
APIs. We’ll analyze the vulnerabilities, understand what the attack
vectors are, and how we address them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn how Open Authorization (OAuth) and OpenID Connect (OIDC)
work for APIs. You’ll learn about the risks and advantages of using
these protocols, known vulnerabilities, and best practices to avoid
them. You’ll also learn about JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) and how to use them
correctly for access authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you’ll learn how to automate the process of detecting and
addressing security vulnerabilities in your APIs using fuzzy testers
like schemathesis and design-testing tools like spectral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the tutorial, we’ll use examples of OpenAPI specifications,
and code examples in Flask and FastAPI. You’ll make the best out of the
tutorial if you have some experience working with APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you work with APIs (who doesn’t!), I’d love to welcome you to this
tutorial to learn how to build and deliver secure APIs!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>