<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Exceeding Classical: Probabilistic Data Structures in Data Intensive Applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/exceeding-classical-probabilistic-data-structures-in-data-intensive-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nowadays, research in every scientific domain, from medicine to
astronomy, is impossible without processing huge amounts of data to
check hypotheses, find new relations, and make discoveries. However, the
traditional technologies which include data structures and algorithms,
become ineffective or require too many resources. This creates a demand
for various optimization techniques, new data processing paradigms, and,
finally, appropriate algorithms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is dedicated to &lt;em&gt;probabilistic data structures&lt;/em&gt; , that
is a common name for advanced data structures based mostly on different
hashing techniques. Unlike classical ones, these provide approximated
answers but with reliable ways to estimate possible errors and
uncertainty. They are designed for extremely low memory requirements,
constant query time, and scaling, the factors that are essential for
data applications. It is hard to imagine a branch that requires learning
from data, where they cannot be applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are not necessarily new. Probably, everybody knows about the Bloom
filter data structure, designed in the 70s, it efficiently solves the
problem of performing membership queries (a task to decide whether some
element belongs to the dataset or not) in a constant time without
requirements to store all elements. This is an example of a
probabilistic data structure, but there are much more that have been
designed for various tasks in many domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I explain &lt;strong&gt;the five most important problems in data
processing&lt;/strong&gt; that occurred in different domains but &lt;strong&gt;can be efficiently
solved with probabilistic data structures and algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;. We cover the
&lt;em&gt;membership querying&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;counting&lt;/em&gt; of unique elements, &lt;em&gt;frequency&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;rank&lt;/em&gt; estimation in data streams, and &lt;em&gt;similarity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody interested in such a topic is welcome to participate in
contributing a free and open-source Python (Cython) library called
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gakhov/pdsa"&gt;PDSA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We interact with an increasing amount of data but classical data
structures and algorithms can't fit our requirements anymore. This talk
is to present the probabilistic algorithms and data structures and
describe the main areas of their applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrii Gakhov</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/exceeding-classical-probabilistic-data-structures-in-data-intensive-applications.html</guid></item><item><title>An Introduction to Time Series Forecasting with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ukraine-2018/an-introduction-to-time-series-forecasting-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time series is an important instrument to model, analyze and predict
data collected over time. In this talk, we learn the basic theoretical
concepts without going deep into mathematical aspects, study different
models, and try them in practice using StatsModels, Prophet,
scikit-learn, and keras.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrii Gakhov</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-28:pycon-ukraine-2018/an-introduction-to-time-series-forecasting-with-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>