<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_perry-greenfield.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>ASDF, a New Scientific Data Format</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/asdf-a-new-scientific-data-format.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Perry Greenfield</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:scipy-2015/asdf-a-new-scientific-data-format.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Astropy - Herding Snakes or Astronomers: which is more difficult?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/astropy-herding-snakes-or-astronomers-which-is.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Tollerud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/astropy-herding-snakes-or-astronomers-which-is.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers and users of astronomical software have long bemoaned the
absence of shared efforts in the field. While there are well known, free
software tools available for astronomy, most have been developed by
large institutions, and the past few decades have seen comparatively
little progress in fostering a community-based set of software tools.
There is hope that is changing now. The continuing growth of Python in
astronomy has led to an increasing awareness of needless duplication of
efforts within the community and the need to make existing packages work
better with each other; such discussions came to a head on the astropy
email list in the spring of 2011 leading to formation of the astropy
project. The first coordination meeting was held in the fall of 2011,
and significant progress has been made in setting up a community
repository of core astronomical packages. We will describe the general
goals of astropy and the progress that has been made to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Astronomy Mini-Symposia"></category></entry><entry><title>Astropy in 2014: What's new, where we are headed</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/astropy-in-2014-whats-new-where-we-are-headed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Perry Greenfield</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/astropy-in-2014-whats-new-where-we-are-headed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We report on the progress made on the Astropy Project in the past year
highlighting the new capabilities added as well as the near-term
development plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astropy continues to see significant growth in available software,
developers, and users. A new major release (V0.3) was made in the past
year as well as many minor releases. V0.4 is scheduled for release by
the time of conference and will include support for the VO SAMP
protocol. We will report on the progress made in building and enhancing
the core libraries in the Astropy Project, including a new model and
fitting framework, enhanced units, quantities, and table functionality,
a VO cone search tool, and a new convolution subpackage. We'll review
the current set of tools available, highlighting in particular the new
capabilities present. We will also give an overview of current
activities and development plans for the core and affiliated packages,
as well as adding new resources/tutorials for learning how to use
astropy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="astropy"></category></entry><entry><title>Astropy and astronomical tools Part I</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/astropy-and-astronomical-tools-part-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Bray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/astropy-and-astronomical-tools-part-i.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introductory session will start with an overview of the astropy
project and the goals of the tutorial, followed by the basics on
accessing astronomical data and the associated attributes of such data,
including the units and coordinates. Also covered is how to use the new
and powerful quantities facility, which allows physical quantities to be
explicitly bound to the units they are defined in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of astropy (15 minutes) [Greenfield]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Import astropy, demonstrate that tools are present and
echo simple examples given. (15 minutes: allowing for typical
start-up problems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Units/quantities (15 minutes) [Droettboom]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Solve problems using standard units; define new unit;
use unit equivalencies; define blackbody function using
quantities/units (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tables (20 minutes) [Aldcroft]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: read in provided table files and apply requested table
manipulations (20 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessing and updating data&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FITS (30 minutes) [Bray]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Open supplied data files; manipulate header
information; manipulate data; write results; update and append
to existing file (30 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ascii tables (15 minutes) [Aldcroft]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise: Open supplied ascii files, modify and convert into
csv files (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coordinates (sky/time) (15 minutes) [Robitaille]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises: solve coordinate/time conversion problems; read in
various string representations for coordinates/times; print
alternate string representations (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="astropy"></category></entry></feed>