<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Zhiqiang Xu</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Practical Riemannian Algorithm for Computing Dominant Generalized Eigenspace</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/a-practical-riemannian-algorithm-for-computing-dominant-generalized-eigenspace.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;A Practical Riemannian Algorithm for Computing Dominant Generalized Eigenspace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhiqiang Xu (Baidu)*; Ping Li (Baidu Research)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominant generalized eigenspace computation, concerned with how to find one of the top-k generalized eigenspaces of a pair of real symmetric matrices, is one of the fundamental problems in scientific computing, data analysis, and statistics. In this work, we propose a practical Riemannian algorithm based on the first-order optimization on generalized Stiefel manifolds while efficiently leveraging second-order information. Particularly, we use inexact Riemannian gradients which result from running a fast least-squares solver to approximate matrix multiplications for avoiding costly matrix inversions involved therein. We also conduct a theoretical analysis that is different than existing ones, achieving a unified linear convergence rate regardless of the conventional generalized eigenvalue gap which is the key parameter to the currently dichotomized analysis: gap-dependent or gap-free. The resulting linear rate, albeit not optimal, remains valid in full generality. Despite the simplicity, empirically, our algorithm as a block generalized eigensolver remarkably outperforms existing solvers.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Zhiqiang Xu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/a-practical-riemannian-algorithm-for-computing-dominant-generalized-eigenspace.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item></channel></rss>