<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Predict timeline - Generating Agile SW metrics w/ Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2017/predict-timeline-generating-agile-sw-metrics-w-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agile methodology is mostly used by project management and software teams for creating a predictable software release timeline. Agile output is measured in form of sprint metrics such as burndown chart, cumulative velocity etc . Usually commercial project management tools provide user stories management and metrics out of the box. Many organizations do not have these expensive tools due to costs and budget or historical choices. This talk describes how daily agile metrics can be generated using Python for any reasonable project management tool that has an Agile template and a webservices API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meenal Pant</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-11:pybay-2017/predict-timeline-generating-agile-sw-metrics-w-python.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>One Pykid at a time</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/one-pykid-at-a-time.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a Pythonista, an educator, STEM supporter, love free software and a parent then you should attend this talk. This talk brings home the importance of brining STEM and computing education to the K-12 school children early and in a timely manner.
​
Abstract
Python is a language that makes learning programming easy and can set the foundation for our children to go on and take STEM coursework or use their knowledge of computing in other subject areas when its time for graduate school. Our school system currently has a gap in their curriculum when it comes to computing and learning how to code. pykids is a voluntary organization that is aiming to fill that gap by providing easy to use learning resources. pykids is also encouraging classroom learning by creating a space for local meetups and volunteer classes that run through the curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pykids set up today includes the following:
- A blog/website where students/instructors register and share ideas
- A jupyter server that allows running notebooks on the fly
- Downloadable Notebooks created for K3-High School students (WIP)
- Teaching material for K-3 students
- Volunteers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All a student needs is a laptop and an internet connection to start learning Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio
Meenal Pant is a mom, long time programmer and yes a Pythonista!. She has worked in both the industry and academic /research institutes and therefore is keen to “build a bond” between technology and education. She is a poster presenter and speaker (education summit/lightening talks) in the past few PyCons - the most recent being PyCon2016. She is actively involved in the STEM education via her workplace and also personally in her kid’s schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/meenal-pant-one-pykid-at-a-time"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/meenal-pant-one-pykid-at-a-time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meenal Pant</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-20:pybay-2016/one-pykid-at-a-time.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks - 2016-05-31 AM</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-05-31-am.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Spang</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-01:pycon-us-2016/lightning-talks-2016-05-31-am.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Data Classification Using Python, Django and R</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2013/data-classification-using-python-django-and-r.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a recent project, I had to develop a real time diagnostics tool with
a web dashboard. The goal of this tool was to assist data experts with
proactive monitoring and trouble-shooting our equipment deployed in the
field. So I decided to design a real time web dashboard with status
updates and email alerts using Python, Django and R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meenal Pant</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-03-17:pycon-us-2013/data-classification-using-python-django-and-r.html</guid><category>poster</category></item></channel></rss>