<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Aaron Gokaslan</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aaron-gokaslan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Impact and Challenges of Open Source Generative Datasets and Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/the-impact-and-challenges-of-open-source-generative-datasets-and-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Gokaslan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/the-impact-and-challenges-of-open-source-generative-datasets-and-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source generative models like OpenGPT2, BLOOM, and others have been pivotal in advancing AI technology. These models leverage extensive text data to achieve advanced linguistic capabilities. However, the trend towards proprietary tools and closed large language models is growing, posing unique challenges in open-source AI development. This discussion …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open source generative models like OpenGPT2, BLOOM, and others have been pivotal in advancing AI technology. These models leverage extensive text data to achieve advanced linguistic capabilities. However, the trend towards proprietary tools and closed large language models is growing, posing unique challenges in open-source AI development. This discussion will explore the intricacies of training such models, the hurdles in dataset management, and the regulation of open-source contributions. We'll explore how to effectively iterate on collected data, prepare for extensive training sessions, and coordinate research across large open-source organizations. We will discuss the challenges of generative models in three different modalities: text, image, and genomics. The talk will draw from the speaker’s personal experience on working on OpenWebText, OpenGPT2, BLOOM, CommonCanvas, Caduceus, and other generative models. We will also cover the changing AI environment and how the future of open souce is threatened by onerous regulation, ever increasing compute costs, and the commoditization of previously open data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Building binary extensions with pybind11, scikit build, and cibuildwheel- Q&amp;A and Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/building-binary-extensions-with-pybind11-scikit-build-and-cibuildwheel-qa-and-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Henry Schreiner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/building-binary-extensions-with-pybind11-scikit-build-and-cibuildwheel-qa-and-panel.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="SciPy 2022"></category></entry></feed>