<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_arthur-street.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Science MiniConf: Monte Carlo Business Case Analysis with pandas by Arthur Street</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/science-miniconf-monte-carlo-business-case-analy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Arthur Street</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-11:pycon-au-2014/science-miniconf-monte-carlo-business-case-analy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is increasingly becoming a standard tool in scientific computing.
Could it also have a role in the CFO's office?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CFOs regularly need to analyse the impact of different projects or
business cases, and they almost universally do this using spreadsheets.
Spreadsheets have many advantages - they have a low barrier to entry and
are easy for most people to understand. However as they get more
complicated, disadvantages start to appear; in particular, they can be
inflexible and highly error-prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will explain how business case analysis can be done using
python and pandas. The python version has several advantages over
spreadsheets: it is more flexible as the business structure changes;
formulas only need to be changed in a single place, reducing the chance
of error; and report-ready plots are quick to produce. I'll go through a
way of structuring the problem for some simple business logic, and ways
to visualise the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example I’ll discuss is made more interesting and useful by being
“Monte Carlo” analysis. Traditional business case analysis takes single
point estimates of sales, costs and prices, and calculates a single
profit forecast. Everybody knows the profit will not turn out to be
exactly equal to the forecast. But it is not clear what the range of
profits might be, or how likely a loss is. &amp;quot;Monte Carlo&amp;quot; analysis solves
this problem by allowing ranges or distributions on the assumptions; the
forecast is then a range of outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I’ll demonstrate how you can use pandas to analyse high-impact
business decisions, and dodge many of the problems of using
spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>