<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_christopher-johnson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Ecommerce in Python: Introduction to Satchmo and GetPaid (#146)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--ecommerce-in-python--introduction-to-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Moffitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--ecommerce-in-python--introduction-to-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ecommerce in Python: Introduction to Satchmo and GetPaid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Christopher Johnson (ifPeople); Chris Moffitt (Satchmo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of open source ecommerce is dominated by PHP-based solutions.
However, in the past few years, there has been significant progress in
building robust python-based alternatives. This discussion will cover 2
different python approaches. Satchmo is based on the Django framework
and GetPaid is a framework for credit card processing in Plone. These
solutions share a similar philosophy and approach but can be used in
very different ways. This discussion will increase awareness of these
applications, feature successful projects, explain how they can be used
in your projects, and help you connect with the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="satchmo"></category></entry><entry><title>Supercharging Web Communications: Integrating Python-based Apps with Salesforce.com CRM (#152)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--supercharging-web-communications--int.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Johnson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--supercharging-web-communications--int.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supercharging Web Communications: Integrating Python-based Apps with
Salesforce.com CRM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Christopher Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce.com is a leading provider of Customer Relationship Management
(CRM) for enterprises (over 55,000 customers) and nonprofits (over 6,000
customers). While it handles sales, marketing and support processes, it
can be extended to automate any business process, making it a core part
of business operations. Python developers working with companies using
salesforce.com need to be able to integrate applications with
Salesforce. Luckily, Salesforce.com has an elegant and powerful SOAP
API. This presentation will introduce an example of using the Python
wrapper for the Salesforce.com API (Beatbox) in an interactive website.
While the library itself is powerful and can be used in custom Python
applications, the Python community can also leverage the advanced
integration between the Plone Content Management System (CMS) and
salesforce.com. We will demonstrate how a Plone website can post forms,
ecommerce transactions, and event RSVPs to salesforce. Additionally, we
will show how developers can make Salesforce.com data interactive in a
Plone website.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="cms"></category><category term="crm"></category><category term="plone"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="web"></category></entry></feed>