<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MiG - A Complete Grid Middleware (mostly) in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/mig-a-complete-grid-middleware-mostly-in-pyth.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Jonas Bardino - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grid computing was all the buzz in the beginning of the millennium and
still has serious attention in different forms although many of the
original grand promises were never delivered. The general level of
ambitions have instead slowly but steadily degraded to those of the
latest buzz word, Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as a project have proven that most of the original promises &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;
actually be delivered and we have done so using Python almost solely as
the implementation language. The choice of Python provided us with a
stable and versatile base for quickly getting this far and it
significantly eases extending and maintaining our middleware in the
future. MiG is currently about 50000 lines of source code but it still
offers more features than competing grid systems with millions of lines
of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from introducing the open source MiG middleware and summarizing
how we got here, this talk will outline some of the core technologies
used to reach that goal and underline why it can make a lot of sense to
choose Python for complex HPC projects like MiG, too. Talk keywords
include Network Programming, Open Source Python projects, Science and
Math and Web-based Systems. There's no special intended audience, but a
certain level of Python knowledge and experience may be an advantage.
Please refer to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/migrid/"&gt;http://code.google.com/p/migrid/&lt;/a&gt; for further MiG
information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jonas Bardino</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/mig-a-complete-grid-middleware-mostly-in-pyth.html</guid><category>forms</category><category>hpc</category><category>network</category><category>science</category></item></channel></rss>