<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Eve - REST APIs for Humans</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-belarus-2018/the-eve-rest-apis-for-humans.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-02-24:pycon-belarus-2018/the-eve-rest-apis-for-humans.html</guid></item><item><title>My story with Python and Open Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/my-story-with-python-and-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how I went from lonely, introvert, C# developer to
open- source Python author and maintainer, speaker, trainer, consultant
and all- around community junkie. With some luck, in the process you
will also hear a few hints on how to become a good open source
contributor and have a chance to ponder on the pros and cons (yes, there
are cons too) of going full monty with open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/my-story-with-python-and-open-source.html</guid><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>My Story with Python and Open Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/my-story-with-python-and-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how I (and with me, my company) went from lonely,
introvert, C# developer to open-source Python author and maintainer,
speaker, trainer, consultant, and all-around community junkie. With some
luck, in the process, you will also hear a few hints on how to become a
good open source contributor and have a chance to ponder on the pros and
cons (yes there are cons too) of going full monty with open source. We
will also look at what changed in my company as we slowly switched from
closed, in-house eco-systems to the open source field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/my-story-with-python-and-open-source.html</guid></item><item><title>Python + Windows, like a boss</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-windows-like-a-boss.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically, Python coding on Windows has been kind of troublesome, but
not anymore. Since a couple of years ago it is possible write awesome
quality Python code with Visual Studio. This is good news for Python
developers of all levels, because Visual Studio offers and incredible
set of tools to enhance all the stages of product development: from
managing virtual environments and handling package management, to
writing and refactoring code, up to testing &amp;amp; debugging - all of that
for free. In this talk I will demo how you can use PTVS to boost your
Python development on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/python-windows-like-a-boss.html</guid><category>windows</category><category>Python</category><category>IDE</category></item><item><title>Panel: Microsoft Azure integration with Open Technologies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/panel-microsoft-azure-integration-with-open-technologies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La posizione di Microsoft verso tecnologie Open Source si basa su quattro pilastri:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abilitazione di numerosissime tecnologie Open Source sulla piattaforma Cloud di Microsoft, che prende il nome di Microsoft Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrazione nativa di diverse tecnologie Open Source con prodotti Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rilascio di diverse tecnologie Microsoft in modalità Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributo alla realizzazione di progetti Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racconto e dimostrazione della integrazione della piattaforma cloud di Microsoft con il mondo non-Microsoft&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/panel-microsoft-azure-integration-with-open-technologies.html</guid></item><item><title>Python on Windows, Like a Boss</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/python-on-windows-like-a-boss.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically, Python coding on Windows has been kind of troublesome,
but not anymore. Since a couple of years ago it is possible write
awesome quality Python code with Visual Studio. This is good news for
Python developers of all levels, because Visual Studio offers and
incredible set of tools to enhance all the stages of product
development: from managing virtual environments and handling package
management, to writing and refactoring code, up to testing &amp;amp;
debugging - all of that for free. In this talk I will demo how you
can use Visual Studio to boost your Python development on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-10:europython-2017/python-on-windows-like-a-boss.html</guid></item><item><title>Eve - REST API for Humans™</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/eve-rest-api-for-humanstm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have data stored somewhere and you want to expose it to your users through a RESTful Web API. Eve is the BSD-licensed, Flask-powered tool that allows you to quickly and easily go online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eve provides a robust, feature rich, REST-centered API implementation. MongoDB support comes out of the box, and community-driven efforts to deliver ElasticSearch and SQLAlchemy data layers are ongoing. Eve approach is such that you only need to configure your API settings and behaviour, plug in your datasource, and you're good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features such as Pagination, Sorting, Conditional Requests, Concurrency Control, Validation, HATEOAS, JSON and XML rendering, Projections, Customisable Endpoints are included. Advanced features such as custom Authentication and Authorization, Custom Validation, Embedded Resource Serialisation are also available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I will introduce the project and its community, recount why and how it's being developed, and show the current roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-24:pycon-italia-2014/eve-rest-api-for-humanstm.html</guid></item><item><title>Eve - REST API per Umani™</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/eve-rest-api-per-umanitm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hai dei dati salvati da qualche parte e desideri esporli ai tuoi utenti attraverso Web Service REST. Eve è una REST API open source basata su Flask che ti consente farlo rapidamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eve mette i principi REST al centro dell'attenzione, offrendo un ricco set di funzionalità integrate . L'approccio che Eve vuole di offrire è quello del plug &amp;amp; play: basta configurare la tua API, collegare la sorgente dati, e sei online. Paginazione, Ordinamenti, Richieste Condizionate, Gestione della Concorrenza, Validazione, HATEOAS, JSON e XML , Proiezioni, Endpoint Personalizzati sono tutte feature già incluse, così come funzionalità più avanzate quali Autenticazione ed Autorizzazione, Validazione Custom, Risorse Embedded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MongoDB ed ElasticSearch sono già supportati, e la community sta sviluppando ai layer SQLAlchemy, Titan ed altro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel corso del mio talk presenterò il progetto, la sua community e vi racconterò perché e come viene sviluppato. Infine vi anticiperò i nostri piani per il futuro.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-24:pycon-italia-2014/eve-rest-api-per-umanitm.html</guid></item><item><title>Convalida dei dati per essere umani</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2016/convalida-dei-dati-per-essere-umani.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-22:pycon-italia-2016/convalida-dei-dati-per-essere-umani.html</guid></item><item><title>Cerberus - Data Validation for Humans</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/cerberus-data-validation-for-humans.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicola Iarocci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon or later in their career, every programmer has to deal with data validation. Be it a web, desktop or mobile application, you just cannot avoid data validation. A robust, powerful yet easy-to-use data validation library can be a valuable tool in your toolset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cerberus is a lightweight and extensible open source data validation library for Python. It provides type checking and other validation, transformation and normalisation rules out of the box and it is designed to be easily extensible and customized. During Beta, which has been around since 2012, Cerberus has been serving as the core validation system for the Eve REST Framework and other open source projects. Just recently the project has hit version 1.0, with many new features and enhancements added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce the project, illustrate some real-life use cases, and show how easily it can be extended and customised to meet the most diverse needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-18:pycon-uk-2016/cerberus-data-validation-for-humans.html</guid></item><item><title>Eve - REST APIs for Humans™</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/eve-rest-apis-for-humanstm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powered by Flask, Redis, MongoDB and good intentions the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python-eve.org"&gt;Eve REST API
framework&lt;/a&gt; allows to effortlessly build and
deploy highly customizable, fully featured RESTful Web Services. The
talk will introduce the project and its community, recount why and how
it's being developed, and show the road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays everyone has data stored somewhere and needs to expose it
through a Web API, possibly a RESTful one.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python-eve.org"&gt;Eve&lt;/a&gt; is the BSD-licensed, Flask-powered
RESTful application and framework that allows to effortlessly build and
deploy highly customizable, fully freatured RESTful Web Services. Eve
features a robust, feature rich, REST-centered API implementation.
MongoDB support comes out of the box and community-driven efforts to
deliver ElasticSearch and SQLAlchemy data layers are ongoing. Eve
approach is such that you only need to configure your API settings and
behaviour, plug in your datasource, and you’re good to go. Features such
as Pagination, Sorting, Conditional Requests, Concurrency Control,
Validation, HATEOAS, JSON and XML rendering, Projections, Customisable
Endpoints, Rate Limiting are all included. Advanced features such as
custom Authentication and Authorisation, Custom Validation, Embedded
Resource Serialisation are also easily available. In my talk I will
introduce the project and its community, recount why and how it's being
developed, show the source code, illustrate key concepts and show the
road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-24:europython-2014/eve-rest-apis-for-humanstm.html</guid></item></channel></rss>