<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_david-kent.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python to drive Australian water availability forecasting</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2013/using-python-to-drive-australian-water-availabili.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Kent</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-07:pycon-au-2013/using-python-to-drive-australian-water-availabili.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Andrew MacDonald and Daehyok Shin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Australian Bureau of Meteorology provides water availability
forecasts to the public and to key stakeholders at different time-scales
across the nation. A number of the systems driving these forecasts make
extensive use of Python. Python is used throughout the forecasting
process - from data ingestion and management, to hydrological modelling
and data analysis through to graphical product generation. A wide
variety of packages are used heavily. These include NumPy, SciPy,
Matplotlib, PyTables and Pandas. Such a suite of scientific computing
packages for Python enables us to complete the development of fully
automated systems quickly even with limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will give an overview of the systems used by the
Bureau in the generation of water availability forecasts and highlight
the wide variety of tasks and processes enabled by Python. In
particular, we will introduce the Hydrologic Reference Stations (HRS)
toolkit and the Water Availability Forecasts for Australian Rivers
(WAFARi) system. The HRS toolkit analyses time-series of streamflow data
and produces a huge number of products describing mean state, trends and
variability in that data, which are released at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bom.gov.au/water/hrs"&gt;http://bom.gov.au/water/hrs&lt;/a&gt;. WAFARi is used to generate probabilistic
seasonal streamflow forecasts along with a suite of graphical products
for each of those forecasts. The system is being used to update
streamflow forecasts available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bom/gov.au/water/ssf"&gt;http://bom/gov.au/water/ssf&lt;/a&gt; every
month.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>