<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Niccolò «Veggero» Venerandi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_niccolo-veggero-venerandi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Write Any Python Program in One Line and Only Using Lambdas!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/write-any-python-program-in-one-line-and-only-using-lambdas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Niccolò «Veggero» Venerandi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/write-any-python-program-in-one-line-and-only-using-lambdas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write Any Python Program in One Line and Only Using Lambdas! - PyCon
Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any program can be written in just one statement and only using lambda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds weird? The first claim will bring us into what functional
programming is (+ map, functools…); the second one will dig into λ …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write Any Python Program in One Line and Only Using Lambdas! - PyCon
Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any program can be written in just one statement and only using lambda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds weird? The first claim will bring us into what functional
programming is (+ map, functools…); the second one will dig into λ
calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why? You will learn the power of λ and how to be concise: a better
pythonist! This talk will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursion! Recursion enables to write simple and concise python code.
We will bring many examples of recursion, how to make it fast with
memoizing and what tail call optimization is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutable vs Immutable objects! Since FP uses a completely immutable
approach, this might be the right time to learn about tuples,
frozendicts, and all immutable data structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher order functions! You can pass functions as arguments and
return them in functions. There are many functions in python that use
this feature: sort, min, max, map, filter etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functools! Functools is the standard python library containing many
useful functional tools. The library functions will be all explained
properly, such as partial and reduce, often used in FP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lambda calculus! λ calculus is the first functional language! In
fact, a λ calculus interpreter could be written using exclusively the
lambda statement (no loops, numbers, standard functions, libraries,
anything).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Niccolò «Veggero» Venerandi&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Italia 2022"></category><category term="functional programming"></category></entry></feed>