<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - James Wade</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Large Language Models in RStudio</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/large-language-models-in-rstudio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs), such as ChatGPT, have shown the potential to transform how we code. As an R package developer, I have contributed to the creation of two packages -- gptstudio and gpttools -- specifically designed to incorporate LLMs into R workflows within the RStudio environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration of ChatGPT allows users to efficiently add code comments, debug scripts, and address complex coding challenges directly from RStudio. With text embedding and semantic search, we can teach ChatGPT new tricks, resulting in more precise and context-aware responses. This talk will delve into hands-on examples to showcase the practical application of these models, as well as offer my perspective as a recent entrant into public package development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Wade</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/large-language-models-in-rstudio.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Posit Academy in the Age of Generative AI - Lessons from the Frontlines</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/posit-academy-in-the-age-of-generative-ai-lessons-from-the-frontlines.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of generative AI is fundamentally changing how we learn to code. At Dow, we've had nearly 200 learners participate in Posit Academy to learn R or Python and apply it to their work. As coders embrace these new tools, we are witnessing a &amp;quot;before and after&amp;quot; moment. This talk will share real-world examples of how researchers at Dow are learning by using code generation, highlighting the most effective tools including copilots and chat agents, to grapple with the challenges and opportunities of learning to code in this transformative era.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Wade</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/posit-academy-in-the-age-of-generative-ai-lessons-from-the-frontlines.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>