<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ravin-kumar.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Making data relevant to business. Its harder than you think!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/making-data-relevant-to-business-its-harder-than-you-think.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ravin Kumar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-04:pydata-la-2019/making-data-relevant-to-business-its-harder-than-you-think.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to use your data skills to empower an organization and influence
your companies strategy? Unfortunately its not as easy as just starting
a jupyter notebook and importing Tensorflow. Making your analysis change
hearts and minds take more than math and code, and is more challenging
than just the algorithm. In this talk I'll share tips of how to make
your data work resonate across your org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making data relevant to your company isn't just math and code. Business
skills are required as well. Many data folks, including myself in the
past, underestimate these &amp;quot;soft skills&amp;quot; and end up feeling frustrated
when your analyses don't have the recognition or impact that you expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll focus on the soft skills of data, and connect these
skills to &amp;quot;hard data&amp;quot;. These include topics such as , story telling,
coalition building, empathizing with stakeholders, making subjective
calls, and negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular I'll talk about my own failures and my most helpful
resources outside of the data &amp;quot;sphere&amp;quot; which have helped me pick up and
practice each of these topics. Ultimately by pairing these human skills
with your data skills you'll better be able to make your voice heard and
influence that change that you're looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Intro to Bayesian Model Evaluation, Visualization, &amp; Comparison Using ArviZ</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/intro-to-bayesian-model-evaluation-visualization-comparison-using-arviz.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Colin Carroll</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/intro-to-bayesian-model-evaluation-visualization-comparison-using-arviz.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we will build your expertise in handling, diagnosing, and understanding Bayesian models. It is intended for Bayesian modelers that know how to fit models, but desire further understanding on model criticism and visualization techniques. We will cover how to work with model data, how to evaluate model fit and how to communicate results. Attendees learn how to 1. Evaluate and visualize models 2. Understand plots commonly encountered in Bayesian contexts Bayesian modeling expertise is not required. Knowledge of python syntax and Numpy/Pandas are helpful to complete activities in this tutorial. Even without coding experience attendees may find value in learning how to interpret Bayesian model diagnoses and visualizations created by others.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing with Pytest for Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2018/testing-with-pytest-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ravin Kumar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-21:pydata-la-2018/testing-with-pytest-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unit Testing isn't just for traditional applications. Testing is useful
in data applications as well, from testing assumptions about the
underlying structure of information, to testing your knowledge of math
libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we'll showing you how to use pytest from scratch. By
the end you'll know enough to be able to use it in your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>