<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Hadley Wickham</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_hadley-wickham.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>It's a Great Time to be an R Package Developer!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/its-a-great-time-to-be-an-r-package-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jenny Bryan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/its-a-great-time-to-be-an-r-package-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Due to unforeseen circumstances, Hadley Wickham presented this talk &amp;quot;slide karaoke&amp;quot; style, from materials prepared by Jenny Bryan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In R, the fundamental unit of shareable code is the package. As of March 2023, there were over 19,000 packages available on CRAN. Hadley Wickham and I recently updated the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Due to unforeseen circumstances, Hadley Wickham presented this talk &amp;quot;slide karaoke&amp;quot; style, from materials prepared by Jenny Bryan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In R, the fundamental unit of shareable code is the package. As of March 2023, there were over 19,000 packages available on CRAN. Hadley Wickham and I recently updated the R Packages book for a second edition, which brought home just how much the package development landscape has changed in recent years (for the better!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I highlight recent-ish developments that I think have a great payoff for package maintainers. I'll talk about the impact of new services like GitHub Actions, new tools like pkgdown, and emerging shared practices, such as principles that are helpful when testing a package.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Updates from Posit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/updates-from-posit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hadley Wickham</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/updates-from-posit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;6:45 Hadley introduces the conference.
10:37 Hadley on Posit, PBC. Who are we, and what we do.
20:41 Charlotte Wickham on Quarto, an open-source scientific and technical publishing system.
31:05 George Stagg on webR, R for WebAssembly. Execute R code in your web browser.
43 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;6:45 Hadley introduces the conference.
10:37 Hadley on Posit, PBC. Who are we, and what we do.
20:41 Charlotte Wickham on Quarto, an open-source scientific and technical publishing system.
31:05 George Stagg on webR, R for WebAssembly. Execute R code in your web browser.
43:34 James Blair with the latest on Posit's partnerships with Databricks and Snowflake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our first Posit Conf 2024 keynote, where we’ll tell you about our mission, our products, and some of the exciting things we’ve been working on over the last year. Hadley Wickham, Chief Scientist, will talk briefly about Posit’s mission and products, before introducing the three speakers who will update you on some of the coolest projects we’ve worked on over the last year. James Blair, Senior Product Manager, will give you the latest on our partnerships with Databricks and Snowflake, and how we’re building seamless integrations that let you focus on data science instead of dealing with technical details. Charlotte Wickham, Developer Educator, will show you what’s new in Quarto, focusing on new ways to build beautiful PDFs with Typst. Finally, George Stagg, Senior Software Engineer, will tell you about the latest innovations in teaching using webR, a tool that lets you compile your R code into standalone HTML files.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>