<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>await kittens()</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2016/await-kittens.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee Symes
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kiwi.pycon.org/schedule/presentation/128/"&gt;https://kiwi.pycon.org/schedule/presentation/128/&lt;/a&gt;
This talk will work through getting pictures(of kittens and other cute things) off Flickr using &lt;cite&gt;asyncio&lt;/cite&gt; in Python 3.5. Showing how to build up from synchronous code to asynchronous code and how to make use of Python 3.5's new language features like &lt;cite&gt;async for&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;async with&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lee Symes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-11:kiwi-pycon-2016/await-kittens.html</guid></item><item><title>Why Python is awesome – and some other languages are cool too</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2015/why-python-is-awesome-and-some-other-languages.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Switching between many languages quickly clarifies each language's
strengths and weaknesses. My background is in Java – however more
recently I have moved onto using Python, JavaScript and PHP, whilst
dabbling in Go. My talk will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asynchronous programming, and the various ways it can be written in
code, with reference to JavaScript and Go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packaging, how some languages do it better and worse than Python, and
what Python can learn from them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit testing in all languages is hard, but the syntactic sugar that
is added can ease the pain, and make the output when your tests
inevitably fail easier to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax Shock, what brackets and semi-colons? Why are you not running
– oh yes I need a semi-colon there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cool stuff with Magic(al) methods and Duck Typing that languages like
Java would not have a hope of implementing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will highlight some of the delight I get when coming back to
Python; and some of the aspects of other languages that I think would be
really cool to add.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lee Symes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-05:kiwi-pycon-2015/why-python-is-awesome-and-some-other-languages.html</guid></item></channel></rss>