<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Joe Kaufeld</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>I Take Exception to Your Exceptions: Using Custom Errors to Get Your Point Across</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2023/i-take-exception-to-your-exceptions-using-custom-errors-to-get-your-point-across.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever used a library, ran into a generic AttributeError, and then had to go chase down what the problem _actually_ was? Wouldn't it be great to help others from running into that same issue on _your_ code? In this talk, we take a look at custom exceptions in Python and ways to structure your code to use them effectively to communicate issues back to the end user (or end developer). We'll also cover a few cool lesser-used things you can do with exceptions to make your code really stand out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joe Kaufeld</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-30:/north-bay-python-2023/i-take-exception-to-your-exceptions-using-custom-errors-to-get-your-point-across.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2023</category></item><item><title>The Tangled Web We Weave: Continuing Education Through Silly Projects</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2025/the-tangled-web-we-weave-continuing-education-through-silly-projects.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joe Kaufeld&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/VMJR8F"&gt;https://pretalx.northbaypython.org/nbpy-2025/talk/VMJR8F&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### Where'd that yellow schoolbus come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things we're told aren't worth building because experts have done them already. Cryptography? Let the experts handle it. Algorithms? Same. Web frameworks? Yep. As a professional web developer focusing on arcane uses of Django (and others) for arcane purposes, it occurred to me a little while ago that I didn’t actually know how a web framework worked. How does routing route? How does middleware work? How do variables in URLs work without regex? (Spoiler: they don't.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So... I wrote one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tangled Web We Weave is a love letter to learning and to doing things they tell you aren't worth your time. Come and get some inspiration on learning the answers to questions you don't know either... even if some folks say it's silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### What to expect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips on how to tackle giant problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three big takeaways learned while designing a WSGI web framework from the ground up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support and encouragement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### Who's this for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who's feeling like they need a push to learn something new, anyone who wants to know some weird facts about web frameworks, and anyone who wants to learn a little bit about the beautiful science of learning with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Apr 27 10:15:00 2025 at Reis River Ranch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub%5Fconfirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub%5Fconfirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joe Kaufeld</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-27:/north-bay-python-2025/the-tangled-web-we-weave-continuing-education-through-silly-projects.html</guid><category>North Bay Python 2025</category></item><item><title>Finding Practical Applications for Your Passion Projects</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2025/finding-practical-applications-for-your-passion-projects.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting from &amp;quot;I'm passionate about this topic&amp;quot; to actually working in
(or on) your dream is a wild leap. Lessons learned from traveling this
path the hard way, from finding the right niche for your passion project
to getting the right collaborators on board, can't be taught in a
classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the lessons formed over six years of growing an
international charity from two through to 6000 volunteers across the
globe. You'll learn tips on applying Python's ecosystem of third-party
tools to your project's aim, assembling a diverse team that can assess
the needs of a diverse world, and using Python-based tools to build your
dream project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joe Kaufeld</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-07-27:/pyohio-2025/finding-practical-applications-for-your-passion-projects.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2025</category></item></channel></rss>