<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Kat Scott</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Open Source Robotics with Python: Learn Robotics with No Robot Required</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/open-source-robotics-with-python-learn-robotics-with-no-robot-required.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you want to learn robotics but are unable to sink thousands of
dollars into a new hobby? Good news! It turns out that many professional
roboticists rarely touch hardware at all! Many modern robot developers
use simulations, basically fancy video games, to develop the source code
for their robots. This new approach to robotics means you too can start
learning robotics without ever touching an Allen wrench or a soldering
iron. More importantly, you can transfer your existing Python skills
into solving challenging robotics problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll walk you through getting started with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ros.org/"&gt;Robot
Operating System 2 (ROS 2)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gazebosim.org/home"&gt;Gazebo
simulator&lt;/a&gt;. ROS 2 and Gazebo are two
large, open-source projects used by thousands of companies, and tens of
thousands of developers, to build the robots we encounter in our daily
lives. Better yet, both ROS 2 and Gazebo support Python, making it
easier than ever to learn robotics fundamentals. In fact, ROS should be
very familiar, it draws much of a project structure from Python itself.
Just like the Python 2 to Python 3 transition. ROS and Gazebo have seen
some major changes in the past few years; and now is a good time for
Python developers to revisit these important tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll introduce you to ROS 2 and Gazebo using existing open
source libraries and robots. We’ll touch on how to get started, the
Python APIs for both projects, and some of the fiddly bits in between
(like CLIs, and other file types) that make robotics simulation
possible. This talk is geared towards novice to intermediate programmers
who are ready to branch out and start applying programming fundamentals
to the domain of robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kat Scott</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-19:/pycon-us-2024/open-source-robotics-with-python-learn-robotics-with-no-robot-required.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>