<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Gil Forsyth</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ibis: A fast, flexible, and portable tool for data analytics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ibis-a-fast-flexible-and-portable-tool-for-data-analytics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ibis provides a common dataframe-like interface to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without ever having to learn SQL. No more pains rewriting pandas code to something else when you run into performance issues; write your code once using Ibis and run it on any supported backend. In this tutorial users will get experience writing queries using Ibis on a number of local and remote database engines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gil Forsyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ibis-a-fast-flexible-and-portable-tool-for-data-analytics.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Ibis: Because SQL is everywhere but you don't want to use it</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-but-you-dont-want-to-use-it.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, come and learn about Ibis! It offers a dataframe-like interface to construct concise and composable queries and then executes them against a wide variety of backends (Postgres, DuckDB, Spark, Snowflake, BigQuery, you name it.).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gil Forsyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-but-you-dont-want-to-use-it.html</guid><category>EuroSciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Introduction to Ibis: blazing fast analytics with DuckDB, Polars, Snowflake, and more, from the comfort of your Python repl.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/introduction-to-ibis-blazing-fast-analytics-with-duckdb-polars-snowflake-and-more-from-the-comfort-of-your-python-repl.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tabular data is ubiquitous, and pandas has been the de facto tool in
Python for analyzing it. However, as data size scales, analysis using
pandas may become untenable. Luckily, modern analytical databases (like
DuckDB) are able to analyze this same tabular data, but perform
orders-of-magnitude faster than pandas, all while using less memory.
Many of these systems only provide a SQL interface though; something far
different from pandas’ dataframe interface, requiring a rewrite of your
analysis code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Ibis comes in. Ibis provides a common dataframe interface
to many popular databases and analytics tools (BigQuery, Snowflake,
Spark, DuckDB, …). This lets users analyze data using the same
consistent API, regardless of which backend they’re using, and without
ever having to learn SQL (but you can use SQL if you want to!). No more
pains rewriting pandas code to something else when you run into
performance issues; write your code once using Ibis and run it on any
supported backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we’ll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basic operations of Ibis (&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;select&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;filter&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;group_by&lt;/tt&gt;,
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;order_by&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;join&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;aggregate&lt;/tt&gt;), and how these operations
may be composed to form more complicated queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Ibis may be used on a number of different local and remote
backend engines to execute the same queries on different systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tradeoffs of different database engines, and recommendations for
how to choose the best tool for the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Ibis integrates into the larger Python data ecosystem, including
tools like Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, PyArrow, pandas, Altair, and
VegaFusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hands-on tutorial, with numerous examples to get your hands
dirty. Participants should ideally have some experience using Python and
pandas, but no SQL experience is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gil Forsyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-15:/pycon-us-2024/introduction-to-ibis-blazing-fast-analytics-with-duckdb-polars-snowflake-and-more-from-the-comfort-of-your-python-repl.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>Numba - Tell Those C++ Bullies to Get Lost</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/numba-tell-those-c-bullies-to-get-lost.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you spent hours fighting with SWIG? Are you mystified by complicated NumPy array operations that you wrote only 2 months ago? Come and learn how to accelerate your existing Python code by an order (or orders!) of magnitude using Numba. You'll learn about using just-in-time compilation, writing custom NumPy ufuncs (the easy way!), and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire tutorial is presented as a series of Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gil Forsyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-11:/scipy-2017/numba-tell-those-c-bullies-to-get-lost.html</guid><category>SciPy 2017</category></item><item><title>SciPy Tools Plenary Day 3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy is a community dedicated to the advancement of scientific computing through open source Python software for mathematics, science, and engineering. The annual SciPy Conference allows participants from all types of organizations to showcase their latest projects, learn from skilled users and developers, and collaborate on code development. SciPy is organized by NumFOCUS, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that promotes open source scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juan Nunez-Iglesias</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-10:/scipy-2023/scipy-tools-plenary-day-3.html</guid><category>SciPy 2023</category></item><item><title>Ibis: because SQL is everywhere and so is Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-and-so-is-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tabular data is ubiquitous, and pandas has been the de facto tool in Python for analyzing it. However, as data size scales, analysis using pandas may become untenable. Luckily, modern analytical databases (like DuckDB) are able to analyze this same tabular data, but perform orders-of-magnitude faster than pandas, all while using less memory. Many of these systems only provide a SQL interface though; something far different from pandas’ dataframe interface, requiring a rewrite of your analysis code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will lay out the current database / data landscape as it relates to the SciPy stack, and explore how Ibis (an open-source, pure Python, dataframe interface library) can help decouple interfaces from engines, to improve both performance and portability. We'll examine other solutions for interacting with SQL from Python and discuss some of their strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gil Forsyth</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/ibis-because-sql-is-everywhere-and-so-is-python.html</guid><category>SciPy 2024</category></item></channel></rss>