<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rebeca-sarai.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Jane Doe will help you improve your project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/jane-doe-will-help-you-improve-your-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rebeca Sarai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-05:pygotham-2019/jane-doe-will-help-you-improve-your-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On days of privacy scandals, the concern about securing customers' data is
bigger than ever, and the solution is farther from locking everything in a
safe box. Sharing data is inevitable, in this talk we will approach the data
anonymity problem, exploring how to use anonymization techniques to secure
users personal information when analyzing, testing, processing, or sharing a
database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers’ data is important. The number of privacy laws in recent years has
grown from 20 to 100, to name a few: PCI compliance in the payment industry,
the European GDPR regulation, and the Brazilian LGPD. All these new
regulations attempt to bridge an old gap: data anonymity. How to handle data
and protect the individuals comprised in it? Companies often face lawsuits
to compensate for personal information breaches in their database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code must be tested. In classic development workflow, many times production
data is copied onto test, QA or staging environments, only to be followed by
exposure to the eyes of testers, receivers, or unauthorized developers on
machines less protected than production environments. It is not seldom for
files also to be shared with external partners, who often require but a
small part of the data transferred, and granting access to user’s data might
be a breach. If in one hand sharing data is both necessary and inevitable,
on the other technologies that assure the privacy of individuals details are
no longer only desirable, but essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Jane Doe is a person without a name that is able to perform actions even
though without any recollection of personal information. We will use this
principle to approach two important areas in software development: how to
streamline when testing complex systems and how to manage data whilst
securing users’ personal information. We will create a boilerplate project
to expose different techniques of anonymization and pseudonymization,
showing that solving the anonymity problem is much more complex than
replacing names, last names, and social security numbers - and all of that
avoiding bottlenecking Django projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A worked example of using statistical and machine learning models to time series prediction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/a-worked-example-of-using-statistical-and-machine-learning-models-to-time-series-prediction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rebeca Sarai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-05:pygotham-2018/a-worked-example-of-using-statistical-and-machine-learning-models-to-time-series-prediction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When making strategic decisions under uncertainty, we all make forecasts. In situations where time and money are directly related especially. The analysis of time series data can be essential in achieving good results, it being a fundamental part within and outside of the field of computer science. In fact, time series are everywhere. They surround the unspoken mysteries of our existence, from forecasting the amount of rain that pours onto a river per year, to the big stock markets, to weekly company sales, just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation discusses the tradeoff between statistical models and neural network-based techniques, the later receiving a lot of attention in the data science community in the past few years. This talk also demonstrates how to apply them to a real problem: How to forecast a high-risk asset, which price can unpredictably increase or decrease over a short period of time, that can also be influenced by a wide range of factors. In other words, what’s gonna be the bitcoin's price? Lastly, this piece compares the advantages and disadvantages of these methods. What will attendees learn: This talk aims to demonstrate that we can apply complex machine-learning knowledge to our daily routine. Not just to forecast Bitcoin, but anything else that looks too complicated or out of reach. It also demonstrates how to use techniques of machine learning and python libraries to build a prediction model.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Previsão de séries temporais com PyData e Inteligência Artificial</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2017/previsao-de-series-temporais-com-pydata-e-inteligencia-artificial.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rebeca Sarai</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-06:python-brasil-2017/previsao-de-series-temporais-com-pydata-e-inteligencia-artificial.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>