<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sagar Aryal</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sagar-aryal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>In-house to open source: Stitching the past to the future with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/in-house-to-open-source-stitching-the-past-to-the-future-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nandita Viswanath</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/in-house-to-open-source-stitching-the-past-to-the-future-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever had to deal with old code that is filled with thousands of repetitive code blocks and too many if statements? It gets harder when the original authors aren't around to explain what they were thinking. These pain points related to legacy software are often the motivation for many …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever had to deal with old code that is filled with thousands of repetitive code blocks and too many if statements? It gets harder when the original authors aren't around to explain what they were thinking. These pain points related to legacy software are often the motivation for many organizations to adopt robust open source solutions. Open source software is becoming more and more the standard in any tech stack. Knowing how to navigate the world of open source software and how to best implement it is a skill that is becoming ever more important for any software engineer. Python is one of the most popular languages when it comes to open source. In this talk, we hope to outline why this is and how you can take advantage of it in your software migrations.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2022"></category></entry></feed>