<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modern Continuous Delivery for Python Developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/modern-continuous-delivery-for-python-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deployment automation, cloud platforms, containerization, short
iterations to develop and release software—we’ve progressed a lot. And
finally it’s official: Kubernetes and OpenShift are the established
platforms to help us do scaling and zero downtime deployments with just
a few hundred lines of YAML. It’s a great time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we finally put all our eggs into one basket? Identify the cloud
platform that fits our needs, and jump on it? That could well backfire:
Vendor lock-in is the new waterfall, it slows you down. In future you’ll
want to jump over to the next better platform, in a matter of minutes.
Not months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about The Art of Writing deployment pipelines that will
survive Kubernetes, OpenShift and the like. It’s for Python developers
and Kubernetes enthusiasts of all levels – no domain specific knowledge
required, all you need to understand will be explained. You’ll learn how
to separate application-specific and deployment-specific configuration
details, to maximize your freedom and avoid vendor lock-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come see a demo of a Django project setup that covers everything from
local development to automatic scaling, flexible enough to be deployed
on any of your favorite container platforms. Take home a working,
future-proof setup for your Python applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Bittner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/modern-continuous-delivery-for-python-developers.html</guid><category>Agile</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>Deployment/Continuous Integration and Delivery</category></item><item><title>Continuous Delivery starts at your Development Environment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/continuous-delivery-starts-at-your-development-environment.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery is the automation of our deployment and QA, isn’t
it? The industrialized software production chain that solves all our
problems. Well, kind of. It’s more than that. Because: You still have
pain when …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You bring new developers on board (e.g. for installing Docker and
friends, IDEs and command line tools).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your development machine behaves weird or needs an upgrade. (Can you
simply re-install it and continue working without losing a day or a
week of productivity?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to explain to your colleagues, or even convince them, how to
configure which of their tools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone turns to you (or your admin wizard) when there are troubles
to get some tools or projects running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks explains how to bootstrap a super-efficient startup, SMB, or
just any development team that needs a development infrastructure.
You’ll see a demo of The Foreman, Puppet, Ansible and optionally FreeIPA
and virtualization technology, which gets you from zero to 100 in just a
few hours. This talk explains how you do infrastructure like software
development. Everything under control. Everything under version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join the show, and take home the recipe that tells you how to step
up the next level of Continuous Delivery! - If you’re a beginner fear
not: this talk starts with an introduction to CI/CD and brings you up to
speed quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 22 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Bittner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/continuous-delivery-starts-at-your-development-environment.html</guid><category>infrastructure</category><category>continuous-delivery</category><category>agile</category><category>ansible</category><category>puppet</category><category>free-software</category><category>FreeIPA</category><category>infrastructure-as-code</category></item><item><title>L'Italia, Python e la chimera dell'Agile</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/litalia-python-e-la-chimera-dellagile.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sono quasi certo che il proverbio “tra il dire e il fare c’è di mezzo
il mare” lo abbiano inventato pensando alle metodologie agili. Forse
in USA o in Svezia ci riescono davvero, ma in Italia? Possiamo dire
di essere agili quando di test ne facciamo “ un po’ “, i task degli
sprint li decide il cliente e il contratto prevede un budget fissato
e una deadline prestabilita? E com’è la situazione tra i pythonisti?
Ne parliamo con Marco Beri, Iacopo Spalletti, Roberto Bettazzoni e
Peter Bittner in un panel dove siete tutti invitati a partecipare e
condividere casi di successo e scheletri nell’armadio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iacopo Spalletti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/litalia-python-e-la-chimera-dellagile.html</guid></item><item><title>Continuous Delivery for Python Developers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/continuous-delivery-for-python-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery sounds easy in theory, but it’s hard to do in
practice. There are myriads of things you can and should do to get your
code delivered faster, reliably. We look at what we can do as Python
developers, or as a small or mid-sized team to make the industrialized
software development production chain come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Continuous Delivery?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should we do it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We explain a hands-on process and show tools and platforms that can
be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may have time to try the demonstrated tools and setups in a hands-on
demo. Bring your own notebook and get an immediate feeling of CD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Bittner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/continuous-delivery-for-python-developers.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning talks - Monday</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-monday.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks covering painless.cloud &amp;amp; SCSS&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Bittner</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/lightning-talks-monday.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Progetti a prezzo fisso e l'Agile</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2016/progetti-a-prezzo-fisso-e-lagile.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Peter Bittner</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-12:pycon-italia-2016/progetti-a-prezzo-fisso-e-lagile.html</guid></item></channel></rss>