<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - David Woods</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fast native data structures: C/C++ from Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/fast-native-data-structures-cc-from-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast native data structures: C/C++ from Python
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Stefan Behnel, David Woods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has very fast and thoroughly optimised data structures: lists, dicts, sets and the collections module make it easy to write simple code that performs well. The flip-side shows when it comes to processing very large amounts of simple data, especially numbers or strings. For these, the object overhead of Python's objects is very large in comparison to the low-level languages C and C++ that benefit directly from bare metal CPU performance as well as from GIL-free multi-threading and parallel computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will show how compiling your Python code with Cython (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cython.org/"&gt;https://cython.org/&lt;/a&gt;) enables you to make direct use of fast and memory efficient native data types and data structures. Cython provides very efficient ways to access the internals of Python data structures, process data from NumPy arrays, and use data structures from native C libraries or the C++ STL standard library as replacements for the high-level Python collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will learn how you can implement high-level Python interfaces that enable fast data processing underneath, without sacrificing the integration with regular Python features and libraries to allow for easy direct data manipulation from Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Behnel</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/fast-native-data-structures-cc-from-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2021</category></item><item><title>Cython and the Limited API</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/cython-and-the-limited-api.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cython and the Limited API by David Woods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/cython-and-the-limited-api"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/cython-and-the-limited-api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cython's Limited API support is finally approaching a usable state. As an example, it is possible to produce a working version of Cython by compiling it in Limited API mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For users the main advantage is to be able to reduce the number of wheels/binaries they have to build in order to be compatible across a range of versions of Python. For Cython itself there is also an advantage in future-proofing: being able to produce simpler code that should continue to work even as the Python interpreter evolves and which is more likely to work with alternative Python implementations, as well as hopefully placating the unease some of the core Python developers have at Cython's use of Python internals (in non-limited API mode).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will start off by looking at the subject from the users' perspective:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why you might want to use the Limited API (from Cython).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of projects are likely to benefit from it (as far as it's ever possible to predict how people will use a tool...).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What you actually need to do to build a Cython module with the Limited API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What the limitations and disadvantages are: there are some features that don't work, some features that only work in recent versions of Python, some speed costs, and complete forward-compatibility might not be all you hope it would be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that &amp;quot;general interest&amp;quot; section is done, I plan to talk about some of the gory implementation details - what &amp;quot;creative&amp;quot; solutions have been employed to work around missing features or things the Limited API was never intended to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Woods</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/cython-and-the-limited-api.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>