<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Elizabeth Johnson</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Skynet 101 How to Keep Your Machine Learning Code From Getting Away From You</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/skynet-101-how-to-keep-your-machine-learning-code-from-getting-away-from-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine&amp;nbsp;learning can feel pretty mysterious at times, but as python
developers you have so many of the tools you need to be a part of it!
With basic python experience you can use libraries like pandas and tools
like Jupyter Notebooks to analyze and manipulate data sets. By apply
Test-Driven Development practices to you analysis you can feel confident
about what your building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can build well developed and well tested cleaning scripts and
functions using pytest and use these functions in your notebooks and
scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even build simple recommendation engines using libraries such as
Scikit Learn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a part of this talk we will walk through the process of data
analysis, data cleaning, feature preparation, and building a simple
movie recommendation engine.&amp;nbsp; As we move through those steps, my main
focus is to teach engineers how they can incorporate Test-Driven
Development into the data cleaning process and the building of our
engine.&amp;nbsp; I will also walk through strategies for data analysis and
explain at a high level a couple ML concepts that we can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As participants get the chance to see live examples of how to use Test
Driven Development in data analysis and machine learning they can get a
handle on some core concepts and learn how to ensure quality in the code
that they produce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elizabeth Johnson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-23:/pycon-us-2023/skynet-101-how-to-keep-your-machine-learning-code-from-getting-away-from-you.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>