<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_edward-schofield.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>What's New in Python for Science and Engineering</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2012/whats-new-in-python-for-science-and-engineering.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Schofield</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-08-21:pycon-au-2012/whats-new-in-python-for-science-and-engineering.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a tutorial about using Python for scientific and engineering
purposes, focusing on the latest and best tools available in 2012. It
will walk you through exploring a variety of interesting domains and
problems using the latest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a presentation about the latest and most exciting tools in
Python for scientific and engineering applications in 2012. It will walk
you through what's now possible with tools like the IPython Notebook,
the Pandas toolkit for data analysis, and IPython integration with
SymPy, R, and Cython. It will then give you an update on the status of
Python 3 ports of major packages. It will show why Python is an
outstanding tool for science and engineering work, and getting better.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>Modern scientific computing and big data analytics in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2013/modern-scientific-computing-and-big-data-analytic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Schofield</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-07:pycon-au-2013/modern-scientific-computing-and-big-data-analytic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a tutorial on using the latest and most exciting tools in Python
for scientific and engineering applications in 2013, with a focus on
'big data' applications. Using real-world data sets and a fully Python 3
environment, it will walk you through what's possible with modern tools
like the machine-learning package scikit-learn, the image-processing
package scikit-image, the Pandas toolkit for data analysis, and
IPython-parallel. It will also review the upcoming generation of tools
like Numba and Blaze.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How (not) to upgrade a platform by Edward Schofield</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/how-not-to-upgrade-a-platform-by-edward-schofie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Schofield</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-07:pycon-au-2014/how-not-to-upgrade-a-platform-by-edward-schofie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guido admitted in his PyCon 2014 keynote that he will never again
conduct a language transition like that from Python 2 to Python 3. The
vast majority of Python code written in 2014 is still a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;SyntaxError&lt;/tt&gt;
on the latest version of Python. Some people have been wondering: will
Python 3 ever take off?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have done some data mining from PyPI to reveal what progress the
community has made so far toward migrating the long tail of packages
towards Python 3 and which packages are most critical in the dependency
graph of unported packages. We extrapolate from current growth rates
about when (if ever) Python 3 support will reach a tipping point after
which more new code will be written in Python 3 than Python 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then share our perspective on mistakes made in the Python 3
transition and lessons that we can all learn from. The lessons apply to
migrating any interface -- a language, a codebase, or a web API.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive visualization for the curious</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/interactive-visualization-for-the-curious.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Schofield</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/interactive-visualization-for-the-curious.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The workhorse plotting tool in Python for most of this century has been
Matplotlib. It is stable, powerful, and comprehensive. But the plots it
produces are (mostly) lifeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web is now emerging as a superior visualization platform to
traditional GUI backends, thanks to SVG, HTML5 Canvas, and WebGL, the
speed and quality of modern browsers, and an explosion of high-quality
visualization libraries in JavaScript. But what is the Python developer
to do? Can we drive these browser-based capabilities from Python?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, several recent Python projects are making progress toward
this goal -- including MPLd3, Bokeh, and VisPy. These each have
different goals and make different design decisions, but all three offer
obvious advantages: being able to publish visualizations that users can
interact with to extract more meaning from data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give shiny demos and review these newer projects
thoroughly vis-a-vis other libraries to help you decide whether, or
when, to adopt one of them as your go-to visualization library. We will
answer these questions: How does the performance compare? Would you need
to rewrite all your plotting code? What would it take to integrate Bokeh
or VisPy well with the current ecosystem of Python plotting libraries
and data analysis tools? What is on the horizon for the different
projects? Where do the Jupyter project's interactive widgets fit into
this picture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to hear a critical review about the past, present, and future of
interactive visualization in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>