<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Florian Angerer</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HPy: The Future of Python Native Extensions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/hpy-the-future-of-python-native-extensions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Forum Hall on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/hpy-the-future-of-python-native-extensions"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/hpy-the-future-of-python-native-extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updating Python versions often forces us to update native extensions at the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;same time. But what if you need to update Python because of a security issue,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but cannot (yet) move to a newer version of a dependency? Or you are running a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;proprietary binary extension that cannot easily be recompiled?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HPy project provides a better C extension API for Python. It compiles to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;binaries that work across all versions of CPython, PyPy, GraalPy. HPy makes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;porting from the existing C API easy and its design ensures that the binaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we produce today stay binary compatible with future Python versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumPy is the single largest direct user of the CPython C API we know of. After&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;over 2 years of work and more than 30k lines of code ported, we can demonstrate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumPy running its tests and benchmarks with HPy. We will show the same NumPy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;binary run on multiple CPython versions and GraalPy. And we will discuss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;performance characteristics of this port across CPython, GraalPy, and PyPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Štěpán Šindelář</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/hpy-the-future-of-python-native-extensions.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2023</category></item></channel></rss>