<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>2FA Mind</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2017/2fa-mind.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;2-Factor Authentication (2FA) empowers people to better protect their online accounts. With daily revelations of mass data breaches, habitual use of 2FA has become vital for anyone whose accounts have access to private or confidential information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the vast majority of ordinary people still aren't using it! There are myths that 2FA is difficult to set up and use, or is only needed by high profile people who are personally targeted. Often users hold back because they perceive 2FA as difficult, complicated, or stressful. Already put off by ever-more-convoluted rules for picking a password, many people expect setting up 2FA to be even more daunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great news is, we can fix this! Newer 2FA methods are making logging in quicker, simpler, and far more secure for users. Meanwhile, 2FA libraries have become widely available in Python and other major programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kick off wider adoption of 2FA, we need a fresh mindset about it. Because in fact there's little that’s novel about 2FA. Each of us already has had years of everyday experience with the core concepts and mindset that are 2FA's foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we can build momentum for broad access to the security wins of 2FA. In this session, you'll discover the simple concepts at the heart of 2FA. You’ll learn about some common 2FA implementation approaches, and you’ll come away with a list of actions any of us—no matter what skill level—can take right now to help make the world a safer place for at least one vulnerable person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carina C Zona</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-12-03:north-bay-python-2017/2fa-mind.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Consequences of an Insightful Algorithm</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2015/consequences-of-an-insightful-algorithm-by-carina.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consequences of an Insightful Algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have ethical responsibilities when coding. We’re able to extract
remarkably precise intuitions about an individual. But do we have a
right to know what they didn’t consent to share, even when they
willingly shared the data that leads us there? A major retailer’s
data-driven marketing accidentially revealed to a teen’s family that she
was pregnant. Eek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are our obligations to people who did not expect themselves to be
so intimately known without sharing directly? How do we mitigate against
unintended outcomes? For instance, an activity tracker carelessly
revealed users’ sexual activity data to search engines. A social
network’s algorithm accidentally triggered painful memories for grieving
families who’d recently experienced death of their child and other loved
ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We design software for humans. Balancing human needs and business specs
can be tough. It’s crucial that we learn how to build in systematic
empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll delve into specific examples of uncritical
programming, and painful results from using insightful data in ways that
were benignly intended. You’ll learn ways we can integrate practices for
examining how our code might harm individuals. We’ll look at how to flip
the paradigm, netting consequences that can be better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HIYS/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HIYS/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carina C. Zona</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-24:djangocon-us-2015/consequences-of-an-insightful-algorithm-by-carina.html</guid></item><item><title>Schemas for the Real World</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2013/schemas-for-the-real-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social app development challenges us to code for users’ personal world.
Users are giving push-back to ill-fitted assumptions about their own
identity — name, gender, sexual orientation, important relationships,
and many other attributes that are individually meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we balance users’ realities with an app’s business requirements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook, Google+, and others are struggling with these questions.
Resilient approaches arise from an app’s own foundation. Discover how
our earliest choices influence codebase, UX, and development itself.
Learn how we can use that knowledge to both inspire the people who use
our apps, and to generate the data that need as developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carina C. Zona</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-06:pycon-au-2013/schemas-for-the-real-world.html</guid></item><item><title>Keynote: Consequences of an Insightful Algorithm</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/keynote-consequences-of-an-insightful-algorithm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have ethical responsibilities when coding. We’re able to extract
remarkably precise intuitions about an individual. But do we have a
right to know what they didn’t consent to share, even when they
willingly shared the data that leads us there? A major retailer’s
data-driven marketing accidentally revealed to a teen’s family that she
was pregnant. Eek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are our obligations to people who did not expect themselves to be
so intimately known without sharing directly? How do we mitigate against
unintended outcomes? For instance, an activity tracker carelessly
revealed users’ sexual activity data to search engines. A social
network’s algorithm accidentally triggered painful memories for grieving
families who’d recently experienced death of their child and other loved
ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We design software for humans. Balancing human needs and business specs
can be tough. It’s crucial that we learn how to build in systematic
empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll delve into specific examples of uncritical
programming, and painful results from using insightful data in ways that
were benignly intended. You’ll learn ways we can integrate practices for
examining how our code might harm individuals. We’ll look at how to flip
the paradigm, netting consequences that can be better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carina C. Zona</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:pycon-au-2015/keynote-consequences-of-an-insightful-algorithm.html</guid></item><item><title>Schemas for the Real World</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/schemas-for-the-real-world-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Development challenges us to code for users’ personal world. Users give
push-back to ill-fitted assumptions about their own name, gender, sexual
orientation, important relationships, &amp;amp; other attributes that are
individually meaningful. We'll explore how to develop software that
brings real world into focus &amp;amp; that allows individuals to authentically
reflect their personhood &amp;amp; physical world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carina C. Zona</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-12:pycon-us-2015/schemas-for-the-real-world-0.html</guid></item></channel></rss>