<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Jeong Ho-jin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jeong-ho-jin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Introduction to Poetry in Deep Learning Development Dependency Management in Testing and Model Packaging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/introduction-to-poetry-in-deep-learning-development-dependency-management-in-testing-and-model-packaging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeong Ho-jin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/introduction-to-poetry-in-deep-learning-development-dependency-management-in-testing-and-model-packaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will introduce a case where I introduced Poetry, a Python dependency management tool, to solve problems in a deep learning development environment while working as an MLOps engineer at Corca. I will explain the difficulties of testing due to the nature of deep learning and the dependency problems …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will introduce a case where I introduced Poetry, a Python dependency management tool, to solve problems in a deep learning development environment while working as an MLOps engineer at Corca. I will explain the difficulties of testing due to the nature of deep learning and the dependency problems that occurred during the checkpoint packaging process, and I will tell you what effects you can achieve through Poetry. I hope that this session will be helpful to many deep learning developers as well as developers who want to effectively manage dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hojin Jeong
I am Hojin Jeong, a researcher and developer. I am on a journey to become someone who makes research from theory and actual products from research.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2023"></category></entry></feed>