<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ryan-petrello.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Distributed Tasks with Celery</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--distributed-tasks-with-celery.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Petrello</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--distributed-tasks-with-celery.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distributed Tasks with Celery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Ryan Petrello&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celery is an open source task queueing system based on distributed
message passing, especially using the AMQP protocol. This talk will
focus on the need for task distribution, the tools celery provides to
meet those needs, and an in-depth discussion of how we've used celery at
ShootQ to improve the efficiency and reliability of our background
processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk (including time for questions) will last approximately 30
minutes and will focus on the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for distributed tasks in real world systems, especially in a
web application environment. This portion of the talk will describe
examples where the traditional request-response model of the web can
be improved with background processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A brief overview of traditional distributed message passing models
and the AMPQ protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of Celery and the variety of tools it provides for task
distribution, scheduling, and execution. This portion of the talk
will also review production-oriented components of Celery, such as
monitoring, error detection/reporting, and error recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real world discussion of several problems we solved at ShootQ using
Celery including before-and-after looks at our implementations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common pitfalls and gotchas we encountered while working with Celery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="amqp"></category><category term="celery"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="queueing"></category></entry></feed>