<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_omer-yuksel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Understanding exchange network dynamics with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2019/understanding-exchange-network-dynamics-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Omer Yuksel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:pydata-london-2019/understanding-exchange-network-dynamics-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk covers a use-case for Python ecosystem at IMC for modelling and understanding trade network dynamics, and predicting the results of the changes we introduce. Approaching the problem from different angles, it will include examples of supervised learning, probabilistic models and discrete-event simulations using modules such as scikit-learn, pymc3, and simpy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Measuring the hay in the haystack: quantifying hidden variables using Bayesian Inference</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/measuring-the-hay-in-the-haystack-quantifying-hidden-variables-using-bayesian-inference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Omer Yuksel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/measuring-the-hay-in-the-haystack-quantifying-hidden-variables-using-bayesian-inference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology-driven trading is a field with many challenges, and
performance and availability of the network communication is essential
to the business. To have a good understanding on the performance and
availability, we monitor certain metrics - however not every interesting
metric is readily available to measure. Some of these have to be
inferred from the data we see in production by incorporating our own
knowledge. What complicates this further is that the relationship
between the hidden variables and the output data is not a deterministic
one, as we are often dealing with a stochastic system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayesian inference is a suitable way to tackle this issue - it allows
encoding our knowledge as a prior distribution of the model parameters.
Here we will go through real-world uses of Bayesian inference at IMC,
using PyMC3 to make an estimate for the hidden metrics in the network
traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge: No prior knowledge of PyMC3 is required. Since this is a
short presentation, the talk with approach the problem and the solution
at a high level instead of implementation details.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Networks"></category></entry><entry><title>We Have Our Ways: Extracting and Analyzing Online Confessions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-paris-2016/we-have-our-ways-extracting-and-analyzing-online-confessions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Omer Yuksel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-14:pydata-paris-2016/we-have-our-ways-extracting-and-analyzing-online-confessions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We Have Our Ways: Extracting and Analyzing Online Confessions, by Omer Yuksel&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>