<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Choi Hong-jun Lee Seung-jae</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_choi-hong-jun-lee-seung-jae.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python in Mobile Networks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2022/python-in-mobile-networks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Choi Hong-jun Lee Seung-jae</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-02:/pycon-korea-2022/python-in-mobile-networks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile network supporting many services 365/24. Unlike other sites, telecommunication companies have the difficulty of stably performing large-scale work on numerous types of equipment. While working as a network engineer for several years, I personally conducted research and PoC such as global case analysis and feasibility review to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile network supporting many services 365/24. Unlike other sites, telecommunication companies have the difficulty of stably performing large-scale work on numerous types of equipment. While working as a network engineer for several years, I personally conducted research and PoC such as global case analysis and feasibility review to fundamentally improve this difficulty. I would like to share with those who are interested in introducing the contents of operational efficiency from the perspective of a network operator. Due to external restrictions during the presentation, I excluded detailed contents and parts unrelated to Python, so I ask for your understanding. This presentation will be briefly explained in the following three points. I will briefly explain the characteristics related to telecommunication company infrastructure operation, why Python is recommended to network engineers, my personal thoughts on candidates for Python frameworks related to network automation, and a comparison summary of each Python framework. Finally, I will present an example of how Python was utilized, and then present the concerns I had while proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Korea 2022"></category><category term="DevOps"></category></entry></feed>