<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Andrew Holz</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_andrew-holz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Oops I'm a Manager - On More Effective 1-on-1 Meetings</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/oops-im-a-manager-on-more-effective-1-on-1-meetings.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Holz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/oops-im-a-manager-on-more-effective-1-on-1-meetings.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a team leader (accidental or not), it's easy to get caught up in the daily grind and overlook the importance of 1-on-1s. Bad idea. 1-on-1s are critical for building trust, providing feedback, and ensuring that everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keys to good 1-on-1s start with a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a team leader (accidental or not), it's easy to get caught up in the daily grind and overlook the importance of 1-on-1s. Bad idea. 1-on-1s are critical for building trust, providing feedback, and ensuring that everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keys to good 1-on-1s start with a small amount of prep and a running shared document of notes and takeaways. Another key is to rotate types of 1-on-1s. Possibilities include &amp;quot;heads down&amp;quot; on recent work, &amp;quot;heads up&amp;quot; looking further out, and career-focused sessions. After some tips on the right sort of questions and uncovering sneaky issues, I will also touch on effective feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share resources and hope to include Seussian visuals and a few poetic lines to help the key points stick.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Oops I'm A Manager - Finding your Minimal Viable Process</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/oops-im-a-manager-finding-your-minimal-viable-process.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Holz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/oops-im-a-manager-finding-your-minimal-viable-process.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In today's fast-paced, data-driven landscape, transitioning to a leadership role can be daunting. This talk is designed for emerging data team leaders, offering insights into striking the right balance between a clear effective process and the flexibility required for team members to do their best work. It emphasizes the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In today's fast-paced, data-driven landscape, transitioning to a leadership role can be daunting. This talk is designed for emerging data team leaders, offering insights into striking the right balance between a clear effective process and the flexibility required for team members to do their best work. It emphasizes the importance of iterative process design, establishing effective feedback loops, and empowering team members with autonomy. These key strategies are put into action as team habits provide a blueprint for an adaptable workflow relevant to a range of different organizations. The talk aims to create a framework where both efficiency and creativity can thrive together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>