<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Yuliia Barabash</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_yuliia-barabash.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Is it me or Python memory management?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yuliia Barabash</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me or Python memory management? by Yuliia Barabash, Laysa Uchoa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered if Python memory management is playing tricks on you? Starting small, everything runs smoothly. But as your application scales, complexity grows …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me or Python memory management? by Yuliia Barabash, Laysa Uchoa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/is-it-me-or-python-memory-management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered if Python memory management is playing tricks on you? Starting small, everything runs smoothly. But as your application scales, complexity grows, and memory issues rear their head. You ask yourself, &amp;quot;Is it me or Python memory management?&amp;quot;In this talk, we'll show you how Python memory works, provide tools to analyze memory usage and share practical optimization tips. Whether you're a seasoned Python developer or just starting on your Python journey, this talk is designed to provide you with techniques to overcome Python memory management challenges and write more efficient, memory-conscious code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Exploring OpenSearch, Python, and Serverless: Crafting Efficient and Modern Search Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2023/exploring-opensearch-python-and-serverless-crafting-efficient-and-modern-search-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Laysa Uchoa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-12-16:/pyohio-2023/exploring-opensearch-python-and-serverless-crafting-efficient-and-modern-search-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenSearch, a community-driven, open-source project, offers a robust
alternative for search and analytics needs. When coupled with Python's
flexibility and the efficiency of serverless architecture, it transforms
into a dynamic trio that empowers developers to create efficient and
modern search applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on a journey as we explore …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenSearch, a community-driven, open-source project, offers a robust
alternative for search and analytics needs. When coupled with Python's
flexibility and the efficiency of serverless architecture, it transforms
into a dynamic trio that empowers developers to create efficient and
modern search applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on a journey as we explore the synergy between OpenSearch,
Python, and serverless architecture. In this talk, we'll provide an
overview of OpenSearch and demonstrate how to utilize Python with
serverless architecture to power your search engine. Additionally, we
will delve into best practices and challenges that arise when employing
this combination in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk, you'll gain a clear understanding of how to
architect, build, and deploy efficient search applications using
OpenSearch, Python, and serverless architecture. Whether you're a
developer aiming to enhance your search capabilities or an architect
exploring modern search solutions, this talk will equip you with the
tools and insights needed to embrace this exciting synergy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyOhio 2023"></category></entry></feed>