<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Evaluation of text analysis in social media a linguistic approach</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2018/evaluation-of-text-analysis-in-social-media-a-linguistic-approach.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The analysis of text data is gaining more and more importance every day. The need for companies to know what people think and want is key to invest money in providing customers what they want. The first approach to text analysis was statistical but adding linguistic information has been proven to work well for improving the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems that you need to address when analyzing social media is time. People are constantly exchanging information, users write comments every day about what they think of a product, what they do or the places they visit. It is difficult to keep track of everything that happens. Moreover, information is sometimes expressed in short sentences, keywords, or isolated ideas, such as in Tweets. Language is usually unstructured because it is composed of isolated ideas, or without context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will talk about the problem of opinion in opinion mining: how do we define opinion. I will also explain briefly how Naïve Bayes classifiers can be useful in sentiment analysis and I will use an example to show how linguistic information can help improve the trainings. I will also evaluate the results and compare them to the results of training without any linguistic information (i.e. supervised vs unsupervised learning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also explain about opinion lexicons, both dictionary based and corpus-based, and about using lexicons for semi-supervised learning and supervised learning. If I have time left, I will explain about other use cases of text analysis, such as spam detection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eulàlia Veny</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-06:pycon-es-2018/evaluation-of-text-analysis-in-social-media-a-linguistic-approach.html</guid></item><item><title>Recipe for text analysis in social media:</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/recipe-for-text-analysis-in-social-media.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The analysis of text data in social media is gaining more and more
importance every day. The need for companies to know what people think
and want is key to invest money in providing customers what they want.
The first approach to text analysis was mainly statistical, but adding
linguistic information has been proven to work well for improving the
results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems that you need to address when analyzing social media
is time. People are constantly exchanging information, users write
comments every day about what they think of a product, what they do or
the places they visit. It is difficult to keep track of everything that
happens. Moreover, information is sometimes expressed in short
sentences, keywords, or isolated ideas, such as in Tweets. Language is
usually unstructured because it is composed of isolated ideas, or
without context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will talk about the problem of text analysis in social media. I will
also explain briefly Naïve Bayes classifiers, and how you can easily
take advantage of them to analyse sentiment in social media, and I will
use an example to show how linguistic information can help improve the
results. I will also evaluate the pros and cons of supervised vs
unsupervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will introduce opinion lexicons, both dictionary based and
corpus- based, and how lexicons can be used in semi-supervised learning
and supervised learning. If I have time left, I will explain about other
use cases of text analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eulalia Veny</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/recipe-for-text-analysis-in-social-media.html</guid></item></channel></rss>