<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_valdemar-svabensky.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>From (Python) zero to hero: How beginner university students learn programming</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2016/from-python-zero-to-hero-how-beginner-university-students-learn-programming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valdemar Švábenský</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-29:pycon-cz-2016/from-python-zero-to-hero-how-beginner-university-students-learn-programming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you curious about how to teach programming effectively? Are you a
Python fan interested in everything Python-related? Or would you
simply like to see a non-standard presentation? If you answered yes
at least once, then this funny and inspiring talk is right for you!
In less than 20 minutes, you'll hear from a young student-teacher
about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What coding skills are taught to beginners and how&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with teaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few surprises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No technical knowledge is needed (some code samples will be shown,
but they're not essential). Discussion at the end is welcome. Looking
forward to seeing you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Make learning great again: It's the how, not what</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/make-learning-great-again-its-the-how-not-what.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valdemar Švábenský</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-11:pycon-sk-2017/make-learning-great-again-its-the-how-not-what.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you curious about how to teach programming effectively? Are you a Python fan interested in everything Python-related? Or would you simply like to see a non-standard presentation? If you answered yes at least once, then this funny and inspiring talk is right for you! In around 20 minutes, you'll hear from a young student-teacher about:
- What coding skills are taught to beginners and how
- Experience with teaching
- A few surprises
No technical knowledge is needed (some code samples will be shown, but they're not essential). Discussion at the end is very welcome. Looking forward to seeing you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>