<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ivana Kellyerova</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ivana-kellyerova.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>import bacon 🥓</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/import-bacon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivana Kellyerova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:/europython-2019/import-bacon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often said that Python comes with batteries included, meaning that
the standard library can do basically anything except for maybe conjure
bacon for you (though I heard that's coming in 3.8). I don't think we
fully appreciate the sheer vastness of it, though, so I went through …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often said that Python comes with batteries included, meaning that
the standard library can do basically anything except for maybe conjure
bacon for you (though I heard that's coming in 3.8). I don't think we
fully appreciate the sheer vastness of it, though, so I went through it
module by module looking for hidden gems (sorry, eggs). This is a by no
means exhaustive compilation of the useful, the underrated, and the
funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the Python standard library, chances are you use it on
a daily basis -- or more likely, a more or less stable subset of it. The
usual way we add things to the subset is by looking for a solution to a
problem and ending up getting pointed to a standard library module.
That, however, means that the odds of you finding out that there is a
whole module whose sole purpose is to tell you if a string is a Python
keyword are very slim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this talk is to showcase CPython libraries that are
interesting in some way: mostly for their usefulness, but in some cases
simply for being wonderfully weird in some way. The talk is not aimed at
any particular level of Python experience - as a beginner you'll get a
taste of just how many batteries Python ships with, and as a person
using the language often you might end up growing your own personal
subset a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2019"></category><category term="CPython"></category><category term="Python general"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Avoid Becoming a 10x Engineer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/how-to-avoid-becoming-a-10x-engineer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivana Kellyerova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/how-to-avoid-becoming-a-10x-engineer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why you should ignore advice by random internet people, by a random internet person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has never failed at being, among other things, a giant treasure of unsolicited advice by random people on all sorts of things, programming being no exception. Wanna become a better coder? Learn to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why you should ignore advice by random internet people, by a random internet person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has never failed at being, among other things, a giant treasure of unsolicited advice by random people on all sorts of things, programming being no exception. Wanna become a better coder? Learn to maximize your WPM (c). Never look at documentation because that's just embarrassing. And for crying out loud, change your screen background to black!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you are, a fairly okay programmer, looking for ways to become better at coding. How do you achieve that? Well I'm no 10x engineer myself (thank goodness), but I do believe that there's a handful of things we can safely rule out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category></entry></feed>