<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reinforcement Learning: Pac-Man</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-la-2019/reinforcement-learning-pac-man.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop serves as an introduction to reinforcement learning where
the participants will implement a Pac-Man agent. The Pac-Man agent will
learn how to solve different maps using Q-learning and Deep Q-learning.
We start out by exploring Q-learning, before diving into deep
Q-learning, which utilizes neural networks. Jupyter notebook and GPUs
will be used to aid us in our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, reinforcement learning (RL) has achieved
promising results and it is currently being explored in a wide range of
fields. In areas such as self driving cars, gaming and medicine, RL is
the frontier of state- of-the-art results. In this workshop we will
explore what the fuss is all about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop serves as an introduction to reinforcement learning where
the participants will implement a Pac-Man agent. The Pac-Man agent will
learn how to solve different maps using Q-learning and Deep Q-learning.
We start out by exploring Q-learning, a cornerstone in RL. Expanding
further, we continue on to deep Q-learning, which utilizes neural
networks. The code is executed in the cloud on Jupyter notebooks, and
for training the neural networks we use GPUs in the cloud. Everything is
written in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prior knowledge of reinforcement learning is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If reinforcement learning has been a mysterious domain to you, this
session will most likely leave you with a greater understanding of the
process and aid you in how to set up projects of your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional preparation for the tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The tutorial will be much like a walkthrough, so it is quite fine to
just follow along without programming yourself. If you do, however,
want to interact with the actual code, it is recommended that you
clone the project and set up the Python environment beforehand. While
most of the tutorial will be in Jupyter Notebook, some setup is also
required on local machines. Since we only have 1.5 hours, we will not
have time to help individual participants setting up the project
during the actual tutorial, but if you do face issues you can send us
an email ahead of the tutorial. We will be happy to help!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Project repository: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/knowit/ml-pacman"&gt;https://github.com/knowit/ml-pacman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Manu: &lt;a class="reference external" href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Malte: &lt;a class="reference external" href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Manu Gopinathan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-03:pydata-la-2019/reinforcement-learning-pac-man.html</guid></item></channel></rss>