<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mandar Deshpande</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Boosting Python Numeric Computations with Dynamic C++ Integration</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2024/boosting-python-numeric-computations-with-dynamic-c-integration.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uncover the secrets to turbocharging your Python numeric computations by
harnessing the dynamic performance of &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;C++&lt;/tt&gt;. This talk is aimed at the
beginner-intermediate Python developer working in the ML/AI infra or
performance optimization space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how the growing usage of the numeric computation
stack, including libraries like numpy, scipy, and scikit-learn, along
with deep learning libraries such as pytorch and tensorflow, are shaping
the future of AI and Machine Learning? And what about the intriguing
fact that these libraries are built on wrappers for the underlying C++
code? Have you considered the benefits this brings, or how the
optimization of these libraries as per the host device - be it CPU, GPU,
or Apple Silicon - enhances performance and efficiency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, let's consider the practical applications and real-world
examples of this integration between Python and C++. What are the
challenges and solutions in bridging the gap between Python and C++ in
the context of AI and Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observing the growing trends at my workplace over the past few years, I
am sure this process is going to be standardised soon with more
developers being involved in such integrations/optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk aims to get the Python community excited for this growing
trend by sharing:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. reasoning&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. Integration framework/paths specifically for pybind&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mandar Deshpande</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-27:/pyohio-2024/boosting-python-numeric-computations-with-dynamic-c-integration.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2024</category></item></channel></rss>