<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Brandon Butler</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_brandon-butler.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>HOOMD-blue: A High Performance Scalable Particle Simulation Python Library</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2020/hoomd-blue-a-high-performance-scalable-particle-simulation-python-library.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brandon Butler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-08:/scipy-2020/hoomd-blue-a-high-performance-scalable-particle-simulation-python-library.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="SciPy 2020"></category></entry><entry><title>signac: Data Management and Workflows for Computational Researchers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2021/signac-data-management-and-workflows-for-computational-researchers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bradley Dice</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-12:/scipy-2021/signac-data-management-and-workflows-for-computational-researchers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The signac data management framework (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://signac.io"&gt;https://signac.io&lt;/a&gt;) helps researchers execute reproducible computational studies, scaling from laptops to supercomputers and emphasizing portability and fast prototyping. With signac, users can track, search, and archive data and metadata for file-based workflows and automate workflow submission on high performance computing (HPC) clusters …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The signac data management framework (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://signac.io"&gt;https://signac.io&lt;/a&gt;) helps researchers execute reproducible computational studies, scaling from laptops to supercomputers and emphasizing portability and fast prototyping. With signac, users can track, search, and archive data and metadata for file-based workflows and automate workflow submission on high performance computing (HPC) clusters. We will discuss recent growth in the software's feature set, scalability, scientific applications, usability, and community. Newly implemented synced data structures, workflow subgraph execution, and performance optimizations will be covered, as well as recent research using the framework and the project's efforts on improving documentation, contributor onboarding, and governance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2021"></category></entry></feed>