<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Shauheen Zahirazami</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_shauheen-zahirazami.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>PyTorch Support by Google Enabling Performance from Cloud to Edge</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/pytorch-support-by-google-enabling-performance-from-cloud-to-edge.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Sherwood</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/pytorch-support-by-google-enabling-performance-from-cloud-to-edge.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session we will cover various ways teams at google are working to help the Pytorch community achieve performance and scale from cloud to edge. We will cover how Google Cloud customers can use PyTorch and OpenXLA to get competitive performance for their ML workloads.  We’ll also …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this session we will cover various ways teams at google are working to help the Pytorch community achieve performance and scale from cloud to edge. We will cover how Google Cloud customers can use PyTorch and OpenXLA to get competitive performance for their ML workloads.  We’ll also cover how Google AI Edge Torch works with Pytorch to help developers integrate LLMs, vision models and more to easily create new edge applications that can run on a wide set of devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>ML.NET in Python with NimbusML</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/mlnet-in-python-with-nimbusml.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matteo Interlandi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/scipy-2019/mlnet-in-python-with-nimbusml.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ML.NET is an open source, cross-platform, machine learning framework for .NET developers. ML.NET was originally developed in Microsoft Research and is now used across many products in Microsoft such as Windows, Bing, and PowerPoint. This talk introduces NimbusML, which brings the ML.NET library to Python. With …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ML.NET is an open source, cross-platform, machine learning framework for .NET developers. ML.NET was originally developed in Microsoft Research and is now used across many products in Microsoft such as Windows, Bing, and PowerPoint. This talk introduces NimbusML, which brings the ML.NET library to Python. With NimbusML, developers familiar with the Scikit-learn API can start to take advantage of ML.NET performance just with few simple changes to their Scikit pipeline. The talk will also cover differentiators, such as NimbusML support for streaming datasets that don’t fit in memory, and featurizers/algorithms not easily available elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2019"></category></entry></feed>