<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Regina Lionheart</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_regina-lionheart.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Making Waves with R, Python, and Quarto</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/making-waves-with-r-python-and-quarto.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Regina Lionheart</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/making-waves-with-r-python-and-quarto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wave models are powerful tools for understanding coastal erosion, but analyzing their outputs poses challenges. Proprietary formats produce inaccessible data that require manual extraction. Final results must also be approachable to a diverse audience of engineers, governments, and coastal communities. In 2022, a project was proposed to investigate how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wave models are powerful tools for understanding coastal erosion, but analyzing their outputs poses challenges. Proprietary formats produce inaccessible data that require manual extraction. Final results must also be approachable to a diverse audience of engineers, governments, and coastal communities. In 2022, a project was proposed to investigate how a restored beach could respond to waves while mitigating erosion and protecting a cultural resource. Using R and Python wrapped in Quarto, wave model outputs were fully scripted to create a single reproducible document flexible enough to answer multiple modeling questions. As coasts change, rapid modeling and analysis may help preserve coastal access for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>