<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Introduction to User Experience Design</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2014/introduction-to-user-experience-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While User Experience Design (UXD) may seem like another buzzword, it
actually has deep roots in usability, visual design, information
architecture, and many other areas that developers and the like may
already be familiar with. UXD is not just another process, but instead a
way of thinking and collaborating that should not be overlooked for cost
or time reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As companies continue to put more pressure on their employees to do more
with less, decision makers, product managers and developers are looking
for ways to solve problems quickly, while still getting high value for
the company and their customers. With changing technologies, strategies
and markets, and a constant push for employees to wear multiple hats and
work more collaboratively, having an amazing user experience is becoming
a &amp;quot;must have&amp;quot; for companies that want to remain competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers, product managers and decision makers who are new to UXD and
curious to learn more will walk away with a clear definition of User
Experience Design, a knowledge of its goals and the basic components
that make up a UX project, such as: User Research, UI Design, Front End
Development, and Content Strategy. Attendees will also walk away with
examples of how UXD can add value to a project for both the business and
the users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meghan Reilly</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-14:djangocon-europe-2014/introduction-to-user-experience-design.html</guid></item></channel></rss>