<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Alon Nir</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alon-nir.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Sliding into Causal Inference, with Python!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/sliding-into-causal-inference-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alon Nir</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/sliding-into-causal-inference-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sliding into Causal Inference, with Python!
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alon Nir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would the world look like if Russia won the cold war? If the Boston Tea Party never happened? And where would we be if Guido van Rossum had decided to go …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sliding into Causal Inference, with Python!
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alon Nir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would the world look like if Russia won the cold war? If the Boston Tea Party never happened? And where would we be if Guido van Rossum had decided to go to music school? Unfortunately we don't have the technology to slide into parallel worlds and explore alternative histories. However it turns out we do have the tools to simulate parallel realities and give decent answers to intriguing 'what if' questions. This talk will provide a gentle introduction to these tools, professionally known as Causal Inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is aimed at data practitioners, preferably with basic knowledge of Python and statistics. That said, the focus of the talk is to nurture an intuitive understanding of the subject first, and implementation second. By the end of the talk I hope audience members could identify causal inference problems, have an intuitive understanding of the different tools they can apply to these problems, and have the appetite to further their learning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover the problem of answering causal questions (The Fundamental Problem of Causal Inference) and the main tools to address it. The emphasis will be on intuitive understanding how the different tools work, rather than pesky underlying assumptions, complex notation or convoluted literature. Just enough theory and lines of code to get the message across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline:
- Introduction to parallel universes and &amp;quot;what if?&amp;quot; questions?
- The golden standard for causal inference.  We'll discuss randomised controlled experiments and also set the scene for cases these aren't possible. [6 mins]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three key tools:
- Differences-in-Differences
- Propensity score methods
- Synthetic Controls (or: creating an alternate universe on your machine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's next:
A wrap up that includes:
- What we didn't cover (a few words about other techniques, DAGs, etc.)
- Quick overview of Python tools for causal inference
- Where do we go from here - resources, curriculums, readings and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides and code: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alonnir/EuroPython-2021-Talk"&gt;https://github.com/alonnir/EuroPython-2021-Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting an Edge with Network Analysis with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/getting-an-edge-with-network-analysis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alon Nir</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-15:/pycon-uk-2018/getting-an-edge-with-network-analysis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Networks are all around us. While Facebook and Twitter are the obvious
examples, every time we shake hands, drive from point A to B, push code
to GitHub, check out a meetup or rate a show on IMDB, we’re
participating in network activity. People, places, things and even …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Networks are all around us. While Facebook and Twitter are the obvious
examples, every time we shake hands, drive from point A to B, push code
to GitHub, check out a meetup or rate a show on IMDB, we’re
participating in network activity. People, places, things and even ideas
are inter-connected in innumerable networks, and these can have a great
(yet sometimes inconspicuous) impact on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to introduce members of the audience to
network analysis and its importance, and give them the basic building
blocks for applied network analysis with Python (using the friendly
NetworkX library). I hope this talk will encourage audience members to
consider network analysis approaches in their line of work/research and
intrigue them to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will weave theory and practice, discussing topics in graph
theory as we’re seeing them in practice during hands on analysis of a
real-life network. Topics covered include: types of graphs (undirected,
directed, multi and bipartite), structures in graphs (triangles,
cliques, connected components), node importance (centrality measures,
PageRank), graph topology and high-level graph descriptions. Practical
applications of these topics will be emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the limited time compared to the breadth of the topic, the focus
would lean towards intuitive understanding of concepts and seeing them
in practice, over deep theoretical formulations and hardcore
mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be given from a data scientist’s perspective with touches
of social sciences flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon UK 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>3 Lessons Data Scientists Can Learn from World War II</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2023/3-lessons-data-scientists-can-learn-from-world-war-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alon Nir</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-24:/pycon-uk-2023/3-lessons-data-scientists-can-learn-from-world-war-ii.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ll revisit three stories from WWII where statisticians for the Allied forces got things perfectly right - and terribly wrong. We'll explore the flaws of averages, survivorship bias, and the German tanks problem. Drawing parallels to modern business situations, we'll discuss the takeaways for modern day data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ll revisit three stories from WWII where statisticians for the Allied forces got things perfectly right - and terribly wrong. We'll explore the flaws of averages, survivorship bias, and the German tanks problem. Drawing parallels to modern business situations, we'll discuss the takeaways for modern day data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World War II, the largest armed conflict in human history, not only required unfathomable firepower but also unprecedented brain power. Data scientists - or statisticians as they were called back in the day - worked tirelessly to advance military technology and produce indispensable intelligence reports. Eighty years on, the lessons they learned remain relevant and are important for anyone doing data science or analysis at present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll visit three stories from WWII and discuss how the lessons learned then apply for modern day business settings. We’ll explore:
- How the flaw of averages made the scientifically optimised cockpit to be a perfect fit for no-one.
- How survivorship bias impacted the armour placed on bomber planes.
- How the need to assess the monthly rate of German tank production bred a simple solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the talk we’ll discuss how learnings from these stories can be used in a business environment, working through business use-cases with real (looking) data and some basic Python manipulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the talk was prepared with data scientists and analysts in mind, anyone with a curious mind may find it worthwhile. Basic familiarity of Python is helpful but not required. By the end of this talk audience members will be familiar with several common pitfalls in data science and equipped to handle business problems in a more mature and well-rounded way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon UK 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting an Edge with Network Analysis with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/getting-an-edge-with-network-analysis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alon Nir</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/getting-an-edge-with-network-analysis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Networks are all around us. While Facebook and Twitter are the obvious examples, every time we shake hands, drive from point A to B, push code to github, check out a meetup or rate a show on IMDB, we’re participating in network activity. People, places, things and even …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Networks are all around us. While Facebook and Twitter are the obvious examples, every time we shake hands, drive from point A to B, push code to github, check out a meetup or rate a show on IMDB, we’re participating in network activity. People, places, things and even ideas are inter-connected in innumerable networks, and these can have a great (yet sometimes inconspicuous) impact on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to introduce members of the audience to network analysis and its importance, and give them the basic building blocks for applied network analysis with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alonnir/PyCon-Us-2021-Talk/"&gt;https://github.com/alonnir/PyCon-Us-2021-Talk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks - Part 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Omer Sagi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-02-16:/pydata-meetups/lightning-talks-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="5%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="18%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="77%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;00:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Omer Sagi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sugar cane yield Prediction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Amit Aronovitch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quick visualization tool for Analysis of Shadows cast by (actual physical) Clouds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;22:02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Feather format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;28:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gidi Shperber&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Modern recommendation engine in python with LightFM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;37:29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alon Nir&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pandas tips and …&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="5%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="18%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="77%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;00:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Omer Sagi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sugar cane yield Prediction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Amit Aronovitch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quick visualization tool for Analysis of Shadows cast by (actual physical) Clouds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;22:02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Feather format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;28:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gidi Shperber&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Modern recommendation engine in python with LightFM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;37:29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alon Nir&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pandas tips and tricks (Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alonnir/PyData-TLV-Talk"&gt;https://github.com/alonnir/PyData-TLV-Talk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Meetups"></category><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry></feed>