<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Activity Detection from GPS Tracker Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/activity-detection-from-gps-tracker-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data gathered by personal GPS trackers are becoming a major source of
information pertaining to human activity and behaviour. This
presentation will include python work flows which aim to accurately and
efficiently carry out the necessary computation required to process
volunteered GPS trajectories into useful spatial information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most modern GPS processing techniques started to utilise the time
interval between points as a major indicator for finding POIs in a
user's trajectories. We are taking step back in this process, and only
account for the spatial distribution of measured points in order to
extract POIs. Time is solely used as a secondary indicator and for
ordering purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points are first cleaned of any highly inaccurate data and stored in a
PostGIS environment. Using developed python module, we extract the point
data and order them by time into one large trajectory. Then, for each
point, we begin selecting its neighbours (both previous and following)
until we reach one within a specified distance of 50m from the first
point.The number of the selected points is added to the original point
as a new attribute.Continuing with the process the newly calculated
values create an imitation of signal, reflecting a point density.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shift in strength of the signal signifies a change in a user's travel
mode which can be used for segmentation of the trajectory into
homogeneous parts. Identification of these parts is currently based on
the decision tree, where individual aspects of the segment (like average
speed, signal strength, time elapsed or centroid) are evaluated and the
segment is categorized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current work seeks to incorporate neural networks into the processing
framework. Since the signal pattern of the each mode of transportation
(car, bus, walk, etc.) is independent from the user behaviour, a
properly trained model should classify more accurately activities for a
broad range of users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jan Vandrol</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/activity-detection-from-gps-tracker-data.html</guid></item></channel></rss>