<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Eric Lagally</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_eric-lagally.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Navigating the AI Labyrinth in Higher Education (Sponsor: Western Governors University)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/navigating-the-ai-labyrinth-in-higher-education-sponsor-western-governors-university.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jared Plumb</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/navigating-the-ai-labyrinth-in-higher-education-sponsor-western-governors-university.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rapid evolution of Artificial Intelligence (AI) presents unique
challenges and opportunities for higher education. This presentation
explores the intricate journey of teaching AI within a landscape where
its definition and applications are continually expanding. As AI
technology advances, academic institutions must adapt to teach a subject
that is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rapid evolution of Artificial Intelligence (AI) presents unique
challenges and opportunities for higher education. This presentation
explores the intricate journey of teaching AI within a landscape where
its definition and applications are continually expanding. As AI
technology advances, academic institutions must adapt to teach a subject
that is inherently multifaceted and ever-changing. The session, led by
professionals from Western Governors University, an institution renowned
for its online and competency-based education model, will delve into the
complexities of integrating AI education in higher education. We'll
examine the varied interpretations of AI across disciplines, discuss the
regulatory challenges universities face in managing AI usage, and share
insights on fostering an adaptable AI curriculum that prepares students
for a future where AI's role is both transformative and omnipresent.
This discussion aims to spark dialogue on effective strategies for
navigating the AI labyrinth in higher education, ensuring that students
are not only proficient in current AI technologies but also prepared for
the ethical and practical challenges of tomorrow's AI innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>