<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nicholas Ursa</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nicholas-ursa.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to bootstrap a Data Warehouse with DuckDB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/how-to-bootstrap-a-data-warehouse-with-duckdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guen Prawiroatmodjo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/how-to-bootstrap-a-data-warehouse-with-duckdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Data Warehouse (DW) is a powerful tool to manage your scientific data, training data, logs, or any other type of relational data. Most Data Warehouses are cloud-based and built to scale to petabyte workflows, but might not be optimal for smaller workloads that need a fast iteration cycle …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Data Warehouse (DW) is a powerful tool to manage your scientific data, training data, logs, or any other type of relational data. Most Data Warehouses are cloud-based and built to scale to petabyte workflows, but might not be optimal for smaller workloads that need a fast iteration cycle. Likewise, a collection of CSV files and python scripts can become painful to share and maintain. This is where DuckDB comes in! DuckDB is a fast, in-process database that you can run on your laptop, supports a rich SQL dialect, and you can push to the cloud with just a single line of code. In this talk, we’ll show you how to bootstrap a Data Warehouse on your laptop using open source, including ETL (extract-transform-load) data pipelines, dashboard visualization, and sharing via the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>