<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_yaman-guclu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PSYDAC: a parallel finite element solver with automatic code generation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/psydac-a-parallel-finite-element-solver-with-automatic-code-generation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yaman Güçlü</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/psydac-a-parallel-finite-element-solver-with-automatic-code-generation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PSYDAC is a Python 3 library for the solution of partial differential
equations. Its current focus is on isogeometric analysis using B-spline
finite elements, but extensions to other methodologies are under
consideration. In order to use PSYDAC, the user defines geometry and
model equations in an abstract form using SymPDE, an extension of Sympy
that provides the mathematical expressions and checks their semantic
validity. Once a finite element discretization has been chosen, PSYDAC
maps the abstract concepts into concrete objects, the basic building
blocks being MPI-distributed vectors and matrices. Python code is
generated for all the computationally intensive operations (matrix and
vector assembly, matrix-vector products, etc.), and it is accelerated
using either Numba, Pythran, or Pyccel. We present the library design,
the user interface, and the performance results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSYDAC takes input from SymPDE (a SymPy extension for partial
differential equations), applies a finite-element discretization,
generates MPI-parallel code, and accelerates it with Numba, Pythran, or
Pyccel. We present design, usage and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>