<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Django as a Micro-Framework: Hacking on the HTTP handlers..</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2019/using-django-as-a-micro-framework-hacking-on-the-http-handlers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon 2019 - Using Django as a Micro-Framework: Hacking on the HTTP handlers and middleware (for fun and profit) by Carlton Gibson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django, being batteries included and all, is meant to big, clumsy, slow. I'm going to show you how use it as a micro-framework.
I'll show you how the base HTTP layer works, and what those middleware things are all about. I'll show you how to customize that so that Django can keep up with anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2019.djangocon.us/talks/using-django-as-a-micro-framework-on-the/"&gt;https://2019.djangocon.us/talks/using-django-as-a-micro-framework-on-the/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LINKS:
Follow Carlton Gibson 👇
On Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/carltongibson"&gt;https://twitter.com/carltongibson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow DjangCon US 👇
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/djangocon"&gt;https://twitter.com/djangocon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow DEFNA 👇
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/defnado"&gt;https://twitter.com/defnado&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.defna.org/"&gt;https://www.defna.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intro music: &amp;quot;This Is How We Quirk It&amp;quot; by Avocado Junkie.
Video production by Confreaks TV.
Captions by White Coat Captioning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlton Gibson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-25:djangocon-us-2019/using-django-as-a-micro-framework-hacking-on-the-http-handlers.html</guid></item><item><title>Your Web Framework Needs You: An Update</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2019/your-web-framework-needs-you-an-update.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon 2019 - Your Web Framework Needs You: An Update by Carlton Gibson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2019.djangocon.us/talk/framework-update-carlton-gibson/"&gt;https://2019.djangocon.us/talk/framework-update-carlton-gibson/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LINKS:
Follow Carlton Gibson 👇
On Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/carltongibson"&gt;https://twitter.com/carltongibson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow DjangCon US 👇
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/djangocon"&gt;https://twitter.com/djangocon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow DEFNA 👇
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/defnado"&gt;https://twitter.com/defnado&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.defna.org/"&gt;https://www.defna.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intro music: &amp;quot;This Is How We Quirk It&amp;quot; by Avocado Junkie.
Video production by Confreaks TV.
Captions by White Coat Captioning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlton Gibson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-24:djangocon-us-2019/your-web-framework-needs-you-an-update.html</guid></item><item><title>Feeding the Pony: Contributing back to Django &amp; How to make that work for you</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2019/feeding-the-pony-contributing-back-to-django-how-to-make-that-work-for-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django’s life-blood is its contributors. This talk is about how we enable more contributors from across the community, how they (You!) can get involved, and how you can make sure that it helps your career.
Django looks like it’s doing just fine: it’s a popular framework in a popular language. We have major releases every six months. We have Django Girls, a Foundation (and Fellows), super conferences in glamorous locations, and more.
But the code is old and there’s only the smallest number of people that regularly contribute. We need more. We need you!
What’s more, as good as we are elsewhere as a community, the group of contributors isn’t as diverse as the community at large: there are clearly barriers to entry here. We’re trying to change that, and we want to invite you to come and join-in.
Contributing to open source is great fun, it’s a great learning opportunity, and it can really help your career.
I’m going to tell you how to get involved, and how to get support in that.
Importantly I’m going to tell you how to avoid the pitfalls.
You are qualified to contribute. More than that, your contribution is the future of Django. Come code!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlton Gibson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-20:djangocon-europe-2019/feeding-the-pony-contributing-back-to-django-how-to-make-that-work-for-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Your web framework needs you!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/your-web-framework-needs-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django looks like it’s doing just fine: it’s a popular framework in a
popular language. We have major releases every six months. We have
Django Girls, a Foundation (and Fellows), super conferences in glamorous
locations, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the code is old, there are 1300+ accepted open issues. There’s only
the smallest number of people that regularly contribute code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s fine now. But it won’t be. Your web framework needs you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to open source is great, and it’s great for you.
Historically we’ve not been that good at encouraging new and diverse
contributors. We’re trying to change that, and we want to invite you to
come and join-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to tell you quickly how to get involved, how to get support in
that, and how to let us know if that’s failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are qualified to contribute. More than that, your contribution is
the future of Django. Come code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlton Gibson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/your-web-framework-needs-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Growing old gracefully: on being a career programmer.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2018/growing-old-gracefully-on-being-a-career-programmer.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software development is often seen as a young person's game. But what if, as you get older, you want to keep at the keyboard? Thoughts from a (now) veteran developer on building your career in software development for the long-haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a community talk. My favourite topics from DjangoConEU 2017 were the non-technical talks. The most interesting (on-topic) conversations I had were about the non-programming aspects of working in software. I wanted to give a talk on that line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prima facie&lt;/em&gt; I'm not the best place person to talk about diversity (white, male, etc), but, having been freelance since 2006, with four young children, and now slightly greying hair, I am in a position to talk about how to build a career in software development for the long-haul. Hiring in tech is massively ageist. I want to discuss strategies to handle that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My target audience is individual programmers (whether freelance or employed) as well as software managers, looking to build &lt;strong&gt;and retain&lt;/strong&gt; a team. (The message for managers is simply that they need to facilitate their employees' careers. This seems obvious but it &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; worth bringing out.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core point of my talk is around the idea that a career is very much a marathon rather than a sprint, and that it needs to be approached in that spirit. (Again, this may seem obvious but it &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; worth bringing out.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects of this. The one is &lt;strong&gt;pace&lt;/strong&gt;. That to work on software day-in, day-out for 10, 20, 30, 40 years (or more) we need to pace ourselves, to manage our reserves, and to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other is that there is noting to be scared of. That expertise which now may seem intimidating is, yes, available to us too. That with 5, 10, 15 years of continued effort we too (yes, us) can be as experienced as whomever, in the speciality we choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bring this out with three points. That we need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be disciplined&lt;/strong&gt;: The key point is to keep going. We each need to find patterns that work for us and develop them into habits that we build into a routine. The great thing is it doesn't have to be 100 hour weeks. As long as we keep doing it, whatever we do builds up over time. Despite the impression to the contrary, time is on our side. Which leads to...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prolific&lt;/strong&gt;: Do lots, and put it out there. This one seems scary. &amp;quot;I'll never do as much as ...&amp;quot; —&amp;nbsp;but it's an illusion. Do one thing. Put that out there. Do something else. Repeat. Again, the work builds up over time, and (seemingly) all of a sudden, you're in a position of being the expert. Finally...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be social&lt;/strong&gt;: And I don't necessarily mean Facebook (unless Facebook is your thing). In whatever environment or medium suits you get out there meet people. (Stretch your comfort zones a bit here.) Share what you've done. Relish in what others have done. Be part of the community. Help build the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three of these are essential. As you get older — all the more as you get older — they allow you to build a sustainable career writing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tale is brought out with stories on finding work, and on choosing clients, and employers, financial planning and job security, on family and free-time, and on the importance self-care. It's part inspiration, part battle-plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carlton Gibson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-24:djangocon-europe-2018/growing-old-gracefully-on-being-a-career-programmer.html</guid></item></channel></rss>