<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Alan Yu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alan-yu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>What we learned from Papermill to operationalize notebooks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/what-we-learned-from-papermill-to-operationalize-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alan Yu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/what-we-learned-from-papermill-to-operationalize-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you hear about beautiful notebook automation, your first thought usually goes to what Netflix is doing with Jupyter Notebooks. Their work is heavily inspired by nteract's papermill, which allows for the parameterization, execution, and analysis of Jupyter notebooks. Notebook operationalization opens many doors for team's troubleshooting pipelines, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you hear about beautiful notebook automation, your first thought usually goes to what Netflix is doing with Jupyter Notebooks. Their work is heavily inspired by nteract's papermill, which allows for the parameterization, execution, and analysis of Jupyter notebooks. Notebook operationalization opens many doors for team's troubleshooting pipelines, and we wanted to learn more from the open source community for how we can work together to empower developers who are on-call. Join us for this code-focused session to hear about our journey of listening and learning to the open source community, and how we used Python to evolve notebook parameterization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2021"></category></entry></feed>