<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Jupyter Enhancement Proposal Story</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/a-jupyter-enhancement-proposal-story.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python users should be familiar with the concept of Python Enhancement
Proposals (PEPs), the way that the Python language evolves over time. In
a similar fashion, the Jupyter project has Jupyter Enhancement Proposals
(JEPs). This talk with cover the proposer first-hand experience when
submiting JEP 23 - Add Template as Metatada enhancement proposal from
it’s beginning, during EuroPython 2017, up to its current status. We
will, in addition, present efforts made as part of the OpenDreamKit
project to perform Jupyter notebooks conversions using custom metadata,
templates, and exporters, in a programmatic way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0:00 - 0:05 Who are we? We are impostors! 0:05 - 0:10 Our previous
experience with Jupyter Notebook. We will talk about the time that
Software Carpentry used Jupyter Notebook for their lesson creation and
OpenDreamKit Jupyter notebook programmatic notebooks conversion. 0:10 -
0:15 You are not alone. We will talk how the idea for the Jupyter
Enhancement Proposals (JEPs) borned at EuroPython 2017 Help Desk 0:15 -
0:20 Writing our first Jupyter Enhancement Proposals. We will cover our
steps to create the pull request required by the Jupyter Project. 0:20 -
0:25 What is the current status of the Jupyter Enhancement Proposals? We
will cover any progress from the time of this talk proposal submission
and the date of it presentation. 0:25 - 0:30 Time for questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raniere Silva</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/a-jupyter-enhancement-proposal-story.html</guid></item><item><title>Community teaching practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/community-teaching-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last five years we saw many groups dedicated to teach people
how to program but any volunteer that is going to start a new teaching
group could have hundreds of questions related with concepts order,
examples, exercises, libraries and text editor/IDE. Panellists will
share their experience when teaching Python to newcomers from different
backgrounds as part of their volunteer work for some organisations such
as PyLadies, DjangoGirls, Code for Life, Software Carpentry,
Data Carpentry, etc. Among the panellists we will have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mateusz Kuzak, from the Netherlands eScience Center and volunteer for Software Carpentry and Data Carpentry;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alice Harpole, from the University of Southampton;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celine Boudier, from Code for Life;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raniere Silva (as moderator), from the Software Sustainability Institute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All questions from the audience are welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alice Harpole</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-13:europython-2017/community-teaching-practices.html</guid></item><item><title>Lightning Talks 20/05/2016</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-20052016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular Dynamics in Ecotoxicology - Nestor Cubas Wendt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⁠⁠⁠Bioinformatics applied to RNA sequencing - Daniella Helena Hock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyLadies São Paulo - Tania Patricia Simões Yamaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to High Performance Scientific Computing with PyOpenCL - Celia Cintas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPython-Unittest - João Felipe Pimentel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Literate Programming, Pweave - Melissa Mendonça&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comunidade SciPy América Latina - Ivan Ogasawara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 Coisas para ler 1 para fazer - Raniere Silva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nestor Cubas Wendt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-24:scipyla-2016/lightning-talks-20052016.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Software Carpentry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipyla-2016/software-carpentry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestrante: Raniere Silva&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raniere Silva</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-20:scipyla-2016/software-carpentry.html</guid></item></channel></rss>