<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to Write Pytest Plugins</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2019/how-to-write-pytest-plugins.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at PyBay2019 - 4th annual Bay Area Regional Python conference. See pybay.com for more details about PyBay and click SHOW MORE for more information about this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description
Pytest is a widely-used, full-featured Python testing tool that helps you write better programs. Did you know that you can easily enhance and customize Pytest through the use of plugins? In this talk, you will learn all about some of the useful Pytest plugins that are available, and learn how to create your own plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Pytest is a widely-used, full-featured Python testing tool that helps you write better programs. Whether you have been using Pytest for years or are just getting started, you may find features of Pytest that you would like to modify or customize for your own environment or specific use cases. Did you know that you can easily enhance and customize Pytest through the use of plugins? In this talk, you will learn all about some of the useful Pytest plugins that are available, and learn how to create your own plugins. We will walk through the plugin creation process by creating a plugin to upload Pytest reports to a Google Cloud Storage bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://t.ly/RX8Yp"&gt;https://t.ly/RX8Yp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker
Darlene Wong is a Silicon Valley native, currently working as a Sr. Software Development Engineer in Test at Palo Alto Networks. In the past, she worked on engineering velocity tools at Tango, security tools at Juniper, data engineering at NearbyNow, and developer productivity tools at Cisco. Darlene holds an MS in Computer Engineering from Santa Clara University and a BS in Computer Science from UCLA. She enjoys dance, volunteering, and travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor Acknowledgement
This and other PyBay2019 videos are via the help of our media partner AlphaVoice (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alphavoice.io/"&gt;https://www.alphavoice.io/&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#pybay #pybay2019 #python #python3 #gdb&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Darlene Wong</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-17:pybay-2019/how-to-write-pytest-plugins.html</guid></item><item><title>Ask Alexa - How Do I Create My First Alexa Skill?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/ask-alexa-how-do-i-create-my-first-alexa-skill.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Darlene Wong</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/ask-alexa-how-do-i-create-my-first-alexa-skill.html</guid></item><item><title>Log Visualization for dummies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2016/log-visualization-for-dummies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this talk the attendees will have an opportunity to use the ELK(Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana) stack to visualize their complex log data.
​
Abstract
Data is the new bacon. For all industries, including health, security, entertainment, etc., it is impossible for anyone to store and analyze data without using an automated platform. A unified platform is needed to provide data visualization and extract intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elasticsearch is a distributed, real-time, search and analytics platform. With the help of a restful API, Elasticsearch saves data and auto indexes the parsed data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our talk, we will walk attendees through configuring the ELK stack and visualize datasets on Kibana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;
Varang Amin is working as a Sr Staff Engineer at Palo Alto Networks. Darlene Wong is working as a Sr Staff Engineer at Palo Alto Networks.
​
Bio2
Darlene Wong is working as a Sr Staff Engineer at Palo Alto Networks. Before PAN, she worked in development role at Juniper Networks &amp;amp; Cisco Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/varang-amin-darlene-wong-log-visualization-for-dummies"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/pybay2016/varang-amin-darlene-wong-log-visualization-for-dummies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Varang Amin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-21:pybay-2016/log-visualization-for-dummies.html</guid></item></channel></rss>