<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Campaign for IT literacy through FOSS and Spoken Tutorials</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/campaign-for-it-literacy-through-foss-and-spoken.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Textbook Companion (TBC) has code for solved problems of textbooks,
coordinated by FOSSEE (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fossee.in"&gt;http://fossee.in&lt;/a&gt;). We explain a collaborative
method that helped create 500 Scilab TBCs (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cloud.scilab.in"&gt;http://cloud.scilab.in&lt;/a&gt;) and
over 100 Python TBCs (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tbc-python.fossee.in/"&gt;http://tbc-python.fossee.in/&lt;/a&gt;). We also explain a
self learning method that trained 250,000 students on FOSS systems using
spoken tutorials (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://spoken-tutorial.org"&gt;http://spoken-tutorial.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FOSSEE team has been promoting the use of FOSS in educational
institutions in India. It focuses on the following FOSS systems
currently: Scilab, Python, Oscad, OpenFOAM, COIN-OR and OpenFormal
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fossee.in"&gt;http://fossee.in&lt;/a&gt;). On each of these systems, the following three
standardised help are provided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support to conduct spoken tutorial based workshops, explained below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of Textbook Companion (TBC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support to Lab Migration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A TBC is a collection of code for solved examples of standard textbooks.
We have completed a large number of TBCs on Scilab and made them
available for online use at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cloud.scilab.in/"&gt;Scilab&lt;/a&gt; and
offline use at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scilab.in/Completed_Books"&gt;Completed
Books&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, one may
access the Python TBC at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tbc-python.fossee.in/"&gt;Python TBC&lt;/a&gt;.
These TBCs are created by students and teachers from many colleges and
each creator is paid an honorarium through a project funded by the
Government of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://spoken-tutorial.org"&gt;Spoken Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; is a screencast of ten
minute duration on a FOSS topic, created for self learning. Using Spoken
Tutorials, we conduct two hour long workshops on FOSS topics through
volunteers, who need not be experts. We conduct online tests and provide
certificates for all who pass the tests. All of these are done
completely free of cost, thanks to the financial support from the
Government of India. Using this method, we have trained more than 200K
students in the last two years in India
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoken-tutorial.org/statistics"&gt;statistics&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students love this method, see some testimonials at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoken-tutorial.org/testimonials"&gt;http://www.spoken-tutorial.org/testimonials&lt;/a&gt;. It is being increasingly
accepted by colleges and universities, officially. We expect to conduct
5K to 10K workshops in 2014, training 200K to 500K students. As we dub
the spoken part into all 22 languages of India, the FOSS topics are
accessible also to students who are not fluent in English, thereby
helping us reach out to many students. Spoken Tutorial, which started as
a documentation project for FOSS systems has transformed into a massive
training programme. Our methods are scalable and are available to the
FOSS enthusiasts in the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kannan Moudgalya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/campaign-for-it-literacy-through-foss-and-spoken.html</guid></item></channel></rss>