<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jakub-macina.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Real-time personalized recommendations using embeddings</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/real-time-personalized-recommendations-using-embeddings.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Mačina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/real-time-personalized-recommendations-using-embeddings.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recommender systems are successfully used in several domains, e.g.
product or movie recommendation. In e-commerce, the aim is to provide
personalized suggestions to users for relevant items out of all products
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will focus on item recommendation for anonymous users
when no historical data about user is available (also referred as a
cold-start problem) and challenges we have encountered. Firstly, I will
dig deeper into similar item recommendation by NLP model comparing
textual descriptions of items. This approach is based on word embeddings
extracted from neural network models, such as word2vec or fasttext.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will talk about how to apply the same idea of word embeddings
to learn a representation of each product. With the product embedding
representation, it is easy to calculate similarities between products in
real- time. Moreover, we found out that product embeddings are able to
capture style of a product, color, category or a price level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the examples will be practical using data about restaurants
reviews and fashion products. Open-source NLP library Gensim is used in
code samples. Presentation will be supported by visualization of
embeddings to get the idea behind. Everybody with any interest in
machine learning is welcome. After the presentation, you will know how
to compute relationship between pizza and pasta or how to capture a
fashion style of a user.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="NLP"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry></feed>