<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Olga Lyashevska</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_olga-lyashevska.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How can machine learning help to predict changes in size of Atlantic herring ?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/how-can-machine-learning-help-to-predict-changes-in-size-of-atlantic-herring.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olga Lyashevska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:/europython-2016/how-can-machine-learning-help-to-predict-changes-in-size-of-atlantic-herring.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Olga Lyashevska - How can machine learning help to predict changes in size of Atlantic herring ?
[EuroPython 2016]
[22 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-can-machine-learning-help-to-predict-changes-in-size-of-atlantic-herring"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-can-machine-learning-help-to-predict-changes-in-size-of-atlantic-herring&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a case-study of how Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciKit-learn)
can be implemented to identify the influence of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Olga Lyashevska - How can machine learning help to predict changes in size of Atlantic herring ?
[EuroPython 2016]
[22 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-can-machine-learning-help-to-predict-changes-in-size-of-atlantic-herring"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/how-can-machine-learning-help-to-predict-changes-in-size-of-atlantic-herring&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a case-study of how Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciKit-learn)
can be implemented to identify the influence of the potential drivers
of a decline in size of Atlantic herring populations using Gradient
Boosting Regression Trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decline in size and weight of Atlantic herring  in the Celtic Sea
has been observed since the mid-1980’s.  The cause of the decline
remains largely unexplained but is likely to be driven by the
interactive effect of various endogenous and exogenous factors. The
goal of this study is to interrogate a long time-series of biological
data obtained from commercial fisheries from 1959 to 2012.  We use
gradient boosting regression trees to identify important variables
underlying changes in growth from various potential drivers, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atlantic multidecadal oscillation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sea surface temperature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salinity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zooplankton abundance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fishing pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This learning algorithm allows to quantify the influence of the
potential drivers of change with the test error lower when compared to
other supervised learning techniques. The predictor variables
importance spectrum (feature importance) helps to identify the
underlying patterns and potential tipping points while resolving the
external mechanisms underlying observed changes in size and weight of
herring.  This analysis is a useful case-study of how Python can be
implemented in academia.  The outputs of the analysis are of relevance
to conservation efforts and sustainable fisheries management which
promotes species resistance and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2016"></category></entry><entry><title>Where is the flock? The use of graph neural networks for bird identification with meteorological radar</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2023/where-is-the-flock-the-use-of-graph-neural-networks-for-bird-identification-with-meteorological-radar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olga Lyashevska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-14:/euroscipy-2023/where-is-the-flock-the-use-of-graph-neural-networks-for-bird-identification-with-meteorological-radar.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this project we generate tools to identify birds within the spatial extent of a meteorological radar. Using the opportunities created by modern dual-polarization radars we build graph neural networks to identify bird flocks. For this, the original point cloud data is converted to multiple undirected graphs following a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this project we generate tools to identify birds within the spatial extent of a meteorological radar. Using the opportunities created by modern dual-polarization radars we build graph neural networks to identify bird flocks. For this, the original point cloud data is converted to multiple undirected graphs following a set of predefined rules, which are then used as an input in graph convolutional neural network (Kipf and Welling, 2017, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1609.02907"&gt;https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1609.02907&lt;/a&gt;). Each node has a set of features such as range, x, y, z coordinates and several radar specific parameters e.g. differential reflectivity and phase shift which are used to build model and conduct graph-level classification. This tool will alleviate problem of manual identification and labelling which is tedious and time intensive. Going forward we also focus on using the temporal information in the radar data. Repeated radar measurements enable us to track these movements across space and time. This makes it possible for regional movement studies to bridge the methodological gap between fine-scale, individual-based tracking studies and continental-scale monitoring of bird migration. In particular, it enables novel studies of the roles of habitat, topography and environmental stressors on movements that are not feasible with current methodology. Ultimately, we want to apply the methodology to data from continental radar networks to study movement across scales.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroSciPy 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Prediction of risk factors for stroke</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/prediction-of-risk-factors-for-stroke.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olga Lyashevska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:/pycon-ireland-2018/prediction-of-risk-factors-for-stroke.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common irregular heartbeat among the world’s population and is a major contributing factor to clot formation within the heart. When such a blood clot enters the cardiovascular system, it first must travel along the ascending aorta. The clot may travel along the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common irregular heartbeat among the world’s population and is a major contributing factor to clot formation within the heart. When such a blood clot enters the cardiovascular system, it first must travel along the ascending aorta. The clot may travel along the aortic arch and travel towards the brain through the left and right common carotid arteries. If clot enters these vessels, it can become lodged within the smaller vessels of the brain and cause a stroke. We apply supervised machine learning classifiers (logit, SVM) for detecting stroke probability using simulation data. Various scenarios are implemented to examine the impact of variables such as shape of the aortic arch, varying clot dimensions and the entry point. Model selection tools (grid search, cross-validation) and classification probability are calculated for each classifier. Application will be shown using Jupyter notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon Ireland 2018"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry></feed>