<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_olivia-wilson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python at Ordnance Survey</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/python-at-ordnance-survey.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Olivia Wilson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-15:pycon-uk-2018/python-at-ordnance-survey.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does a National Mapping Agency use python to help map Great Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Meet Ordnance Survey (OS), the national mapping agency of Great
Britain with a wealth of data going back centuries, and now looking
forward into the geospatial age. Most people know us for our paper map
products of popular walking and hiking destinations, but the main
resource we have is from digital data such as MasterMap – the most
detailed topographic map of Great Britain.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;But where does Python come into all this, you ask? In many areas
across the business Python is a key language, particularly within our
data science and research teams. We use Python to automate processes
as well as discover more about our data and infer from our existing
products. Python automates the quality measures of our data and
products as well as geoprocessing of those products. All of our deep
learning research is carried out using python libraries such as keras,
tensorflow and quiver. So come along to find out more about Python at
OS and particularly about our deep learning work and investigation of
models trained on aerial imagery – including demonstrations.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>