<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creating experiences with information!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-australia-2018/creating-experiences-with-information.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write the Docs Australia 2018&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Stevens</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-15:write-the-docs-australia-2018/creating-experiences-with-information.html</guid><category>WTD Australia 2018</category><category>write the docs</category><category>wtd australia 2018</category></item><item><title>Atlassian: My Information Experience Adventure</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/atlassian-my-information-experience-adventure.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daniel Stevens
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzwb/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzwb/&lt;/a&gt;
Come with me on a journey and learn how Atlassian went from the traditional &amp;amp;quot;Technical Writing&amp;amp;quot; team, to the Information Experience team. What began as a simple challenge to the Atlassian Technical Writing team, to make quality and success measurable and repeatable, grew into a journey to create a &amp;amp;quot;cradle to grave&amp;amp;quot; Information Experience. And we&amp;amp;#39;re just getting started. During the last two Write the Docs I&amp;amp;#39;ve given a lightning talk, Write Measure Repeat, which covers one very small part of the change we&amp;amp;#39;ve undergone. This year I&amp;amp;#39;d like to tell the rest of a story, which is some of the most exciting work I&amp;amp;#39;ve done in my career. I&amp;amp;#39;ll talk about the process of creating and growing a writing culture which is technically accurate, writes with a human voice, and connects to every other part of the information experience. While talking everyone through the journey I&amp;amp;#39;ll be sure to cover specific examples of using content strategy, user research, data analytics and a touch of team process. All this with a bit of humor and a passion which is obvious to anyone who&amp;amp;#39;s ever met me.
Main points I&amp;amp;#39;ll touch on:
How we worked through resistance to change.
What Information Experience means to us and why it&amp;amp;#39;s not just a fancy title.
Moving from the Quality Assistance team to the Design team win&amp;amp;#39;s, frustrations, hopes.
Building a better site with Confluence and considering/using other tools. Light on the tools part here, just covering the visual change and referencing how we did the actual tooling changes.
What this means to me and what I hope we&amp;amp;#39;re beginning to see in the tech comm world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Stevens</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:write-the-docs-2016/atlassian-my-information-experience-adventure.html</guid></item></channel></rss>