<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Bhawna Singh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_bhawna-singh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Generative AI: Beyond technicalities - an ethical perspective</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/generative-ai-beyond-technicalities-an-ethical-perspective.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bhawna Singh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/generative-ai-beyond-technicalities-an-ethical-perspective.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-20]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/generative-ai-beyond-technicalities-an-ethical-perspective"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/generative-ai-beyond-technicalities-an-ethical-perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machines have become smarter than ever before. Recently, we have started using computers for solving problems beyond computations, and it might not be wrong to call them electronic creators. The future laptop might have a prompt …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2B on 2023-07-20]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/generative-ai-beyond-technicalities-an-ethical-perspective"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/generative-ai-beyond-technicalities-an-ethical-perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machines have become smarter than ever before. Recently, we have started using computers for solving problems beyond computations, and it might not be wrong to call them electronic creators. The future laptop might have a prompt based word application, replacing the current Word, where one has to type their thoughts and formulate an entire document from  scratch. Similarly, we might see a prompt based Paint application, instead of the typical Paint program, that generates the paintings for us. In my opinion, AI-based applications are not in fiction anymore, and we may soon be using them on our computers. However, there is a possibilty that the Generative AI can be potentially harmful for society. We need to explore the ethical concerns, and how the AI can impact our society. In this talk, we will try to understand how Generative AI is becoming a part of our future and how we can use it in a responsible and ethical manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry></feed>