<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Julius Busecke</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Xgcm: Analyzing General Circulation Models in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/xgcm-analyzing-general-circulation-models-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will introduce and demonstrate xgcm, a python package which builds on top of xarray and dask to allow users to easily analyze data finite-volume general circulation models, as commonly found in weather, climate, and ocean modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Abernathey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/scipy-2019/xgcm-analyzing-general-circulation-models-in-python.html</guid><category>SciPy 2019</category></item><item><title>Cutting Edge Climate Science in the Cloud with Pangeo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/cutting-edge-climate-science-in-the-cloud-with-pangeo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Climate change is one of the most challenging issues of our time. To prevent the worst outcomes, we need to drastically accelerate the creation and distribution of scientific knowledge. But the complex and massive datasets produced by numerical climate models render the common 'download and analyze' workflow inefficient, blocking innovative analysis and fast scientific discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present python tools and cloud infrastructure developed within the Pangeo community, enabling cutting edge climate science from a web-browser, making it efficient, reproducible, and inclusive. To demonstrate these capabilities we will reproduce a plot from the IPCC report in a live cloud demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Julius Busecke</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/cutting-edge-climate-science-in-the-cloud-with-pangeo.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item><item><title>Enabling Petabyte-scale Ocean Data Analytics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/enabling-petabyte-scale-ocean-data-analytics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The largest oceanographic simulations available are petabyte-scale, presenting a huge challenge when computing even relatively simple analysis functions. Furthermore, doing vector calculus with data living on a staggered grid requires specific numerical schemes to guarantee correctness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XGCM solves both these problems - it applies common vector calculus operations in a grid-aware manner, and now uses the minimum number of dask tasks. This works by applying operations atomically as a “grid ufunc”, using a protocol which generalises numpy ufuncs to specify the input and output grids for a given computation. Using this approach in conjunction with another package, xhistogram, we computed vorticity-strain histograms in different ocean basins globally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Nicholas</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/enabling-petabyte-scale-ocean-data-analytics.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item></channel></rss>