<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Larissa Haas</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_larissa-haas.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>XAI meets Natural Language Processing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/xai-meets-natural-language-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Larissa Haas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-13:/pycon-de-2022/xai-meets-natural-language-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Larissa Haas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Natural Language Processing
The idea of Explainable AI (XAI) gets more and more attention, as customers and users want to understand AI models and the reason behind predictions. But it is difficult to apply &amp;quot;traditional&amp;quot; XAI approaches out of the box to Natural Language …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Larissa Haas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Natural Language Processing
The idea of Explainable AI (XAI) gets more and more attention, as customers and users want to understand AI models and the reason behind predictions. But it is difficult to apply &amp;quot;traditional&amp;quot; XAI approaches out of the box to Natural Language Processing/Understanding models. For human viewers, sentences lose their meaning when turned into numbers and vectors, words become irrelevant when they appear midst of 1000 others. In this talk, I will show you different solution options and approaches, alternatives, and lessons learned based on a real-world NLP use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/F3SZL3"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/F3SZL3&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2022"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConDE"></category><category term="pyconde2022"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="pydataberlin2022"></category></entry><entry><title>Bringing NLP to Production (an end to end story about some multi-language NLP services)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/bringing-nlp-to-production-an-end-to-end-story-about-some-multi-language-nlp-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Larissa Haas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/bringing-nlp-to-production-an-end-to-end-story-about-some-multi-language-nlp-services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Models in Natural Language Processing are fun to train but can be difficult to deploy. The size of their models, libraries and necessary files can be challenging, especially in a microservice environment. When services should be built as lightweight and slim as possible, large (language) models can lead to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Models in Natural Language Processing are fun to train but can be difficult to deploy. The size of their models, libraries and necessary files can be challenging, especially in a microservice environment. When services should be built as lightweight and slim as possible, large (language) models can lead to a lot of problems. With a recent real-world use case as an example, which runs productively for over a year and in 10 different languages, I will walk you through my experiences with deploying NLP models. What kind of pitfalls, shortcuts, and tricks are possible while bringing an NLP model to production?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn about different ways and possibilities to deploy NLP services. I will speak briefly about the way leading from data to model and a running service (without going into much detail) before I will focus on the MLOps part in the end. I will take you with me on my past journey of struggles and successes so that you don't need to take these detours by yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2023"></category></entry></feed>