<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Lirong Xia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Private Are Commonly-Used Voting Rules?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/how-private-are-commonly-used-voting-rules.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How Private Are Commonly-Used Voting Rules?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ao LIU (Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute); Yun Lu (University of Edinburgh)*; Lirong Xia (RPI); Vassilis Zikas (University of Edinburgh)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differential privacy has been widely applied to provide privacy guarantees by adding random noise to the function output. However, it inevitably fails in many high-stakes voting scenarios, where  voting rules are required to be deterministic.
In this work, we present the first framework for answering the question:
How private are commonly-used voting rules?
Our answers are two-fold. First, we show that deterministic voting rules provide sufficient privacy in the sense of distributional differential privacy (DDP). We show that assuming the adversarial observer has uncertainty about individual votes, even publishing the histogram of votes achieves good DDP. Second, we introduce the notion of exact privacy to compare the privacy preserved in various commonly-studied voting rules, and obtain dichotomy theorems of exact DDP within a large subset of voting rules called generalized scoring rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ao Liu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/how-private-are-commonly-used-voting-rules.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item><item><title>Optimal Statistical Hypothesis Testing for Social Choice</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/optimal-statistical-hypothesis-testing-for-social-choice.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Optimal Statistical Hypothesis Testing for Social Choice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lirong Xia (RPI)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We address the following question in this paper: “What are the most robust statistical methods for social choice?” By leveraging the theory of uniformly least favorable distributions in the Neyman-Pearson framework to finite models and randomized tests, we characterize uniformly most powerful (UMP) tests, which is a well-accepted statistical optimality w.r.t. robustness, for testing whether a given alternative is the winner under Mallows’ model and under Condorcet’s model, respectively.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lirong Xia</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/optimal-statistical-hypothesis-testing-for-social-choice.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item></channel></rss>