<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ryan-wilson-perkin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>WSGI for Web Developers</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2018/wsgi-for-web-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Wilson-Perkin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ca-2018/wsgi-for-web-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;WSGI is the foundation of most Python web frameworks, but there's a good chance you've never had to interact with it directly. In this talk we'll explore why it exists, how it works, and what the heck it's doing in your stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great web framework abstracts away all the low-level stuff so that you can focus on the core functionality of your application. This is helpful for getting you going quickly but can be a source of frustration when you want to start optimizing your application. In the Law of Leaky Abstractions Joel Spolsky makes the case that abstracting away the low-level stuff prevents us from learning important concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's learn about WSGI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WSGI is the Web Server Gateway Interface and it's the foundation of almost every Python web framework. This isn't going to be a talk that you'll walk out of with immediate tips for tuning your web service (don't worry, Graham Dumpleton has that covered). Instead, you'll develop an appreciation for the low-level goings on of your stack every time you handle a request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is intended primarily for Python web developers, but should be approachable for anyone with an intermediate experience of Python. I look forward to talking to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation page -- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2018.pycon.ca/talks/talk-PC-55186/"&gt;https://2018.pycon.ca/talks/talk-PC-55186/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>