<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_luke-spademan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Writing Beautiful Python - An Overview of PEP 8</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2019/writing-beautiful-python-an-overview-of-pep-8.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luke Spademan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-14:pycon-uk-2019/writing-beautiful-python-an-overview-of-pep-8.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing code that looks nice can be hard. Why do we need nice looking code anyway? In this talk I'll give you a tour of PEP 8 (The Style Guide for Python Code) and show you how you can force yourself to write code that looks nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Controling a robotic arm with micro:bits. How to make computer science education more interesting.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/controling-a-robotic-arm-with-microbits-how-to-make-computer-science-education-more-interesting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luke Spademan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-22:pycon-sk-2019/controling-a-robotic-arm-with-microbits-how-to-make-computer-science-education-more-interesting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Captivating a group of children for a sustained period of time is
notoriously hard. I will be exporing with you how the micro:bit can be
used to engage a young audience with interactive demos and programming
activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children love to physically interact with hardware. That is what is
great about the micro:bit. It not only has built in LEDs and buttons but
can also control bigger more exciting electronics like robotic arms.
This allows for setup that gives students of all ability levels a
challenge. Students that are beginners to programming can be given a
more complete program or walk throught a worksheet that takes them
through the process of controling the device (in this case a robotic
arm) step by step. Students that have higher programming skills can be
given a more bare bones / boilerplate source file and can write code to
control the arm with less guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Devops with Django Docker and Gitlab</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/devops-with-django-docker-and-gitlab.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luke Spademan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-16:pycon-uk-2018/devops-with-django-docker-and-gitlab.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitLab doesn't host your git repos, it also allows for continuous
integration and deployment. This means that after pushing to the Git
repo, your code is tested them deployed automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this with Docker allows for fast Python deployments to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will be showing you how to setup a basic CI/CD with
GitLab. We will be making a basic Django project as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lessons from combining microbits raspberry pis and tensorflow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/lessons-from-combining-microbits-raspberry-pis-and-tensorflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-26T12:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-26T12:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Luke Spademan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-26:pycon-uk-2017/lessons-from-combining-microbits-raspberry-pis-and-tensorflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am 15 year old that came to pyconuk last year and gave a lightening talk on how I made a micro:bit calculator that could then communicate with other micro:bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have since broadened by learning to create the connect 4 game that I hinted at creating, and then combined it with google's neural net framework (tensorflow) and a raspberry pi to add an AI opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be showing you what I learnt from developing my ideas, and how I overcame any issues I faced.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>