<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Robert Shelton</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_robert-shelton.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Blazing the AI Trail: Using LangGraph to Conquer the Oregon Trail</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-virginia-2025/blazing-the-ai-trail-using-langgraph-to-conquer-the-oregon-trail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Shelton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2025-04-18:/pydata-virginia-2025/blazing-the-ai-trail-using-langgraph-to-conquer-the-oregon-trail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agents have become one of the most talked-about topics in the AI community, but much of the discussion focuses on its potential impact rather than practical implementation. This hands-on workshop will guide data scientists and engineers through building a complete workflow using LangGraph, and will show how to define …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agents have become one of the most talked-about topics in the AI community, but much of the discussion focuses on its potential impact rather than practical implementation. This hands-on workshop will guide data scientists and engineers through building a complete workflow using LangGraph, and will show how to define custom tools, implement vector retrieval, leverage semantic caching, incorporate allow/block list routing, and structure model output for downstream consumption. In order to participate, attendees will need to have Python (3.11 or later), docker, an OpenAI api key, and the starter code for the project cloned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starter code: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/redis-developer/agents-redis-lang-graph-workshop"&gt;https://github.com/redis-developer/agents-redis-lang-graph-workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: participants can test their environment setup ahead of time by following the Readme and running python test_setup.py before the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Virginia 2025"></category></entry></feed>