<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_pranav-suri.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How I Used Data Visualization in My Quest for the Perfect Wine</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/how-i-used-data-visualization-in-my-quest-for-the-perfect-wine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pranav Suri</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-04:pydata-delhi-2019/how-i-used-data-visualization-in-my-quest-for-the-perfect-wine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many, wine is a taste acquired over many years; others use data. In
this talk, I recite the story of how I uncovered the constituents of a
good wine using Data Visualization while discussing the nuances of
Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) – the process of taking the first glance
at data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="idea-behind-the-talk"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Idea Behind The Talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of tools allowing for smooth implementation of powerful
algorithms, it is tempting to skip EDA. However, &lt;strong&gt;EDA is just as
important as any part of a data project; if you don't know your data
well enough, you can end up doing very shallow work&lt;/strong&gt; , i.e., inaccurate
models, choosing wrong variables, inefficient use of resources, or all
of the above. Sometimes, EDA uncovers more than what the confirmatory
study would've done otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis is what one should do when first encountering
a dataset. However, it's not a one-off process: there are setbacks,
multiple iterations, and the process sets the tone for a more formal
analysis of data in hand. &lt;strong&gt;With a story-like format, the presentation
mentions the setbacks one faces when performing a real data study.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The motivation behind creating this talk is to impart the idea of
Exploratory Data Analysis, and how Data Visualizations help uncover
patterns (not limited to the findings of the wine study). Moreover, I
believe the format of a sharing a real story with the idea of &amp;quot;how to
reach and infer from a specific plot&amp;quot; would help the audience understand
data visualization better than talking about syntactic sugar of a
particular visualization library. Moreover, the ideas can be further
generalized to any other visualization library.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="outline-of-the-talk"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Outline of the Talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History of Wine &amp;amp; Data Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Data Visualization? – Anscombe's Quartet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Grammar of Graphics: Why I used ggplot2?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wine-project-finding-constituents-of-good-red-white-wines"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Wine Project: Finding Constituents of Good Red &amp;amp; White Wines&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About the Project &amp;amp; How to Replicate It?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Quantify ‘Artistic’ Measures?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principles of Data Visualization to Uncover Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspecting Data Using Univariate, Bivariate &amp;amp; Multivariate Plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="aspects-of-eda-not-used-in-the-wine-project"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Aspects of EDA Not Used In the Wine Project&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Prepare Your Dataset? – Data Aggregation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Remove Outliers Using Data Visualization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Decide the Best Fit During EDA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When to Transform Variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>