<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Angie Reed</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_angie-reed.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Using Data to Protect Traditional Lifeways</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/using-data-to-protect-traditional-lifeways.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Angie Reed</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/using-data-to-protect-traditional-lifeways.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The spirit of Penobscot Nation's work to protect the health of their relative, the Penobscot River, is embodied in the Penobscot water song which says &amp;quot;&amp;quot;Water, we love you, thank you so much water, we respect you.&amp;quot;&amp;quot; Because the Penobscot River is not a natural resource - she is a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The spirit of Penobscot Nation's work to protect the health of their relative, the Penobscot River, is embodied in the Penobscot water song which says &amp;quot;&amp;quot;Water, we love you, thank you so much water, we respect you.&amp;quot;&amp;quot; Because the Penobscot River is not a natural resource - she is a relative, family - this song describes the foundation of our efforts to protect her health and well-being. The identity of Penobscot people cannot be disconnected from the river, and protecting this traditional lifeway is at the heart of our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For over a decade we have used R to manage, transform, analyze, and visualize data, and the free, open-source Posit products help us leave a legacy of good data management and the ability to share results with Penobscot Nation citizens. You will learn more about how our use of R has helped us achieve more stringent protections for the Penobscot River and how we engage young people in every step of this work. We are also part of a larger network of tribal environmental professionals, working together to learn R and share data and insights. We will give you information about how you can volunteer to help expand the network of folks providing technical assistance on any R and RStudio related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>bRewing code: Ingredients for successful tribal collaboration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/brewing-code-ingredients-for-successful-tribal-collaboration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alena Reynolds</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/brewing-code-ingredients-for-successful-tribal-collaboration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone will have their own recipe for bRewing a great collaboration, but we wanted to share ours. Ingredients: equal parts learner and teacher, 90 kg of supportive management, 1 whole database, complete or incomplete, a dash of creativity, 60 hours of time (recipe included in the main presentation), fun …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone will have their own recipe for bRewing a great collaboration, but we wanted to share ours. Ingredients: equal parts learner and teacher, 90 kg of supportive management, 1 whole database, complete or incomplete, a dash of creativity, 60 hours of time (recipe included in the main presentation), fun to taste. First, make sure your ingredients are organized, and the prep area is tidy. Sift data into a central database and simmer and stir into separate R scripts. In a large cauldron, combine scripts and narrative into one giant Rmarkdown. Lubridate your pan and knit into the desired format. We want to share the rest of our recipe to make a delicious report that builds confidence in the learner, new and strong friendships, and lifelong skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>