<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Nicholas Masel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_nicholas-masel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Open-Source Initiatives in Pharma - What's Out There and Why You Should Join</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/open-source-initiatives-in-pharma-whats-out-there-and-why-you-should-join.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicholas Masel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/open-source-initiatives-in-pharma-whats-out-there-and-why-you-should-join.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pharmaceutical industry has come a long way when it comes to using open-source and collaborating on initiatives to solve complex industry issues. The number of initiatives and working groups that are now available have grown so much over the last 5 to 10 years that understanding what to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pharmaceutical industry has come a long way when it comes to using open-source and collaborating on initiatives to solve complex industry issues. The number of initiatives and working groups that are now available have grown so much over the last 5 to 10 years that understanding what to join, or even just what to keep track of, can feel like selecting an R package, you’ve got a lot of options! This is a good problem to have, but it can also feel like a barrier to entry for companies or individuals in the industry who are looking to learn and/or contribute. In this talk, I will present guidance to the pharmaceutical industry to help them navigate the open-source collaboration landscape to help companies and individuals get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>