<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Bae Doo-sik</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Growing with Open SourceFeat Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-korea-2023/growing-with-open-sourcefeat-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;‘Growth’, the concern of all developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share my experience of growing as a developer through open source contributions. I prepared the presentation based on what I learned while contributing to ‘Django’, a representative web framework in Python among many open sources.
As a developer, I was able to experience growing not only technically but also mentally while contributing to open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also share tips on how to start contributing to open source and tips on how to contribute to open source with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not contributed much to open source yet, but I thought it would be good to contribute to open source and grow together with more Korean Python developers, so I decided to give the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bae Doo-sik (Jordan)
I am developing a credit rating analysis platform and data platform at Verticah, which creates the future sales transaction platform, Revenue Market. After graduating from college, I started my career in circuit design at LG and then switched to becoming a software engineer. After switching, I worked as a server engineer, data infrastructure engineer, and data engineer at various large and small startups such as Ateamventures, Sendbird, Chai, and Quotabook. I have been working in various positions and have been solving business and technical problems without any boundaries in the field. I try to make time to contribute to open source often and recently I have been interested in building a good data platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bae Doo-sik</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-08-12:/pycon-korea-2023/growing-with-open-sourcefeat-django.html</guid><category>PyCon Korea 2023</category></item></channel></rss>