<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ryan Abernathey</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Xgcm: Analyzing General Circulation Models in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/xgcm-analyzing-general-circulation-models-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will introduce and demonstrate xgcm, a python package which builds on top of xarray and dask to allow users to easily analyze data finite-volume general circulation models, as commonly found in weather, climate, and ocean modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Abernathey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-13:/scipy-2019/xgcm-analyzing-general-circulation-models-in-python.html</guid><category>SciPy 2019</category></item><item><title>Ocetrac morphological image processing for monitoring ocean temperature extremes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2021/ocetrac-morphological-image-processing-for-monitoring-ocean-temperature-extremes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dangerous hot-water events, called marine heatwaves, cause prolonged periods of thermal stress in the marine environment that can lead to widespread coral bleaching, harmful algal blooms, unproductive fisheries, and even economic loss. Anticipating the paths of destructive marine heatwaves remains a challenge owing to the complex spatiotemporal evolution of these events. We present a novel open source package called Ocetrac that implements morphological image processing and tracking to aid in the analysis of marine heatwave detection and movement. We discuss how this approach can be applied to monitor other extreme ocean conditions, such as deoxygenation and acidification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hillary Scannell</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-12:/scipy-2021/ocetrac-morphological-image-processing-for-monitoring-ocean-temperature-extremes.html</guid><category>SciPy 2021</category></item><item><title>Pangeo Forge: Crowdsourcing Open Data in the Cloud</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2022/pangeo-forge-crowdsourcing-open-data-in-the-cloud.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pangeo Forge is an open source platform for the curation of analysis-ready, cloud-optimized scientific datasets. We are using Pangeo Forge to populate a multi-petabyte-scale open-access library of scientific data in the cloud. You will leave this talk with a clear understanding of how to access this data library, craft your own Pangeo Forge recipe, and become a contributor to our growing “recipe box.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ryan Abernathey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/scipy-2022/pangeo-forge-crowdsourcing-open-data-in-the-cloud.html</guid><category>SciPy 2022</category></item></channel></rss>