<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Carrie Wright</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_carrie-wright.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Supporting Social Good Through Community-Based Data Science Education</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/supporting-social-good-through-community-based-data-science-education.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carrie Wright</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/supporting-social-good-through-community-based-data-science-education.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this data-centric era, the demand for responsible data science practitioners is more crucial than ever. However many data science education programs don’t adequately emphasize data ethics. To address this need, my colleagues, Ava Hoffman, Michael Rosenblum, and I have developed a course at Johns Hopkins, offering students …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this data-centric era, the demand for responsible data science practitioners is more crucial than ever. However many data science education programs don’t adequately emphasize data ethics. To address this need, my colleagues, Ava Hoffman, Michael Rosenblum, and I have developed a course at Johns Hopkins, offering students hands-on experiences collaborating with community-based organizations on diverse data science projects. We've partnered with organizations championing various causes, including youth leadership, voting rights, transportation advocacy, and community tool banks. We've gained valuable insights about hands-on data ethics education and demonstrated that even data science education itself can support social good.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>