<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Michal Cyprian</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michal-cyprian.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to deliver 3x faster with effective API design</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/how-to-deliver-3x-faster-with-effective-api-design.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michal Cyprian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/how-to-deliver-3x-faster-with-effective-api-design.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to deliver 3x faster with effective API design by Michal Cyprian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-deliver-3x-faster-with-effective-api-design"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-deliver-3x-faster-with-effective-api-design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today's fast-paced world, the ability to deliver new features quickly is crucial for product-oriented companies. In this talk, we'll dive into architectural patterns that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Forum Hall on 2024-07-10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to deliver 3x faster with effective API design by Michal Cyprian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-deliver-3x-faster-with-effective-api-design"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/how-to-deliver-3x-faster-with-effective-api-design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today's fast-paced world, the ability to deliver new features quickly is crucial for product-oriented companies. In this talk, we'll dive into architectural patterns that optimize the delivery of multiple client implementations in complex client-server architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of the mobile age has dramatically altered the landscape of typical client-server models. Delivering a new feature on multiple platforms is complicated and time-consuming because it requires several engineering teams to communicate extensively and separately code and test the same feature in different languages for each platform. Let's see how architectural patterns known as Backend for Frontend (BFF) and Server-driven UI can help with solving these challenges and what the limitations are. We'll explore Python optimizations, caching strategies, and SQLAlchemy preloading techniques, which were crucial to the success of the case study I will share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to provide you with an overview of useful architectural patterns, insights on how to implement and optimize them in Python, and strategies to make your product managers happy by shortening your time to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Make sudo pip Safe Again</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2017/make-sudo-pip-safe-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michal Cyprian</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-03-10:/pycon-sk-2017/make-sudo-pip-safe-again.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the present time, running sudo pip3 in Fedora is not safe. Pip shares its installation directory with DNF package manager, can remove DNF-managed files and generally break the Python 3 interpreter.
In this talk i'll try to describe the problem, possible solutions that have been discussed and the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the present time, running sudo pip3 in Fedora is not safe. Pip shares its installation directory with DNF package manager, can remove DNF-managed files and generally break the Python 3 interpreter.
In this talk i'll try to describe the problem, possible solutions that have been discussed and the result of work which was proposed as a Fedora Change. I will also mention the process of discovering initialization of Python interpreter and I will show you a couple of live demos.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon SK 2017"></category></entry></feed>