<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inheriting code, and I don't mean classes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-latam-2019/inheriting-code-and-i-dont-mean-classes.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-31:pycon-latam-2019/inheriting-code-and-i-dont-mean-classes.html</guid></item><item><title>Marconi: Queuing and Notification service for OpenStack</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/marconi-queuing-and-notification-service-for-openstack.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/marconi-queuing-and-notification-service-for-openstack.html</guid><category>MessageQueues</category><category>WSGI</category><category>mongodb</category><category>REST</category><category>tdd</category><category>application-design</category><category>architecture</category><category>cloud</category></item><item><title>OpenStack: A python based IaaS provider</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/openstack-a-python-based-iaas-provider.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/openstack-a-python-based-iaas-provider.html</guid><category>scm</category><category>cloud</category><category>gerrit</category><category>community</category></item><item><title>Don’t try to look smart, be smart!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not gonna go Deepak Chopra on you — for a second what would happen
if you had the chance to start your career all over again. if you had a
chance to you do all the things that you’ve done and imagine what you
would change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I want you to imagine that you don’t have all the time
that you’ve had so far, you have way less time than you’ve had so far.
Imagine what you would do and what you would change. I’ll give you just
like a couple of seconds to go through that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic is a bit hard for me as it covers some of the things I’ve
gone through in my career that made me feel like an idiot when they
happened. With time, I’ve realized that these are the things that have
taken me where I’m at and I hope they will be useful to you as they were
for me. I don’t intend to look smart but rather be honest, as honest as
I can be about my past so that you can, perhaps, start ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 20 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</guid></item><item><title>Keeping up with the pace of a fast growing community without dying</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;New open source communities are born everyday. Some of them are meant to
last long and some others aren’t. There’s a moment in every community
where it needs to outgrow itself, expand its limits and aim way higher
than ever. This is no necesarily related to its goals but the ecosystem
it needs to stay alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a community has gone beyond its limits, the community members,
consumers and leaders will have to keep up with its pace. How do we help
it to remain sane? How do we keep our goals on track while allowing for
further growth? How do we allow it to keep expanding without further
damaging the community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all questions we ask ourselves everyday in the OpenStack
community and that we’ve managed to work on without killing ourselves on
the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>open-source</category><category>community</category></item><item><title>Don't try to look smart. Be smart</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The technology industry is growing and already huge. The number of
humans in this industry and the number of areas they can work on are
overwhelming. The number of opportunities often don’t seem as many for
an industry that big, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how long you’ve been in this industry, you often feel
overwhelmed, unfocused, demotivated by the size of the industry, the
uncertainty it generates and the urge of doing something others consider
important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this talk, the audience will learn how to grow in an industry
that is often blasted with intellectual appearances, quantity over
quality and unstoppable, constant, changes. The talk provides tips to
cope with large communities and fields as well as experiences and
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</guid><category>Growth</category><category>community</category></item><item><title>Lessons Learned from Working Remote</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2018/lessons-learned-from-working-remote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working Remotely brings a whole new set of challenges. It can be rewarding, challenging, fun and exciting. But it can also be lonely, depressing and frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll focus on some of the negatives and on how you or your employer can work to combat them so you can sit and enjoy all the good that comes with remote working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk dives into the lessons learned from an employee of Elastic, one from Red Hat and other companies that have distributed and remote teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-03:pycon-cz-2018/lessons-learned-from-working-remote.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduzione a Openstack: uno IaaS provider in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/introduzione-a-openstack-uno-iaas-provider-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenStack è un provider IaaS scritto in Python. Fornisce un sistema operativo scalabile e servizi quali: Image, Storage, Object, Computer, ecc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questo talk ha come obiettivo dare alla platea un overview su OpenStack, le sue caratteristiche, i suoi moduli, il coding style, il workflow e l'organizzazione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come caso di successo di un prodotto con sviluppo guidato dalla comunità, è assolutamente un ottimo punto di riferimento per chiunque voglia intraprendere una strada simile, o entrare per collaborare in progetti simili.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-25:pycon-italia-2014/introduzione-a-openstack-uno-iaas-provider-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Procrastination makes you better: Life of a remotee</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2014/procrastination-makes-you-better-life-of-a-remotee.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, more and more companies are moving towards &amp;quot;being remote&amp;quot;. Likewise, more and more people want to work remotely. I get asked quite often what it is like to work remotely, how I manage to respect deadlines and actually do some work. Many people think that working remotely is hard and that just a small set of folks can actually do it. This is not true!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working remotely is not just about getting things done. It's more about getting yourself to the point where you're able to get things done. Going remote forces people to deal with things like having a good place to work from, being comfortable, managing their own time, defining priorities themselves and having time for themselves as well. Unfortunately, it doesn't matter how hard people try not to procrastinate, one way or another, procrastination manages to fill a huge part of the time and you know what, THAT'S FINE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll share my experience as a remote developer, the things that have changed in my life since I stopped commuting every day and decided to be a prisoner of my own house. I'll go through the things I struggled with, the things I learned to deal with and how I embrace procrastination. This talk is a great opportunity for everyone to learn and share from real life experiences about this work arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From commuting to computing
Getting out of bed
First fears and troubles as a remotee
Baby steps towards enjoying a remote position
Missing the office and dealing with it&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-24:pycon-italia-2014/procrastination-makes-you-better-life-of-a-remotee.html</guid></item><item><title>Systems Integration: The OpenStack success story</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2014/systems-integration-the-openstack-success-story.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic: Systems Integration: The OpenStack success story
Prelegent/Speaker: Flavio Percoco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is a huge, open-source cloud provider. One of the main tenets of OpenStack is the (Shared Nothing Architecture) to which all modules stick very closely. In order to do that, services within OpenStack have adopted different strategies to integrate themselves and share data without sacrificing performance nor moving away from SNA. This strategies are not applicable just to OpenStack but to any distributed system. Sharing data, regardless what that data is, is a must-have requirement of any successful cloud service. This talk will present some of the existing integration strategies that are applicable to cloud infrastructures and enterprise services. The talk will be based on the strategies that have helped OpenStack to be successful and most importantly, scalable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-18:pycon-pl-2014/systems-integration-the-openstack-success-story.html</guid></item><item><title>Procrastination makes you better: Life of a remotee</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pl-2014/procrastination-makes-you-better-life-of-a-remotee.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tytuł/Topic:  Procrastination makes you better: Life of a remotee
Prelegent/Speaker: Flavio Percoco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, more and more companies are moving towards “being remote”. Likewise, more and more people want to work remotely. I get asked quite often what it is like to work remotely, how I manage to respect deadlines and actually do some work. Many people think that working remotely is hard and that just a small set of folks can actually do it. This is not true! Working remotely is not just about getting things done. It’s more about getting yourself to the point where you’re able to get things done. Going remote forces people to deal with things like having a good place to work from, being comfortable, managing their own time, defining priorities themselves and having time for themselves as well. Unfortunately, it doesn’t matter how hard people try not to procrastinate, one way or another, procrastination manages to fill a huge part of the time and you know what, THAT’S FINE! In this talk, I’ll share my experience as a remote developer, the things that have changed in my life since I stopped commuting every day and decided to be a prisoner of my own house. I’ll go through the things I struggled with, the things I learned to deal with and how I embrace procrastination. This talk is a great opportunity for everyone to learn and share from real life experiences about this work arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda"&gt;http://pl.pycon.org/2014/pl/agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-16:pycon-pl-2014/procrastination-makes-you-better-life-of-a-remotee.html</guid></item><item><title>Systems Integration: The OpenStack success story</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/systems-integration-the-openstack-success-story.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is a huge, open-source cloud provider. One of the main tenets
of OpenStack is the (Shared Nothing Architecture) to which all modules
stick very closely. In order to do that, services within OpenStack have
adopted different strategies to integrate themselves and share data
without sacrificing performance nor moving away from SNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strategies are not applicable just to OpenStack but to any
distributed system. Sharing data, regardless what that data is, is a
must-have requirement of any successful cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present some of the existing integration strategies that
are applicable to cloud infrastructures and enterprise services. The
talk will be based on the strategies that have helped OpenStack to be
successful and most importantly, scalable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="abstract"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is a huge, open-source cloud provider. One of the main tenets
of OpenStack is the (Shared Nothing Architecture) to which all modules
stick very closely. In order to do that, services within OpenStack have
adopted different strategies to integrate themselves and share data
without sacrificing performance nor moving away from SNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strategies are not applicable just to OpenStack but to any
distributed system. Sharing data, regardless what that data is, is a
must-have requirement of any successful cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will present some of the existing integration strategies that
are applicable to cloud infrastructures and enterprise services. The
talk will be based on the strategies that have helped OpenStack to be
successful and most importantly, scalable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="details"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Details&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the lines of what I've described in the abstract, the presentation
will walk the audience through the state of the art of existing system
integration solutions, the ones that have been adopted by OpenStack and
the benefits of those solutions. At the end of the talk, a set of
solutions under development, ideas and improvements to the existing ones
will be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is oriented to distributed services, fault-tolerance
and replica determinism. It's based on a software completely written in
python and running successfully on several production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will be split in 3 main topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="distributed-system-integration"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Distributed System integration&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's it ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is it essential for cloud infrastructures?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing methods and strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="openstack-success-story"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;OpenStack success story&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which methods did OpenStack adopt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How / Why do they work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What else could be done?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coming-next"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Coming Next&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some issues of existing solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are we doing to improve that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other solutions coming up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-23:europython-2014/systems-integration-the-openstack-success-story.html</guid></item><item><title>Breaking backwards compatibility: The easy way!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/breaking-backwards-compatibility-the-easy-way-0.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say you have this piece of software that many people use. One day, you
wake up and you have the urge to make them suffer. Well, there’s no
better way to do so than breaking the software they’re using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll walk you through very good ways to do so by showing
examples taken from experience - because experience is the only thing
that matters (TM) - so that you’ll be able, by the time this talk ends,
to do the same to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S: If you’ve a kinder hearth, you can also do the exact opposite of
what I’ll say and keep your users happy.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/breaking-backwards-compatibility-the-easy-way-0.html</guid></item><item><title>Fast-forward to today's Zaqar</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/fast-forward-to-todays-zaqar.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zaqar is probably one of the projects that had been debated the most in
OpenStack. Nonetheless, this service capable of providing multi-tenant
messaging is now becoming a more relevant part of the OpenStack
infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One feature at a time, it's achieving its goals and improving itself.
From multi-tenantcy, to subscriptions and persistent transports. In this
talk, I'll present the project and its goals, the current state of art,
its capabilities and architecture, the tools available and the related
maintenance cost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/fast-forward-to-todays-zaqar.html</guid></item><item><title>*aaS Royal Rumble - Q&amp;A</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/aas-royal-rumble-qa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La sessione di Q&amp;amp;A ti permetterà di approfondire le differenze tra le
varie piattaforme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Martelli</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:pycon-italia-2015/aas-royal-rumble-qa.html</guid></item><item><title>Don't let your passion kill your motivation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/dont-let-your-passion-kill-your-motivation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I would ask you to sit down and do some work right now (assuming
you’re not doing it), how would you feel about it? Would you be
motivated enough to take off your laptop and start coding? Or would you
rather do something else? Programming is more about other things than
just coding. Great books - like The Passionate Programmer by Chad Fowler
- have eloquently explained the different perspectives there are about
what programming is and how you can take the most out of your skills.
Nonetheless, programming is even more than that. Programming is more
than just producing results and it’s definitely more than just being
“smart”. In fact, programming is probably more about how to keep
programming than actually doing it. Likely, one of the things we,
developers, struggle the most with is motivation. Therefore, join me in
this talk while I share some of my motivational ups and downs and walk
you through some of the things that have worked for me along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-30:pycon-italia-2015/dont-let-your-passion-kill-your-motivation.html</guid></item><item><title>Breaking backwards compatibility The easy way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/breaking-backwards-compatibility-the-easy-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say you have this piece of software that many people use. One day, you
wake up and you have the urge to make them suffer. Well, there’s no
better way to do so than breaking the software they’re using. In this
talk, I’ll walk you through very good ways to do so by showing examples
taken from experience - because experience is the only thing that
matters (TM) - so that you’ll be able, by the time this talk ends, to do
the same to your users. (P.S: If you’ve a kinder hearth, you can also do
the exact oposite of what I’ll say and keep your users happy.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-29:pycon-italia-2015/breaking-backwards-compatibility-the-easy-way.html</guid></item><item><title>Keeping up with the pace of a fast growing community without dying</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;New open source communities are born everyday. Some of them are meant to
last long and some others aren't. There's a moment in every community
where it needs to outgrow itself, expand its limits and aim way higher
than ever. This is no necesarily related to its goals but the ecosystem
it needs to stay alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a community has gone beyond its limits, the community members,
consumers and leaders will have to keep up with its pace. How do we help
it to remain sane? How do we keep our goals on track while allowing for
further growth? How do we allow it to keep expanding without further
damaging the community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all questions we ask ourselves everyday in the OpenStack
community and that we've managed to work on without killing ourselves on
the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html</guid></item><item><title>Don't try to look smart. Be smart</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The technology industry is growing and already huge. The number of
humans in this industry and the number of areas they can work on are
overwhelming. The number of opportunities often don't seem as many
for an industry that big, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how long you've been in this industry, you often feel
overwhelmed, unfocused, demotivated by the size of the industry, the
uncertainty it generates and the urge of doing something others consider
important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this talk, the audience will learn how to grow in an industry
that is often blasted with intellectual appearances, quantity over
quality and unstoppable, constant, changes. The talk provides tips to
cope with large communities and fields as well as experiences and
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flavio Percoco</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-05:pycon-za-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</guid></item></channel></rss>