<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using NLP To Reduce Wealth Flowing Into Local Human Trafficking Economies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/using-nlp-to-reduce-wealth-flowing-into-local-human-trafficking-economies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With $150 billion generated in profit a year, human trafficking is an
illicit business model that affects children and adults in every community
in the United States. Any strategy to reduce the prevalence of the crime
must include reducing the amount of profit. Working with the New York Police
Department, I built a prototype using NLP to target the buyers contributing
the wealth to New York's human trafficking economy. That prototype went on
to serve nine jurisdictions across the United States and reach tens of
thousands of buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk explores the development of the chatbot engaging with buyers every
hour of every day across the country to reduce the economic incentives
behind human trafficking. We'll explore scoping the domain of an NLP
problem, designing the right machine learning model to address it, and
creative ways to collect sufficient data to train an effective model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Spectre</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/using-nlp-to-reduce-wealth-flowing-into-local-human-trafficking-economies.html</guid></item><item><title>DjangoCon EU 2013: Rob Spectre - Bleed for Speed: Django for Rapid Prototyping</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2013/djangocon-eu-2013-rob-spectre-bleed-for-speed-django-for-rapid-prototyping.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Videos from DjangoCon Europe 2013 are kindly provided by Heroku, a cloud application platform -- a new way of building and deploying web apps: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://heroku.com/"&gt;http://heroku.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Spectre</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-05-15:djangocon-europe-2013/djangocon-eu-2013-rob-spectre-bleed-for-speed-django-for-rapid-prototyping.html</guid></item></channel></rss>