<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_valentin-haenal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Compress Me, Stupid!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/compress-me-stupid.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valentin Haenal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-23:europython-2014/compress-me-stupid.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compression is a general technique for reducing the size of datasets
that normally lie on disk or that should be sent remotely. But time has
come to use it as a means to accelerate applications that uses in-memory
data too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.blosc.org"&gt;Blosc&lt;/a&gt; is a high-performance meta-compressor
that is meant to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compression is a technique to reduce the number of bits needed to
represent a given dataset. A very common use-case in the distributed
digital age is to reduce the size of files in order to reduce the time
and bandwidth requirements of sending a file from one location to
another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a large variety of different algorithms and implementations of
so called &amp;quot;codecs&amp;quot; - a term is derived from the fact that programs that
implement a compression algorithm commonly constitute of both a
compressor and a corresponding decompressor. There are many different
special purpose compressors that exploit specifics in the structure of
the input data, for example: MP3, Ogg and FLAC for audio data such as
music, GIF, JPEG and PNG for images and MPEG for encoding video. Also,
there are many general purpose codecs that make no assumptions about the
structure of the data, for example: Zlib(DEFLATE), Bzip2(BWT) and LZMA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, and due to the ever growing divide between memory access
latency and CPU clock speed a new use-case beyond faster file transfers
and more efficient use of disk-space has emerged: &amp;quot;in-memory
compression&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping data in RAM that is compressed also means that the CPU has to do
more work in order to make use of it. However, if the compressor is fast
enough, this decompression overhead could pay off, and applications
could work with compressed data transparently, and so not even noticing
the slowdown due to the extra effort for compression/decompression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technique can be very beneficial in a variety of scenarios where
RAM availability is critical. For example, in-memory caching systems
like Memcached or Redis could store more data using the same resources
thereby optimizing resource usage. Another use case is to use
compression for in-memory data containers, à la NumPy's ndarray or
Pandas' DataFrame, allowing for improved memory usage and potentially
allow for accelerated computations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our talk, we will explain first why we are in a moment of computer
history that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pytables.org/docs/CISE-12-2-ScientificPro.pdf"&gt;in-memory compression can be beneficial for modern
applications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we will introduce &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.blosc.org"&gt;Blosc&lt;/a&gt;, a high speed
meta-compressor, allowing other existing compressors (BloscLZ, LZ4,
Snappy or even Zlib) to leverage the SIMD and multithreading framework
that it provides and help achieving extremely fast operation (frequently
faster than a plain memcpy() system call).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will show some existing data handling libraries
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Blosc/bloscpack"&gt;Bloscpack&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pytables.org"&gt;PyTables&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://continuum.io/blog/blz-format"&gt;BLZ&lt;/a&gt;) -- all written in Python
-- that already use Blosc today for fulfilling the promise of faster
operations by doing in-memory compressing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>