<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Yangbo He</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Collapsible IDA: Collapsing Parental Sets for Locally Estimating Possible Causal Effects</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/collapsible-ida-collapsing-parental-sets-for-locally-estimating-possible-causal-effects.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Collapsible IDA: Collapsing Parental Sets for Locally Estimating Possible Causal Effects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yue Liu (Peking University); Zhuangyan Fang (Peking University); Yangbo He (Peking University)*; Zhi Geng (Peking University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear that some causal effects cannot be identified from observational data when the causal directed acyclic graph is absent. In such cases, IDA is a useful framework which estimates all possible causal effects by adjusting for all possible parental sets. In this paper, we combine the adjustment set selection procedure with the original IDA framework. Our goal is to find a common set that can be subtracted from all possible parental sets without influencing the back-door adjustment. To this end, we first introduce graphical conditions to decide whether a treatment's neighbor or parent in a completed partially directed acyclic graph (CPDAG) can be subtracted and then provide a procedure to construct a subtractable set from those subtractable vertices. We next combine the procedure with the IDA framework and provide a fully local modification of IDA. Experimental results show that, with our modification, both the number of possible parental sets and the size of each possible parental set enumerated by the modified IDA decrease, making it possible to estimate all possible causal effects more efficiently.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yue Liu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/collapsible-ida-collapsing-parental-sets-for-locally-estimating-possible-causal-effects.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item><item><title>IDA with Background Knowledge</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/uai-2020/ida-with-background-knowledge.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;IDA with Background Knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhuangyan Fang (Peking University); Yangbo He (Peking University)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we consider the problem of estimating all possible causal effects from observational data with two types of background knowledge: direct causal information and non-ancestral information. Following the IDA framework, we first provide locally valid orientation rules for maximal partially directed acyclic graphs (PDAGs), which are widely used to represent background knowledge. Based on the proposed rules, we present a fully local algorithm to estimate all possible causal effects with direct causal information. Furthermore, we consider non-ancestral information and prove that it can be equivalently transformed into direct causal information, meaning that we can also locally estimate all possible causal effects with non-ancestral information. The test results on both synthetic and real-world data sets show that our methods are efficient and stable.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Zhuangyan Fang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-08-03:/uai-2020/ida-with-background-knowledge.html</guid><category>UAI 2020</category></item></channel></rss>