<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>System testing with Pytest, Docker, and Flask</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/system-testing-with-pytest-docker-and-flask.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The composability of fixtures in pytest is an improvement over
traditional xUnit setup/teardown, reducing the incentive to commit
testing crimes such as multi-stage and stepwise tests. This is great out
of the box for unit tests, but I’m going to show how to combine the
power of pytest fixtures with Docker to build high-level integration
tests for microservices or other complex systems with multiple
components. I’ll then build on that to show how to embed mock web
services written with Flask right into the test code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a sample Java application that makes use of some external resources
to offer a data processing service I’ll first quick an overview of
Pytest, Docker, and Flask. Then I’ll mix some pre-built code with live
test coding to demonstrate how to build high-level system tests which
spin up the application and its dependencies in Docker. I’ll then mock
one of the external dependencies using Flask, allowing the test to
control and verify interaction between the system components. Finally
I’ll show how to wrap the Flask application in a WSGI middleware that
lets the test inspect interaction with the mocked service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a learning and development point of view, building your own is
better than re-using someone else’s code so I’ll show how the support
code for these features is relatively simple and how the audience can
build it themselves to exactly meet their own needs. And I’ll do it all
with a sense of fun, a joke or two and maybe a little storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Neil Gall</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-27:europython-2018/system-testing-with-pytest-docker-and-flask.html</guid></item></channel></rss>