<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_francoise-provencher.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Biases are bugs: algorithm fairness and machine learning ethics</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/biases-are-bugs-algorithm-fairness-and-machine-learning-ethics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Françoise Provencher</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/biases-are-bugs-algorithm-fairness-and-machine-learning-ethics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Biases are bugs. They need to be found, fixed, and learnt from. A mix of good ethics and good engineering practices can get us a long way towards that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you'll learn what biases are, what software tools can help, and how to adopt engineering practices that can make your algorithms fairer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithms can make decisions, and these decisions can have an impact on people's lives. By feeding data into these algorithms, they can reproduce or amplify our societal biases and take unfair decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biases are bugs. They need to be found, fixed, and learnt from. A mix of good ethics and good engineering practices can get us a long way towards that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn what biases are, see examples of algorithms gone wrong, and explore some software tools you can use and engineering practices you can adopt in your own work to make your algorithms more fair.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ethics in Machine Learning Panel</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roelof Pieters</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advances in AI are happening at a tremendous pace, and especially Machine Learning systems are hastily deployed in settings that span as wide as social media, search engines, advertising, military use, and legal systems. At first sight results are often promising, but more and more &amp;quot;outliers&amp;quot; are becoming visible as well. Systemic bias in culture, language, or business practices often become intensified: From the Tay-chatbot turning racist, to both Google and Flickr classifying images of African-Americans as &amp;quot;monkeys&amp;quot;, to discrimination and sexism encoded in language models used for everything from translation, to court sentencing decision. Luckily, initiatives that address some of these concerns is happening through more interpretable models, new privacy regulations, novel privacy-preserving learning algorithms, and researchers and engineers standing up for more just and transparent machine learning models and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel aims to debate these themes with speakers, and the audience, and go beyond the usual &amp;quot;AI hype&amp;quot; and discuss both the amazing progress, as well as the setbacks, in making societies better, more humane, and ready for the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the panel will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roelof Pieters, Panel Host, Co-founder at creative.ai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marek Rosa, CEO/CTO at GoodAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Françoise Provencher, Data Team Lead at Shopify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hendrik Heuer, Researcher at Institute for Information Management (ifib) at the University of Bremen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andreas Dewes, Founder at 7scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katharine Jarmul, Founder at kjamistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to Q&amp;amp;A: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw"&gt;https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw&lt;/a&gt; (Second pyvideo tab)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="panel"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry></feed>