<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - David Pugh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_david-pugh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Python for economists (and other social scientists!)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/python-for-economists-and-other-social-scientist.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Pugh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:/scipy-2014/python-for-economists-and-other-social-scientist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have developed a curriculum for a three part, graduate level course on
computational methods designed to increase the exposure of graduate
students and researchers to basic techniques used in computational
modeling and simulation using the Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Together with theory and experimentation, computational modeling and
simulation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have developed a curriculum for a three part, graduate level course on
computational methods designed to increase the exposure of graduate
students and researchers to basic techniques used in computational
modeling and simulation using the Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Together with theory and experimentation, computational modeling and
simulation has become a &amp;quot;third pillar&amp;quot; of scientific enquiry. I am
developing a curriculum for a three part, graduate level course on
computational methods designed to increase the exposure of graduate
students and researchers in the College of Humanities and Social
Sciences at the University of Edinburgh to basic techniques used in
computational modeling and simulation using the Python programming
language. My course requires no prior knowledge or experience with
computer programming or software development and all current and future
course materials will be made freely available online via GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Tutorial: Introduction to Conda for (Data) Scientists</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-japan-2020/tutorial-introduction-to-conda-for-data-scientists.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Pugh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-30:/scipy-japan-2020/tutorial-introduction-to-conda-for-data-scientists.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is a Software Carpentry-style introduction to Conda for (data) scientists. This tutorial motivates the use of Conda as a development tool for building and sharing project specific software environments that facilitate reproducible (data) science workflows. Particular attention is given to using Conda to create reproducible environments with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is a Software Carpentry-style introduction to Conda for (data) scientists. This tutorial motivates the use of Conda as a development tool for building and sharing project specific software environments that facilitate reproducible (data) science workflows. Particular attention is given to using Conda to create reproducible environments with NVIDIA GPU dependencies (including environments for Horovod, TensorFlow, PyTorch, and NVIDIA RAPIDS) as well as a discussion of best practices for using Conda in HPC environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorial Prerequisites: Basic familiarity with Python programming and Bash shell concepts (i.e., basic commands, environment variables, etc). Familiarity installing NVIDIA CUDA Toolkit would be beneficial for NVIDIA GPU focused episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Scipy Japan 2020"></category></entry></feed>