<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ryan Roggenkemper</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ryan-roggenkemper.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>AI for Content Moderation at PayPal</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/ai-for-content-moderation-at-paypal.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Raghotham Sripadraj</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/ai-for-content-moderation-at-paypal.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - AI for Content Moderation at PayPal - presented by Raghotham Sripadraj &amp;amp; Ryan Roggenkemper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online content moderation at scale is a non trivial task especially with an ever changing landscape of hate, hate speech with changing geopolitical scenarios. Moderation platforms need to support multiple …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - AI for Content Moderation at PayPal - presented by Raghotham Sripadraj &amp;amp; Ryan Roggenkemper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online content moderation at scale is a non trivial task especially with an ever changing landscape of hate, hate speech with changing geopolitical scenarios. Moderation platforms need to support multiple typologies like - hate, sexually explicit, violence, bullying, spam and other toxic material. Add multi-language support for all typologies and it becomes an uphill task. In this talk we will cover the below topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is Text Content Moderation is hard? Why we need AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the available open-source datasets to train models?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the available pre-trained models for content moderation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why pre-trained models do not always work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data labelling strategies and how to leverage open data and models?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build multi-language support and challenges?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>