<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sam Craig</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sam-craig.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Implementing Strong Data Encryption in Python Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2022/implementing-strong-data-encryption-in-python-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sam Craig</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-03-21:/python-web-conf-2022/implementing-strong-data-encryption-in-python-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data encryption is essential for the modern business. It’s necessary for preventing data breaches, achieving regulatory compliance, and minimizing risk to customers, shareholders, and the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that most data encryption solutions are a band-aid that doesn’t meet a business’s actual needs. Encrypting data …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data encryption is essential for the modern business. It’s necessary for preventing data breaches, achieving regulatory compliance, and minimizing risk to customers, shareholders, and the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that most data encryption solutions are a band-aid that doesn’t meet a business’s actual needs. Encrypting data at some point in its lifecycle provides no benefit if the data is unencrypted when an attacker tries to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses the limitations of common encryption schemes and the threats that they do and don’t protect against. After discussing what doesn’t work, we’ll look at how to implement encryption that actually works in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PWC2022 attracted nearly 375 attendees from 36 countries and 21 time zones making it the biggest and best year yet. The highly engaging format featured 90 speakers, 6 tracks (including 80 talks and 4 tutorials) and took place virtually on March 21-25, 2022 on LoudSwarm by Six Feet Up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the conference can be found at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2022.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2022"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2022"></category></entry></feed>