<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_paul-wessel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building an Object-Oriented Python Interface for the Generic Mapping Tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/building-an-object-oriented-python-interface-for-the-generic-mapping-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leonardo Uieda</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/building-an-object-oriented-python-interface-for-the-generic-mapping-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are building a Python wrapper for the Generic Mapping Tools (GMT), a
set of command-line programs used across the Earth, Atmospheric, and
Ocean Sciences to process and visualize geographic data. At Scipy 2017,
we presented the project goals and an initial prototype. The feedback
received led to improvements in the design of the library, mainly the
creation of an object- oriented API. We will present the newest
developments including support for numpy arrays and pandas Dataframes,
interactive visualization in the Jupyter notebook using NASA WorldWind,
and more. Once again, we seek feedback from the community to guide us
moving forward.Presenter(s): Speaker: Leonardo Uieda, Department of
Geology and Geophysics, University of Hawaii at Manoa Speaker: Paul
Wessel, Department of Geology and Geophysics, University of Hawaii at
Manoa&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Bringing the Generic Mapping Tools to Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/bringing-the-generic-mapping-tools-to-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leonardo Uieda</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-14:scipy-2017/bringing-the-generic-mapping-tools-to-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Generic Mapping Tools (GMT) is an open-source software package widely used in the geosciences to process and visualize time series and gridded data. Maps generated by GMT are ubiquitous in scientific publications in areas such as seismology and oceanography. We present a new GMT Python wrapper library built by the GMT team. We will show the design plans, internal implementations, and demonstrate an initial prototype of the library. Our wrapper connects to the GMT C API using ctypes and allows input and output using data from numpy ndarrays and xarray Datasets. The library is still in early stages of design and implementation and we are eager for contributions and feedback from the Scipy community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>