<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_joshua-warner.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Image Analysis in Python with SciPy and Scikit Image</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/image-analysis-in-python-with-scipy-and-scikit-image.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Nunez-Iglesias</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:scipy-2019/image-analysis-in-python-with-scipy-and-scikit-image.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From telescopes to satellite cameras to electron microscopes, scientists are producing more images than they can manually inspect. This tutorial will introduce image analysis using the idea that &amp;quot;images are just NumPy arrays&amp;quot;. Then we will run through various fundamental image analysis operations (filters, morphology, segmentation), and finally we will demonstrate one or two advanced real-world examples. This tutorial is aimed at people who are familiar with NumPy, SciPy, and Matplotlib, but it does not require any previous knowledge of image analysis or image processing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Image Analysis in Python with SciPy and scikit-image</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/image-analysis-in-python-with-scipy-and-scikit-image.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stéfan van der Walt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-09:scipy-2018/image-analysis-in-python-with-scipy-and-scikit-image.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From telescopes to satellite cameras to electron microscopes, scientists
are producing more images than they can manually inspect. This tutorial
will introduce automated image analysis using the idea that &amp;quot;images are
just numpy arrays&amp;quot;. Then we will run through various fundamental image
analysis operations(filters, morphology, segmentation), and finally we
will demonstrate one or two advanced real-world examples. This tutorial
is aimed at people who are familiar with NumPy, SciPy, and Matplotlib,
but it does not require any previous knowledge of image analysis or
image processing.Presenter(s): Speaker: Stéfan van der Walt, University
of California, Berkeley Speaker: Juan Nunez-Iglesias, University of
Melbourne Speaker: Joshua Warner, Core Developer, Scikit
Image/University of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>