<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_alexandr-honchar.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Deep learning: the final frontier for time series analysis and signal processing?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-the-final-frontier-for-time-series-analysis-and-signal-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexandr Honchar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-the-final-frontier-for-time-series-analysis-and-signal-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep neural networks are becoming irreplaceable for analyzing most kinds
of data that humans supposed to exceed in - images, video, sounds,
texts. They can not only predict something based on some input but also
generate new images or sounds. Meanwhile, we are forgetting about
another very important source of data - signals (or time series, which
will be interchangeably here), that gets less hype in public but
benefits a lot from applying deep learning comparing to classical
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will review what are sources of time series and what
business goals are we solving while analyzing them, what are “old” tools
for analysis and how deep neural nets overcome them, we will learn the
latest trends and ruin some myths and, moreover, we will see how
generative models can be applied to the signal processing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, you’ll be able to boost your current solutions in
signal processing or time series analysis with deep learning. It will be
also interesting for practitioners in other areas, like computer vision
or NLP since we will discuss some concepts that are widely applicable.
Previous experience with time series is not required, but some
theoretical or practical experience with machine learning and/or neural
networks is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1716"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="biomedical-data-science"></category><category term="TimeSeries"></category><category term="signal-processing"></category><category term="neural network"></category><category term="finance"></category></entry></feed>