<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>KubeFlow: Pythonic Machine Learning at Scale on Kubernetes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/kubeflow-pythonic-machine-learning-at-scale-on-kubernetes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“KubeFlow marks the beginning of the end of the data scientist and/or
software engineer as disparate roles. Like DevOps has merged operations
and development, DataDevOps will consume data science.” - Philip Winder,
an engineer and consultant at Container Solutions &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://container"&gt;http://container&lt;/a&gt;-
solutions.com/tensorflow-on-kubernetes-kubeflow/ You've created and
tuned a machine learning model, using TensorFlow, PyTorch, or
scikit-learn - now what? How can you ensure that the model is deployed
to your DevOps team as production-ready code, and can scale as needed on
incoming data? How can you seamlessly migrate a model from your local
laptop / virtual machine to a hosted server on your cloud platform of
choice? This talk walks through the architecture of Kubeflow: a project
dedicated to answering those questions - and to making machine learning
on Kubernetes simple, portable and scalable. We will describe, in
detail, the three components of the project: * a JupyterHub platform
for creating and managing Jupyter notebook servers that are used by data
science and research groups; * a Tensorflow Customer Resource for
managing compute resources to a specific cluster size; and * a
Tensorflow Serving container to house the machine learning work. By the
end of this talk, you will have a firm understanding of why Kubernetes
would be useful to machine learning engineers, and how you can deploy
it, today, to support your predictive models.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflowPresenter(s"&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflowPresenter(s&lt;/a&gt;): Speaker: Paige Bailey,
Microsoft Speaker: David Aronchick, Google&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/kubeflow-pythonic-machine-learning-at-scale-on-kubernetes.html</guid></item></channel></rss>