<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Introduction to citizen data science with Home-Assistant</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pylondinium-2018/introduction-to-citizen-data-science-with-home-assistant.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Home-Assistant is an open-source python-3 platform home automation that is ideal for gathering, analysing and acting on data from a wide range of sources. Citizen-scientists can use Home-Assistant as their data backend, allowing them to integrate their project into their daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Oliver Crask</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-09:pylondinium-2018/introduction-to-citizen-data-science-with-home-assistant.html</guid></item><item><title>Particulater - Air quality monitoring for everyone</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/particulater-air-quality-monitoring-for-everyone.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A citizen data science project for monitoring an individuals exposure to pollutants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air pollution is getting worse across the world, but how does an
individual know how to reduce their exposure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be presenting my project that is focused on personalised air
quality monitoring. The battery-powered device measures air pollution,
as well as a series of other environmental variables. The data is then
transmitted wirelessly to my Home Assistant instance. This allows a user
to monitor, visualise and ultimately predict their daily exposure to
pollutants. In addition the Home Assistant integration makes it simple
to trigger actions based on their data. For example, flash a light in a
user’s home or send them a notification, if the pollutant concentration
rises. All that you need to make your own is a low cost micro-controller
and a few readily available components.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Oliver Crask</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-17:pycon-uk-2018/particulater-air-quality-monitoring-for-everyone.html</guid></item></channel></rss>