<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ursa Labs and Apache Arrow in 2019</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-miami-2019/ursa-labs-and-apache-arrow-in-2019.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-01-09:pydata-miami-2019/ursa-labs-and-apache-arrow-in-2019.html</guid><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Looking backward, looking forward</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/keynote-looking-backward-looking-forward.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/keynote-looking-backward-looking-forward.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Modern Open Source: Challenges and Opportunities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/modern-open-source-challenges-and-opportunities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern Open Source: Challenges and Opportunities
Community-led Open Source and You
This keynote gives a broad overview of the social, commercial and technological context of the open source software development.
In closing, Wes introduces URSA LABS, an innovation lab to support the creation of data science tools. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ursalabs.org"&gt;https://ursalabs.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wes McKinney has been creating fast, easy-to-use data wrangling and statistical computing tools, mostly in the Python programming language, since 2007. He is best known for creating the pandas project and writing the book Python for Data Analysis.
He is a PMC member of the Apache Arrow and Parquet projects in The Apache Software Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:pycon-thailand-2018/modern-open-source-challenges-and-opportunities.html</guid></item><item><title>Apache Arrow: A Cross-language Development Platform for In-memory Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/apache-arrow-a-cross-language-development-platform-for-in-memory-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses Apache Arrow project and its uses for high
performance analytics and system interoperability. I discuss the current
development initiative and future roadmap as it relates to the Python
data community.Presenter(s): Speaker: Wes McKinney, Two Sigma, pandas,
Apache Software Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-11:scipy-2018/apache-arrow-a-cross-language-development-platform-for-in-memory-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Python Data Ecosystem: Thoughts on Building for the Future</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2016/python-data-ecosystem-thoughts-on-building-for-the-future.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://de.slideshare.net/wesm/python-data-ecosystem-thoughts-on-building-for-the-future"&gt;http://de.slideshare.net/wesm/python-data-ecosystem-thoughts-on-building-for-the-future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-31:pydata-berlin-2016/python-data-ecosystem-thoughts-on-building-for-the-future.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>Keynote: My Data Journey with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/keynote-my-data-journey-with-python.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-09:scipy-2015/keynote-my-data-journey-with-python.html</guid><category>keynote</category></item><item><title>PyData: Data Analysis in Python with Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata/pydata-data-analysis-in-python-with-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming from the 2012 PyData Workshop, Wes McKinney, CTO and cofounder of
Lambda Foundry, gives us a tour of Pandas, a rich data manipulation tool
built on top of NumPy. Frustrated with working in R, Wes started
building Pandas in 2008 with a focus on fast, intuitive data structures
and data manipulation capabilities. The Pandas project has seen huge
growth in the last few years, and aims to be the ultimate data tool for
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-30:pydata/pydata-data-analysis-in-python-with-pandas.html</guid><category>numpy</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>PyGotham 2011: Powerful Pythonic data analysis using pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2011/pygotham-2011--powerful-pythonic-data-analysis-us.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will give an overview on the pandas data analysis package
for Python, its features, and plans for future development. I'll use
various interesting data sets to illustrate the features and give
motivation for how the tools can be applied in a diverse set of fields.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-16:pygotham-2011/pygotham-2011--powerful-pythonic-data-analysis-us.html</guid><category>dataanalysis</category><category>pandas</category><category>pygotham</category><category>pygotham2011</category></item><item><title>Time Series Manipulation with pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/time-series-manipulation-with-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll discuss major developments in pandas over the last
year related to time series handling and processing. This includes the
integration of the new NumPy datetime64, implementation of rich and high
performance resampling methods, better visualization, and a generally
cleaner, more intuitive and productive API. I will also discuss how
functionality from the defunct scikits.timeseries project has been
integrated into pandas, thus providing a unified, cohesive set of time
series tools for many different problem domains. Lastly, I'll give some
details about the pandas development roadmap and opportunities for more
people to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/time-series-manipulation-with-pandas.html</guid><category>General</category></item><item><title>Time Series Data Analysis with pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/time-series-data-analysis-with-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I'll give a brief overview of pandas basics for new
users, then dive into the nuts of bolts of manipulating time series data
in memory. This includes such common topics date arithmetic, alignment
and join / merge methods, resampling and frequency conversion, time zone
handling, moving window functions like moving mean and standard
deviation. A strong focus will be placed on working with large time
series efficiently using array manipulations. I'll also illustrate
visualization tools for slicing and dicing time series to make
informative plots. There will be several example data sets taken from
finance, economics, ecology, web analytics, or other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target audience for the tutorial includes individuals who already
work regularly with time series data and are looking to acquire
additional skills and knowledge as well as users with an interest in
data analysis who are new to time series. You will be expected to be
comfortable with general purpose Python programming and have a modest
amount of experience using NumPy. Prior experience with the basics of
pandas's data structures will also be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-17:scipy-2012/time-series-data-analysis-with-pandas.html</guid><category>advanced</category></item><item><title>Python-powered Business Analytics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2014/python-powered-business-analytics-pycon-apac-201.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll discuss how the modern Python stack has enabled
innovation in business analytics and general purpose small, medium, and
big data workflows. I'll talk about how the architecture of pandas and
related projects will need to adapt and grow to suit the needs of the
next decade of data analysis. Lastly, I will also give an overview of
how this all relates to my company: DataPad, an early-stage business
intelligence company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wes McKinney is an open-source Python hacker, author, and entrepreneur.
He's the creator of pandas and author of O'Reilly book Python for Data
Analysis. Currently, he is the Founder and CEO of DataPad, a new
analytics and business intelligence company based in San Francisco. He
has also been an occasional contributor to statsmodels. He started
building pandas at AQR Capital Management in response to the growing
need for better data manipulation tools in Python for business analytics
and data science use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-07:pycon-apac-2014/python-powered-business-analytics-pycon-apac-201.html</guid></item><item><title>Python in quantitative finance (#158)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/python-in-quantitative-finance-158.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python in quantitative finance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Wes McKinney (AQR Capital Management, LLC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will show how Python and libraries such as NumPy were
instrumental at AQR for building a robust research platform for
prototyping and implementing quantitative trading models. We will
discuss many different tools, including pandas, a new open source
library designed for analyzing common financial and economic data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A variety of examples will be presented to explore Python's current
status as a replacement for other statistical computing environments (as
compared with R, MATLAB, or other commercial and open-source statistical
products).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/python-in-quantitative-finance-158.html</guid><category>numpy</category><category>pandas</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category></item><item><title>pandas: Powerful data analysis tools for Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/pandas-powerful-data-analysis-tools-for-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pandas is a Python library providing fast, expressive data structures
for working with structured or relational data sets. In addition to
being used for general purpose data manipulation and data analysis, it
has also been designed to enable Python to become a competitive
statistical computing platform. In this talk, I will discuss the
library's features and show a variety of topical examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-09:pycon-us-2012/pandas-powerful-data-analysis-tools-for-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Data analysis in Python with pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/data-analysis-in-python-with-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will give a hands-on introduction to manipulating and
analyzing large and small structured data sets in Python using the
pandas library. While the focus will be on learning the nuts and bolts
of the library's features, I also aim to demonstrate a different way of
thinking regarding structuring data in memory for manipulation and
analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wes McKinney</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-07:pycon-us-2012/data-analysis-in-python-with-pandas.html</guid></item></channel></rss>