<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Python for Garbage Collection</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/florida-pycon-2017/using-python-for-garbage-collection.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the major things that my wife and I have looked for wherever we
move is natural beauty and a good collection of public green space. So,
when I walked by a park and creek reserve on the north end of our city,
only to find more trash than green space, I was mortified. Working
together with several individuals from Reddit we got the park to a
reasonably clean state, removing over 400 gallons of trash. The
experience made me realize, however, with over 480 parks, that as our
city grew we needed a more self-sustaining solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sharing the story on Reddit, one thing that struck me was how many
people were eager and capable of physically helping with the problem but
had insufficient supplies or funds, and how many people couldn’t
physically help, but were eager to throw money at the problem. I’m not
political, and I certainly don’t have the time or ability to clean up
480+ parks, but like many of you, I know how to throw some code
together. So I decided to build a tool that would connect those
individuals with the funds to help to those with the time and physical
ability. This talk is about how I created that tool, which consists of
REST API, Website, and Android/IOS application using only Python and
Open Source technologies. Finally, it is about how all of us as
programmers have the power to make a visibly positive impact in our
community even from the comfort and familiarity of our keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Timothy Crosley</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-07:florida-pycon-2017/using-python-for-garbage-collection.html</guid></item></channel></rss>