<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ivan-tsyganov.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>(Un)safe python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2017/unsafe-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivan Tsyganov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-16:pycon-russia-2017/unsafe-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every developer expects his app is vulnerability safe. But we all know that such applications do not exist, but we usually deal with not enough tested. This year the Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) has published TOP-10 most critical vulnerabilities of web applications. I'll tell you what it is and what was changed over the last 4 years from the moment of publication of the previous version. I'm going to explain which types of vulnerabilities are the developer's responsibility and which we can't influence on. I'll show how the popular frameworks help us to develop secure applications and in which situations they can't help.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Осторожно, DSL!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2016/ostorozhno-dsl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivan Tsyganov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-03:pycon-russia-2016/ostorozhno-dsl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Каждый разработчик рано или поздно сталкивается с предметно-ориентированными языками (DSL). Мы разберемся, зачем же нам нужны DSL, и какие проблемы они нам помогают решать. Поймем, в каких случаях нам стоит разрабатывать свой язык, а в каких — использовать уже существующий. Попробуем провести грань и решить, где у нас просто библиотека, а где — предметно ориентированный язык. Придумаем свой DSL и сравним различные подходы к работе с ним в Python. Увидим, как работают лексический и синтаксический анализаторы. Обязательно поговорим про то, как облегчить жизнь пользователям нашего языка. Как сделать информативными сообщения об ошибках? Как тестировать сценарии, написанные на нашем языке? На эти вопросы мы сможем дать ответ.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>