<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ellis Hughes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Can I Have a Word?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/can-i-have-a-word.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since its release, {gt} has won over the hearts of many due to its flexible and powerful table-generating abilities. However, in cases where office products were required by downstream users, {gt}'s potential remained untapped. That all changed in 2022 when Rich Iannone and I collaborated to add Word documents as an official output type. Now, data scientists can engage stakeholders directly, wherever they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me for an upcoming talk where I'll share my excitement about the new opportunities this update presents for the R community as well as future developments we can look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ellis Hughes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/can-i-have-a-word.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Be Kind, Rewind</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/be-kind-rewind.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where crafting a stunning, insightful data visualization is not just about the end product, but the journey. A world where every decision, every tweak, every step in your creative process is not just a fleeting moment, but a valuable artifact. {camcorder} is an innovative R package that revolutionizes the way you create and share your data visualizations. It not only allows you to preview your visualizations exactly as they will be saved but also records every plot you create, turning your creative process into a compelling narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discover the inspiration behind {camcorder}’s creation, its use, and explore the ways you can leverage it to tell captivating stories to your stakeholders. Are you ready to press play?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ellis Hughes</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/be-kind-rewind.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>