<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hands-on Satellite Imagery Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/hands-on-satellite-imagery-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Satellite data is more widely available than ever before, and it is now possible for the public to access sub-weekly and even daily imagery of the Earth's entire landmass. In this tutorial, gain hands-on experience exploring Planet’s publicly-available satellite imagery and using Python tools for geospatial and time-series analysis of medium- and high-resolution imagery data. Using free &amp;amp; open source libraries, learn how to perform foundational imagery analysis techniques and apply these techniques to real satellite data. At the end of the workshop, we’ll demonstrate how the skills you've learned can be applied to investigate real-world environmental and humanitarian challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samapriya Roy</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:scipy-2019/hands-on-satellite-imagery-analysis.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Hands-on Satellite Imagery Analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/hands-on-satellite-imagery-analysis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Satellite data is more widely available than ever before, and it is now
possible for the public to access sub-weekly and even daily imagery of
the Earth's entire landmass. In this tutorial, you will gain hands-on
experience exploring publicly-available satellite imagery and using
Python tools for geospatial and time-series analysis of medium- and
high-resolution imagery data. At the end of the workshop, you will apply
what you've learned to investigate real-world environmental and
humanitarian challenges. This tutorial is for intermediate Python
developers. It would help if learners attending this workshop also had
some familiarity with map data, but the instructors will not assume
background knowledge of satellite imagery or geo- data tools. Learners
will come away from the workshop with: - a solid understanding of
satellite imagery and geo-data concepts; - strategies for wrangling,
processing, and analyzing satellite imagery using several Python- based
open-source toolkits; - hands-on experience using satellite imagery to
better understand and address real-world challengesPresenter(s):
Speaker: Sara Safavi, Planet Speaker: Dana Bauer, Planet&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sara Safavi</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-10:scipy-2018/hands-on-satellite-imagery-analysis.html</guid></item><item><title>GIS for Python People</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/gis-for-python-people.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems like everyone is talking about GIS lately, but what exactly is
it, anyway? And more importantly: as a Python user, why should you care?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk's goal is twofold: first, to try and demystify the basic idea
of &amp;quot;GIS&amp;quot; for people who are interested in the topic and are coming from
a Python background. I'll cover general GIS concepts, talk about spatial
data, and what makes it unique. Second, to show how you might be able to
use and integrate GIS into your work. I'll go over some of the more
common Python tools available for working with GIS data, and show
examples of use-cases. Although I'll briefly touch on major GIS industry
players, my main focus will be on easily-accessible, free &amp;amp; open source
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an all-levels talk: like the title says, this is for &amp;quot;Python
People&amp;quot;! Whether you consider yourself a seasoned Python developer, an
enthusiastic fan, or are just getting started: you should be able to
learn something new while following along with the concepts &amp;amp; examples
I'll discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sara Safavi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-05:pytexas-2014/gis-for-python-people.html</guid></item></channel></rss>