<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Plan your next eclipse viewing with Jupyter and geopandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/plan-your-next-eclipse-viewing-with-jupyter-and-geopandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maps are powerful tools that we use every day. Python is well-equipped
to handle spatial data and with well documented robust libraries to help
you perform spatial analysis and create beautiful maps. In this talk,
we'll discover the fascinating world of spatial analysis by solving a
fun problem: where can we go to see an upcoming solar eclipse? Along the
way we'll learn about mapping topics like projections and coordinate
systems, best practices for map making, and intricacies of spatial data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/plan-your-next-eclipse-viewing-with-jupyter-and-geopandas.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Planea el próximo eclipse con Jupyter y geopandas.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/planea-el-proximo-eclipse-con-jupyter-y-geopandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Los mapas son herramientas poderosas que usamos todos los días. Python está bien equipado para manejar datos espaciales y tiene muchas bibliotecas para ayudarte a realizar un análisis espacial y crear hermosos mapas. En esta charla, descubriremos el fascinante mundo del análisis espacial resolviendo un problema divertido: ¿dónde podemos ir para ver el próximo eclipse solar? A lo largo del camino, aprenderemos sobre temas de mapeo como proyecciones y sistemas de coordenadas, mejores prácticas para hacer mapas y complejidades de datos espaciales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/planea-el-proximo-eclipse-con-jupyter-y-geopandas.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Map it with Python! Intro to GIS and Python mapping modules.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/north-bay-python-2018/map-it-with-python-intro-to-gis-and-python-mapping-modules.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maps are powerful tools that we use every day. Come learn about how
Python can be used to handle spatial data and create beautiful maps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-04:north-bay-python-2018/map-it-with-python-intro-to-gis-and-python-mapping-modules.html</guid></item><item><title>Intro to Spatial Analysis and Maps with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/intro-to-spatial-analysis-and-maps-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will introduce Python as a spatial problem solving and data visualization tool. To demonstrate the power of Python for spatial analysis, we will solve a spatial problem and make a beautiful map of our results. Along the way, we will discuss considerations when dealing with spatial data and the wide range of Python tools available for spatial analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christy Heaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/intro-to-spatial-analysis-and-maps-with-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>