<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Nix for Repeatable Python Environments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/using-nix-for-repeatable-python-environments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packaging and dependency management is foundational in software deployment, but is often implemented so that outcomes depend on state and are not repeatable. This has implications for reproducing computational experiments, which require repeatable deployment of environments whenever possible. For example, the popular package managers Conda and Pip are both examples of imperative and stateful implementations. In contrast, the Nix package manager is a functional package manager that implements fully repeatable environment deployment in a systematic manner. The talk will introduce the Nix package manager and demonstrate using Nix to generate repeatable Python environments as well as environments involving multiple languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Wheeler</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/using-nix-for-repeatable-python-environments.html</guid></item><item><title>Using Sumatra to Manage Numerical Simulations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/using-sumatra-to-manage-numerical-simulations-sc.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sumatra is a lightweight system for recording the history and provenance
data for numerical simulations. ... The speaker will provide an
introduction to Sumatra as well as demonstrate some typical usage
patterns and discuss achievable future goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authors: Davison, Andrew, CNRS (principal developer); Wheeler, Daniel,
NIST (speaker)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: Reproducible Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sumatra is a lightweight system for recording the history and provenance
data for numerical simulations. It works particularly well for
scientists that are in the intermediate stage between developing a code
base and using that code base for active research. This is a common
scenario and often results in a mode of development that mixes branching
for both code development and production simulations. Using Sumatra
avoids this unintended use of the versioning system by providing a
lightweight design for recording the provenance data independently from
the versioning system used for the code development. The lightweight
design of Sumatra fits well with existing ad-hoc patterns of simulation
management contrasting with more pervasive workflow tools, which can
require a wholesale alteration of work patterns. Sumatra uses a
straightforward Django-based data model enabling persistent data storage
independently from the Sumatra installation. Sumatra provides a command
line utility with a rudimentary web interface, but has the potential to
become a full web-based simulation management solution. During the talk,
the speaker will provide an introduction to Sumatra as well as
demonstrate some typical usage patterns and discuss achievable future
goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Wheeler</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:scipy-2013/using-sumatra-to-manage-numerical-simulations-sc.html</guid><category>numerical simulations</category><category>provenance</category><category>reproducibility</category><category>sumatra</category></item></channel></rss>