<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tuesday Lightning Talks (Write The Docs NA 2016)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/tuesday-lightning-talks-write-the-docs-na-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzwd/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbzwd/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0:00:00 Mike Jang - State of the Write the Docs Meetups
0:04:11 Elisa Sawyer - Writing THE Story
0:09:35 Kenzie Woodbridge - You Can Do Policy!
0:14:09 Jack Twilley - Better Mead Through the Power of Science
0:19:09 Laurel Nicholes - What is trusted content?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mike Jang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:write-the-docs-2016/tuesday-lightning-talks-write-the-docs-na-2016.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Start Your Own Write The Docs Meetup Group</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2015/start-your-own-write-the-docs-meetup-group.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Jang
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2015/writethedocs/sdmwwy/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2015/writethedocs/sdmwwy/&lt;/a&gt;
With just a little work, you can feel the joy of Write The Docs all year!
I started the Write The Docs PDX Meetup Group back in May of 2014, just after last year’s conference. As the only writer in my office, I often feel alone. At Write The Docs NA 2014 conference, I felt the joy of interacting with documentarians like myself, people who were facing similar challenges. I wanted to continue feeling that joy.
I’ll describe my experiences creating a Write The Docs Meetup group in Portland. I’ll show you how easy⃰ it is to create a Meetup group, attract members, get sponsors, find speakers, and make sure all members of your group feel welcome. I’ll tell you about the Meetups we’ve had, and what we learned from each other.
More importantly, I’ll lay out the ways you can continue the conversation we’ve had during WTD 2015. I’ll share my best practices for excellent Meetups for Documentarians.
⃰Yes, “easy” is a euphemism for a lot of hard work. But the people you’ll meet and the contacts that you’ll make can reward you and your company in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mike Jang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-19:write-the-docs-2015/start-your-own-write-the-docs-meetup-group.html</guid></item></channel></rss>