<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Ines Montani</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ines-montani.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to Ignore Most Startup Advice and Build a Decent Software Business</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/how-to-ignore-most-startup-advice-and-build-a-decent-software-business.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ines Montani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-26:/europython-2018/how-to-ignore-most-startup-advice-and-build-a-decent-software-business.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a great time to be a software developer. Platforms are steadily
becoming more mature, useful tools are released almost daily and things
that seemed hopelessly futuristic only a few years ago are suddenly
commercially viable. Despite this, the software world is awash with
bullshit. The success of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a great time to be a software developer. Platforms are steadily
becoming more mature, useful tools are released almost daily and things
that seemed hopelessly futuristic only a few years ago are suddenly
commercially viable. Despite this, the software world is awash with
bullshit. The success of the largest technology companies has led to a
very skewed set of lessons. This narrow focus is amplified by the
venture capital industry and the fact that nobody really knows what’s
going to happen next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is, none of this actually matters. The basics of creating
something useful and selling it for money remain the same. In this talk,
I’m not going to give you “one weird trick” or tell you to ~* just
follow your dreams *~. But I’ll share some of the things we’ve learned
from building a successful software company around commercial developer
tools and our open- source library spaCy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2018"></category></entry><entry><title>Large Language Models: From Prototype to Production</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/large-language-models-from-prototype-to-production.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ines Montani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/large-language-models-from-prototype-to-production.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Forum Hall on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/large-language-models-from-prototype-to-production"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/large-language-models-from-prototype-to-production&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown some impressive capabilities and their impact is the topic of the moment. What will the future look like? Are we going to only talk to bots? Will prompting replace programming? Or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — Forum Hall on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/large-language-models-from-prototype-to-production"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/large-language-models-from-prototype-to-production&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown some impressive capabilities and their impact is the topic of the moment. What will the future look like? Are we going to only talk to bots? Will prompting replace programming? Or are we just hyping up unreliable parrots and burning money? In this talk, I'll present visions for NLP in the age of LLMs and a pragmatic, practical approach for how to use Large Language Models to ship more successful NLP projects from prototype to production today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category><category term="Keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Reality Is Not an End-to-End Prediction Problem: Applied NLP in the Age of Generative AI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2024/reality-is-not-an-end-to-end-prediction-problem-applied-nlp-in-the-age-of-generative-ai.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ines Montani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-11-03:/pycon-fr-2024/reality-is-not-an-end-to-end-prediction-problem-applied-nlp-in-the-age-of-generative-ai.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) and in-context learning have introduced a new paradigm for developing natural language understanding systems: prompts are all you need! Prototyping has never been easier, but not all prototypes give a smooth path to production. In this talk, I'll share the most important lessons we've learned …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) and in-context learning have introduced a new paradigm for developing natural language understanding systems: prompts are all you need! Prototyping has never been easier, but not all prototypes give a smooth path to production. In this talk, I'll share the most important lessons we've learned from solving real-world information extraction problems in industry, and show you a new approach and mindset for designing robust and modular NLP pipelines in the age of Generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking down larger business problems into actionable machine learning tasks is one of the central challenges of applied natural language processing. I will walk you through example applications and practical solutions, and show you how to use LLMs to their fullest potential, how and where to integrate your custom business logic and how to maximize efficiency, transparency and data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon FR 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote - Ines Montani</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-india-2019/keynote-ines-montani.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ines Montani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-12:/pycon-india-2019/keynote-ines-montani.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="PyCon India 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>Incorporating GPT-3 into practical NLP workflows</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/incorporating-gpt-3-into-practical-nlp-workflows.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ines Montani</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/incorporating-gpt-3-into-practical-nlp-workflows.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show how large language models such as GPT-3 complement rather than replace existing machine learning workflows. Initial annotations are gathered from the OpenAI API via zero- or few-shot learning, and then corrected by a human decision maker using an annotation tool. The resulting annotations can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show how large language models such as GPT-3 complement rather than replace existing machine learning workflows. Initial annotations are gathered from the OpenAI API via zero- or few-shot learning, and then corrected by a human decision maker using an annotation tool. The resulting annotations can then be used to train and evaluate models as normal. This process results in higher accuracy than can be achieved from the OpenAI API alone, with the added benefit that you'll own and control the model for runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category></entry></feed>