<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>G.Tool: a Python-based DSL for managing information security governance information</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/gtool-a-python-based-dsl-for-managing-information-security-governance-information.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security professionals don't have great tools for managing their
governance programs (audit, risk, system descriptions, etc.) and
typically need to buy very expensive tools or resort to using Excel
spreadsheets. G.Tool is an opensource python based framework that uses
pyparsing to implement a user DSL and file ORM for building your
security governance tools without writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ben-sapiro-bio"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ben Sapiro Bio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the head of Security at Vision Critical (a SaaS company) and have
worked in both infosec consulting and operations since graduated from
b-school. I'm a regular contributor on the LiquidMatrix Podcast
(whenever we get around to recording it) and helps run BSidesTO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I built an internal tool (in Python) at work and it went
reasonably well to I decided so I decided to rebuild, from scratch, an
open source and generalized version of the tool to help security
professionals manage different information processes from audit
reporting to risk management and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a professional developer but I've dabbled with Python for
years. This is my first serious release in Python. Prior to this I
released an opensource tool called Binary Risk Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Sapiro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/gtool-a-python-based-dsl-for-managing-information-security-governance-information.html</guid></item></channel></rss>