<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_paul-bell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Low Cost GNSS Tide &amp; Sea Level Measurements - LoCTIPS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/low-cost-gnss-tide-sea-level-measurements-loctips.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Bell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-17:pycon-uk-2018/low-cost-gnss-tide-sea-level-measurements-loctips.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measuring Sea levels and tides using an ultra low cost Python driven logging system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent Natural Environment Research Council funded proof of concept
award to the UK's National Oceanography Centre successfully demonstrated
that Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) signals reflected off the
sea surface and received by very low cost (~£30) GPS receivers can be
used to estimate the difference in height between the GPS receiver and
the water. This represents a method of remotely sensing tidal elevations
and, if averaged over time, mean sea level. These could be routinely and
remotely measured at a cost that would allow unprecedented numbers of
systems to be deployed around the world by research departments of all
sizes and levels of funding. A second follow-on project is currently
underway to develop the concept further and produce a working prototype
system using a Raspberry Pi as the data logger and potentially also to
conduct the real-time processing required to extract the sea level
signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe the background to this concept of using GPS
signals for this purpose, and the early results from our test site in
Sligo Bay in the Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>