<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Giuseppe Angelo Porcelli</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_giuseppe-angelo-porcelli.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Boost productivity with generative AI and scalable development using Jupyter</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/boost-productivity-with-generative-ai-and-scalable-development-using-jupyter.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Angelo Porcelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/boost-productivity-with-generative-ai-and-scalable-development-using-jupyter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI/ML can make you a disruptive innovator in any industry. As an active sponsor and contributor to Project Jupyter, our goal at AWS is to help Jupyter become the best possible notebook platform for data science and machine learning. Join this session to learn about the latest innovations …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI/ML can make you a disruptive innovator in any industry. As an active sponsor and contributor to Project Jupyter, our goal at AWS is to help Jupyter become the best possible notebook platform for data science and machine learning. Join this session to learn about the latest innovations you can use anywhere your Jupyter Notebook runs to accelerate your development productivity. You will also learn how to increase ML development productivity by 10x with collaborative, and fully managed notebooks on Amazon SageMaker, providing the most comprehensive set of tools and fully managed infrastructure to help you build, train, and deploy ML models at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry></feed>