<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Predicting Real-Time Transaction Fraud Using Python and spark (Sponsored Talk)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-delhi-2019/predicting-real-time-transaction-fraud-using-python-and-spark-sponsored-talk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predicting transaction fraud in real-time is an important challenge due
to large data size, imbalanced target class, ever changing fraud MOs &amp;amp;
strict requirement for prediction inference speed which machine learning
models can help to solve. Using open source technologies &amp;amp; distributed
computing, Barclays has been developing solutions to reduce fraud losses
and limit adverse customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="transaction-fraud-model-development"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Transaction Fraud Model Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predicting transaction fraud of debit and credit card payments in
real-time is an important challenge, which new technologies and
state-of-art supervised machine learning models can help to solve. While
different supervised learning techniques, like Logistic Regression and
Neural Networks, have been used for many years, recent developments in
Deep Learning, Gradient Boosted Machines, and Recurrent Neural Networks,
have opened up a wealth of options that can provide significant
improvements over the existing models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="advantages-of-distributed-computing"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Advantages of Distributed Computing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the transaction volumes are humongous (billions of transaction per
year), non-distributed packages like numpy or pandas easily run out of
memory. Distributed computing solves this problem. Spark serves as a
solution to Raw data processing, Data Quality and Reconciliation and
most importantly Feature engineering where thousands of features are
being created and tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="real-challenges-with-fraud-data"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Real Challenges with fraud data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning techniques are in general well-suited for transaction
fraud, however, large data volumes (billions of transaction per year),
very imbalanced target class (rare events), ever changing fraud MOs, and
strict requirements for the prediction inference speed, mean that some
methods are better suited than others. With the help of open source
technologies like python and distributed computing using spark, Barclays
has been developing and testing different solutions to reduce fraud
losses and limit adverse customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main emphasis of the talk is to show how to train supervised
transaction fraud models that can be implemented and how these models
improve both customer experience and help to reduce fraud losses. The
presentation will show results of a machine learning model that is
operating in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will learn - how real-time transaction fraud models work
and the main challenges in transactions fraud modelling - how
distributed computing can come to an advantage - which supervised
machine learning techniques are most applicable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mayank Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-03:pydata-delhi-2019/predicting-real-time-transaction-fraud-using-python-and-spark-sponsored-talk.html</guid></item></channel></rss>