<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Testing Django applications with pytest</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/testing-django-applications-with-pytest.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Pelme</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/testing-django-applications-with-pytest.html</guid><category>testing</category><category>tdd</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>pytest: helps you write better Django apps</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2014/pytest-helps-you-write-better-django-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pytest is a full featured testing tool that can make your testing
experience better. This talk will introduce you to pytest and show how
easy it is to get started with pytest in your own project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good practices are crucial to effective testing. This talk will cover
Django testing best practices with a lot of concrete examples. It will
also discuss how to write faster tests and how to improve test run time
by running tests in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Pelme</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-15:djangocon-europe-2014/pytest-helps-you-write-better-django-apps.html</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to pytest</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/introduction-to-pytest.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pytest is a full featured testing tool that makes it possible to write
&amp;quot;pythonic&amp;quot; tests. This talk will introduce pytest and some of its unique
and innovative features. It will help you get started with pytest for
new or existing projects, by showing basic usage and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will show introduce pytest and show some unique and innovative
features. It will show how to get started using it and some of the most
important features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these features is the ability to write tests in a more “pythonic”
way by using the assert statement for assertions. Another feature in
pytest is fixtures – a way to handle test dependencies in a structured
way. This talk will introduce the concept of fixtures and show how they
can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No previous knowledge of pytest is required – this talk is for people
who are new to testing or has experience with other Python testing tools
such as unittest or Nose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Pelme</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-23:europython-2014/introduction-to-pytest.html</guid></item></channel></rss>