<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tensorflow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-japan-2019/tensorflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A hands-on introduction to TensorFlow 2.0. In this 3.5 hour tutorial, we will briefly introduce TensorFlow, then dive in to training neural networks. This tutorial is targeted at folks new to TensorFlow, and/or Deep Learning. Our goal is to help attendees get started efficiently and effectively, so they can continue learning on your own. Attendees will need a laptop with an internet connection, there is nothing to install in advance.
Prerequisites: Prior machine learning experience is not assumed. We will do our best to introduce relevant concepts as needed. The goal of our tutorial is not to teach you everything you need to know, but to get attendees started and overcome any initial barriers so they can continue learning on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio: Josh Gordon works on the TensorFlow team at Google, and teaches Applied Deep Learning at Columbia University. He has over a decade of machine learning experience to share. You can find him on Twitter at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/random_forests"&gt;https://twitter.com/random_forests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="connect-with-us"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Connect with us!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/enthought"&gt;https://twitter.com/enthought&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/Enthought/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Enthought/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/enthought"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/enthought&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josh Gordon</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-23:scipy-japan-2019/tensorflow.html</guid><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Getting Started with TensorFlow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/getting-started-with-tensorflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A friendly introduction to Deep Learning, taught at the beginner level.
We’ll work through introductory exercises across several domains -
including computer vision, natural language processing, and structured
data classification. We’ll introduce TensorFlow - the world’s most
popular open source machine learning library - preview the latest APIs
(including Eager Execution), discuss best practices, and point you to
recommended educational resources you can use to learn more.
Prerequisite skills: NumPyPresenter(s): Speaker: Josh Gordon, Google&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josh Gordon</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-09:scipy-2018/getting-started-with-tensorflow.html</guid></item></channel></rss>