<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Tomasz Choduń</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tomasz-chodun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Monolithic app to microservices transition is easy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pywaw-summit-2015/monolithic-app-to-microservices-transition-is-easy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tomasz Choduń</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-11-02:/pywaw-summit-2015/monolithic-app-to-microservices-transition-is-easy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk: Monolithic app to microservices transition is easy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microservices architecture is trendy right now ;) It's often a good choice for building sophisticated applications but on the other hand you have to be aware about difficulties with this architecture. What do you need to remember about if you have monolithic …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk: Monolithic app to microservices transition is easy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microservices architecture is trendy right now ;) It's often a good choice for building sophisticated applications but on the other hand you have to be aware about difficulties with this architecture. What do you need to remember about if you have monolithic app right now and want to move into microservices world? I would like to summarize what I've learned about this transition process recently. This presentation will shortly cover main issues you will have to solve during transition process and how Python can help here:This talk will be of greatest interest to everybody feeling responsible for architecture of Python systems they are working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tomasz Choduń. Experienced software developer and software architect. Was working with few startups (some of them successful;)) and quite big companies. Loves clean, readable code and nice software design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/TomaszChodu/pywaw-summit2015tomaszchodun-48752792"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/TomaszChodu/pywaw-summit2015tomaszchodun-48752792&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: For reuse of this video under a more permissive license please get in touch with us. The speakers retain the copyright for their performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://summit.pywaw.org"&gt;http://summit.pywaw.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyWaw Summit 2015"></category></entry></feed>