<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Abby Carey</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_abby-carey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Developing Flask Applications for Google Cloud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/developing-flask-applications-for-google-cloud.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abby Carey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/developing-flask-applications-for-google-cloud.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing Flask Applications for Google Cloud
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Abby Carey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build Flask apps for Cloud Run, one of Google Cloud's serverless platforms. To accelerate the Cloud Run development loop, we'll be using Cloud Code, an IDE plugin that makes working with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing Flask Applications for Google Cloud
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-30 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Abby Carey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build Flask apps for Cloud Run, one of Google Cloud's serverless platforms. To accelerate the Cloud Run development loop, we'll be using Cloud Code, an IDE plugin that makes working with Cloud Run easy. We'll also cover how to integrate products like Cloud SQL, Pub/Sub, and Secret Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>Am I a bad person Beginner mistakes with privacy and ownership</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2020/am-i-a-bad-person-beginner-mistakes-with-privacy-and-ownership.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Abby Carey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-10-24:/pytexas-2020/am-i-a-bad-person-beginner-mistakes-with-privacy-and-ownership.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Am I a bad person? Beginner mistakes with privacy and ownership
GDPR shook things up for tech in 2018. CCPA is doing the same. It’s our responsibility to respect our users’ data. But as beginners, sometimes we don’t know better. We’ll walk through morally grey mistakes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Am I a bad person? Beginner mistakes with privacy and ownership
GDPR shook things up for tech in 2018. CCPA is doing the same. It’s our responsibility to respect our users’ data. But as beginners, sometimes we don’t know better. We’ll walk through morally grey mistakes I’ve made when creating client-facing Flask apps and how to fix them up like a good netizen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Abby Carey
Abby is a Developer Advocate at Google Cloud. She's currently working on tooling and creating a better Python developer experience. Coming from a Technical Writing background, she has always had a passion for helping developers find solutions to their problems. In her down time, she tinkers with VR web development, studies Python fundamentals, and can't put down a good fan fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2020"></category></entry></feed>