<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_fabien-bochu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Grocker, a Python build chain for Docker</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/grocker-a-python-build-chain-for-docker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Fabien Bochu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/grocker-a-python-build-chain-for-docker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fabien Bochu - Grocker, a Python build chain for Docker
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/grocker-a-python-build-chain-for-docker"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/grocker-a-python-build-chain-for-docker&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grocker is a Docker build chain for Python. It transforms your Python
package into a self-contained Docker image which can be easily
deployed in a Docker infrastructure. Grocker also adds a Docker entry
point to easily start your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Polyconseil, we build Paris electric car sharing service: Autolib'.
This system is based on many services developed using web
technologies, Django and our own libraries to handle business logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packaging is already a difficult problem, deploying large Python
projects is even more difficult. When deploying on a live and user-
centric system like Autolib', you cannot rely on Pip and external PyPI
servers which might become unavailable and are beyond your control. In
the beginning we used classic Debian packaging: it was a maintenance
hell. It took hours to build our packages and update their metadata to
match our Python packages. So we switched to Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker allows us to have a unique item that is deployed in production
systems: code updates are now atomic and deterministic! But before
deploying the Docker image, you need to build it. That's where Grocker
comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grocker is a Docker build chain for Python. It will transform your
Python package into a self-contained Docker image which can be easily
deployed in a Docker Infrastructure. Grocker also adds a Docker entry
point to easily start your application.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>