<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ralf-gommers.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Inside NumPy: Preparing for the Next Decade</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/inside-numpy-preparing-for-the-next-decade.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ralf Gommers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/inside-numpy-preparing-for-the-next-decade.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, and for the first time since its creation, NumPy has been operating with dedicated funding. NumPy developers think it has invigorated the project and its community. But is that true, and how can we know? We will give an overview of the actions we've taken to improve the sustainability of the NumPy project and its community. We will draw some lessons from a first year of grant-funded activity, discuss key obstacles faced, attempt to quantify what we need to operate sustainably, and present a vision for the project and how we plan to realize it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The evolution of array computing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2019/the-evolution-of-array-computing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ralf Gommers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-10:pydata-amsterdam-2019/the-evolution-of-array-computing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: SciPy 1.0 and Beyond - a Story of Code and Community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/keynote-scipy-10-and-beyond-a-story-of-code-and-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ralf Gommers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-11:scipy-2018/keynote-scipy-10-and-beyond-a-story-of-code-and-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From humble beginnings in 2001, the SciPy library has grown into one of
the cornerstones of the scientific Python ecosystem, and it recently had
a milestone 1.0 release. In this talk I'd like to explore the road to
that 1.0 release, as well as some questions and ideas about what's next
for the project and community. How do we grow and sustain the project in
the future? What is happening around sustainability of projects in the
ecosystem? And what does this mean for users and aspiring
contributors?Presenter(s): Speaker: Ralf Gommers, FP Innovations, Scion&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="keynote"></category></entry></feed>