<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Thorsten Kranz</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_thorsten-kranz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Delivering AI at Scale</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/delivering-ai-at-scale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Severin Schmitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/delivering-ai-at-scale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows our yellow vans, trucks and planes around the world. But do you know how data drives our business and how we leverage algorithms and technology in our core operations? We will share some “behind the scenes” insights on Deutsche Post DHL Group’s journey towards a Data-Driven …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows our yellow vans, trucks and planes around the world. But do you know how data drives our business and how we leverage algorithms and technology in our core operations? We will share some “behind the scenes” insights on Deutsche Post DHL Group’s journey towards a Data-Driven Company.
• Large-Scale Use Cases: Challenging and high impact Use Cases in all major areas of logistics,
including Computer Vision and NLP
• Fancy Algorithms: Deep-Neural Networks, TSP Solvers and the standard toolkit of a Data
Scientist
• Modern Tooling: Cloud Platforms, Kubernetes , Kubeflow, Auto ML
• No rusty working mode: small, self-organized, agile project teams, combining state of the art
Machine Learning with MLOps best practices
• A young, motivated and international team – German skills are only “nice to have”
But we have more to offer than slides filled with buzzwords. We will demonstrate our passion for our work, deep dive into our largest use cases that impact your everyday life and share our approach for a timeseries forecasting library - combining data science, software engineering and technology for efficient and easy to maintain machine learning projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category></entry></feed>