<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Brian McNamara</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Best Practices for Using Python to Power Serverless Applications (Sponsor: Capital One)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/best-practices-for-using-python-to-power-serverless-applications-sponsor-capital-one.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital One uses Python to power a large number of serverless
applications to improve developer experience and increase customer
value. Because Python enables fast development cycles, engineers and
data scientists at Capital One have more time to focus on delighting our
customers. Our Python development is also more potent on serverless as
it eliminates multiple overhead requirements. In this talk, we will
cover best practices we've learned along the way for using Python to
build serverless solutions to enable a fast, intuitive and iterative
developer experience for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streaming data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will learn the techniques and tools available when using
Python to build a production-grade serverless system complete with
observability and development practices baked in without ever
provisioning a server. The presentation will feature a demonstration of
Python-based AWS Lambda functions-as-a-service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian McNamara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-20:/pycon-us-2023/best-practices-for-using-python-to-power-serverless-applications-sponsor-capital-one.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Python Powered Serverless Observability (Sponsor: Capital One)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/python-powered-serverless-observability-sponsor-capital-one.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.capitalone.com/tech/open-source/?utm_campaign=%7Bcampaign%7D&amp;amp;utm_adgroup=%7Badgroup%7D&amp;amp;utm_keyword=capital%20one%20open%20source&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAuNGuBhAkEiwAGId4agbGyBFD9IwTS1Jnii6jaj-90H8_o6rau7CIj-0ZQeYCGl8kqj86hhoCPEQQAvD_BwE"&gt;Capital
One&lt;/a&gt;
for a presentation about Python and how it continues to power the
majority of the serverless world. From each of the major cloud providers
and across functions to big data, the common denominator is Python. This
means that a growing segment of Python developers are serverless
developers as well. In this session, we’ll explore the community
libraries that exist to improve application observability. We will walk
through&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Python to build an example service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveling up the observability through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telemetry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observability using cloud-native services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observability using Open Telemetry (OTEL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step-by-Step Instrumentation of code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an attendee of this session, you’ll walk away with an understanding
of how to approach making your serverless development observable by
design and what some of the basic tools available to you look like as
they function and you scale your services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian McNamara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-16:/pycon-us-2024/python-powered-serverless-observability-sponsor-capital-one.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>