<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Design and Implementation of pyPRISM: A Polymer Liquid-State Theory Framework</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/design-and-implementation-of-pyprism-a-polymer-liquid-state-theory-framework.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polymer Reference Interaction Site Model (PRISM) theory describes the
equilibrium spatial-correlations, thermodynamics, and structure of
liquid-like polymer systems and macromolecular materials. Here, we
present a Python-based, open-source framework, pyPRISM, for conducting
PRISM theory calculations. pyPRISM provides data structures, functions,
and classes that streamline predictive PRISM calculations and can be
extended for use in other tasks such as the coarse-graining of atomistic
simulation force-fields or the modeling of experimental scattering data.
The goal of providing this framework is to reduce the barrier to
correctly and appropriately using PRISM theory and to provide a platform
for rapid calculations of the structure and thermodynamics of polymeric
fluids and nanocomposites.Presenter(s): Speaker: Tyler Martin, NIST
Author: Thomas Gartner, University of Delaware Author: Ronald Jones,
NIST Author: Chad Snyder, NIST Author: Arthi Jayaraman, University of
Delaware&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tyler Martin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/design-and-implementation-of-pyprism-a-polymer-liquid-state-theory-framework.html</guid></item><item><title>Designing a Python-based Monte Carlo Tool for Generating Non-Equilibrium Semi-Crystalline Polymer Configurations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/designing-a-python-based-monte-carlo-tool-for-generating-non-equilibrium-semi-crystalline-polymer-configurations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Semi-crystalline polymers are a class of polymers which are used in applications ranging from piping to photovoltaics to food packaging. Despite their near-ubiquitous use, our understanding of semi-crystalline polymer microstructure and its connection to mechanical properties is far from complete. While measuring the mechanical properties of material systems using Molecular Dynamics simulations is routine, generating the initial conditions for semi-crystalline polymers is difficult due to their non-equilibrium, kinetically trapped nature. In this contribution, I discuss the development of a python-based simulation tool which uses an adapted Configurational Bias Monte Carlo technique to “grow” coarse-grained representations of semi-crystalline polymer systems. Specifically, I will discuss the process of developing a performant and flexible simulation tool for materials simulation using various tools in the python ecosystem including NumPy, Cython, VTK, and various profiling tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tyler Martin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-18:scipy-2017/designing-a-python-based-monte-carlo-tool-for-generating-non-equilibrium-semi-crystalline-polymer-configurations.html</guid><category>monte carlo</category></item></channel></rss>