<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Big Data Analytics with Python using Stratosphere</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2014/big-data-analytics-with-python-using-stratosphere.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stratosphere.eu/"&gt;Stratosphere&lt;/a&gt; is a distributed platform for
advanced big data analytics. It features a rich set of operators,
advanced, iterative data flows, an efficient runtime, and automatic
program optimization. We present Stratophere's new Python programming
interface. It allows Python developers to easily get their hands on Big
Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stratosphere.eu/"&gt;Stratosphere&lt;/a&gt; is implemented in Java. In
2013 we introduced support for writing Stratosphere programs in Scala.
Since Scala also runs in the Java JVM the language integration was easy
for Scala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2013, we started to develop a generic language binding framework
for Stratosphere to support non-JVM languages such as Python,
JavaScript, Ruby but also compiled languages such as C++. The language
binding framework uses &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/protobuf/"&gt;Google’s Protocol
Buffers&lt;/a&gt; for efficient data
serialization and transportation between the languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since many “Data Scientists” and machine learning experts are using
Python on a daily basis, we decided to use Python as the reference
implementation for Stratosphere’s language binding feature. Our talk at
the EuroPython 2014 will present how Python developers can leverage the
Stratosphere Platform to solve their big data problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce the most important concepts of Stratosphere such as the
operators, connectors to data sources, data flows, the compiler,
iterative algorithms and more. Stratosphere is a mature, next generation
big-data analytics platform developed by a vibrant &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/stratosphere/stratosphere"&gt;open-source
community&lt;/a&gt;. The system
is available under the Apache 2.0 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project started in 2009 as a joint research project of multiple
universities in the Berlin area (Technische Universität, Humboldt
Universität and Hasso-Plattner Institut). Nowadays it is an award
winning system that has gained worldwide attention in both research and
industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note to the program committee: As mentioned, the development of the
Python language binding of Stratosphere has started a few months ago,
therefore, the code is not yet in the main development branch. However,
we are already able to execute the “Hello World” of big data, the “Word
Count” example using the Python interface. See this example in the
development branch:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/filiphaase/stratosphere/blob/langbinding/stratosphere-addons/stratosphere-language-binding/src/main/python/eu/stratosphere/language/binding/wordcountexample/WordCountPlan.py"&gt;https://github.com/filiphaase/stratosphere/blob/langbinding/stratosphere-addons/stratosphere-language-binding/src/main/python/eu/stratosphere/language/binding/wordcountexample/WordCountPlan.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact us if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chesnay Schepler</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-25:europython-2014/big-data-analytics-with-python-using-stratosphere.html</guid></item></channel></rss>