<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Chad Carlson</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_chad-carlson.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Sponsored Talk: Production Django on Platform.sh: reaching operational maturity in days, not years</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2022/sponsored-talk-production-django-on-platformsh-reaching-operational-maturity-in-days-not-years.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chad Carlson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-10-18:/djangocon-us-2022/sponsored-talk-production-django-on-platformsh-reaching-operational-maturity-in-days-not-years.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delivering Django applications doesn’t just mean deployment. It means clearly defining
a delivery lifecycle so that updates and upgrades are consistently tested and packaged,
infrastructure is reliably provisioned, and deployed production code comes with a level
of observability that makes responding to problems feasible. Throughout it all, it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delivering Django applications doesn’t just mean deployment. It means clearly defining
a delivery lifecycle so that updates and upgrades are consistently tested and packaged,
infrastructure is reliably provisioned, and deployed production code comes with a level
of observability that makes responding to problems feasible. Throughout it all, it needs
to be secure and increasingly compliant, with those same standards replicated for all of
the apps important to your organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This real need can lead organizations to grow “platform teams”, or “Cloud Centers of
Excellence” - an interdisciplinary group of people tasked with defining, creating and
maintaining a high level of operational standards so complexity can be managed, drift is
minimized, and so everything stays relatively stable as technologies deprecate and
people off- and on-board. The thing is, implementing stability in-house is an expensive
moving target - in time, money, and environmental impact. Deprecating tools and
essential people with too many responsibilities leaving the organization will have you
reinventing the wheel forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, I’ll show you how Platform.sh can allow your team to deploy updates and
upgrades that are secure, compliant, stable, and consistently tested. We’ll explore ways
that our tooling provides insights into your code’s performance, all while providing your
teams with clearly defined lifecycles and guardrails that ensure standards are replicated
for all your organization’s apps. And for far less money and time than trying to build it
in-house.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2022"></category></entry></feed>