<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_mark-ramm-christensen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>A Python Takeover</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/a-python-takeover.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Ramm-Christensen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/a-python-takeover.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Mark Ramm-Christensen - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I started working on SourceForge with a couple of python
developers. Back then the site was written in PHP and was in some ways
buried in technical debt. Everything is different today, we have a
complete set of tools for Ticket tracking, Wiki documents, Git,
Mercurial, Subversion, and IRC - all written in Python, and now released
as open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how the amazing libraries, tools, and talent in the
Python web community has radically changed an established company, and
allowed us to reinvent sourceforge.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will go over our tech stack, talk about the libraries we used,
the way we solved scalability, internationalization, and performance
issues issues. Ultimately we know that without python, we could not have
built a flexible plugin based system, and gotten permission from
management to open source it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="python,"></category><category term="sourceforge"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Relate or !Relate</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/relate-or-relate.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Ramm-Christensen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/relate-or-relate.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Mark Ramm-Christensen - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To Relate or Not to Relate, that is the question raised by the NoSQL
movement. There is a lot of buzz about Couch, Casandra, MongoDB, and
other non relational databases, and at the same time there are decades
of hard work that's gone into optimizing databases built around the
relational model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would actually argue that there is no such thing as a NoSQL database -
there are a variety of compelling options to relational database - each
of which have different features and different performance
characteristics. So no one- sized fits all comparison will do. So, I'll
try to outline a general taxonomy for persistence mechanisms, and then
proceed to comparing relational DB's to their new friends in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will contain quite a few stories from the trenches with
CouchDB, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, Tokyo Cabinet, ZODB, and other
databases, and will help you think about the data storage needs of your
applications in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="database"></category><category term="nosql"></category><category term="optimizing"></category><category term="performance"></category></entry></feed>