<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Keynote: Mark Ramm</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-mark-ramm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Ramm delivers keynote address: &amp;quot;Building a better framework - A Turbogears guy on what Django should learn from Zope.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Ramm</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-mark-ramm.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>keynote</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>Keynote: What to build. How to build it. Python can help!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2012/keynote-what-to-build-how-to-build-it-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's been a lot of buzz about &amp;quot;Lean Startups,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Customer
Development,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Business Model Generation&amp;quot; and related topics lately. And
there is a real transformation in the way we design and build products
at work behind all that buzz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of buzz about “Lean Startups,” “Customer
Development,” “Business Model Generation” and related topics lately. And
there is a real transformation in the way we design and build products
at work behind all that buzz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the fundamental principle behind all of them is applying scientific
and experimental methodologies to product design decision making. The
tools of Lean Startups are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data collection and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing hypothesis and models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating experiments to test those models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning from those experiments, and refining/redesigning the model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately Python is a great tool for those looking to apply data
science to product design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python can help with everything from statistical analysis, to rapid
development of viable products, to the creation of complex models that
can be used to tweak the levers of growth, and it’s easy to combine
these with off the shelf tools that help you analyze traffic patterns
and figure out what product changes actually make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Ramm</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-08-21:pycon-au-2012/keynote-what-to-build-how-to-build-it-python.html</guid></item><item><title>To relate or not to relate, that is the question (#99)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--to-relate-or-not-to-relate--that-is-t.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To relate or not to relate, that is the question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Mark Ramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of buzz about Couch, Casandra, MongoDB, and other non
relational databases, and at the same time there are decades of hard
work that's gone into optimizing databases built around the relational
model. This talk will focus on comparing relational DB's to their new
friends in practice, and on providing practical tools for deciding
what's right for your project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Ramm</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--to-relate-or-not-to-relate--that-is-t.html</guid><category>database</category><category>nosql</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category></item><item><title>An (biased) survey of the python web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--an--biased--survey-of-the-python-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An (biased) survey of the python web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Mark Ramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may be BDFL of one framework, but that's also why I pay attention to
the whole ecosystem. From the release of Plone 4, TurboGears 2, Django
1.2 and Pylons 1 ,it's been an interesting year. And things like
html5lib, an updated WSGI spec, and a contender for the next generation
WSGI have all made things interesting. Come explore the wild and dynamic
jungle that I call &amp;quot;the python web toolkit.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will not teach people to use python to make websites. It's to
teach people who already use python, that there are lots of different
tools out there, and to help us all get some perspective on the python
web toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005 Pycon had the great PyWebOff, and while this talk won't be about
throwing Twisted into a cage match with Zope3, or setting Flask up in a
fight to the death against web.py, it will one again provide an attempt
to survey the full landscape of the python web world, and to see how far
we've come in the last 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've definitely come a long way. Django has brought over many converts
to Python, google released app engine with python as the first supported
language, and there are quite a few sites in the top 100 using python to
serve up dynamic content to hundreds of millions of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it hasn't all been good either, there's more fragmentation than
ever. We've also got more half finished libraries, and broken framework
extensions, and abandoned projects littering up the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Ramm</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--an--biased--survey-of-the-python-web.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>web</category><category>webframeworks</category></item><item><title>Scaling Python past 100</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--scaling-python-past-100.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scaling Python past 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Mark Ramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sourceforge.net has been in the top 100 sites on the internet, and we
discovered that python was easily able to scale up to handle that
traffic. In fact Python is now the core language for all new features,
and is taking over all of sourceforge.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path from legacy PHP to modern python tools has been long an bumpy,
and this is the story of how we took Python from a single prototype
site, to the core technology driving SourceForge.net. I will discuss the
mistakes we made along the way, the benefits that sold python, and the
real secret behind our python transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we abused libraries for fun and profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How a major mistake made us look good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the python community worked for us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we couldn't have done it without Django AND TurboGears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Ramm</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--scaling-python-past-100.html</guid><category>casestudy</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>scalability</category><category>sourceforge</category><category>turbogears</category></item><item><title>State of Pylons/TurboGears 2/repoze.bfg</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--state-of-pylons-turbogears-2-repoze-b.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;State of Pylons/TurboGears 2/repoze.bfg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Chris McDonough, Ben Bangert, and Mark Ramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A three-for-one talk by the main developers of three popular Python web
frameworks! We'll (very) briefly cover the state of each of our
individual frameworks and communities, and then we'll describe the
results of our efforts to work together and share code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pylons is a popular, lightweight Python web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TurboGears 2 is a full-stack framework built atop Pylons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;repoze.bfg is a moderately popular, lightweight Python web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main developers and community leaders of these frameworks have been
working together and sharing as much as possible over the course of
roughly the last year. We'll very briefly describe to the audience the
states of our individual efforts, then we'll discuss how we intend to
move forward and share more code and effort in the year to come. The
talk will be more socially- oriented than technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's unusual for open source code and communities to bridge minor
perceived differences in scope and style and to start sharing code and
ideas openly. If you're a user of any of these frameworks, you'll want
to be present for this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ben Bangert</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--state-of-pylons-turbogears-2-repoze-b.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>pylons</category><category>pyramid</category><category>repoze.bfg</category><category>turbogears</category></item></channel></rss>