<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Swati Gharse</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_swati-gharse.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Llama V2 in Azure AI for Finetuning, Evaluation and Deployment from the Model Catalog</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2023/llama-v2-in-azure-ai-for-finetuning-evaluation-and-deployment-from-the-model-catalog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Swati Gharse</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/pytorch-conference-2023/llama-v2-in-azure-ai-for-finetuning-evaluation-and-deployment-from-the-model-catalog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Llama 2 is now available in the model catalog in Azure Machine Learning. The model catalog in AzureML is your hub for foundation models. Azure native support for Llama 2 in the model catalog enables you use these models, without having to manage any of the infrastructure or environment …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Llama 2 is now available in the model catalog in Azure Machine Learning. The model catalog in AzureML is your hub for foundation models. Azure native support for Llama 2 in the model catalog enables you use these models, without having to manage any of the infrastructure or environment dependencies. It provides out-of-the-box support for model finetuning and evaluation,  and includes options for optimizer libraries like DeepSpeed and ORT (ONNX RunTime), which speed up fine-tuning, and LoRA (Low-Rank Adaptation of Large Language Models), which greatly reduces memory and compute requirements for fine-tuning. Deployments of Llama 2 models in Azure have Azure AI Content Safety integrated by default, offering a built-in layered approach to safety, and following responsible AI best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2023"></category></entry></feed>