<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Testing: Choose Your Weapons</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2013/testing-choose-your-weapons.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good suite of tests is a programmer's best friend. But a poorly
designed testing strategy can result in tests that are unwieldy,
fragile, and above all no fun to write or maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will offer a smorgasbord of testing ideas, ranging from simple
tips and tricks to fully-fledged testing frameworks for Python. We will
touch on automation, table-based testing, round-trip testing, UI
testing, property checking, testing Twisted Python applications, and
more. Be prepared to think outside the box, as we will see that testing
is an area where creativity and pragmatism pay off better than following
a rigid set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone should come away with a few new ideas, and renewed enthusiasm
for test-driven development!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Todd Owen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-06:pycon-au-2013/testing-choose-your-weapons.html</guid></item><item><title>Ansible, Simplicity, and the Zen of Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/ansible-simplicity-and-the-zen-of-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a configuration management tool, written in Python, that has
taken the world of IT automation by storm. Its most remarkable quality
is simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zen of Python is a set of aphorisms which capture the design
philosophy of the Python language, one being &amp;quot;Simple is better than
complex&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll look at some of the concrete ways that Ansible
embodies the Zen of Python, in an attempt to unravel the true meaning of
the sometimes cryptic aphorisms. Along the way we will consider why
simplicity is a such good thing, yet tantalisingly out of reach in most
software projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Todd Owen</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/ansible-simplicity-and-the-zen-of-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>