<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Santiago Soler</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_santiago-soler.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning Talks (PyCascades 2023)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/lightning-talks-pycascades-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jim De la Hunt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-19:/pycascades-2023/lightning-talks-pycascades-2023.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jim De la Hunt
Lightning Talk: Global domain names and email addresses, or, email me at जिम&amp;#64;डाटामेल.भारत . Alerting people that non-ASCII domain names are in use and spreading. Our code should be able to handle them. Python tools and online resources …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jim De la Hunt
Lightning Talk: Global domain names and email addresses, or, email me at जिम&amp;#64;डाटामेल.भारत . Alerting people that non-ASCII domain names are in use and spreading. Our code should be able to handle them. Python tools and online resources to get domain names and email right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Wes Lord
Lightning Talk: The surprising alternative to git rebase (it's git reset)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Sam Edwardes
Lightning Talk: How to do &amp;quot;everything&amp;quot; with Pydantic. I want walk the audience through using Pydantic to do a few really cool things including: (1) parsing JSON into python objects, (2) validating data, (3) refactoring your code, (4) talking to a SQL database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Tony Fast
Lightning Talk: Important digital accessibility language, standards, and tools for designing inclusive technology . Attendees will learn community and industry standards for auditing and understanding web content accessibility guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Mariatta Wijaya
Lightning Talk: PyCon US 2023: the 20 years celebration special. I will tell attendees about info about PyCon US 2023: registration, schedule, venue, etc. While this year's travel grant application has closed, it's still worth knowing that it exists and I will share how attendees can stay updated on PyCon US news so they can apply for next year's travel grants. I'll also share how attending PyCon has impacted my personal growth and career and opens up opportunities, and I would love for more people to have the same experience by attending PyCon US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Robin Reynolds-Haertle
Lightning Talk: Yellowstone Codera - Python programming puzzles with a Yellowstone theme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Santiago Soler
Lightning Talk: During this lightning talk I'll present Pooch, an open-source Python library for downloading and catching data files from the web. It provides easy ways to download data files from different protocols, cache it locally, check their integrity through checksums, and more. It also provides tools for downloading collections of files, useful for managing sample datasets for scientific and data-processing Python packages. Currently Pooch is being used by well-known libraries like SciPy, scikit-learn, Xarray and scikit-image, amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Andres Pineda
Lightning Talk: Invite to Pycon Latam&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCascades 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Pooch: a friend to fetch your data files</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/pooch-a-friend-to-fetch-your-data-files.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Santiago Soler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/pooch-a-friend-to-fetch-your-data-files.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pooch is a Python library that can download and locally cache files from the web without hassle. Novices can use it to simply download files in one line of code and focus on the data. Package maintainers can use it to provide sample datasets to their users, in examples …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pooch is a Python library that can download and locally cache files from the web without hassle. Novices can use it to simply download files in one line of code and focus on the data. Package maintainers can use it to provide sample datasets to their users, in examples and tutorials, as libraries like SciPy, scikit-image, napari and MetPy do. During this talk, we'll show you how you can use the different features that Pooch offers and also how you can extend its capabilities by writing your own downloaders or post-processors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>