<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_e-franchi.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Complex and social network analysis in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/complex-and-social-network-analysis-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>E Franchi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-04:europython-2012/complex-and-social-network-analysis-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] E Franchi - 3 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A complex network is a network that has non trivial topological
properties, i.e., properties hinting the presence of elaborate
relationships among the actors, opposed to simple networks such as
regular lattices or random graphs. Examples of complex networks are most
social, technological or biological networks, such as the internet, the
web, a professional network, the nervous system of an animal or the
contact network of any social networking system. Network analysis has
many practical applications, e.g., ranking or grouping items on the
basis of their position in the network, and is also the basis of some
collective intelligence and data mining techniques. Recently network
analysis is also applied to security problems in the form of trust
networks. Along with the basic concepts, working Python code is
presented, both using existing network analysis Python tools and numeric
packages. The focus is mainly placed on code, which will be shown and
discussed together with the theory, with the idea that running code and
simulations are easier to understand that formal maths. Since complex
network datasets are typically huge, some high-level optimization
techniques are also discussed. Although formulas are kept at the
minimum, some maths skills are required along with basic knowledge of
the Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>