<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Christoph Scheuch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_christoph-scheuch.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Empowering Reproducible Finance through Tidy Finance with R and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/empowering-reproducible-finance-through-tidy-finance-with-r-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christoph Scheuch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/empowering-reproducible-finance-through-tidy-finance-with-r-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidy Finance merges cutting-edge research in financial economics with the principles of transparency and reproducibility, providing a novel, open-source toolkit available in both R and Python. This multi-language approach simplifies financial data analysis while teaching best practices for reproducible research, integrating narrative with clean, easy-to-read code and replicable results …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidy Finance merges cutting-edge research in financial economics with the principles of transparency and reproducibility, providing a novel, open-source toolkit available in both R and Python. This multi-language approach simplifies financial data analysis while teaching best practices for reproducible research, integrating narrative with clean, easy-to-read code and replicable results. By promoting transparent code, public sharing, and multi-language support, Tidy Finance equips researchers, educators, and students with critical tools that foster a more reproducible academic environment. This talk will explore the development and impact of Tidy Finance, offering inspiration for attendees from various fields to advance open-source and reproducibility in their own work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>