<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Maya Costantini</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Introduction to Sigstore: cryptographic signatures made easier</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-fr-2023/introduction-to-sigstore-cryptographic-signatures-made-easier.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last few years have seen a significant raise in Supply Chain attacks targeting third party software used in larger projects. With the need for developers to attest of the integrity and provenance of their software dependencies, alternatives have emerged to make tracing software back to the source more accessible, without a need for specific knowledge of cryptographic protocols used for generating and verifying artifact signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Sigstore (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sigstore.dev/"&gt;https://www.sigstore.dev/&lt;/a&gt;) is a new standard for signing, verifying and protecting software. This talk will provide an introduction to Sigstore, explaining the different components the project is built upon and how developers can use it to sign and verify software artifacts (Python packages, container images...) in a secure way.
Notably, Sigstore solves the issue of private key storage and management by implementing &amp;quot;keyless&amp;quot; signing, where users can generate ephemeral key pairs and sign an artifact using an identity provider such as GitHub, Microsoft or Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of this talk will be on the efforts made by the Python community to adopt Sigstore, showing how it is used to sign CPython releases and with a demo of the new sigstore-python client developers can use to get started with securing their Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maya Costantini</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-18:/pycon-fr-2023/introduction-to-sigstore-cryptographic-signatures-made-easier.html</guid><category>PyCon FR 2023</category></item><item><title>How to Make Your Python Jupyter Notebook Standalone and Reproducible to allow others to replicate your experiments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2022/how-to-make-your-python-jupyter-notebook-standalone-and-reproducible-to-allow-others-to-replicate-your-experiments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though many developers (including data scientists) focus on their core problems when working on their experiments, one basic aspect can make these projects not reusable. We are not considering anything machine learning-related yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first steps during the development of a project is the selection of libraries or dependencies. When someone runs pip install package-name, they might not be aware that along with the library that is going to be installed, so-called direct dependency, many other dependencies will be installed on your machine, so-called transitive dependencies. Any change in one of those dependencies can break your experiment. It’s fundamental to have a way to state all the dependencies used, including the operating system, python interpreter, and hardware used to run a certain experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, the speakers will present an open source JupyterLab extension for Python dependency management developed by the Thoth team. They will learn what resolution engine can be used (e.g. Pipenv, Thoth), the difference between these resolution engines. Moreover they will learn what to do in different scenarios emulating typical Jupyter notebook experiences to learn how to use the new extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this session, attendees will learn the importance of reproducibility, how to use the Thoth Jupyterlab extension for Python projects and the benefits of a cloud resolution engine with respect to other existing ones. They will be able to run a tutorial using only a GitHub account and a browser as it will be run in a completely open cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Murdaca</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-04-27:/pycon-us-2022/how-to-make-your-python-jupyter-notebook-standalone-and-reproducible-to-allow-others-to-replicate-your-experiments.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2022</category></item></channel></rss>