<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ria Bhatia</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python on the Rocks: Crafting a Smooth Blend with RocksDB</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/python-on-the-rocks-crafting-a-smooth-blend-with-rocksdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2A on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python on the Rocks: Crafting a Smooth Blend with RocksDB by Ria Bhatia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/python-on-the-rocks-crafting-a-smooth-blend-with-rocksdb"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/python-on-the-rocks-crafting-a-smooth-blend-with-rocksdb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to selecting a high-performance database for your application, RocksDB emerges as a top contender, offering a lightweight and efficient solution. RocksDB brings a robust set of features to the table, but what lies beneath its surface? Let's dive into the world of RocksDB with Python, uncovering the mysteries of its internal workings and exploring the principles that make data storage and retrieval seamlessly efficient. Get ready to equip yourself with the knowledge to harness the full potential of RocksDB and elevate your applications to new heights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Bhatia</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/python-on-the-rocks-crafting-a-smooth-blend-with-rocksdb.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item><item><title>Demystifying SQLite with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2023/demystifying-sqlite-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to choosing a light, simple and high performance database for your python application, SQLite surely comes to mind. Learning and befriending SQlite has several benefits, and it is a must have tool for every programmer. But have you ever wondered what is happening behind the scenes which makes its storage and retrieval so efficient? How is data being managed internally? Let's explore the SQLite database using python while learning some intriguing underlying principles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Bhatia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-03-18:/pycascades-2023/demystifying-sqlite-with-python.html</guid><category>PyCascades 2023</category></item><item><title>Cache me if you can: Boosting performance with Data Caching in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyladiescon-2023/cache-me-if-you-can-boosting-performance-with-data-caching-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the joys of data caching in Python and how it can turbocharge your code's performance. We'll dive deep into caching, explaining what it is and why it's crucial for optimizing code performance. We'll discuss various caching techniques and approaches, so you can take away practical knowledge on how to implement caching in Python.
And wait, there's more! We'll also cover bottlenecks and things to consider when implementing caching to ensure optimal performance.
By the end of this talk, you'll have a newfound appreciation for the power of caching and will be amazed at how easy it is to get started with caching. If you want to say &amp;quot;goodbye&amp;quot; to long load times and &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; to efficient programming- this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Bhatia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-02-12:/pyladiescon-2023/cache-me-if-you-can-boosting-performance-with-data-caching-in-python.html</guid><category>PyLadiesCon 2023</category></item><item><title>From Code to Clarity: How Good Technical Documentation is the Key to Great Software</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2023/from-code-to-clarity-how-good-technical-documentation-is-the-key-to-great-software.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As developers, we know that writing code is only half the battle. The
other half is writing documentation that effectively communicates our
ideas and helps others understand and use our code. But how do we write
good technical documentation that is both accurate and engaging? In this
talk, let's explore the secrets to mastering the art of software
technical documentation and transform the way you approach technical
writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ria Bhatia</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-12-16:/pyohio-2023/from-code-to-clarity-how-good-technical-documentation-is-the-key-to-great-software.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2023</category></item></channel></rss>