<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Winston Chang</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>20 questions and AI chat bots</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/20-questions-and-ai-chat-bots.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Winston Chang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/20-questions-and-ai-chat-bots.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>AI and Shiny for Python: Unlocking New Possibilities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/ai-and-shiny-for-python-unlocking-new-possibilities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past year, people have come to realize that AI can revolutionize the way we work. This talk focuses on using AI tools with Shiny for Python, demonstrating how AI can accelerate Shiny application development and enhance its capabilities. We'll also explore Shiny's unique ability to interface with AI models, offering possibilities beyond Python web frameworks like Streamlit and Dash. Learn how Shiny and AI together can empower you to do more, and do it faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Winston Chang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/ai-and-shiny-for-python-unlocking-new-possibilities.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Building ML and AI apps with Shiny for Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/building-ml-and-ai-apps-with-shiny-for-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, the best LLMs have taken a big step forward in their ability to help write code. We’ve been building a tool that uses an LLM to help you learn Shiny and build Shiny applications much faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel like you don’t have the time to invest in learning Shiny, this might change your mind. You’ll get up and running with Shiny in no time, and you’ll be able to learn from the AI as you go. If you already know Shiny, you’ll be able to dramatically accelerate your development process, and you’ll find yourself trying out new things that wouldn’t have been worth the effort before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Winston Chang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/building-ml-and-ai-apps-with-shiny-for-python.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>