<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Michal Maciejewski</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michal-maciejewski.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>When Models Query Models</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/when-models-query-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michal Maciejewski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/when-models-query-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - When Models Query Models - presented by Michal Maciejewski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of large-scale engineering systems, including but not limited to aerospace, particle accelerators, nuclear power plants, is carried out by a wide range of numerical models such as CAD files, finite-element models, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - When Models Query Models - presented by Michal Maciejewski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey Hall 1 on 2022-07-15]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of large-scale engineering systems, including but not limited to aerospace, particle accelerators, nuclear power plants, is carried out by a wide range of numerical models such as CAD files, finite-element models, and machine learning surrogate models to name a few. In order to provide a uniform modelling interface, we encapsulate numerical models in notebooks. A notebook is controlling model creation, execution, and query of results. Numerical solvers are embedded into Docker containers and provide an isolated and reproducible environment exposing a language-agnostic REST API. A model registry enables efficient queries of models. The overall system is represented as a collection of models that exchange data. Then, the design optimization involves execution of a dependency tree of models to study the impact of a parameter change and perform its optimization. In this contribution, we present a model query mechanism allowing notebook models to query one another. The model dependencies are represented with a graph with suitable processing algorithms. In order to ensure that only affected models are executed we derive and cache a model resolution order. The presented modelling framework relies on open source-technologies (packages: pydantic, Fast API, Jupyter, papermill, scrapbook, containers: Docker and Openshift as well as databases: MongoDB and Redis) and the talk will focus on good practices and design decisions encountered in the process.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licence: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>