<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Docker for Data Scientists - Simplify Your Workflow and Avoid Pitfalls</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/docker-for-data-scientists-simplify-your-workflow-and-avoid-pitfalls.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeff Fischer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/docker-for-data-scientists-simplify-your-workflow-and-avoid-pitfalls.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and IoT: From Chips and Bits to Data Science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2017/python-and-iot-from-chips-and-bits-to-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will take you through the design of a smart lighting system, including sensor hardware and software (based around MicroPython), data analysis (using NumPy, Pandas, and Jupyter), and lighting control (using Hidden Markov Models via Hmmlearn). From the talk, you should get a sense of how the hardware, software, and math fit together to create a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever want to know what is behind the &amp;quot;Internet of Things&amp;quot; hype? I wanted to as well, so I embarked on a side project to learn more. This talk is the story of my journey, using, of course, my favorite programming language, Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will take you through my project, a lighting replay system. The application monitors the light levels in several rooms of a residence and then replays a similar pattern when the house is unoccupied. The goal is to make the house look occupied, with a lighting pattern that is different every day, but looks realistic. It accounts for the different patterns found in each individual room as well as seasonal factors (e.g. changing sunrise/sunset times). The full source code for the application is available on github &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mpi-sws-rse/thingflow-examples/tree/master/lighting_replay_app"&gt;https://github.com/mpi-sws-rse/thingflow-examples/tree/master/lighting_replay_app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeff Fischer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-06:pydata-seattle-2017/python-and-iot-from-chips-and-bits-to-data-science.html</guid><category>iot</category><category>micropython</category></item><item><title>BayPiggies October 2016 talk by Jeff Fischer at LinkedIn: Python and IoT</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/baypiggies-october-2016-talk-by-jeff-fischer-at-linkedin-python-and-iot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Chips and Bits to Data Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever want to know what is behind the &amp;quot;Internet of Things&amp;quot; hype? Back in Feburary, I wanted to as well, so I embarked on a side project to learn more. This talk is the story of my journey, using, of course, my favorite programming language, Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will take you through my project, a lighting replay system. I captured light sensor data (using Micropython and the ESP8266) in three rooms of my house. I then analyzed the data using Jupyter notebooks, Numpy, Pandas, and Scikit-learn. My goal was to replay realistic light usage when my family and I are out of town. After exploring several machine learning approaches, I settled on Hidden Markov Models (using Hmmlearn). I now have a simple application that runs on my Raspberry Pi and controls Phillips Hue lights based on the learned model. Along the way, I played around with hardware for the first time since college and co-developed an open source data filtering framework, called AntEvents&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeff Fischer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-27:bay-piggies/baypiggies-october-2016-talk-by-jeff-fischer-at-linkedin-python-and-iot.html</guid></item></channel></rss>