<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_jill-cates.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-03T17:10:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to Design and Build a Recommendation System Pipeline in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2018/how-to-design-and-build-a-recommendation-system-pipeline-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jill Cates</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ca-2018/how-to-design-and-build-a-recommendation-system-pipeline-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to know how Spotify, Amazon, and Netflix generate recommendations for their users? This talk walks through the steps involved in building a recommendation pipeline, from data cleaning, hyperparameter tuning, model training and evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personalized recommendation systems play an integral role in e-commerce platforms, with the goal of driving user engagement. While there is extensive literature on the theory behind recommendation systems, there is limited material that describes the underlying infrastructure of a recommendation system pipeline. In this talk, we will walk through the process of designing and building a recommendation system pipeline. We will specifically discuss techniques for data cleaning and normalization, hyperparameter tuning, model training and fitting, as well as quantitative and qualitative model evaluation. By the end of this talk, you will learn how to design your own recommendation system pipeline from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jill is a data scientist at BioSymetrics, where she applies machine learning techniques to biomedical data. Outside of work, Jill is working on an open-source toolkit for implicit feedback recommendation systems. She is a member of PyLadies and Women Who Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation page -- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2018.pycon.ca/fr/talks/talk-PC-55468/"&gt;https://2018.pycon.ca/fr/talks/talk-PC-55468/&lt;/a&gt;
Author website -- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://topspinj.github.io/"&gt;https://topspinj.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to Build a Clinical Diagnostic Model in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/how-to-build-a-clinical-diagnostic-model-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T17:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T17:10:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jill Cates</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/how-to-build-a-clinical-diagnostic-model-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diagnosing a patient requires consideration of a wide variety of
factors: past medical history and comorbidities, physical exam findings,
lab results, imaging, ECG findings, and in some cases, genomic testing.
Clinical diagnosis and prognostic assessment currently relies on expert
knowledge of the treating physician. Recent developments in machine
learning make it possible to build automated clinical diagnostic and
risk assessment tools using data from the electronic medical record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk walks through the steps involved in building a clinical risk
assessment model, using sepsis as a case study. A large part of the talk
will focus on the tools and techniques involved in pre-processing
complex medical data, and strategies for evaluating model results.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="talk"></category></entry></feed>