<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_julia-signell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data-centric exploration using intake, dask, hvplot, datashader, panel, and binder</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-centric-exploration-using-intake-dask-hvplot-datashader-panel-and-binder.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Julia Signell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-05:pydata-new-york-city-2019/data-centric-exploration-using-intake-dask-hvplot-datashader-panel-and-binder.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discovering a new dataset is exciting, but it can also be daunting. How will you read it? Will it fit in memory? What meaning can be derived? Can you share that with others? This talk describes an opinionated method of data exploration going from data ingestion to dashboard deployment and showing how everything comes together into a complete and repeatable workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Visualize any Data Easily, from Notebooks to Dashboards</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2019/visualize-any-data-easily-from-notebooks-to-dashboards.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Bednar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:scipy-2019/visualize-any-data-easily-from-notebooks-to-dashboards.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial you will see how to visualize and communicate your data easily and effectively using Python tools. You'll learn how to use Panel to lay out your existing plots with widgets to make apps in the notebook or as deployed dashboards, hvPlot to make your Pandas or Xarray .plot() API calls return interactive, explorable plots, HoloViews and GeoViews to help you explore multidimensional data naturally without having to build a plot for each combination or sample of the data space, and Datashader to visualize even the very largest datasets faithfully in a web browser. See pyviz.org for links to all these tools and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category></entry></feed>