<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Chris Morrow</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_chris-morrow.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Introduction to Exploratory Data Analysis with the Sci-Analysis Python Package</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2019/introduction-to-exploratory-data-analysis-with-the-sci-analysis-python-package.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Morrow</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-13:/pytexas-2019/introduction-to-exploratory-data-analysis-with-the-sci-analysis-python-package.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis is an important step in data science and analysis. The PyData stack has many useful tools for performing EDA but the learning curve to use these tools can be steep. Sci-Analysis simplifies EDA by combining meaningful visualizations with the appropriate statistical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2019"></category><category term="Sci-Analysis"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>Automating Build Tasks With Build-magic</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2022/automating-build-tasks-with-build-magic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Chris Morrow</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-21:/pytexas-2022/automating-build-tasks-with-build-magic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers like writing software but loath building software. Amongst platform specific scripts, Makefiles, and CI pipelines, there’s no shortage of fragile, frustrating processes for building a software project. Build-magic aims to simplify builds with a declarative, repeatable tool for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Chris Morrow
Chris Morrow is a Staff …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers like writing software but loath building software. Amongst platform specific scripts, Makefiles, and CI pipelines, there’s no shortage of fragile, frustrating processes for building a software project. Build-magic aims to simplify builds with a declarative, repeatable tool for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Chris Morrow
Chris Morrow is a Staff Software Developer at Q2 in Austin Texas, and previously worked at Silicon Labs and Samsung. He is a Python, Go, and Elixir developer with experience in Cybersecurity, Web Development, Statistics, Data Engineering, and Data Science. Chris is also involved in mentoring and teaching programming with organizations such as Breakthrough Central Texas and Code2College. In 2018, Chris was selected as a member of the Leadership Austin Emerge class. He also participates in Austin Young Chamber and is a supporting member of the Python Software Foundation. Chris has given previous talks on SQLAlchemy at The Austin Python Meetup and An Evening of Python Coding, as well as a talk on his open source project sci-analysis at PyTexas 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTexas 2022"></category></entry></feed>