<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Aaron Bockover</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_aaron-bockover.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Lightning Talk: Streamlining Model Export with the New ONNX Exporter</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-streamlining-model-export-with-the-new-onnx-exporter.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maanav Dalal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/pytorch-conference-2023/lightning-talk-streamlining-model-export-with-the-new-onnx-exporter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us for a 10-minute talk on the new TorchDynamo-based ONNX exporter, redefining how we convert machine learning models to the ONNX format, with the power of PyTorch 2.0. The talk covers: Exporting with torch.onnx.dynamo_export, Inference with ONNXRuntime, and a variety of of State-of-the-Art models being …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us for a 10-minute talk on the new TorchDynamo-based ONNX exporter, redefining how we convert machine learning models to the ONNX format, with the power of PyTorch 2.0. The talk covers: Exporting with torch.onnx.dynamo_export, Inference with ONNXRuntime, and a variety of of State-of-the-Art models being converted easily. Learn about how ONNX enables more PyTorch models to be cross-platform, all the great benefits of ONNX standard, and all the other features we have baked into the new exporter, including: Symbolic model tracing: Export large models without computation cost involving original data/parameters, saving time and preventing OOM issues. ONNX Script: A new way to architect ONNX Models and the backbone of the Dynamo Exporter Preserving original modules structure as ONNX functions: allowing for a better resulting model that is layered. Better diagnostics: Clearly identify the root of your conversion issues faster!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2023"></category><category term="Lightning Talk"></category></entry></feed>