<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Ken Whitesell</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Autonomous Vehicles, Intelligent Transportation Systems, and yes, Django!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/autonomous-vehicles-intelligent-transportation-systems-and-yes-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the components in an autonomous vehicle? How do they work with
other vehicles and an intelligent infrastructure? In this talk I will
cover all the components involved in intelligent infrastructures and how
Django is being used in current research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="topics-include"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Topics include&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of the infrastructure&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where are we right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the eventual goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we get there?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OnBoard Units (OBUs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road-Side Units (RSUs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communications among components&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interoperability as a fundamental requirement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Message types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communications standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Django&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrading equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuring equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ken Whitesell</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-15:/djangocon-us-2018/autonomous-vehicles-intelligent-transportation-systems-and-yes-django.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2018</category></item><item><title>WebRTC with Django, Channels, HTMX, and coturn</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/webrtc-with-django-channels-htmx-and-coturn.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Audio/Video conferencing has become standard in many areas for augmenting communications among individuals. Modern browsers facilitate this by including support for Web Real Time Communications (WebRTC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebRTC itself is a point-to-point protocol, which means that two browsers using this for a video call are talking directly to each other. But, before that can happen, the those browsers need to know that each other exists and are looking to establish this connection. Then they need to negotiate the parameters for the connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are many network-related issues that can affect the ability for those two browsers to connect.  Things like firewalls and Network Address Translation (NAT) can affect how each side &amp;quot;sees&amp;quot; the other side, further complicating the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these issues have known solutions. The WebRTC APIs have matured to the point where they can be considered reasonably stable and reliable. It has become practical to incorporate these solutions in a Django-based website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will discuss one implementation of a Django-based website that facilitates a group video conferencing system, using Channels as the signalling mechanism, HTMX for page-content management, and coturn as the NAT transveral and and gateway server.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ken Whitesell</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-25:/djangocon-us-2024/webrtc-with-django-channels-htmx-and-coturn.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item></channel></rss>