<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sandra-becker.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Visual storytelling – why we love it?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/visual-storytelling-why-we-love-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sandra Becker</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-08:pycon-cz-2017/visual-storytelling-why-we-love-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data, data, data and even more data. How can we handle all this data,
of course by analysing them with Python :) But neither Python nor any
other program, software etc. can tell us the story, which is hidden
in the data. The story is created by a human interaction with the
data. In this process data visualisation is our friend as it helps us
to discover patterns, outliers and everything we need to create the
data story. At the same time data visualisation is a language we all
understand and enjoy using, therefore it is the logical bridge
between the data and the story. In this talk I want to show you why
we love visual storytelling and inspire your own imagination by
explaining to you how one of the best visual data stories have been
created&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandra’s biggest passion is and always was analysing and visualising
data in order to discover the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the last 10 years she had the pleasure to design statistical
models and create analytical solutions in various interesting
projects while working in market research institutes, brand, media
and advertisement agencies in Germany, UK and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara is German but she would consider heself already as half Spanish
as she've been living in her favourite city of Madrid for nearly
three years now. In her last position she'd led the data
visualisation training program for Telefonica Spain and LATAM by
helping them to understand, use and communicate their data in an
efficient, attractive and dynamic way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now as a profesor and teacher for data visualisation she has the
possibility to focus on new ways to explore and represent data,
especially using open source software like D3.js, R shiny &amp;amp; ggplot2,
Python and CARTO and with a passion for the visual storytelling. Her
final objective is to transmit high quality knowledge combined with
enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>