<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Mayank Khanduja</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Earth Observation through Large Vision Models</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/earth-observation-through-large-vision-models.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — North Hall on 2024-07-11]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth Observation through Large Vision Models by Mayank Khanduja&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/earth-observation-through-large-vision-models"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/earth-observation-through-large-vision-models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how location planning is done to build city infrastructure? Or when there is a disaster, how do we determine the possible affected areas and send reinforcements there? We require overhead imagery for that, which we mainly obtain from satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Space Agency has sent various satellites however, the dataset from these satellites is huge and may even contain multiple bands from the electromagnetic spectrum. Large AI models have a huge potential in this domain, if they are developed to work well with this dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of pre-trained Generative &amp;amp; Large Vision models on platforms like HuggingFace, Kaggle, etc., but these models do not integrate well with a specific domain like satellite datasets, hence the need to train or fine-tune them. In this talk, we are going to see from where we can access open satellite datasets, fine-tune various Vision Models and Multimodals on it, and examine the following applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform Zero-Shot classification and object detection on satellite images with human language input using Multimodal models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image-to-image translation on satellite imagery using generative vision models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mayank Khanduja</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/earth-observation-through-large-vision-models.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>