<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_maria-molina-contreras.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>“When a biologist met Python”</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/when-a-biologist-met-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maria Molina-Contreras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/when-a-biologist-met-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Biology and computing are closer than we usually think, for example
many algorithms are inspired in biology patterns, and complementary to
that, researchers needs special algorithms to have a better
understanding of our environment. Thus, there is a strong relation an
dependency.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In the past years, Biology has been transformed into computational
biology. Therefore&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;technological advances helps us to predict physical interactions
between atoms and DNA, because we are being able to integrate
information from biology into algorithms.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become a popular programming language in biosciences because
it has a clean syntax that makes it easy to read language. In addition
to this, there are many modules (toolkits) extending to different
biological domains, like metabolomics, structure analysis,
phylogenomics, molecular biology and others. Python is currently
improving researcher’s workflow, helping us to focus on the theory or
experimental part, instead of fighting with old buggy applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to be oriented to all audiences (with/without biological
background) since we will go together through an amazing adventure into
the natural sciences using tools like Biopython, Bokeh, Networkx, Ecopy
and much more! Are you brave enough to follow me on this journey?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Natural Science"></category><category term="Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)"></category><category term="python"></category></entry></feed>