<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Chirag Gupta</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_chirag-gupta.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Parity Calibration</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/uai-2023/parity-calibration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Youngseog Chung</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-31:/uai-2023/parity-calibration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Parity Calibration&amp;quot;
Youngseog Chung, Aaron Rumack, Chirag Gupta
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/chung23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/chung23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In a sequential regression setting, a decision-maker may be primarily concerned with whether the future observation will increase or decrease compared to the current one, rather than the actual value of the future …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Parity Calibration&amp;quot;
Youngseog Chung, Aaron Rumack, Chirag Gupta
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/chung23a.html"&gt;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v216/chung23a.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
In a sequential regression setting, a decision-maker may be primarily concerned with whether the future observation will increase or decrease compared to the current one, rather than the actual value of the future observation. In this context, we introduce the notion of parity calibration, which captures the goal of calibrated forecasting for the increase-decrease (or “parity&amp;quot;) event in a timeseries. Parity probabilities can be extracted from a forecasted distribution for the output, but we show that such a strategy leads to theoretical unpredictability and poor practical performance. We then observe that although the original task was regression, parity calibration can be expressed as binary calibration. Drawing on this connection, we use an online binary calibration method to achieve parity calibration. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on real-world case studies in epidemiology, weather forecasting, and model-based control in nuclear fusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/631-oral-slides.pdf"&gt;https://www.auai.org/uai2023/oral_slides/631-oral-slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="UAI 2023"></category></entry></feed>