<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Christian Ledermann</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_christian-ledermann.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A Tale of two Kitchens, hyper modernizing your codebase</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/a-tale-of-two-kitchens-hyper-modernizing-your-codebase.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Ledermann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/a-tale-of-two-kitchens-hyper-modernizing-your-codebase.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - A Tale of two Kitchens, hyper modernizing your codebase. - presented by Christian Ledermann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey A on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Consistent style and standard and the consistent use of the same tools in all your code, makes it easier to reason about, reduces context switching, thus reducing waste (in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - A Tale of two Kitchens, hyper modernizing your codebase. - presented by Christian Ledermann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey A on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Consistent style and standard and the consistent use of the same tools in all your code, makes it easier to reason about, reduces context switching, thus reducing waste (in the LEAN sense). A clean environment is good for your health and safety, enabling you to deliver quality faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk goes deeper into how to modernize your legacy codebase to reduce your technical debt, to make it easier for you to tackle the real challenges without ever having to discuss a style guide again. It will provide tips, tricks and tools to make your “hypermodernization” effort as smooth and easy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry></feed>