<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sylvain Marié</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sylvain-marie.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Powerful tests and reproducible benchmarks with `pytest-cases`</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/powerful-tests-and-reproducible-benchmarks-with-pytest-cases.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sylvain Marié</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/powerful-tests-and-reproducible-benchmarks-with-pytest-cases.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powerful tests and reproducible benchmarks with &lt;cite&gt;pytest-cases&lt;/cite&gt;
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Sylvain Marié&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pytest is undoubtedly the most popular test framework for python. Its fixture and parametrization mechanisms, as well as its detailed hook API and vibrant plugin ecosystem make it a must-know for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powerful tests and reproducible benchmarks with &lt;cite&gt;pytest-cases&lt;/cite&gt;
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-28 - Parrot [Data Science]]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Sylvain Marié&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pytest is undoubtedly the most popular test framework for python. Its fixture and parametrization mechanisms, as well as its detailed hook API and vibrant plugin ecosystem make it a must-know for any developer wishing to create quality software. Some key limitations in its engine and API, however, prevent users from truly unleashing their testing scenarii. Creating tests with complex parametrization is complicated, and users trying to explore this direction may loose the legendary elegance and maintainability of pytest tests on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pytest-cases extends pytest so that users can manage their parameters the same way they manage tests: as python functions. This separates test cases from test functions in an elegant way, encouraging developers to add more cases without decreasing readability. With this new paradigm it becomes ridiculously simple to create tests where several &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot; of parameters coexist nicely: datasets come both from files, databases and simulations ; distinct algorithms can be evaluated and compared, with possible variants ; etc. Fixtures can be leveraged by any of these, in an intuitive manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally pytest-cases can also be used in combination with pytest-harvest to generate scientific results tables in a reproducible manner. Reproducible research projects may therefore wish to use it to replace an &amp;quot;ad-hoc&amp;quot; benchmark engine. That way, adding datasets and algorithms in the benchmark becomes as easy as creating new python functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation is for python developers and data scientists at ease with python, with basic experience of pytest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>`python-m5p` - M5 Prime regression trees in python, compliant with scikit-learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2022/python-m5p-m5-prime-regression-trees-in-python-compliant-with-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sylvain Marié</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-05-12:/pycon-de-2022/python-m5p-m5-prime-regression-trees-in-python-compliant-with-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Sylvain Marié&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Machine Learning &amp;amp; Stats
Regression trees are powerful Machine Learning models capable of both flexibility in modeling as well as interpretability when the tree is not too deep. The M5 algorithm, introduced by Quinlan in 1992 to provide more compact and smooth models for regression …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker:: Sylvain Marié&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: PyData: Machine Learning &amp;amp; Stats
Regression trees are powerful Machine Learning models capable of both flexibility in modeling as well as interpretability when the tree is not too deep. The M5 algorithm, introduced by Quinlan in 1992 to provide more compact and smooth models for regression, was improved by Wang &amp;amp; Witten in 1997, under the name M5 Prime (acronym M5' or M5P). The algorithm gained popularity in particular a dozen years later with the Weka Machine Learning toolbox, providing a java-based implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;python-m5p&lt;/cite&gt; is an implementation of the M5P algorithm compliant with scikit-learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the PyConDE &amp;amp; PyData Berlin 2022 conference, April 11-13 2022.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de&lt;/a&gt;
More details at the conference page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2022.pycon.de/program/8KXYBD"&gt;https://2022.pycon.de/program/8KXYBD&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pydataberlin"&gt;https://twitter.com/pydataberlin&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pyconde"&gt;https://twitter.com/pyconde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon DE 2022"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConDE"></category><category term="pyconde2022"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="pydataberlin2022"></category></entry></feed>