<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Donata Stroink-Skillrud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_donata-stroink-skillrud.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The Three Things All Web Professionals Must Know About Privacy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-web-conf-2021/the-three-things-all-web-professionals-must-know-about-privacy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Donata Stroink-Skillrud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-03-22:/python-web-conf-2021/the-three-things-all-web-professionals-must-know-about-privacy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Three Things All Web Professionals Must Know About Privacy&amp;quot; by: Donata Stroink-Skillrud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients trust web professionals to build them a website that generates leads. An unfortunate side effect of lead generation is the collection of personal information. For example, a website that has a contact form that collects …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Three Things All Web Professionals Must Know About Privacy&amp;quot; by: Donata Stroink-Skillrud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients trust web professionals to build them a website that generates leads. An unfortunate side effect of lead generation is the collection of personal information. For example, a website that has a contact form that collects a name and an email address collects personal information. Laws require most websites that collect PI to have a Privacy Policy. Clients often look to web professionals to answer the questions “do I really need a Privacy Policy, and why?” The fact is that most web professionals should have some knowledge of why privacy is important, what websites need a Privacy Policy, and should be the ones speaking to their clients about the topic. In this talk, I will answer all of the above questions and empower web professionals to be true advocates for privacy and protection for their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded at the 2021 Python Web Conference (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pythonwebconf.com"&gt;https://2021.pythonwebconf.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Python Web Conf 2021"></category><category term="PythonWebConf"></category><category term="PythonWebConf2021"></category></entry></feed>