<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Sage Abdullah</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sage-abdullah.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>✨ Modern editing experience for your Django models with Wagtail 🐦</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/modern-editing-experience-for-your-django-models-with-wagtail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sage Abdullah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-16:/djangocon-us-2023/modern-editing-experience-for-your-django-models-with-wagtail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can content management features be useful when managing arbitrary Django models?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wagtail is an open source, Django-powered Content Management System (CMS). It is built on the concept of pages as tree-structured Django models. As a CMS, Wagtail gives you the power to save revisions, manage live/draft versions, moderate …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can content management features be useful when managing arbitrary Django models?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wagtail is an open source, Django-powered Content Management System (CMS). It is built on the concept of pages as tree-structured Django models. As a CMS, Wagtail gives you the power to save revisions, manage live/draft versions, moderate your content, _live_ preview as you edit, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical Wagtail project would have your user-facing website structure be defined by the tree structure of the Page model. However, if you have an existing Django project with your own defined Django views, and you don't want to use Wagtail's Page model, you can still get plenty of benefits from Wagtail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will learn how to benefit from powerful content-management features for your existing Django models by integrating Wagtail CMS into your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk does not require any pre-existing knowledge about Wagtail CMS, though familiarity with Django models and external apps is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be structured as follows:
- What Wagtail CMS is and how it compares with Django itself
- Wagtail features likely relevant to many Django projects and how they work
- How to integrate Wagtail into an existing Django project
- How to progressively enable Wagtail's features and use them to manage your Django models&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>Django: the web framework that changed my life</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/django-the-web-framework-that-changed-my-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sage Abdullah</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-23:/djangocon-us-2024/django-the-web-framework-that-changed-my-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The year was 2018. I was studying computer science at the University of Indonesia. I learned Django as part of a web programming course. At the time, Django felt just like any other framework out there – it's part of the tech stack that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later, I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The year was 2018. I was studying computer science at the University of Indonesia. I learned Django as part of a web programming course. At the time, Django felt just like any other framework out there – it's part of the tech stack that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later, I tried my luck with Django in [Google Summer of Code](&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://g.co/gsoc"&gt;https://g.co/gsoc&lt;/a&gt;). I took a deep dive into Django's codebase to implement the cross-database &lt;cite&gt;JSONField&lt;/cite&gt;. The feature managed to make it in Django 3.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to now, I've got a job in the UK to work on the Django-powered Wagtail CMS.  Since then, I've had the opportunity to give talks at conferences in Europe and the US, including this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a story of how Django changed ~~my life~~ people's lives – and how you played a part in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll go through:
- How Django can be used to teach web programming
- Django's participation in Google Summer of Code
- The awesome Django community and what it means for us
- What we can do to make Django change the lives of even more people&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="DjangoCon US 2024"></category></entry></feed>