<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - André Roberge</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>It doesn't work!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/it-doesnt-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(André Roberge) When beginners encounter tracebacks, they are often intimidated and do not know what to do with the information, which may tempt them to give up. In this talk, I will demonstrate a tool that can help them (and you) get all the information necessary to find the exact cause of an exception as well as some possible hints leading you to a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/EKJR9K/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/EKJR9K/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 11:00:00 2021 at Education&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">André Roberge</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/it-doesnt-work.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2021</category><category>AndréRoberge</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2021</category></item><item><title>Lightning Talks 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2021/lightning-talks-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agenda of Lightning Talks  - Hosted by Dustin Ingram and Lorena Mesa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;André Roberge - Friendlier tracebacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernat Gabor - tox 4 is happening!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brett Cannon - Introducing the Python Launcher for Unix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheuk Ho - What happens when the developer decided that your name is too short&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepa - A tale of mutability and recursion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason C. McDonald - Code Review For Great Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jürgen Gmach - How to Maintain Many, Many, Many, Many... Many Git Repositories?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mfon Eti-mfon - Queer Struggles in Africa: Fighting Hate With Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Jones - What’s new in Flask&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clint Cameron - How to take ownership of security in your Python code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel J. Dufour - Load Django Settings from Environmental Variables with One Magical Line of Code&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dustin Ingram</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-05-14:/pycon-us-2021/lightning-talks-1.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2021</category></item></channel></rss>