<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pypedia: a python development environment on a wiki</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/pypedia-a-python-development-environment-on-a-wi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] A Kanterakis - 4 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we present PyPedia. PyPedia is an effort to host a Python
programming environment in a MediaWiki content management system. The
concept is similar to any wiki except that each article contains the
documentation, python source code and unit tests for a known and well
defined computational problem. Through an article, a user can edit the
source code, download it, execute it locally, in a remote computer
through SSH, or in Google App Engine (GAE). Moreover, through a python
package users can import PyPedia methods in their local python
environment. In the source code, a developer can simply call a function
or instantiate a class that is defined in another article. In every code
edit, the article’s unit-tests are evaluated in GAE before saving. A
special parameters section allows editors to build an HTML form within
the article that help fellow users to execute the method as a simple
online service. Articles are divided in two categories: User and Main.
In User articles, the creator of the article manages the edit privileges
of each section. Any non-deliberately malicious content is allowed. Main
articles are selected from the pool of User articles that exhibit highly
qualitative content and can be edited only by trusted users. All content
is under the simplified BSD license. The vision of this project is to
create an encyclopedia of documented, executable and verifiable python
implementation of common algorithms or computational problems through
the development of a vivid community. Specialized or user aware content
is also encouraged in the User namespace. The source code of PyPedia is
available under the GPL v.3 license. Availability:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pypedia.com"&gt;http://www.pypedia.com&lt;/a&gt; Video demonstration:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube%20.com/watch?v=25jMEivICD8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=25jMEivICD8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">A Kanterakis</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-04:europython-2012/pypedia-a-python-development-environment-on-a-wi.html</guid></item></channel></rss>