<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Peter Sun</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_peter-sun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>mrfmsim: a modular simulation platform for magnetic resonance force microscopy experiments</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2024/mrfmsim-a-modular-simulation-platform-for-magnetic-resonance-force-microscopy-experiments.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Sun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/scipy-2024/mrfmsim-a-modular-simulation-platform-for-magnetic-resonance-force-microscopy-experiments.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present mrfmsim, an open-source framework that facilitates the design, simulation, and signal validation of magnetic resonance force microscopy experiments. The mrfmsim framework uses directed acyclic graphs (DAGs) to model experiments and employs a plugin system that adds custom experiments and functionalities. Differing from common DAG-powered workflow packages, mrfmsim …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present mrfmsim, an open-source framework that facilitates the design, simulation, and signal validation of magnetic resonance force microscopy experiments. The mrfmsim framework uses directed acyclic graphs (DAGs) to model experiments and employs a plugin system that adds custom experiments and functionalities. Differing from common DAG-powered workflow packages, mrfmsim allows flexible customizations of experiments post-definition without rewriting the internal model, such as optimized looping. In the talk, we present the challenges in building simulation packages for experiments undergoing continuous development in a graduate research setting. We discuss the current one-off approach that led to error-prone code and how modularity, extendibility, and readability can speed up the development cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2024"></category></entry></feed>