<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deep Learning without a PhD</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2019/deep-learning-without-a-phd.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroSciPy 2019 Bilbao
September 5, Thursday
Mitxelena. Talk. 11.00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning without a PhD
Paige Bailey&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-05:euroscipy-2019/deep-learning-without-a-phd.html</guid></item><item><title>KubeFlow: Pythonic Machine Learning at Scale on Kubernetes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/kubeflow-pythonic-machine-learning-at-scale-on-kubernetes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“KubeFlow marks the beginning of the end of the data scientist and/or
software engineer as disparate roles. Like DevOps has merged operations
and development, DataDevOps will consume data science.” - Philip Winder,
an engineer and consultant at Container Solutions &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://container"&gt;http://container&lt;/a&gt;-
solutions.com/tensorflow-on-kubernetes-kubeflow/ You've created and
tuned a machine learning model, using TensorFlow, PyTorch, or
scikit-learn - now what? How can you ensure that the model is deployed
to your DevOps team as production-ready code, and can scale as needed on
incoming data? How can you seamlessly migrate a model from your local
laptop / virtual machine to a hosted server on your cloud platform of
choice? This talk walks through the architecture of Kubeflow: a project
dedicated to answering those questions - and to making machine learning
on Kubernetes simple, portable and scalable. We will describe, in
detail, the three components of the project: * a JupyterHub platform
for creating and managing Jupyter notebook servers that are used by data
science and research groups; * a Tensorflow Customer Resource for
managing compute resources to a specific cluster size; and * a
Tensorflow Serving container to house the machine learning work. By the
end of this talk, you will have a firm understanding of why Kubernetes
would be useful to machine learning engineers, and how you can deploy
it, today, to support your predictive models.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflowPresenter(s"&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflowPresenter(s&lt;/a&gt;): Speaker: Paige Bailey,
Microsoft Speaker: David Aronchick, Google&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-13:scipy-2018/kubeflow-pythonic-machine-learning-at-scale-on-kubernetes.html</guid></item><item><title>Well Aged Bacon predicting Kevin Bacon's age with the Python Cognitive Services API</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-new-york-city-2017/well-aged-bacon-predicting-kevin-bacons-age-with-the-python-cognitive-services-api.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will walk through functionality of the Azure Cognitive Services API, in the context of a specific use case (predicting Kevin Bacon's age from 1978 - 2016). Topics addressed include age approximation, emotion detection, hair color, gender, likelihood of moustache or glasses, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-27:pydata-new-york-city-2017/well-aged-bacon-predicting-kevin-bacons-age-with-the-python-cognitive-services-api.html</guid></item><item><title>Hacks of Kindness (PyTexas 2017 Keynote)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2017/hacks-of-kindness-pytexas-2017-keynote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paige Bailey is a Sr. Cloud Developer Advocate at Microsoft specializing in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Paige’s education was focused on the earth sciences (geophysics, carbonate geology) and computer science (data analytics); and her previous work experience was geared toward drilling and completions optimization, data science, and geophysical plug-in development for the energy industry. When Paige is not sitting in front of glowing rectangular screens at work, she absolutely adores hiking / kayaking / mountain-biking around Texas’ glorious Green Belt; resuscitating Apple ][s; and (poorly!) attempting to play bass guitar. Personal passions are sustainable energy and climate change research; STEM education reform; and empowering local governments via data science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-11-19:pytexas-2017/hacks-of-kindness-pytexas-2017-keynote.html</guid></item><item><title>I ♥ Maps: Quantum GIS + Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/i-maps-quantum-gis-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quantum GIS (QGIS) is an open-source, highly customizable geospatial
application that's great for data exploration, manipulation, and
cartographic preparation -- in other words, it's software that allows
you to make detailed, aesthetically-pleasing maps for free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QGIS is also &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; script-able with Python, and integrates with a
large number of database and analysis backends (GRASS, R, PostGIS,
etc.). In this talk, Paige Bailey will be giving a short overview of
QGIS; detailing a few mapping case studies; then showing how to leverage
additional functionality by writing custom Python plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-04:pytexas-2014/i-maps-quantum-gis-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Python 101++: Let's Get Down to Business</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/python-101-lets-get-down-to-business.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You've started the Codecademy and Coursera courses; you've thumbed
through Zed Shaw's &amp;quot;Learn Python the Hard Way&amp;quot;; and now you're itching
to see what Python can help you do. This is the workshop for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the breakdown: we're going to be taking you on a whirlwind tour
of Python's capabilities. By the end of the workshop, you should be able
to easily follow any of the widely available Python courses on the
internet, and have a grasp on some of the more complex aspects of the
language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don't forget to bring your personal laptop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: This course is aimed at those who already have some basic
programming experience, either in Python or in another high level
programming language (such as C/C++, Fortran, Java, Ruby, Perl, or
Visual Basic). If you're an absolute beginner -- new to Python, and new
to programming in general -- make sure to check out the &amp;quot;Python 101&amp;quot;
workshop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chapters: (00:00) (0:01:33) (0:01:39) (0:09:39) (0:10:24) (0:14:34)
(0:18:11) (0:23:45) (0:24:06) (0:25:37) (0:37:31) (1:28:25) (1:28:27)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pytexas-2014/python-101-lets-get-down-to-business.html</guid></item><item><title>Python 101: Python for Absolute Beginners</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/python-101-python-for-absolute-beginners.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you're absolutely new to Python, and to programming in general, this
is the place to start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the breakdown: by the end of this workshop, you'll have Python
downloaded onto your personal machine; have a general idea of what
Python can help you do; be pointed in the direction of some excellent
practice materials; and have a basic understanding of the syntax of the
language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don't forget to bring your laptop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &amp;quot;Python 101&amp;quot; is geared toward individuals who are new to
programming. If you've had some programming experience (shell scripting,
MATLAB, Ruby, etc.), then you'll probably want to check out the more
intermediate workshop, &amp;quot;Python 101++&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pytexas-2014/python-101-python-for-absolute-beginners.html</guid></item><item><title>Wrangling Big Data in the Energy Industry</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/wrangling-big-data-in-the-energy-industry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paige Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-15:pytexas-2015/wrangling-big-data-in-the-energy-industry.html</guid></item></channel></rss>