<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_wesley-chun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>What is Google App Engine?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wesley Chun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-23:pycon-ar-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk description: Google App Engine is an exciting development and cloud-hosting platform that lets you build &amp;amp; deploy web (and non-web) applications on Google's scalable high-traffic infrastructure using familiar development environments. App Engine apps execute on servers in Google data centers and use the same technology that powers Google's websites for speed, scalability, and reliability. Applications are easy to maintain and scale as your traffic and resource needs grow (or shrink). With App Engine, there is no need to think about virtual machine images, operating systems, databases, Web servers, licensing, software updates/patches, load-balancing, or other hardware requirements. You just upload your code to Google: use our simple deployment system will have your app up and ready to serve the world generally in less than 60 seconds!. The conference was in Junín ( Buenos Aires, Argentina ) in Septiembre 2011, and it was managed by PyAr ( Python Argentina ).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The bots are coming! Writing chatbots with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2018/the-bots-are-coming-writing-chatbots-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wesley Chun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-08-18:pybay-2018/the-bots-are-coming-writing-chatbots-with-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Get with it</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2017/get-with-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wesley Chun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-13:pybay-2017/get-with-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The with statement is relatively recent, having been introduced in Python 2.5. You have most likely used it or have seen it used with files. What's a &amp;quot;context manager&amp;quot; anyway, and why can't I use any Python object with with unless it has one? In this talk, we'll cover some background, objects you can use with the with statement, and show you how to add context management to your own objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The with statement is relatively recent, having been introduced into Python by PEP 343 and making its debut in Python 2.5. You have likely now used it or seen it used with files. Those who are long-time members of the Python community are getting with it now (pun indented). What's a &amp;quot;context manager&amp;quot; anyway, and why can't I use any Python object with with unless it has one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll go over the background on it, covering the motivation behind context management, and how the with statement uses it and follows the RAII concept where &amp;quot;resource allocation is initialization.&amp;quot; We'll describe what Python objects you can use with the with statement, and show you how to add context management to your own objects so you can use them with with. This includes writing your own context manager class as well as short-form alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WESLEY CHUN is the author of Prentice Hall's bestselling &amp;quot;Core Python&amp;quot; (corepython.com) series, co-author of Python Web Development with Django (withdjango.com), and has written for Linux Journal, CNET, and InformIT. In addition to being an engineer &amp;amp; Developer Advocate at Google, he runs CyberWeb (cyberwebconsulting.com), a consultancy specializing in Python training. He has over 25 years of programming, teaching, and writing experience, including over two decades of Python! Wesley was one of the original Yahoo! Mail engineers and holds degrees in CS, Math, and Music from the University of California. He is a Fellow of the Python Software Foundation and can be reached on Google+ (+WesleyChun) or Twitter (&amp;#64;wescpy).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>BayPiggies August 2016 Talk by Wesley Chun at LinkedIn: Exploring Google APIs with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/bay-piggies/baypiggies-august-2016-talk-by-wesley-chun-at-linkedin-exploring-google-apis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wesley Chun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-25:bay-piggies/baypiggies-august-2016-talk-by-wesley-chun-at-linkedin-exploring-google-apis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to integrate Google technologies into the web+mobile apps that you build? Did you know Google has various open source libraries that help you do exactly that? Users who may have tried &amp;amp; failed, run into roadblocks, been confused about using our APIs, or had issues with authentication are welcome to come and make these non-issues moving forward. Finally, we'll demo using multiple Google APIs to give you an idea of what it's all about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WESLEY CHUN, MSCS, is the author of Prentice Hall's bestselling &amp;quot;Core Python&amp;quot; book series &amp;amp; companion videos (corepython.com), co-author of &amp;quot;Python Web Development with Django&amp;quot; (withdjango.com), and has written for Linux Journal, CNET, and InformIT. In addition to being an engineer &amp;amp; Developer Advocate at Google, he runs CyberWeb (cyberwebconsulting.com), a consultancy specializing in Python training. Wesley has over 25 years of programming, teaching, and writing experience, including helping create Yahoo!Mail using Python almost 2 decades ago. He holds degrees in CS, Math, and Music from the University of California and loves traveling worldwide to meet developers, whether at a technical conference, user group meeting, or on a university campus. Wesley is a Fellow of the Python Software Foundation and can be reached on Google+ or Twitter (&amp;#64;wescpy).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>