<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_giuseppe-jurman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Differential network analysis and graph classification: a glocal approach</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/differential-network-analysis-and-graph-classification-a-glocal-approach.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Jurman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/differential-network-analysis-and-graph-classification-a-glocal-approach.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We propose a novel solution in differential network analysis to both the
network comparison and the classification tasks by introducing the
glocal HIM metric for comparing graphs and a graph kernel induced by the
HIM measure. The HIM distance is defined as the one-parameter family of
product metrics linearly combining the normalised Hamming distance H and
the normalised Ipsen- Mikhailov spectral distance IM. The combination of
the two components within a single metric allows overcoming their
drawbacks and obtaining a measure which is simultaneously global and
local. Furthermore, plugging the HIM kernel into a Support Vector
Machine gives us a classification algorithm based on the HIM distance.
Here we outline the underlying theoretical details of the metric
construction, and we present several applications of the HIM distance
and the HIM kernel to datasets belonging to different areas, including
socioeconomics, neuroscience, oncogenomics and developmental genomics,
supporting the adoption of the HIM family as a general analysis tool for
information extraction based on a quantitative evaluation of the
difference among diverse instances of a complex system. We conclude
introducing the Open Source implementation of the HIM metrics provided
in the R package nettols and in its web interface ReNette.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mathematics"></category><category term="algebra"></category><category term="Network"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Basic principles of scientific data visualization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/basic-principles-of-scientific-data-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Jurman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/basic-principles-of-scientific-data-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific data visualization has its rules, and they are essential to
warrant effectiveness of the desired message one wants to convey. In
this talk, following the guidelines of Edward Tufte, a master of data
visualization, we show why these rules are important, and what happens
if some of them are not properly followed and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DataVisualization"></category></entry></feed>