<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DjangoCon 2019- The promised Django Land; the tale of one team’s epic journey...</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2019/djangocon-2019-the-promised-django-land-the-tale-of-one-teams-epic-journey.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon 2019 - The promised Django Land; the tale of one team’s epic journey from Flask by Nicole Zuckerman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many orgs change frameworks mid-stream to more or less success; in this talk, you'll get a real-life fairytale of switching from Flask to Django, why each was valuable, how they got team buy-in, what technical decisions made things easier/harder, and how they switched without stopping product work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2019.djangocon.us/talks/the-promised-django-land-the-tale-of-one/"&gt;https://2019.djangocon.us/talks/the-promised-django-land-the-tale-of-one/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LINKS:
Follow Nicole Zuckerman 👇
On Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/zuckerpunch"&gt;https://twitter.com/zuckerpunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow DjangCon US 👇
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/djangocon"&gt;https://twitter.com/djangocon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow DEFNA 👇
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/defnado"&gt;https://twitter.com/defnado&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.defna.org/"&gt;https://www.defna.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intro music: &amp;quot;This Is How We Quirk It&amp;quot; by Avocado Junkie.
Video production by Confreaks TV.
Captions by White Coat Captioning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Zuckerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-23:djangocon-us-2019/djangocon-2019-the-promised-django-land-the-tale-of-one-teams-epic-journey.html</guid></item><item><title>The promised Django Land; the tale of one team’s epic journey from the country of Flask to Django Land</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2019/the-promised-django-land-the-tale-of-one-teams-epic-journey-from-the-country-of-flask-to-django-land.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your product doesn't stop while you take the time to do a massive rewrite in
order to change your language or framework.  It seems everyone has an
opinion on what the 'best' tools are, and views changing tools as a red
flag.  Many organizations do change frameworks or languages mid-stream, to
greater or lesser success; in this talk, you'll get a real-life fairy tale
of one company's move from Flask to Django, why each was the best choice at
the time, how they got team buy-in, what technical decisions made things
easier or harder, and how they switched without stopping all product work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Zuckerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-04:pygotham-2019/the-promised-django-land-the-tale-of-one-teams-epic-journey-from-the-country-of-flask-to-django-land.html</guid></item><item><title>One Engineer, an API, and an MVP: Or, how I spent one hour improving hiring data at my company.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/one-engineer-an-api-and-an-mvp-or-how-i-spent-one-hour-improving-hiring-data-at-my-company.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;announcer&amp;gt; This one quick trick will help you measure the diversity
of your hiring pipeline! Read on to hear how! &amp;lt;/announcer&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One challenge in improving diversity within a hiring pipeline is the
struggle to measure what exists in the first place. It's hard to know
where to focus your resources until you know what you have to work with,
and can identify what steps make a difference and what efforts don't.
Using python/django and an api key for our recruiting vendor, you can
make this information visible and, therefore, actionable, with very
little work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Zuckerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/one-engineer-an-api-and-an-mvp-or-how-i-spent-one-hour-improving-hiring-data-at-my-company.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>One Engineer, an API, and an MVP: Or how I spent one hour improving hiring data at my company.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2018/one-engineer-an-api-and-an-mvp-or-how-i-spent-one-hour-improving-hiring-data-at-my-company.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact that tech is struggling to hire or retain employees from
diverse backgrounds has been written about and discussed thoroughly,
particularly in the last few years. The economic, societal, and moral
benefits of diversity are also well documented. Why is it hard, then,
for well-intentioned organizations to shift their demographics? There
are a number of reasons, but one that doesn’t appear to have been
thoroughly discussed already is the challenge of gathering and
responding to data about diversity within a company’s hiring pool and
existing employees. One hack day, I was involved in too many projects
and had only a token amount of time to devote to the one I was most
interested in; seeing if we could determine whether we had sufficient
diversity for any given role to start interviewing candidates, or if we
needed to spend more efforts sourcing diverse candidates for the pool. I
accomplished an MVP in approximately an hour, once I had an api key and
permissions. It doesn’t necessarily require a huge effort to make a big
difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’ll walk through the MVP indicating, for each role,
whether there was “sufficient diversity”. I’ll also address gotchas,
limitations, and What Now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Zuckerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-16:djangocon-us-2018/one-engineer-an-api-and-an-mvp-or-how-i-spent-one-hour-improving-hiring-data-at-my-company.html</guid></item><item><title>Best Intentions, Least Measured</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2018/best-intentions-least-measured.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact that tech is struggling to hire or retain employees from diverse backgrounds has been written about and discussed thoroughly, particularly in the last few years.  The economic, societal, and moral benefits of diversity are also well documented.  Why is it hard, then, for well-intentioned organizations to shift their demographics?  There are a number of reasons, but one that doesn’t appear to have been thoroughly discussed already is the challenge of gathering and responding to data about diversity within a company’s hiring pool and existing employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizations have at least made some efforts to increase diversity, inclusion, or both; but how do you know which strategies were successful? What does success mean, and how do you measure the results of your effort?  Where do you even start?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data driven decision making is very popular in tech, but in order to measure an increase, you first need to know your starting point, and then you need to set up a repeatable data collection process to measure the change over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will describe the barriers to collecting information from employees and the candidate pool that prevent organizations from knowing what’s working, pitfalls to watch out for, and some tools that have helped us obtain data necessary to make informed choices and improve our diversity and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Zuckerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-05:pygotham-2018/best-intentions-least-measured.html</guid></item><item><title>Fixing the Tech Interview</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2017/fixing-the-tech-interview.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technical interviewing is a mess. Social media is full of stories from experienced, qualified developers who struggle to get through even initial screening at tech companies, and those same tech companies' blogs are full of stories about how they can't find enough qualified developers. Something is very obviously wrong here, but what? And what can we do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing from experience on both ends of the interviewing table, this talk will explore some of the underlying causes of bad interviews, challenge assumptions baked in to popular interview processes, and discuss ways to build more reliable and more humane technical interviews. This talk is for anyone involved in tech hiring who's interested in learning why current approaches so often fail, and how to fix it. No experience as an interviewer or hiring manager is required. Attendees will come away with an understanding of major systemic issues in how tech interviews are typically conducted, and a framework and specific suggestions for how to remedy these issues and build interview processes which are better and more useful for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bennett</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-07:pygotham-2017/fixing-the-tech-interview.html</guid></item><item><title>The Glory of pdb's set_trace</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/the-glory-of-pdbs-set_trace.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs to debug code, and it can take up a non-trivial portion
of our time to wait for code to complete execution and write print
messages to stdout. There’s one function in particular in the python
debugger (pdb) library that can give you a much clearer understanding of
what’s going on in your code, much more quickly; pdb.set_ trace(). In
this talk, we’ll identify the most useful things you can do when you use
set trace, that can make debugging exponentially more efficient and
enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Zuckerman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-19:pycon-us-2017/the-glory-of-pdbs-set_trace.html</guid><category>debugging</category><category>tools</category></item><item><title>Technical on-boarding, training, and mentoring.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2014/technical-on-boarding-training-and-mentoring.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a talk about how to make junior and new engineers into
independent and productive members of your engineering team faster and
cheaper. We will focus on python specific resources and libraries that
will help you create a simple but effective on boarding program, and
talk about case studies of companies that have had success using these
techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kate Heddleston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-04-13:pycon-us-2014/technical-on-boarding-training-and-mentoring.html</guid></item><item><title>Getting comfortable with web security: A hands-on session</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/getting-comfortable-with-web-security-a-hands-on.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web application security can be an intimidating discipline, yet it can
be of supreme importance for the people who use the things we build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you'll learn about essential topics in web security,
and you will gain hands-on practice identifying and leveraging
vulnerabilities in a Python-based web app. For each issue, we will cover
how your code can stay on the side of safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Asheesh Laroia</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-10:pycon-us-2015/getting-comfortable-with-web-security-a-hands-on.html</guid></item></channel></rss>