<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Rob de Wit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Transforming a Jupyter Notebook into a reproducible pipeline for ML experiments</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/transforming-a-jupyter-notebook-into-a-reproducible-pipeline-for-ml-experiments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks are part of every data scientist's arsenal and for
good reason. But while they're great for prototyping in data science
projects, they are not ideal for experimenting with different
configurations. I have been guilty of running experiments with changing
parameters while keeping track on a notepad, and the result has always
been messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will explore how we can transform our notebook
prototype into a reproducible pipeline. We will discuss what goes wrong
without proper experiment tracking, why reproducibility is the key to
solving this, and how we can achieve that with Git and DVC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss this topic using a text2image project with Stable
Diffusion. I'll show how to break up a notebook into modules, create a
pipeline from them, run experiments through the pipeline, and compare
their results to find the best possible outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target audience will be data scientists that don't have a strong
engineering background but would like to move beyond messing about in
notebooks. Much like myself a year or two ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob de Wit</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/transforming-a-jupyter-notebook-into-a-reproducible-pipeline-for-ml-experiments.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>