<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ingrid-budau.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The Apprentice's Enthusiastic Guide to pandas (or how to look at the world through the gentle eyes of one)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2019/the-apprentices-enthusiastic-guide-to-pandas-or-how-to-look-at-the-world-through-the-gentle-eyes-of-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ingrid Budau</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-03-24:pycon-sk-2019/the-apprentices-enthusiastic-guide-to-pandas-or-how-to-look-at-the-world-through-the-gentle-eyes-of-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pandas soon realized there's no way they are going to survive the
ordeals and hardships of this world, if they didn't finally and without
the blink of an eye of hesitation pull themselves together, stop being
the lazy fluffy beings, they have long been known for and start
reorganizing their lives ASAP. They needed a fresh view over the world
and its intrinsic mechanisms, light had to be shed upon the information
they possessed about survival, in a few words, they had to start over.
This is how in the midst of the forest a high performative library was
coming to life, whose powerful toolkit would enable them a long lasting
life of happiness and joy. This long-dreamed library should import the
information they have been gathering about the world for long gone
centuries and help them look at it through different eyes. They wanted
to structure their world views and beliefs into sensible types and
categories, remove from their genes their procrastinative behavioural
patterns, drop them altogether. After laborious efforts of dealing with
missing data about their surroundings, grouping and counting the
meaningful rest, filtering the nonsensical superstitions, they could
finally and, without doubt, point out with precision, where the bamboo
sprouts were freshest, most succulent, fiber rich, absolutely
scrumptious and the moment of the year, dictated by the moon calendar,
when they are fluffiest, cosiest, most willing and irresistibly fall for
one another and cuddle up. They put all this secret survival kit into
easily understandable pictures and graphs for the dreamers out of them,
who weren't prepared to put in all the effort of learning all those
complicated symbols, just in order to survive and just wanted to admire
the sky goddess, the moon. But wait, they didn't have a name for their
grandiose library, so they just wanted to make a statement of being the
most diligent creature of them all and called it, simply and
unmistakably, pandas!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>