<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lachlan-blackhall.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Analysing a TwitterBot using TextBlob, NLTK and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/analysing-a-twitterbot-using-textblob-nltk-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lachlan Blackhall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/analysing-a-twitterbot-using-textblob-nltk-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64;MagicRealismBot is a Twitter bot that randomly generates succinct story synopses that it can tweet. In this talk we will show how we can use TextBlob (and NLTK) to analyse the stories generated by &amp;#64;MagicRealismBot and extract the underlying patterns used to generate the tweets. We will show how TextBlob can be used to analyses the tweets (for example, by sentence extraction and part-of-speech tagging) allowing us to 'reverse engineer' the underlying patterns of the Twitter bot. We will also highlight the variety of other analyses that TextBlob can perform and touch on the state of natural language processing in Python, and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Working with real-time data streams in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/working-with-real-time-data-streams-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lachlan Blackhall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:pycon-au-2016/working-with-real-time-data-streams-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of devices and applications are producing vast amounts of data in real time. This can include measurements, sensor readings, and performance data. Making this data useful often requires that we analyse and use the data in real time but this requires techniques to aggregate, filter, and smooth the data. Drawing on simple and well-tested techniques from mathematics and engineering allows us to solve these problems quickly and efficiently. This talk will describe how Python can be used to develop powerful capabilities for working with real-time data streams and provide simple examples you can start using yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Internet-of-Things"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Real-time"></category><category term="Kalman Filter"></category></entry><entry><title>Graphs, Networks and Python: The Power of Interconnection by Lachlan Blackhall</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/graphs-networks-and-python-the-power-of-interc.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lachlan Blackhall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-09:pycon-au-2014/graphs-networks-and-python-the-power-of-interc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graph and network structures are everywhere and can be found in social,
biological and technological networks that impact us on a daily basis.
Understanding, and exploiting, graphical structures creates
opportunities for obtaining new analytic insights, implementing new
computational paradigms, and better defining the relationship between
objects of any sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python provides access to these graph and network structures using the
fantastic NetworkX library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://networkx.github.io/"&gt;http://networkx.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;) . In this
presentation we will give an introduction to the NetworkX library,
showing how easy it is to build and exploit simple graphical and network
structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that starting point we will then discuss a number of more
complicated, real world examples of how the NetworkX library can be used
to: - Analyse social networks to extract valuable information about
people / entities within those networks. - Implement reconfigurable
processing pipelines (something we refer to as computational graphs) for
data capture, processing and analytics. - Easily track the relationship
between Python objects in a variety of other interesting and useful
scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will be targeted at intermediate developers and no
prior experience with graphs, networks or NetworkX is required. This
presentation will offer an easy introduction to the world of networks
and graphs in Python and will illustrate real world uses of this
powerful and useful paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Learn You a Flask</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/learn-you-a-flask.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lachlan Blackhall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/learn-you-a-flask.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flask is a Python web framework that is both lightweight and powerful.
With an active community, and a diverse and versatile choice of plugins,
Flask allows you to scale from simple single-URL websites through to
highly complex website architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will begin by setting up a simple Flask powered website
and get it running on the Heroku PaaS. We will then demonstrate how to
integrate Flask and SQLAlchemy (a powerful ORM) to allow database access
and get this uploaded and working on Heroku as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we will discuss some more advanced concepts and review a number
of the Flask plugins to get you started on the path to building great
web-based projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>