<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Our Data, Ourselves</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-london-2015/our-data-ourselves.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;20 young coders with smartphones pre-loaded with an app that gathered
data on the network activity of the other apps they used. Their data
was captured using the Python-based data portal CKAN, analysed with
SciKit-Learn, then returned to them using Docker and the Ipython
Notebook. Python also played a role in the reverse-engineering of
some of the more interesting apps we discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://big-social-data.net/"&gt;Our Data, Ourselves&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; project
seeks to explore the possibility of making the data-trails of smartphone
users available ethically in a &amp;quot;social data commons&amp;quot;. We issued 20 young
coders from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.yrs.io/"&gt;Young Rewired State&lt;/a&gt; with Android
smartphones pre- loaded with an
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kingsbsd.github.io/MobileMiner/"&gt;app&lt;/a&gt; that tracked their
other apps' network usage and recorded commonly captured data. This was
collected using the Python-based data portal
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ckan.org/"&gt;CKAN&lt;/a&gt;, the advantages and pitfalls of which will
be discussed. Users' GSM cell-tower locations from the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencellid.org/"&gt;OpenCellId&lt;/a&gt; database were clustered using
k-means via SciKit-Learn. Careful feature-vector selection yielded deep
insights into their everyday lives. This helped provoke discussions with
the participants about their understanding of privacy related to their
mobile app usage. We held a hack-day to return their data to them using
a Docker container wrapping a copy of the CKAN instance that could be
queried through an Ipython Notebook. Further details about the users'
apps were obtained by scraping the Google PlayStore, which presented
some challenges. Apps with particularly interesting patterns of network
usage were reverse-engineered and their network traffic captured. We
have run a &amp;quot;masterclass&amp;quot; on Android app reversal supported by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kingsbsd.github.io/DroidDestructionKit/"&gt;distributing software
tools&lt;/a&gt; in another
Docker container, many of them Python-based. The final phase of our
project will be conducted in conjunction with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opendatainstitute.org/"&gt;Open Data
Institute&lt;/a&gt;, integrating our app with
M.I.T's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://openpds.media.mit.edu/"&gt;Open Personal Data Store&lt;/a&gt;,
also written in Python, to give its users greater granularity of control
as to how their data is used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giles Greenway</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-21:pydata-london-2015/our-data-ourselves.html</guid></item></channel></rss>