<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Eric Nantz</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_eric-nantz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A New Era for Shiny-based Clinical Submissions using WebAssembly</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/a-new-era-for-shiny-based-clinical-submissions-using-webassembly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eric Nantz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/a-new-era-for-shiny-based-clinical-submissions-using-webassembly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In life sciences, Shiny has enabled tremendous innovations to produce web interfaces as front-ends to sophisticated analyses, interactive visualizations, and clinical reporting. While industry sponsors have widely adopted Shiny, a relatively unexplored frontier has been the inclusion of a Shiny application inside a submission package to the FDA. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In life sciences, Shiny has enabled tremendous innovations to produce web interfaces as front-ends to sophisticated analyses, interactive visualizations, and clinical reporting. While industry sponsors have widely adopted Shiny, a relatively unexplored frontier has been the inclusion of a Shiny application inside a submission package to the FDA. The R Consortium R-Submissions Working Group has continued the momentum of previous submission pilots, such as the successful Shiny app submission to the FDA in 2023. In this talk, I will share the journey of how we used containers and WebAssembly for a new and innovative approach to sharing a Shiny application directly with the FDA, paving the way for new innovation in the clinical submission process.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Posit:Conf 2024"></category></entry></feed>