<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Uzoma Nicholas Muoh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_uzoma-nicholas-muoh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Into the Logisticverse: Improving Efficiency in Transportation Networks using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/into-the-logisticverse-improving-efficiency-in-transportation-networks-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Uzoma Nicholas Muoh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-21:/pycon-us-2023/into-the-logisticverse-improving-efficiency-in-transportation-networks-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we think about what Python is for, we often think of things like
analytics, machine learning, and web apps but python is a workhorse that
plays a tremendous and often invisible role in our day-to-day lives,
from medicine to finance, and even the transportation of goods from
manufacturers …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we think about what Python is for, we often think of things like
analytics, machine learning, and web apps but python is a workhorse that
plays a tremendous and often invisible role in our day-to-day lives,
from medicine to finance, and even the transportation of goods from
manufacturers to the shelves of our neighborhood stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transportation networks are highly dynamic, goods are always moving from
point A to point B and money every minute is being gained or lost.
Improving efficiency in a transportation network is critical to the
survival of a business that provides transportation and distribution
services as well as ensuring timely delivery of goods to customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk examines 3 real-world examples of how Python is used to
improve the efficiency of transportation networks, particularly we will
explore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding the optimal match between a driver and a load at the lowest
possible cost using google's &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ortools&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generating recommendations for macro level optimizations to a
transportation network using &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;networkX&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping the descision making process by answering the question
&amp;quot;Should I accept this work?&amp;quot; using &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;skfuzzy&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph analytics and data science concepts that facilitate getting
goods from manufacturers to stores more efficiently and at a lower
cost to businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An appreciation of the complexity of the logistics industry and the
role Python plays in making the life of drivers better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2023"></category></entry></feed>