<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Syed Ahmed</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_syed-ahmed.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Making the Most of Heterogeneous Memory Capacity Using PyTorch</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytorch-conference-2024/making-the-most-of-heterogeneous-memory-capacity-using-pytorch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Syed Ahmed</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-18:/pytorch-conference-2024/making-the-most-of-heterogeneous-memory-capacity-using-pytorch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Memory intensive deep learning workloads require efficient use of all kinds of memories that are available in a system. In this session, we will discuss how we can utilize such heterogeneous memory through memory pools in PyTorch. We will show how to mix-and-match different CUDA system allocators in the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Memory intensive deep learning workloads require efficient use of all kinds of memories that are available in a system. In this session, we will discuss how we can utilize such heterogeneous memory through memory pools in PyTorch. We will show how to mix-and-match different CUDA system allocators in the same PyTorch program using memory pools. Consequently, this API unlocks new use cases such as Extended GPU Memory (EGM) based all-gathers, Unified Virtual Memory (UVM), and NVLink Sharp (NVLS) reductions. New NVIDIA architectures accelerate such use cases with high-bandwidth and low-latency interconnects in the hardware, driven by extended functionality of CUDA system allocators in the software. Learn how to use these techniques on memory-intensive deep learning models like LLMs, and discover new CUDA features powered by PyTorch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyTorch Conference 2024"></category><category term="Lightning Talk"></category></entry></feed>