<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Katelyn Morrison</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Civic Hacking &amp; Urban Informatics: Mapping Data with GeoPandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2020/civic-hacking-urban-informatics-mapping-data-with-geopandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As more and more communities are experiencing rapid urban sprawl, the
management of infrastructure and resources provided is becoming crucial.
Open source datasets are imperative to monitoring and implementing
change throughout cities; in fact, a large majority of these datasets
can be mapped spatially. But how can you visualize multiple datasets
spatially without skills in ArcGIS? This 10 minute thunder talk
highlights how to harness libraries in Python to visualize data
spatially through an urban informatics case study on bike sharing
systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mapping data geographically at industry level is performed in ArcGIS,
but ArcGIS is a complex, costly application. Mapping data helps us
understand how socio-technical systems are disrupted or improved by
laws, policies, and infrastructure projects. For example, in ArcGIS you
can map the percentage of the population within a high-crime
neighborhood or understand how the location of public transit correlates
to a neighborhood’s socioeconomic status. But, you can also map this
data using libraries in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is geared towards those who have a basic understanding of data
science and data visualization, but want to dive deeper into the realms
of mapping data science for social good. From briefly reviewing methods
in Pandas to diving deep into methods in GeoPandas, the audience will
gain a better understanding of how to derive a spatial component from a
dataset, how to turn shapefiles into GeoDataFrames and plot them, and
how to create quantitative and thematic maps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katelyn Morrison</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-25:/pyohio-2020/civic-hacking-urban-informatics-mapping-data-with-geopandas.html</guid><category>PyOhio 2020</category></item></channel></rss>