<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning talk 02 - Creating the Next Generation of Billionaires</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2019/lightning-talk-02-creating-the-next-generation-of-billionaires.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilian Nandi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-31:pycon-se-2019/lightning-talk-02-creating-the-next-generation-of-billionaires.html</guid><category>lightning talk</category></item><item><title>Secret Arts of Teaching Coding to the Next Generation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/secret-arts-of-teaching-coding-to-the-next-generation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Secret &amp;amp; Undiscovered Arts of Teaching Coding to the Next Generation Successfully&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Science is now the leading discipline of the 21st century.
Computers and technology are now ubiquitous and prevalent in all sectors
of society such as the arts, sciences, medicine, commerce, etc.
Technology also plays a huge role in the world economy and the market
capitalisation of the FAANGs' Facebook, Apple, Amazon, Netflix and
Alphabet’s Google along with a couple of other technologies is more or
less equivalent to the GDP of Japan - the world's 3rd richest nation.
Therefore, computer programming is now regarded as an essential skill
for the young person, and it has been dubbed the ‘4th’ R’ (computer
pRogramming) along with reading, writing and arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In recognition of the new status of computer programming, governments
worldwide have launched initiatives to have it taught in schools from
Kindergarten through to junior school and all the way through
secondary school.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;So, the question emerges is how do we best teach the next generation
in acquiring this skill? Given the fact that this field is very much
in its infancy, there is very little pedagogy to guide the educator.
Therefore, the whole world is learning how best to teach this subject
by trial and error.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will describe a case study whereby coding/computer programming,
in the form of Python, was introduced to a group of 110 young people
from the ages of 11 to 18 (Years 7-13 in an UK secondary school). The
talk will include descriptions of the various teaching methodologies
introduced to the young people for this purpose and the outcomes; the
talk will also address various challenges and questions about how to
teach programming to young people. The talk will conclude with helpful
suggestions, based on the findings of the case study, on how to proceed
with the teaching of computer programming to these people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilian Nandi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-16:pycon-uk-2018/secret-arts-of-teaching-coding-to-the-next-generation.html</guid></item></channel></rss>