<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vinicius-gubiani-ferreira.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Effective Code Reviews</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/effective-code-reviews.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinicius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/effective-code-reviews.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The edge between hard skills and soft skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does your company uses code review? In this talk I will demonstrate why it should start using them immediately, share the many benefits and situations we've gone through, besides good practices that should be used for effective code reviews, that add …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The edge between hard skills and soft skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does your company uses code review? In this talk I will demonstrate why it should start using them immediately, share the many benefits and situations we've gone through, besides good practices that should be used for effective code reviews, that add quality to the product/service that is being delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Agile"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Clean Code"></category><category term="Code Analysis"></category><category term="Communication"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Anti-Patterns</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2021/python-anti-patterns.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinicius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-26:/europython-2021/python-anti-patterns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python Anti-Patterns
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Vinicius Gubiani Ferreira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people heard at least once or focused really hard on studying design patterns. But did you know there are also lots of anti-patterns we should try to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I intend to present some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python Anti-Patterns
[EuroPython 2021 - Talk - 2021-07-29 - Brian]
[Online]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Vinicius Gubiani Ferreira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people heard at least once or focused really hard on studying design patterns. But did you know there are also lots of anti-patterns we should try to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I intend to present some of the most known anti-design patterns that we'll promise never to use ... but for some reason or slip end up using it anyway. I will start showing more generic anti-patterns that apply to all languages and software in general, and move on to Python specifics, by using The Little Book of Python Anti-Patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there will be Python code, attendees should fell confort with some basic to intermediate Python knowledge. For example: know about classes, constructors, parameters/arguments, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License: This video is licensed under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;
Please see our speaker release agreement for details: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/"&gt;https://ep2021.europython.eu/events/speaker-release-agreement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2021"></category></entry><entry><title>From pip to poetry - Python ways of packaging and publishing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/from-pip-to-poetry-python-ways-of-packaging-and-publishing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/from-pip-to-poetry-python-ways-of-packaging-and-publishing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - From pip to poetry - Python (many) ways of packaging and publishing - presented by Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever had issues to manage your python packages and environment? Do you know how to create and share a package to the community? It can be challenging …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - From pip to poetry - Python (many) ways of packaging and publishing - presented by Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Liffey B on 2022-07-13]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever had issues to manage your python packages and environment? Do you know how to create and share a package to the community? It can be challenging if you've never done it, but it also doesn't have to be hard. There is always a better tool to fit our needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, I'd like to discuss how Python's package managers appeared and evolved with time. Discussing pip, pipenv, and poetry, presenting each of their weak and strong points. Also intend to present how to package and publish a simple code with each one of them, and suggest which package manager should you choose, whether you are just starting with python, or feel like there is something bothering and never knew you could solve it easily and painless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be accessed here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/vinigfer/europython_2022_slides"&gt;https://github.com/vinigfer/europython_2022_slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2022"></category></entry><entry><title>CLI application development made easier with typer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2023/cli-application-development-made-easier-with-typer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-07-17:/europython-2023/cli-application-development-made-easier-with-typer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/cli-application-development-made-easier-with-typer"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/cli-application-development-made-easier-with-typer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you feel like digging through github code to learn how to use it is painful? Also think simply packaging and publishing your library to the world on pypi sometimes isn't enough to help others use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2023 — South Hall 2A on 2023-07-19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/cli-application-development-made-easier-with-typer"&gt;https://ep2023.europython.eu/session/cli-application-development-made-easier-with-typer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you feel like digging through github code to learn how to use it is painful? Also think simply packaging and publishing your library to the world on pypi sometimes isn't enough to help others use what you are working on? Then come join me, as this talks is definitely for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, I'd like to present you typer, and why it's probably the easiest and most affordable way to create command line applications (in 2023) that your users will love to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll discuss it's key strong points, how to structure your CLI application, and make it ready to be packaged and published with no hussle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2023"></category></entry><entry><title>PEP 683: Immortal Objects - A new approach for memory managing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PEP 683: Immortal Objects - A new approach for memory managing by Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most people that use Python, worrying about memory is not an issue. But that's not the case when you have to handle …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — Terrace 2B on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PEP 683: Immortal Objects - A new approach for memory managing by Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most people that use Python, worrying about memory is not an issue. But that's not the case when you have to handle a lot of requests on a large scale. So how do you reduce memory consumption without affecting the CPU?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I'll discuss about memory management in Python from the basics, where the necessity for PEP 683 came from, and the changes introduced by it. I also intend to discuss why this PEP is so important for the language, and what we'll be able to achieve with it in the future, such as changes to the GIL and true parallelism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is targeted for folks who are intermediate/advanced pythonistas. People who are just starting with Python (maybe less than 1.5 years) may feel a bit lost. Even so, curious learners are more than welcome to join, and I'll try my best to make it easy for all audiences on this advanced topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this presentation, participants will learn a bit more about how memory management works under the hood in python, and how it may change in the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>PEP 683: Immortal Objects - A new approach for memory managing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2024/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinícius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2024-05-17:/pycon-us-2024/pep-683-immortal-objects-a-new-approach-for-memory-managing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most people that use Python, worrying about memory is not an issue.
But that's not the case when you have to handle a lot of requests on a
large scale. So how do you reduce memory consumption without affecting
the CPU?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I'll discuss about memory …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most people that use Python, worrying about memory is not an issue.
But that's not the case when you have to handle a lot of requests on a
large scale. So how do you reduce memory consumption without affecting
the CPU?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I'll discuss about memory management in Python from
the basics, where the necessity for PEP 683 came from, and the changes
introduced by it. I also intend to discuss why this PEP is so important
for the language, and what we'll be able to achieve with it in the
future, such as changes to the GIL and true parallelism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is targeted for folks who are intermediate/advanced
pythonistas. People who are just starting with Python (maybe less than
1.5 years) may feel a bit lost. Even so, curious learners are more than
welcome to join, and I'll try my best to make it easy for all audiences
on this advanced topic. After this presentation, participants will learn
a bit more about how memory management works under the hood in python,
and how it may change in the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon US 2024"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting started with Fuzz testing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2021/getting-started-with-fuzz-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinicius Gubiani Ferreira</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-10-02:/pygotham-2021/getting-started-with-fuzz-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is your project safe against unforeseen scenarios? Are you sure? How about
if we take it for a ride then? There is almost no software completely error
free. And catch all of the possible errors is hard, not to say almost
impossible, but what if we use tools that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is your project safe against unforeseen scenarios? Are you sure? How about
if we take it for a ride then? There is almost no software completely error
free. And catch all of the possible errors is hard, not to say almost
impossible, but what if we use tools that help us bring possible issues to
our attention? Those that might cause security issues, or bad user
experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation I'll discuss how to get started with fuzz testing: The
art of hitting software with invalid, unexpected, or random data and seeing
how it reacts. I'll present valid scenarios for fixing the bugs found, some
of the existing tools, and how to integrate fuzz testing with our existing
tests.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyGotham 2021"></category></entry></feed>