<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_eric-evenchick.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Hacking Cars with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/hacking-cars-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eric Evenchick</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-21:pycon-us-2017/hacking-cars-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern cars are networks of computers, and a high end vehicle could have
nearly 100 different computers inside. These devices control everything
from the engine to the airbags. By understanding how these systems work,
we can interface with vehicles to read data, perform diagnostics, and
even modify operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll discuss pyvit, the Python Vehicle Interface Toolkit.
This library, combined with some open source hardware, allows developers
to talk to automotive controllers from Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will begin with an introduction to automotive networks, to provide a
basis for understanding the tools. Next, we will look at the tools and
show the basics of using them. Finally, we'll discuss real world
applications of these tools, and how they're being used in the
automotive world today.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hacking Cars with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2016/hacking-cars-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eric Evenchick</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-12:pycon-ca-2016/hacking-cars-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern cars are basically networks of computers, which control
everything from the engine to the airbags. We'll briefly cover how
vehicle networks work, then demonstrate how to access to the network
using Python and open-source hardware. Finally, we'll discuss some
attacks that can be performed on these systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>