<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michael-mathioudakis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Visualizing twitter discussions with networkx</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2016/visualizing-twitter-discussions-with-networkx.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kiran Garimella</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-31:pycon-finland-2016/visualizing-twitter-discussions-with-networkx.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visualizing twitter discussions with networkx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, millions of people use social media like Twitter or Facebook, to catch up on news and engage in discussions with other users. Our research group at Aalto University analyzes such discussions and studies how people interact on social media. Towards this end, visualization can be a very useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we use networkx, a python library, to process and visualize user interactions on Twitter. We introduce networkx with simple examples and continue with the visualization of twitter data. During the talk, we’ll see that discussions about polarized topics (e.g., elections) look quite different than non-polarised ones.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the authors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiran Garimella is a PhD student at the Department of Computer Science, Aalto University. For his PhD, Kiran studies controversy and polarization on social media. Earlier in his career, he worked as Research Engineer at Yahoo! Research and the Qatar Computing Research Institute, and Machine Learning / Data Science intern at LinkedIn and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Mathioudakis is a postdoctoral researcher at the Department of Computer Science, Aalto University. His research focuses on social media, social networks, and urban computing. Earlier, Michael did a PhD at the University of Toronto, and worked as Research Intern at Microsoft and Yahoo! Research. He is also currently working as a Data Scientist at Sometrik.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>