<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Vinay Kakade</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_vinay-kakade.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Simplify DevOps with Executable Notebooks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/jupytercon-2023/simplify-devops-with-executable-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Amit Rathi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-05-10:/jupytercon-2023/simplify-devops-with-executable-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, Jupyter Notebooks are mostly confined to science, research &amp;amp; education. But notebooks can provide organizations with a powerful general-purpose “executable documentation” platform. A solid use case for this is DevOps &amp;amp; more specifically, IT incident response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology teams usually have an on-call rotation with static wiki-style documentation to guide the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, Jupyter Notebooks are mostly confined to science, research &amp;amp; education. But notebooks can provide organizations with a powerful general-purpose “executable documentation” platform. A solid use case for this is DevOps &amp;amp; more specifically, IT incident response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology teams usually have an on-call rotation with static wiki-style documentation to guide the on-call engineer. Jupyter Notebooks can replace static documentation with executable notebooks. E.g. “fetch service logs” and “rollback last deployment” can simply mean executing a code cell that’s available alongside the markdown instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the benefits of executable vs. static documentation for DevOps -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick e.g. “check DB latency” is 1-click notebook code cell execution to plot latency graph vs. going to a third-party UI in the middle of an incidence
Precise e.g. “promote read replica to master” can mean a series of steps &amp;amp; possibility of human error; codifying the steps in advance removes ambiguity &amp;amp; results in precise action.
“Executable documentation” is a simple yet powerful concept that can extend to other use cases such as - API documentation, developer onboarding, data visualization &amp;amp; reporting, scheduling routine tasks &amp;amp; so on. Think of it as executable GoogleDocs powered by Jupyter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’d like to,
- Introduce the concept of Jupyter powered “executable documentation” platform, particularly for DevOps and Incident Response,
- Show a demo of how it’d work - (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vvLXSAHCGF8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vvLXSAHCGF8&lt;/a&gt;)
- Talk about important challenges, and propose a way forward to make this a mainstream application of Jupyter notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="JupyterCon 2023"></category></entry></feed>