<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Chelsea Parlett-Pelleriti</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shiny for Python Machine Learning Apps with pandas, scikit-learn and TensorFlow</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2023/shiny-for-python-machine-learning-apps-with-pandas-scikit-learn-and-tensorflow.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the introduction of Shiny for Python in 2022, users can now use the power of reactivity with their favorite Python packages. Shiny can be used to build interactive reports, dashboards, and web apps, that make sharing insights and results both simple and dynamic. This includes apps to display and explore popular Machine Learning models built with staple Python packages like pandas, scikit-learn, and TensorFlow. This talk will demonstrate how to build simple Shiny for Python apps that interface with these packages, and discuss some of the benefits of using Shiny for Python to build your web apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chelsea Parlett-Pelleriti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-09-17:/positconf-2023/shiny-for-python-machine-learning-apps-with-pandas-scikit-learn-and-tensorflow.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2023</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning is Just LEGO: &amp; Other Hands on Machine Learning Activities</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/positconf-2024/deep-learning-is-just-lego-other-hands-on-machine-learning-activities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning involves a lot of math, and a lot of code. But it can also involve LEGO, coloring sheets, and 3D-printed gradients! Hands-on, kinesthetic activities help people learn complex technical concepts in an intuitive way, and, to be honest, provide a welcome break from all the formulas and function definitions. These activities not only increase engagement but make the topic more accessible to a wider range of people. Come learn how to use and design these activities for yourself, or for a class!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chelsea Parlett-Pelleriti</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-08-12:/positconf-2024/deep-learning-is-just-lego-other-hands-on-machine-learning-activities.html</guid><category>Posit:Conf 2024</category></item></channel></rss>