<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Natalia Bidart</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inside Out: My Journey of Understanding Inclusion</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2023/inside-out-my-journey-of-understanding-inclusion.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll share my personal journey of understanding diversity and inclusion.
Being part of a minority group, I have encountered numerous challenges, I've learned
a lot, and made my fair share of mistakes along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation is an opportunity to reflect on my experiences, sharing the lessons
learned and real-life stories that have shaped my view on the matter. Get ready for a
captivating array of anecdotes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll openly discuss the challenges I've faced and the insights I've gained,
highlighting both successes and shortcomings, always offering a perspective rather than
definitive solutions or comprehensive analysis. I'll cover topics such as tone connotations,
inclusive[n|l]ess of different languages, the importance of company policies, quirks
derived from cultural and social norms, and more. In the final segment of this talk, I
will discuss my recent experience within the Django project and community as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is not intended to provide a one-size-fits-all approach, but rather to inspire
thought, reflection, and positive change. I hope to encourage open dialogue among
attendees, as we explore strategies for creating a more inclusive, diverse and
equitable environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalia Bidart</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-10-18:/djangocon-us-2023/inside-out-my-journey-of-understanding-inclusion.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2023</category></item><item><title>Keynote - The Fellowship of the Pony</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2024/keynote-the-fellowship-of-the-pony.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This keynote will present the Django Fellowship program, highlighting its critical role in the maintenance and development of the Django project. It will cover the purpose and significance of the Fellowship, illustrating how it contributes to the project's overall success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will explore the daily tasks and responsibilities of a Django Fellow, including their priorities and key activities, with a focus on the contributing process . We will reflect on how we can make the most of the current Fellowship program, which is supported by 1.5 Fellows, and also on how the active involvement of the community is essential to Django's evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalia Bidart</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-09-25:/djangocon-us-2024/keynote-the-fellowship-of-the-pony.html</guid><category>DjangoCon US 2024</category></item><item><title>PyGtk</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2011/pygtk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descripción de la charla: GTK+ [0] es un poderoso toolkit para desarrollar aplicaciones gráficas. Está escrito en C, pero podemos usarlo desde varios lenguajes gracias al proyecto Gobject Instrospection, entre ellos, desde Python. Esta charla hará las veces de introducción para desarrollar una aplicación básica GTK+ usando Python. Para ello, vamos a mostrar (y explicar) snippets de código que se irán complejizando a medida que la charla progrese. La construcción de la interfaz gráfica la haremos con Glade, y daremos un pantallazo de cómo se usa, para qué sirve, y qué problemas nos soluciona.. La conferencia tuvo lugar en Junín, Buenos Aires, Argentina en Septiembre de 2011, y fué organizada por PyAr ( Python Argentina ).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalia Bidart</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-23:/pycon-ar-2011/pygtk.html</guid><category>PyCon Ar 2011</category></item><item><title>Call me maybe, Test me always</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2013/call-me-maybe-test-me-always.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lo largo de todos estos años ya se predicó lo suficiente sobre la necesidad y beneficio de testear los programas hechos en Python. Ahora, vamos a convencerte de lo fácil y divertido que es testear los programas hechos en C, usando Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/DKnx/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/DKnx/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalia Bidart</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-24:/pycon-ar-2013/call-me-maybe-test-me-always.html</guid><category>PyCon Ar 2013</category></item><item><title>Me voy a hacer pypy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2013/me-voy-a-hacer-pypy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/DKoA/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/DKoA/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalia Bidart</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-24:/pycon-ar-2013/me-voy-a-hacer-pypy.html</guid><category>PyCon Ar 2013</category></item></channel></rss>