<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fantastic Data and Where To Find Them: An introduction to APIs, RSS, and Scraping</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/fantastic-data-and-where-to-find-them-an-introduction-to-apis-rss-and-scraping.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re building a custom web application, getting started in
machine learning, or just want to try something new, everyone needs
data. And while the web offers a seemingly boundless source for custom
data sets, the collection of that data can present a whole host of
obstacles. From ever-changing APIs to rate-limiting woes, from
nightmarishly nested XML to convoluted DOM trees, working with APIs and
web scraping are challenging but critically useful skills for
application developers and data scientists alike. In this tutorial,
we’ll introduce RESTful APIs, RSS feeds, and web scraping in order to
see how different ingestion techniques impact application development.
We’ll explore how and when to use Python libraries such as
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;feedparser&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;requests&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;beautifulsoup&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;urllib&lt;/tt&gt;. And
finally we will present common data collection problems and how to
overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll take a hands-on, directed exercise approach combined with short
presentations to engage a range of different APIs (with and without
authentication), explore examples of how and why you might web scrape,
and learn the ethical and legal considerations for both. To prepare
attendees to create their own data ingestion scripts, the tutorial will
walk through a set of examples for robust and responsible data
collection and ingestion. This tutorial will conclude with a case study
of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/baleen/0.3.3"&gt;Baleen&lt;/a&gt;, an automated
RSS ingestion service designed to construct a production-grade text
corpus for NLP research and machine learning applications. Exercises
will be presented both as Jupyter Notebooks and Python scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Donnelly</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-17:pycon-us-2017/fantastic-data-and-where-to-find-them-an-introduction-to-apis-rss-and-scraping.html</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting critical food violations at restaurants using open data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/forecasting-critical-food-violations-at-restaurants-using-open-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Dc 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/NicoleDonnelly6/pydatadc-forecasting-critical-food-violations-at-restaurants-using-open-data"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/NicoleDonnelly6/pydatadc-forecasting-critical-food-violations-at-restaurants-using-open-data&lt;/a&gt;
Github: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/nd1/DC_RestaurantViolationForecasting"&gt;https://github.com/nd1/DC_RestaurantViolationForecasting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many as 105 million Americans suffer from foodborne illness annually. In 2014, the City of Chicago began forecasting these outbreaks targeting limited health inspection resources toward likely sites, showing a 7 day improvement in locating critical violations at food establishments. This talk provides an end-to-end walkthrough of predicting critical violations in Washington, DC using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Donnelly</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/forecasting-critical-food-violations-at-restaurants-using-open-data.html</guid><category>Data</category></item></channel></rss>