<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Michele Martone</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michele-martone.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Portable performance on multi threaded Sparse BLAS operations with PyRSB</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2021/portable-performance-on-multi-threaded-sparse-blas-operations-with-pyrsb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michele Martone</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-07-12:/scipy-2021/portable-performance-on-multi-threaded-sparse-blas-operations-with-pyrsb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PyRSB package offers portable threaded performance on Sparse BLAS operations. These include multiplication of sparse matrices by vectors or multi-vectors. Their speed is essential in the iterative solutions of sparse linear systems. PyRSB is a Python interface to the LGPLv3-licensed LIBRSB library. LIBRSB uses the Recursive Sparse Blocks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PyRSB package offers portable threaded performance on Sparse BLAS operations. These include multiplication of sparse matrices by vectors or multi-vectors. Their speed is essential in the iterative solutions of sparse linear systems. PyRSB is a Python interface to the LGPLv3-licensed LIBRSB library. LIBRSB uses the Recursive Sparse Blocks (RSB) format, a storage scheme supporting cache efficient multithreaded Sparse BLAS operations. RSB is characterized by a recursive subdivision of matrices and uses a mix of sparse subformats. A user needs not to know that: PyRSB is largely compatible with SciPy's sparse matrix classes, but runs faster than reference scipy.sparse.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="SciPy 2021"></category></entry></feed>