<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Automated river plastic monitoring using deep learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-eindhoven-2019/automated-river-plastic-monitoring-using-deep-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To combat complex challenges such as plastic pollution, we require a
proper understanding on characteristics of the problem through time and
space. This is one of the problems that the Ocean Cleanup tackles. In
the past two years, we supported them in developing a deep learning
solution to monitor river plastic. The system is now ready for global
scaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine plastics are a widespread concern to the environment because of
its negative impact the marine ecosystem and human health. Quantifying
plastic pollution in rivers is essential to mitigate the negative
impact, but challenging to realize due to lack of availability of
scalable monitoring methods. Together with The Ocean Cleanup, we went
through the journey of installing cameras, labeling data, training
object detection models and more. Currently, our paper on the study has
been submitted, and the cameras, cloud architecture and models are
almost ready for scaling. Our talk will take you along our journey,
sharing what we have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sodascience.nl/"&gt;Soda science&lt;/a&gt;, we aim to create
social impact through data science by partnering with challenge experts,
such as The Ocean Cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Colin van Lieshout</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-11-30:pydata-eindhoven-2019/automated-river-plastic-monitoring-using-deep-learning.html</guid></item></channel></rss>