<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Visualisation in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/visualisation-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to explore and grasp data structures through quick and intuitive visualisation is a key skill of any data scientist. Different tools in the Python ecosystem required varying levels of mental-gymnastics to manipulate and visualise information during a data exploration session. The array of Python libraries, each with their own idiosyncrasies, available can be daunting for newcomers and data scientists-in-training. In this talk, we will examine the core data visualisation libraries compatible with the popular Pandas data wrangling library. We'll look at the base-level Matplotlib library first, and then show the benefits of the higher-level Pandas visualisation toolkit and the popular Seaborne library. By the end of the talk, you'll be bar plotting, scatter plotting, and line plotting (never pie charting) your way to data visualisation bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shane Lynn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/visualisation-in-python.html</guid><category>data visualization</category><category>seaborn</category><category>matplotlib</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Text Classification with Word Vectors &amp; Recurrent Neural Networks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2017/text-classification-with-word-vectors-recurrent-neural-networks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Globally, research teams are reporting dramatic improvements in text classification accuracy and text processing by employing deep neural networks. But what are deep nets? Can you harness these techniques in your own projects? How much training data do you need? What are the libraries required? Do you need a super computer? Do these techniques improving accuracy and are they worth the hassle? In this talk, we'll examine some basic neural architectures for text classification, we'll run through how to use the Python Keras library for classification, and speak a little about our experience in using these techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shane Lynn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-21:pycon-ireland-2017/text-classification-with-word-vectors-recurrent-neural-networks.html</guid><category>keras</category></item></channel></rss>