<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Miloslav Pojman</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HTTP/3 – Why should I care?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/http3-why-should-i-care.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet foundations reworked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTP is the foundation of the current web, and HTTP/3 is the upcoming major version of it. The new version is built on top of the QUIC transport protocol, originally developed in Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTP/3 can change the Internet as we know it today. Since its beginning in the 90s, HTTP transfers data over TCP to ensure reliable connections between clients and servers. QUIC is a TCP alternative, reimplemented on top of unreliable and connectionless UDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proprietary Google implementation of QUIC is deployed worldwide and supported by Chrome browsers. Future HTTP/3 will be hopefully standardized by IETF soon, but many diverse implementations are available already today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTP/3 improves performance and increases privacy. The switch from TCP to QUIC allows us to address the inherent limitations of previous HTTP versions. The QUIC protocol is completely encrypted, including traffic control headers, which are visible in TCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces HTTP/3 and the underlaying QUIC protocol. It shows both advantages and disadvantages of the new technology, and it describes the landscape of the current implementations and suggests what you can try today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miloslav Pojman</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/http3-why-should-i-care.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>HTTP</category><category>Internet</category><category>Privacy</category><category>Web</category><category>Web Protocols</category></item><item><title>How I wrote a Python client for HTTP/3 proxies</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/how-i-wrote-a-python-client-for-http3-proxies.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - How I wrote a Python client for HTTP/3 proxies - presented by Miloslav Pojman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Wicklow Hall 1 on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MASQUE (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tools.ietf.org/id/draft-schinazi-masque-01.html"&gt;https://tools.ietf.org/id/draft-schinazi-masque-01.html&lt;/a&gt;) (Multiplexed Application Substrate over QUIC Encryption) is a draft of a new protocol that allows running proxy or VPN services indistinguishable from HTTPS servers. Akamai built a managed proxy service based on the MASQUE protocol to provide egress proxy (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.akamai.com/blog/cloud/powering-and-protecting-online-privacy-icloud-private-relay"&gt;https://www.akamai.com/blog/cloud/powering-and-protecting-online-privacy-icloud-private-relay&lt;/a&gt;) for iCloud Private Relay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on the proxy at Akamai, I wrote a Python client for testing the proxy service. The MASQUE protocol can tunnel traffic through HTTP/3 or HTTP/2, but common Python libraries only support HTTP/1.1. The tunneled traffic can use any protocol on top of TCP or UDP, including all HTTP versions, so MASQUE can be proxied through MASQUE for onion routing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will show that the MASQUE proxy design is simple and yet client implementations are complex. To put everything into context, I will recap how HTTP proxies operate and how HTTP versions differ. I will highlight lessons learned from designing a low-level HTTP client using Python asyncio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miloslav Pojman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/how-i-wrote-a-python-client-for-http3-proxies.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Pytest Design Patterns</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2024/pytest-design-patterns.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2024 — North Hall on 2024-07-12]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pytest Design Patterns by Miloslav Pojman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pytest-design-patterns"&gt;https://ep2024.europython.eu/session/pytest-design-patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proper testing of your Python application doesn't require a rewrite into hexagonal architecture (whatever it means 🤷). In this session, we'll explore battle-tested techniques to enhance the maintainability of your test suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embracing Well-Known Patterns:&lt;/em&gt; The test client or transaction-bound tests are well-established patterns originating from Django. We will explore how to extend these foundational practices within pytest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Employing Fixture Factories:&lt;/em&gt; How to ensure that our test data clearly cover the intended scenarios? Unpack the utility of fixture factories, streamlining the setup process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mocking without Monkey Patching:&lt;/em&gt; Learn effective mocking, steering clear of the problematic practice of monkey patching. We'll explore strategies to achieve accurate testing using favorite frameworks and libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Covering More with Parametrized Fixtures:&lt;/em&gt; Many developers are familiar with pytest fixtures and parametrized tests, but may not be aware of the power of their combination: parametrized fixtures. Discover how to easily build more comprehensive tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rethinking Test Categorization:&lt;/em&gt; The traditional division into unit and integration tests often falls short in practical application. We'll check an alternative approach that can better align with real-world scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is not merely to report higher coverage but to have tests that can be trusted. By incorporating established patterns, you'll be empowered to focus on what truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miloslav Pojman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2024-07-08:/europython-2024/pytest-design-patterns.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2024</category></item></channel></rss>