<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How is python used in biomolecular sciences?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/how-is-python-used-in-biomolecular-sciences.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last ten years scientists working on computational problems
involving proteins and other small molecules have largely moved to using
python when developing simulation and data analysis tools allowing for a
fast prototyping and development of new ideas. One big challenge is
dealing with the compatibility of different tools and using these to
create very complex adaptive, yet robust workflows in order to be able
to guide cutting edge experiments e.g. predicting how well a small drug
like molecule can bind to a protein that could serve as a target for a
new drug. The talk will give a gentle introduction to what kind of
python related tools are available in the field of computational
molecular biology, how they are used, and what kind of complex workflows
scientist have to solve. I will then introduce BioSimSpace an open
source python library and flagship project of the CCPBioSim consortium
in the UK, which provides a common API to avoid having to learn many
individual tools facing compatibility and dependency challenges allowing
scientists to focus on the scientific question at hand and not solving
programming challenges. BioSimSpace allows fast and interoperable
building of workflow components (nodes) for bimolecular problems, which
can easily be used on a variety of different computational resources. In
particular I will introduce the cloud facilities available for fast
prototyping using a Jupyter notebook interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonia Mey</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/how-is-python-used-in-biomolecular-sciences.html</guid></item></channel></rss>