<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Django and the joys and benefits of live coding</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2015/django-and-the-joys-and-benefits-of-live-coding.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the rise of live video streaming, such as Periscope for social and Twitch/Youtube for gaming, there has been a rise in the interest in sharing what you're currently doing with the world as well as also interacting with those people who choose to watch what you're streaming. One of the biggest problems with learning and/or improving your programming abilities is not always being able to get instant feedback on demand or having others provide helpful suggestions instantly. Bring forth a platform that allows programmers to share their projects live and interact with those viewing their stream, LiveCoding.tv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django and the joys and benefits of live coding seeks to cover Wesley's most recent Bitcoin project that was built solely while streaming with LiveCoding.tv. Django and the joys and benefits of live coding will cover the basics of Wesley's project as well as the trials, tribulations, pros and cons of building a project live in front of people from all over the globe, all walks of life, all programming backgrounds and skill levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking for a platform where you can help others, get help from other, watch other create projects or just socialize in real time with other programmers Django and the joys and benefits of live coding is a talk for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley Stratton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-11-08:pycon-ca-2015/django-and-the-joys-and-benefits-of-live-coding.html</guid></item></channel></rss>