<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Website for Interacting with Oceanographic Data and Numerical Model Output</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2018/website-for-interacting-with-oceanographic-data-and-numerical-model-output.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Texas Automated Buoy System (TABS) has been recording and serving
online velocity and other in situ water data since 1995. We have
recently modernized the website to include more data and operational
numerical model output, and to improve ease of use. This effort relies
heavily on Python for plotting and data handling, especially relying on
packages pandas for reading in and manipulating data, and matplotlib for
plotting. The website includes an interactive map with data overlaid on
model output and combines the robustness of the leaflet library with the
flexibility of svg vectorial plotting and graphical objects
manipulation.Presenter(s): Speaker: Kristen Thyng, Assistant Research
Scientist, Texas A&amp;amp;M; University Speaker: Martinho Marta-Almeida&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kristen Thyng</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-12:scipy-2018/website-for-interacting-with-oceanographic-data-and-numerical-model-output.html</guid></item><item><title>Perceptual Color Maps in matplotlib for Oceanography</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/perceptual-color-maps-in-matplotlib-for-oceanography.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kristen Thyng</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:scipy-2015/perceptual-color-maps-in-matplotlib-for-oceanography.html</guid></item><item><title>Python in Tidal Energy Three Tools Used in a Collaboration on Array Optimization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/python-in-tidal-energy-three-tools-used-in-a-collaboration-on-array-optimization.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kristen Thyng</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:scipy-2015/python-in-tidal-energy-three-tools-used-in-a-collaboration-on-array-optimization.html</guid></item><item><title>TracPy: Wrapping the FORTRAN Lagrangian trajectory model TRACMASS</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/tracpy-wrapping-the-fortran-lagrangian-trajector.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An example of a Python wrapper of a FORTRAN code, applications of a
Lagrangian trajectory model, and lessons learned about code development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numerical Lagrangian tracking is a way to follow parcels of fluid as
they are advected by a numerical circulation model. This is a natural
method to investigate transport in a system and understand the physics
on the wide range of length scales that are actually experienced by a
drifter. TRACMASS is a tool for Lagrangian trajectory modeling that has
been developed over the past two decades. It has been used to better
understand physics and its applications to real-world problems in many
areas around the world, in both atmospheric and oceanic settings.
TRACMASS is written in FORTRAN, which is great for speed but not as
great for ease of use. This code has been wrapped in Python to run
batches of simulations and improve accessibility --- and dubbed TracPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will outline some of the interesting features of the
TRACMASS algorithm and several applications, then discuss the layout of
the TracPy code. The code setup and organization have been a learning
process and I will also share some of my hard-earned lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TracPy is continually in development and is available &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/kthyng/tracpy"&gt;on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kristen Thyng</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/tracpy-wrapping-the-fortran-lagrangian-trajector.html</guid></item></channel></rss>