<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GraphQL in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2018/graphql-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(A replacement for REST?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GraphQL is a recent specification that is a good replacement for REST
APIs. It is flexible and gives frontend developers a high degree of
control over what data they get back. It allows much faster iteration,
with less negotiation between front and backend developers, and
requiring significantly less upfront planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been used to great success at Facebook, Khan Academy, GitHub and
many other developer led companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give a brief overview of GraphQL. Followed by a deeper
dive into Python support for it through the Graphene library. It will
show how GraphQL can be easily integrated into Django and Flask
webframeworks, and be automatically reflected from Django ORM or
SqlAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ed Singleton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-15:pycon-uk-2018/graphql-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Autism in development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2018/autism-in-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autism is a condition that correlates with engineering. Many people in
the industry are diagnosed autistic, undiagnosed autistic, or near
autistic. There are many lessons that can be learned from how to deal
with autistic people that are very useful in our industry. These lessons
are often also useful when dealing with non-autistic people. There are
many lessons on how to deal with your own autism that are useful to
undiagnosed autistic people and near autistic people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover the basics of autism, and related conditions. We will
cover simple tricks that can make discussions and changes easier in
workplaces (&amp;quot;10 Simple tricks to make your autistic colleagues shout
less!&amp;quot;). We will also cover techniques you can use for dealing with your
own autistic tendencies (&amp;quot;100 coping mechanisms to pretend that you are
normal!&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a late diagnosis autistic person myself, and will discuss the
difference between knowing and not knowing that you are autistic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ed Singleton</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-07-25:europython-2018/autism-in-development.html</guid></item><item><title>Form Follows Functions</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2016/form-follows-functions.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ed Singleton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revolution in materials lead to a revolution in architecture, and a complete rethink of how we design buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lessons learned in this process are still lessons we need to remember today, and they can be used to change the way we argue with each other over styles and patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be looking at the history of what happened, and then trying to apply &amp;quot;form follows function&amp;quot; to some controversial areas to see if it helps us resolve them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ed Singleton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-29:pycon-uk-2016/form-follows-functions.html</guid></item></channel></rss>