<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Iqbal Abdullah</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2022/diversity-inclusion-in-the-python-community-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;EuroPython 2022 - Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion in the Python Community Panel - presented by Tereza Iofciu, Marlene Mhangami, Naomi Ceder, Nabanita Roy &amp;amp; Iqbal Abdullah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Auditorium on 2022-07-14]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come meet some of the folks working on Diversity and Inclusion in the global Python Community!
Join the live panel discussion to hear about the challenges and the work they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Marlene Mhangami, Nabanita Roy, Iqbal Abdullah, Tereza Iofciu. Chaired by Naomi Ceder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tereza Iofciu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-07-11:/europython-2022/diversity-inclusion-in-the-python-community-panel.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2022</category></item><item><title>Changing the World, One PyCon at a Time (Ver. 2022)｜Iqbal Abdullah｜主題演講 Keynotes｜PyCon APAC 2022</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-apac-2022/changing-the-world-one-pycon-at-a-time-ver-2022iqbal-abdullahzhu-ti-yan-jiang-keynotespycon-apac-2022.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon APAC 2022｜主題演講 Keynotes｜國泰金控 Cathay Financial Holdings / 美光科技 Micron 冠名贊助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🪄 說明 Description 🪄
Iqbal will be speaking about the past, present and his hopes for the future of the community, from a people mover and organizer point of view.
There will be nostalgic pictures, thoughts on diversity, inclusion, generational change, burnout and hopefully opportunities to reflect during this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 講者介紹 About Speaker - Iqbal Abdullah 🚀
I am a Malaysian who has been a resident of Japan for the past 20 years. Career wise, I am the founder and CEO of LaLoka Labs. My previous company, Xoxzo was acquired in Sept 2021 which I still currently serve as the COO. In the past, I have worked in engineering positions within Yahoo! Japan and business roles within Amazon. The experiences working within these organizations have tremendously influenced me on my ideas and philosophies concerning engineering and business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Python journey started in 2002 with ver. 1.5.2 when I started working at Yahoo! Japan. The language has led me to the community behind it. My first PyCon APAC was in 2010 in Singapore.
Within the Python community, I co-founded PyCon JP and PyCon MY, I help manage PyCon APAC, and I am also involved with the Trademarks Working Group (WG) and the Diversity and Inclusion WG of the Python Software Foundation (PSF).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also ran for a seat on the PSF board, and after failing spectacularly for the second time, wrote an essay on my thoughts on what needs to be done for the PSF. I would like to believe that this directly had an impact on the PSF's decision to start the D&amp;amp;I Workgroup in Dec 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experiences working with the community has tremendously shaped my views on how and why we need to be present and actively participate within the community with ideas, effort and money. It also has shown me how the rest of us are lacking the opportunities that some of us have. Opening those opportunities to more people has and still is a constant personal mission that I have. After all, we are living off the goodwill which the people before us have left us with, and replacing that goodwill is the least we can do. Feel free to connect with me or learn more about myself from Twitter, LinkedIn or even LaLoka Labs's blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#python #pycontw #pyconapac2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow “PyCon Taiwan”
⭐️ Official Website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tw.pycon.org"&gt;https://tw.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Facebook: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Instagram: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/pycontw"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Twitter: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/PyConTW"&gt;https://twitter.com/PyConTW&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ LinkedIn: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/pycontw&lt;/a&gt;
⭐️ Blogger: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pycontw.blogspot.com"&gt;https://pycontw.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iqbal Abdullah</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-09-03:/pycon-apac-2022/changing-the-world-one-pycon-at-a-time-ver-2022iqbal-abdullahzhu-ti-yan-jiang-keynotespycon-apac-2022.html</guid><category>PyCon APAC 2022</category></item><item><title>PyCons in APAC</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-thailand-2018/pycons-in-apac.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk gives an overview of PyCons in the Asia-Pacific region, since 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day job is running Xoxzo Inc, a cloud telephony platform based in Tokyo.
Helped found PyCon JP and PyCon MY.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iqbal Abdullah</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-16:/pycon-thailand-2018/pycons-in-apac.html</guid><category>PyCon Thailand 2018</category><category>lightning talk</category></item><item><title>Diversity and Inclusion Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2023/diversity-and-inclusion-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity and Inclusion Panel&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Débora Azevedo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-22:/pycon-us-2023/diversity-and-inclusion-panel.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2023</category></item></channel></rss>