<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Meson: compiling the world with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2017/meson-compiling-the-world-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compiling source code into libraries and executables has always been
problematic, especially for cross platform projects. Typical problems
in existing build systems include slow build times, undecipherable
syntax, lack of support for cross compilation and so on. Some people
choose to not use a build system at all but instead just write a
one-off Makefile, which will usually work fine on their machine and
nowhere else. All this makes software development slower than it
needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meson build system (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mesonbuild.com"&gt;http://mesonbuild.com&lt;/a&gt;) is a new build system
designed from the ground up to provide a solution for these (and
other) problems. It is implemented in Python 3 and provides a simple,
non-Turing complete DSL for describing the build. The project
provides built-in support for common tasks such as documentation
generation, building Qt apps and Python extension modules. Meson is
currently seeing a lot of uptake in the Free software world with big
projects such as GStreamer, parts of GNOME, Wayland and even the X
server either transitioning, or very strongly considering the
transition to Meson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we go over the design of Meson, how to use it for new
and existing projects and the benefits this brings, including faster
compiles, less time wasted debugging the build system environment and
easy access to modern software development tools and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jussi Pakkanen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-10:europython-2017/meson-compiling-the-world-with-python.html</guid></item></channel></rss>