<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_rachel-rakov.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python for Sarcasm Detection in Speech</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2015/using-python-for-sarcasm-detection-in-speech.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rachel Rakov</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-16:pygotham-2015/using-python-for-sarcasm-detection-in-speech.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I discuss my work using Python to create a system for
sarcasm detection in speech. My goal in this task is to determine
whether human intonation alone can be modeled to predict sarcastic
speech. I first extracted speech samples from the titular character of
MTV’s late ‘90s hit TV show “Daria”. Using crowdsourcing techniques to
get the speech labeled for sarcasm, I created a corpus of speech that is
annotated for sarcasm and sincerity. I used several Python toolkits to
extract a number of acoustic features from this speech that are
indicative of sarcasm. The first tool I used was Snack Sound Toolkit, a
library for Python that does basic sound handling and analysis. I used
tools in Snack to extract a baseline of basic acoustic features that
have been found to be helpful in human sarcasm identification. I then
used NumPy, SciPy, and NLTK to model prosodic contours, and applied
these contours to the task of automatic sarcasm detection. This approach
applies sequential modeling to representations of pitch and intensity
curves obtained via k-means clustering. Using machine learning
(specifically Weka’s SimpleLogistic (LogitBoost) classifier), this
system is able to predict sarcasm with 81.57% accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>