<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_zuzanna-kunik.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Command line language – where NLP and cyber security meets</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-2019/command-line-language-where-nlp-and-cyber-security-meets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zuzanna Kunik</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-13:pydata-warsaw-2019/command-line-language-where-nlp-and-cyber-security-meets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the cyber security world, analysis of command line logs is important
for breach detection, but it is one of the most challenging problems. To
simplify this process, we propose a framework called CMDLang – command
line language, which has features of natural language. I will present
results of successful POS and NER training using popular NLP algorithms
and demonstrate a real use case of CMDLang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At F-Secure, in order to protect our customers, we use streams of
command line logs coming from their systems to detect breaches and
anomalies. Analysis of such data is one of the most challenging problems
in the cyber security world. It requires domain knowledge and is hard to
encapsulate in sets of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we treat command lines logs as semi-structured text data? They
follow a set of grammar rules and have semantics. Therefore, we propose
the framework of CMDLang – command line language, which has features of
natural language. We performed successful trainings of part of speech
(POS) tagger and named entities recognition (NER) models. Using CMDLang
along with NLP methods enables normalization of logs, parsing and their
categorization. With a defined language framework, we are able to
analyze huge streams of data faster, which improves our detection
capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the talk, I will present results of the CMDLang creation using
popular, open-source NLP algorithms. I will give a walkthrough of the
process and define the main ideas behind this language. At the end I
will demonstrate usage of CMDLang in a real use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be interesting for every NLP enthusiast, as well for
people working with (semi-)structured text data or log processing.
During the presentation, I will explain any cyber security terminology
used.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>