<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Identity 2.0: the what, why and how of social and federated login</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/identity-20-the-what-why-and-how-of-social-and-federated-login.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you're developing public-facing web apps or deploying behind
the corporate firewall, the days of identity silos are over.  Social
auth (&lt;em&gt;log in with FooBookHub&lt;/em&gt;) and federated identity (&lt;em&gt;SAML&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;OpenID Connect&lt;/em&gt; and friends) are the new normal.  The advantages
are clear: developers and operators have less security-sensitive
code to write and deploy, while users experience less password/account fatigue, and
enjoy improved productivity through &lt;em&gt;single sign-on&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there's no such thing as a free lunch; like most things in technology there are
trade-offs.  Federated authentication protocols are inherently more
elaborate than plain old passwords; more moving parts means more
complex deployment and more points of failure.  Fortunately there are
tools to ease the burden and smooth the process of securing your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this extended session for web developers and
administrators/operations folks, attendees will learn and experience
how to deploy and use federated auth, end-to-end from the identity
provider to the app.  The session will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basics of federated authentication including &lt;strong&gt;protocol
overviews&lt;/strong&gt; and comparisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use &lt;strong&gt;social auth&lt;/strong&gt; providers for public-facing
applications, allowing users to log in with an account they
already have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to leverage accounts in centralised identity management
systems (&lt;em&gt;FreeIPA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Active Directory&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;LDAP&lt;/em&gt;, etc) for &lt;strong&gt;single
sign-on&lt;/strong&gt; in an organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How &lt;strong&gt;identity brokers&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;em&gt;Keycloak&lt;/em&gt; make it easy to use a
variety of external authentication providers, and provide a
consistent user experience across multiple applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use external identities in your applications with the help
of your web server, focusing in particlar on popular &lt;strong&gt;Python web
frameworks&lt;/strong&gt; and Apache (though the principles are more widely
applicable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; characteristics, and discussion of some challenging
scenarios including testing, account merging and single sign-out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fraser Tweedale</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/identity-20-the-what-why-and-how-of-social-and-federated-login.html</guid></item><item><title>Saturday PM Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2017/saturday-pm-lightning-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks Saturday, August 05 2017 04 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Ansell - Python on FPGAs 1:15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicky Ringland and Jim Mussared - National Computer Science School 6:28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinton McKinnon - The Amazing StarLAB 11:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josh Simmons - Open Source in Education 13:32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Weipa - Systematic Problem Solving 18:34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Leslie - PEP-628 The world's oldest bug 23:50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Moore - OMNICODE 29:08&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Lonsdale - FASTQE 33:22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tisham Dhar - Energy Monitor 37:29&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhydwyn McGuire - R 42:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josh Driver - Faster PostgreSQL Text Search 44:26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fraser Tweedale - On naming things 49:49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Leonard - High Risk Demo Episode 2 55:28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ned Letcher - PyEnv 59:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke Deller - Garbage Collection Live demo 1:04:25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Ansell</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-05:pycon-au-2017/saturday-pm-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Integrating Python Apps with Centralised Identity Management Systems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2015/integrating-python-apps-with-centralised-identity.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most Python web developers are familiar with authentication and
authorisation on the open web, but the requirements and technologies
used inside companies and large organisations are different:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identities and groups are probably stored in an external identity
management system's directory rather than in an application's
database tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorisation decisions will be based on group membership and
policies that are defined outside the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users may be expected or required to use a &lt;em&gt;single sign-on&lt;/em&gt;
technology such as Kerberos or SAML to authenticate to applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will familiarise the audience with these technologies and
demonstrate how Python web applications can be integrated with an
identity management system to meet business requirements while providing
a positive user experience. Particular technologies covered will
include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.freeipa.org"&gt;FreeIPA&lt;/a&gt;: an open-source identity
management solution, for defining users, groups and authorisation
policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/modauthgssapi/mod_auth_gssapi"&gt;mod_auth_gssapi&lt;/a&gt;
/ mod_auth_kerb: Apache modules for Kerberos authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adelton.com/apache/mod_lookup_identity/"&gt;mod_lookup_identity&lt;/a&gt;:
Apache module to retrieve user information from a directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will conclude with discussion about upcoming Kerberos features,
techniques for dealing with multiple authentication methods, and
progress in making identity management integration easier for Python
(and in particular, Django) developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People developing or deploying Python web applications in business
environments or for large open source projects with centralised identity
management will get the most out of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fraser Tweedale</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-05:kiwi-pycon-2015/integrating-python-apps-with-centralised-identity.html</guid></item><item><title>Descriptors: attribute access redefined by Fraser Tweedale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2014/descriptors-attribute-access-redefined-by-fraser.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descriptors are a powerful feature of Python that can be used to augment
or replace traditional attribute access with arbitrary behaviours. Such
versatility makes the descriptor protocol a valuable tool for any Python
programmer, yet although most of us have used descriptors, fewer have
implemented one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will explain the use cases that motivate descriptors
and how other features in Python fall short. We will then look at some
of the descriptors that the audience may already have used (even if they
didn't know they were using descriptors!) This will be followed with an
explanation of the descriptor protocol and some implementation and usage
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss some of the finer details of descriptor implementation
and will conclude with a look at Elk - a declarative object system
authored by the presenter and inspired by Perl's Moose - and the
descriptors that power it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fraser Tweedale</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-08-07:pycon-au-2014/descriptors-attribute-access-redefined-by-fraser.html</guid></item><item><title>Cooking with Cryptography</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/cooking-with-cryptography.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;cryptography&lt;/tt&gt; library emerged in 2014 with the goal of becoming
Python's &amp;quot;cryptographic standard library&amp;quot;. It is designed to be easy to
use but flexible, exposing a &lt;em&gt;recipes&lt;/em&gt; layer for common use cases, and a
&lt;em&gt;hazmat&lt;/em&gt; layer that provides crypto primitives but demands users know
what they're doing in order to use them properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain the motivations and goals of the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;cryptography&lt;/tt&gt;
library, take a tour of its features and discuss its implementation.
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;cryptography&lt;/tt&gt; will be compared to some other popular and emerging
crypto libraries. Finally, we will examine some real-world use of the
library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience members should have a passing familiarity with cryptography
(e.g. know the differences between hashing and encryption, or public key
and private key crypto) to get the most out of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fraser Tweedale</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-17:pycon-au-2015/cooking-with-cryptography.html</guid></item><item><title>Integrating Django with Identity Management Systems</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/integrating-django-with-identity-management-syste.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most Django developers are familiar with authentication and
authorisation on the open web, but the requirements and technologies
used inside companies and large organisations are different:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identities and groups are probably stored in an external identity
management system's directory rather than in an application's
database tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorisation decisions will be based on group membership and
policies that are defined outside the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users may be expected or required to use a &lt;em&gt;single sign-on&lt;/em&gt;
technology such as Kerberos or SAML to authenticate to applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will familiarise the audience with these technologies and
demonstrate how Django applications can be integrated with an identity
management system to meet business requirements while providing a
positive user experience. Particular technologies covered will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FreeIPA: an open-source identity management solution, for defining
users, groups and authorisation policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mod_auth_gssapi / mod_auth_kerb: Apache modules for Kerberos
authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mod_lookup_identity: Apache module to retrieve user information
from a directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will conclude with discussion about upcoming Kerberos features,
techniques for dealing with multiple authentication methods, and
progress in making identity management integration easier for Django
developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People developing or deploying Django applications in business
environments or for large open source projects with centralised identity
management will get the most out of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fraser Tweedale</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/integrating-django-with-identity-management-syste.html</guid></item></channel></rss>