<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_piwheels.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-29T16:30:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>piwheels: a faster Python package repository for RaspberryPi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/piwheels-a-faster-python-package-repository-for-raspberrypi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-29T16:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-29T16:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ben Nuttall</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/piwheels-a-faster-python-package-repository-for-raspberrypi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;piwheels is a Python package repository providing Python wheels natively compiled for the Raspberry Pi's ARM architecture. It solves the problem that &amp;quot;pip install&amp;quot; can take a long time to build packages implemented in C. Wheels are a general solution to this problem, but PyPI does not currently allow maintainers to upload ARM platform wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote some tooling for automating the building of all 115,000+ packages on PyPI, including all version releases, which totals up to over 750,000 package builds, monitoring the build status and logging the output.in a database, and providing the wheels in a pip-compatible web server. Raspberry Pi users can now &amp;quot;pip install&amp;quot; from this server (a Raspberry Pi) and get pre-built Python wheels, which take just seconds to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first build run I completed was on a Raspberry Pi in my living room: I built the latest version of every package (110k). Then, in order to build all versions of all packages (750k), I moved the project to a cluster of 20 Raspberry Pis in a data centre.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="piwheels"></category></entry></feed>