<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Docker meets Python - A look on the Docker SDK for Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/docker-meets-python-a-look-on-the-docker-sdk-for-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My talk aims to introduce and have a closer look on the Docker SDK for
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I will cover:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How and where to get the SDK&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How it works and how to use it in general&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Possible use-cases like: Processing Container-Logs, Testing with
pytest on different Python Versions, Deploy via Python Script, etc..&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;For my talk, you should know what Docker is and how to use it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;A basic idea of pytest and server administration is nice to have, but
not necessarily needed to follow my talk.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jan Wagner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/docker-meets-python-a-look-on-the-docker-sdk-for-python.html</guid><category>Deployment/Continuous Integration and Delivery</category><category>DevOps general</category><category>Docker</category><category>Testing</category><category>Virtualization</category></item><item><title>Google Cloud for Pythonistas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/google-cloud-for-pythonistas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support for Python on Google Cloud has never been better. Join us for a
tour of Python runtimes, services and client libraries, including App
Engine, Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, and more. We'll also discuss tools
for monitoring and debugging your Python application, and best practices
for using Python on Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dustin Ingram</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/google-cloud-for-pythonistas.html</guid><category>Deployment/Continuous Integration and Delivery</category><category>DevOps general</category><category>Development</category><category>Public Cloud (AWS/Google/...)</category><category>Web</category></item><item><title>Introduction to low-level profiling and tracing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/introduction-to-low-level-profiling-and-tracing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has built-in tracing and profiling facilities in form of callback
hooks in the sys module. The settrace and setprofile callbacks have
several drawbacks. They slow down the Python interpreter considerable
and only allow tracing of Python code. Modern OS and CPUs come with a
variety of APIs for efficient and low-level tracing down to system
calls, Kernel space code, and hardware events. Some tools even create
code that runs in Kernel space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks is an introduction and comparison of various low and high
level tools for profiling and tracing as well as visualization tools
like flame graphs. It covers ptrace, perf, SystemTap, and BCC/eBPF.
Ptrace based commands like strace are easy to use but slow. Perf allows
lightweight profiling of hardware events and CPU instructions. SystemTap
is a powerful toolkit plus DSL to instrument probe points inside the
Kernel as well as static SystemTap/DTrace markers in libs and languages
like Java, PHP, and Python. CPython comes with a set of instrumentations
for SystemTap. BCC is a collection of tools that run as JIT optimized
eBPF code in Kernel space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is an introduction to basic concepts of low-level tracing and
profiling on Linux. The main goal is the show the potential of the
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Heimes</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/introduction-to-low-level-profiling-and-tracing.html</guid><category>CPython</category><category>DevOps general</category><category>Performance</category></item></channel></rss>