<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Validazione e decodifica di file XML con Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/validazione-e-decodifica-di-file-xml-con-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Per la schematizzazione di documenti XML sono disponibili diversi
standard, tra questi XML Schema. La prima problematica è quella di poter
validare file XML secondo il loro rispettivo schema. Un’altra esigenza è
la conversione dell’XML in strutture dati in cui siano valorizzati i
tipi base definiti nello schema e la struttura nidificata in cui sono
inseriti, similmente a quello che è già reso disponibile per JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ambito scientifico, nell’ambito delle attività del progetto europeo
MaX (Materials design at the Exascale), per semplificare l’interscambio
di dati dati XML tra diversi software di simulazione, si è deciso di
adottare un approccio unitario e sistematico alla validazione e alla
decodifica dei dati XML prodotti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pertanto è in fase di sviluppo una nuova libreria (xmlschema), basata
sulla libreria standard ElementTree di Python, che permette di validare
e decodificare dati XML con schemi XSD. La decodifica di un documento
XML produce un dizionario nidificato con i valori terminali appartenenti
ai corrispondenti tipi elementari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nella presentazione parlerei delle problematiche degli schemi XSD,
dell’ambito scientifico in cui è stata sviluppata la libreria e della
struttura della libreria stessa, illustrando e magari raccogliendo
qualche idea per migliorarla.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Davide Brunato</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/validazione-e-decodifica-di-file-xml-con-python.html</guid><category>xml</category><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>encoding</category><category>Python</category><category>simulation</category><category>validation</category><category>physics</category><category>metadata</category></item><item><title>PyOhio 2010: Implementation of a Numerical Simulation in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--implementation-of-a-numerical-simula.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of a Numerical Simulation in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jeffrey B. Armstrong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python programming language is well suited for numerical computation
under a variety of circumstances. Python offers advantages over
competing free and commercial technologies, including price,
functionality, and maintainability. Specifically, the combination of
mature numerical libraries and liberal licensing allow complex
simulations to be coded with ease and to be made available to nearly all
interested parties. !NumPy/!SciPy, database access, networking, and
optimization techniques are examined in detail with respect to numerical
computation. A practical example involving an aerothermal commercial
turbofan aircraft engine simulation showcases these advantages. An
aircraft engine is broken down into discrete stages, including
compressors, turbines, and other flow-related components. Commonalities
between components, such as rotation and the presence of inlet and exit
conditions, map cleanly to the object-oriented nature of Python. Based
on simulation needs and hardware availability, Python allows for the
parallel computation of simulations without the expense and complexity
of commercial parallelization packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeffrey Armstrong</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-07-31:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--implementation-of-a-numerical-simula.html</guid><category>database</category><category>networking</category><category>numpy</category><category>optimization</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2010</category><category>scipy</category><category>simulation</category></item><item><title>Multibody Dynamics and Control with Python part 1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/multibody-dynamics-and-control-with-python-part-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, attendees will learn how to derive, simulate, and
visualize the motion of a multibody dynamic system with Python tools.
These methods and techniques play an important role in the design and
understanding of robots, vehicles, spacecraft, manufacturing machines,
human motion, etc. Attendees will develop code to simulate the motion of
a human or humanoid robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, attendees will learn how to derive, simulate, and
visualize the motion of a multibody dynamic system with Python tools.
The tutorial will demonstrate an advanced symbolic and numeric pipeline
for a typical multibody simulation problem. These methods and techniques
play an important role in the design and understanding of robots,
vehicles, spacecraft, manufacturing machines, human motion, etc. At the
end, the attendees will have developed code to simulate the uncontrolled
and controlled motion of a human or humanoid robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will highlight the derivation of realistic models of motion with the
SymPy Mechanics package. We will walk through the derivation of the
equations of motion of a multibody system (i.e. the model or the plant),
simulating and visualizing the free motion of the system, and finally we
will addfeedback controllers to control the plants that we derive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is best if the attendees have some background with calculus-based
college level physics. They should also be familiar with the SciPy
Stack, in particular IPython, SymPy, NumPy, and SciPy. Our goal is that
attendees will come away with the ability to model basic multibody
systems, simulate and visualize the motion, and apply feedback
controllers all in a Python framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial materials including an outline can be viewed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydy/pydy-tutorial-pycon-2014"&gt;https://github.com/pydy/pydy-tutorial-pycon-2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason K. Moore</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/multibody-dynamics-and-control-with-python-part-1.html</guid><category>robots</category><category>simulation</category><category>sympy</category></item><item><title>Multibody Dynamics and Control with Python part 2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/multibody-dynamics-and-control-with-python-part-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, attendees will learn how to derive, simulate, and
visualize the motion of a multibody dynamic system with Python tools.
These methods and techniques play an important role in the design and
understanding of robots, vehicles, spacecraft, manufacturing machines,
human motion, etc. Attendees will develop code to simulate the motion of
a human or humanoid robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, attendees will learn how to derive, simulate, and
visualize the motion of a multibody dynamic system with Python tools.
The tutorial will demonstrate an advanced symbolic and numeric pipeline
for a typical multibody simulation problem. These methods and techniques
play an important role in the design and understanding of robots,
vehicles, spacecraft, manufacturing machines, human motion, etc. At the
end, the attendees will have developed code to simulate the uncontrolled
and controlled motion of a human or humanoid robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will highlight the derivation of realistic models of motion with the
SymPy Mechanics package. We will walk through the derivation of the
equations of motion of a multibody system (i.e. the model or the plant),
simulating and visualizing the free motion of the system, and finally we
will addfeedback controllers to control the plants that we derive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is best if the attendees have some background with calculus-based
college level physics. They should also be familiar with the SciPy
Stack, in particular IPython, SymPy, NumPy, and SciPy. Our goal is that
attendees will come away with the ability to model basic multibody
systems, simulate and visualize the motion, and apply feedback
controllers all in a Python framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial materials including an outline can be viewed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydy/pydy-tutorial-pycon-2014"&gt;https://github.com/pydy/pydy-tutorial-pycon-2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason K. Moore</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/multibody-dynamics-and-control-with-python-part-2.html</guid><category>robots</category><category>simulation</category><category>sympy</category></item><item><title>Derivatives Analytics with Python &amp; Numpy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/derivatives-analytics-with-python-numpy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Yves Hilpisch - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In financial engineering and derivatives analytics, C/C++/Java/VBA and
other languages are still dominating. Visixion has developed with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dexision.com"&gt;DEXISION&lt;/a&gt; the first full fledged
derivatives analytics suite with Python as core language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEXISION is an On Demand application that is completely Open Source
based (LAMP). For derivatives valuation, it uses Monte Carlo simulation
- an approach known to be computationally demanding. However, Numpy
provides the performance and functionality needed to implement financial
simulation algorithms in a fast and compact manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk illustrates the architecture of our analytics suite and
demonstrates how to implement fast and compact simulation algorithms
with Python and Numpy. The talk shows that the Python/Numpy combination
reaches sufficient speed for productive financial applications -
something still widely doubted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[No prerequisites.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/derivatives-analytics-with-python-numpy.html</guid><category>architecture</category><category>engineering</category><category>numpy</category><category>performance</category><category>simulation</category></item><item><title>DEXISION -- Moderne Finanztheorie und -praxis mit Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/dexision-moderne-finanztheorie-und-praxis-mit.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DEXISION ist eine kommerzielle Bewertungslösung für Finanzderivate. Sie
wurde durch die Visixion GmbH im Wesentlichen auf Basis von Python
entwickelt. Der Vortrag zeigt, wie moderne, Web-basierte Finanzlösungen
mittels Python zu implementieren sind. Aspekte wie Effizienz in der
Entwicklung, Performance, Erweiterbarkeit, Wartbarkeit und Sicherheit
sind dabei von besonderer Bedeutung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Architektur von DEXISION fußt auf einem LAMP-Stack und es kommen
dabei nur Open Source-Komponenten zum Einsatz. Unseres Wissens nach ist
DEXISION nach wie vor die einzige kommerzielle Finanzlösung dieser Art,
die in allen Bereichn -- auch bei rechenintensiven Simulationsaufgaben
-- voll auf Python setzt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-30:pycon-de-2012/dexision-moderne-finanztheorie-und-praxis-mit.html</guid><category>bewertung von derivaten</category><category>dexision</category><category>finanzen</category><category>on demand</category><category>scientific python</category><category>simulation</category></item><item><title>Ereignis-diskrete Simulation mit SimPy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/ereignis-diskrete-simulation-mit-simpy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simulationen kommen immer dann zum Einsatz, wenn Experimente an realen
Systemen mit hohen Risiken bzw. Kosten verbunden oder gar nicht erst
möglich sind. Zudem erlauben Simulationen es, Vorgänge, die in der
realität lange Zeiträume beanspruchen, in zumeist wesentlich kürzerer
Zeit nachzuvollziehen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nach einer kurzen Einführung in das Thema zeigt dieser Vortrag anhand
einfacher Beispiele, wie sich Ereignis-diskrete Simulationen mit SimPy
umsetzen lassen und welche Funktionen SimPy zur Umsetzung komplexerer
Simulationen bietet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefan Scherfke</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-16:pycon-de-2013/ereignis-diskrete-simulation-mit-simpy.html</guid><category>ereignis-diskret</category><category>generators</category><category>simpy</category><category>simulation</category><category>zeit-diskret</category></item><item><title>Using Python to Create Robotic Simulations for Planetary Exploration (#159)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--using-python-to-create-robotic-simula.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Python to Create Robotic Simulations for Planetary Exploration
(#159)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Dr. Jonathan M Cameron (Jet Propulsion Laboratory (NASA))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary activity of the Dartslab (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dartslab.jpl.nasa.gov"&gt;http://dartslab.jpl.nasa.gov&lt;/a&gt;) at
Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) is to create simulations of robotic
vehicles for planetary exploration. We have created simulations of a
wide variety of robotic vehicles such as spacecraft, rovers, and
airships. We have been using Python in a variety of ways to build our
simulations. In this talk we will outline how we use Python to set up a
runtime environment for our simulations and to tie together
computationally intense C++ code modules at runtime. We will also
discuss how we have been using Python to help prototype and design C++
code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Jonathan M Cameron</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--using-python-to-create-robotic-simula.html</guid><category>nasa</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>robotics</category><category>simulation</category></item></channel></rss>