<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - polars</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_polars.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Polars - make the switch to lightning-fast dataframes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/polars-make-the-switch-to-lightning-fast-dataframes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Bierhance</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/polars-make-the-switch-to-lightning-fast-dataframes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will report on our experiences switching from Pandas to Polars in a real-world ML project. Polars is a new high-performance dataframe library for Python based on Apache Arrow and written in Rust. We will compare the performance of polars with the popular pandas library, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will report on our experiences switching from Pandas to Polars in a real-world ML project. Polars is a new high-performance dataframe library for Python based on Apache Arrow and written in Rust. We will compare the performance of polars with the popular pandas library, and show how polars can provide significant speed improvements for data manipulation and analysis tasks. We will also discuss the unique features of polars, such as its ability to handle large datasets that do not fit into memory, and how it feels in practice to make the switch from Pandas. This talk is aimed at data scientists, analysts, and anyone interested in fast and efficient data processing in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category><category term="polars"></category></entry><entry><title>Raised by Pandas, striving for more: An opinionated introduction to Polars</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/raised-by-pandas-striving-for-more-an-opinionated-introduction-to-polars.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nico Kreiling</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/raised-by-pandas-striving-for-more-an-opinionated-introduction-to-polars.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is the de-facto standard for data manipulation in python, which I personally love for its flexible syntax and interoperability. But Pandas has well-known drawbacks such as memory in-efficiency, inconsistent missing data handling and lacking multicore-support. Multiple open-source projects aim to solve those issues, the most interesting is Polars …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is the de-facto standard for data manipulation in python, which I personally love for its flexible syntax and interoperability. But Pandas has well-known drawbacks such as memory in-efficiency, inconsistent missing data handling and lacking multicore-support. Multiple open-source projects aim to solve those issues, the most interesting is Polars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polars uses Rust and Apache Arrow to win in all kinds of performance-benchmarks and evolves fast. But is it already stable enough to migrate an existing Pandas' codebase? And does it meet the high-expectations on query language flexibility of long-time Pandas-lovers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will explain, how Polars can be that fast, and present my insights on where Polars shines and in which scenarios I stay with pandas (at least for now!)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category><category term="polars"></category><category term="pandas"></category></entry></feed>