<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Text Extraction from PDFs made Easy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/text-extraction-from-pdfs-made-easy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Overview:*&lt;/strong&gt; PDFs are one of the widely used digital media formats
and are used to present and exchange information reliably, independent
of the software, hardware and operating system. Extracting data from PDF
files can be a tricky task. This is because of the complicated formats,
fonts, and layouts that are stored in PDF files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text Extraction from PDFs is one of the most common problems that is
prevalent in every industry. I shall be showing you how to extract data
directly from n number of PDF files using just one Python Library -
Regex. I encountered a similar problem while working with my company and
utilized Regular Expressions to automate an otherwise strenuous task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*1. Who is this talk for?*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone who is dealing with the problem of extracting data from
unstructured data at their workplace/ university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone who wants to learn Regular Expression in a fun and easy
manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*2. What background knowledge or experience should the audience
have?*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will be a beginner’s talk. The basis of Regex will be built from
the ground up during the talk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*3. What will the audience learn after attending the talk?*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The audience will get a crisp overview of Regular Expressions, that
can assist them in a wide spectrum of tasks, from wrangling data to
qualifying and categorizing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ll be showing them a use-case/demo of a problem statement that I
encountered at my workplace, giving the attendees more clarity about
the extent of usage of Regex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1632"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aakriti Jain</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/text-extraction-from-pdfs-made-easy.html</guid><category>textextraction</category><category>datawrangling</category><category>datamining</category></item><item><title>Introduction to machine learning using Python tools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/introduction-to-machine-learning-using-python-tools.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Satish Shankar</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/introduction-to-machine-learning-using-python-tools.html</guid><category>statistics</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>datamining</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>scientific-computing</category><category>sklearn</category></item><item><title>PostgreSQL is Web-Scale (Really :) )</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/postgresql-is-web-scale-really.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I show you how to set up a python and PostgreSQL based
system which is easy to set up and easy to scale, provides ACID
guarantees where they are needed and delays time-consistency between
unrelated objects for scalability and availability where the latter are
deemed more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing is that this kind of scalability work for both OLTP and
OLAP workloads, so with some planning you can have just a single large
“database” which can take almost any type of load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you hate SQL, you can do all the OLTP stuff in a pythonic way
using an automagically generated ORM layer inside the database, near the
data. If you are really masochistic, you can use the same ORM also for
map-reduce type distributed data processing, though on this side the
small effort of learning SQL usually pays off when queries get more
complex. But as I said, everything runs inside the databse, near the
data and thus even the ORM &amp;amp; map-reduce analytics works fast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hannu Krosing</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/postgresql-is-web-scale-really.html</guid><category>postgresql</category><category>nosql</category><category>datamining</category><category>parallelization</category><category>distributed</category><category>bigdata</category><category>scalability</category><category>pl/python</category><category>olap</category><category>optimization</category><category>orm</category><category>sql</category><category>performance</category></item><item><title>Tensor decomposition with Python: Learning structures from multidimensional data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/tensor-decomposition-with-python-learning-structures-from-multidimensional-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many problems in signal processing and machine learning generate massive
amounts of multidimensional data. Data sources from sensor networks and
Internet-of-Things applications promise a wealth of interaction data
that can be naturally represented as tensors. Tensor decompositions have
gained a steadily increasing popularity in data mining and machine
learning, with applications in psychometrics, chemometrics, signal
processing, computer vision, neuroscience, graph analysis, and more. For
example, time-varying social networks collected from wearable proximity
sensors can be represented as 3-way tensors, and tensor decomposition
can be used to extract community structures with their structural and
temporal signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current standard framework for working with tensors, however, is
Matlab. We will show how tensor decompositions can be carried out using
Python, how to obtain latent components and how they can be interpreted,
and what are some applications of this technique in the academy and
industry. We will see a use case where a Python implementation of tensor
decomposition is applied to a dataset that describes face-to-face social
interactions of people, collected using the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sociopatterns.org/"&gt;SocioPatterns&lt;/a&gt; platform. This
platform was deployed in different settings such as conferences, schools
and hospitals, in order to support mathematical modelling and simulation
of airborne infectious diseases. Tensor decomposition has been used in
these scenarios to solve different types of problems: it is used for
data cleaning, where time-varying graph anomalies can be identified and
removed from data; it have been also used to assess the impact of
face-to-face interactions in the spreading of diseases. These examples
show the potential of this technique in data mining and machine learning
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">André Panisson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/tensor-decomposition-with-python-learning-structures-from-multidimensional-data.html</guid><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>datamining</category><category>machine-learning</category></item></channel></rss>