<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Getting more developer girls using python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/getting-more-developer-girls-using-python.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lynn Root</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-01:europython-2013/getting-more-developer-girls-using-python.html</guid><category>women</category></item><item><title>Django Girls Italia: entrare in contatto con le donne tecnologiche, davvero</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/django-girls-italia-entrare-in-contatto-con-le-donne-tecnologiche-davvero.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parlare di inclusività e tematiche di genere è ormai una moda.
Affrontare il tema donne che lavorano nell’industria IT con toni
tragici, come si trattasse di esseri mitologici, lo è ancora di più.
Come passare oltre il “velo di Maya” e bypassare la disinformazione?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel 2015 insieme alla community Python Italiana abbiamo gettato le basi
per portare in Italia Django Girls, workshop nato per contribuire a
colmare quel gender gap di cui si parla tanto. In tre anni di “duro
lavoro” come organizzatrice di laboratori in Italia, sono entrata in
contatto con oltre 400 donne appassionate di tecnologia: studentesse di
ingegneria informatica, architetti, insegnanti, casalinghe, web
desinger. E anche con sviluppatori pronti a supportare la causa ( sì,
potete essere una “Django Girl” anche se avete la barba) che hanno
contribuito a far crescere la community con il loro entusiasmo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;45 minuti per conoscere la mission Django Girls, entrare in contatto con
la community italiana e per sfatare i falsi miti. Un talk entry level
per tutti, per chi è interessato a portare il progetto nella propria
città, per chi vorrebbe fare il coach e per chi semplicemente vorrebbe
sapere di più sull’iniziativa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laura Bartoli</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/django-girls-italia-entrare-in-contatto-con-le-donne-tecnologiche-davvero.html</guid><category>women</category><category>inclusion</category><category>diversity</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Programação além de código</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/caipyra-2016/programacao-alem-de-codigo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra da Letícia Portella no Caipyra 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programação além de código&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/leportella/programacao-alem-do-codigo-comunidade-e-mulheres-na-tecnologia"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/leportella/programacao-alem-do-codigo-comunidade-e-mulheres-na-tecnologia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leticia Portella</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:caipyra-2016/programacao-alem-de-codigo.html</guid><category>diversity</category><category>women</category></item><item><title>Is it too late to learn how to program and how being a developer changed my life</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/is-it-too-late-to-learn-how-to-program-and-how-being-a-developer-changed-my-life.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How I became a developer in my 50th. the challenges, the assumption and
the victories and how women are not being recognized as an important
part of the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How and why I wanted to be an iOS mobile developer at the age of 51.
Some people want to believe that people my age are out of touch with
technology and as a woman, I have seen the best and the worst in the
tech community but I also now that there is a solution at the end of the
rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the boom in use of smartphones, we have seen a corresponding growth
in numbers of available apps, some of which are being leveraged for
social change. What people don’t know is 70% of women are more active on
our mobile device than men, women are more active with social media,
shopping, photo apps, are more connected to entertainers and play more
games on their smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said we the tech community need to open up our arm and
embrace the change and think about how women in tech can change the way
we see and create apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/is-it-too-late-to-learn-how-to-program-and-how-being-a-developer-changed-my-life.html</guid><category>diversity</category><category>android</category><category>iOS</category><category>women</category></item><item><title>Python in Africa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</guid><category>conferences</category><category>business</category><category>startup</category><category>beginner</category><category>community</category><category>women</category><category>teamwork</category><category>OpenSource</category><category>social</category><category>pyladies</category><category>education</category><category>Learning environment</category><category>user-groups</category></item></channel></rss>