<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Python and the Elephant: Large Scale Natural Language Processing with NLTK and Dumbo (#120)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--the-python-and-the-elephant--large-sc.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python and the Elephant: Large Scale Natural Language Processing
with NLTK and Dumbo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Nitin Madnani (University of Maryland, College Park); Dr.
Jimmy J Lin (University of Maryland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A practical look at NLTK and Dumbo, python-powered and open-source
toolkits and APIs for processing natural language on a large scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people like us who make a living trying to make a computer
&amp;quot;understand&amp;quot; human language, Python is a very powerful language, given
its rapid prototyping abilities, native unicode support and a stellar
standard library. This relationship has been strengthened further by an
open-source, python- based Natural Language ToolKit
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nltk.org/"&gt;www.nltk.org&lt;/a&gt;) which is being widely used in
the community for both teaching and research purposes and gaining
traction in the general Python community as well
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nltk.org/book"&gt;www.nltk.org/book&lt;/a&gt;). Recently, the Python
community has seen the release of Dumbo
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wiki.github.com/klbostee/dumbo"&gt;http://wiki.github.com/klbostee/dumb
o&lt;/a&gt;), an open-source,
python-based cloud-computing API (based on Hadoop) via the hands of
Klaas Bosteels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we show how the amalgamation of Python, NLTK and Dumbo can
allow for very large-scale natural language processing efficiently and
elegantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Jimmy J Lin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--the-python-and-the-elephant--large-sc.html</guid><category>dumbo</category><category>nltk</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category></item></channel></rss>