<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_go-lang.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Go(lang) to Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/golang-to-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Baerisch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/golang-to-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and Go are a great combination. Like Python, Go is easy to learn,
powerful to use and has many useful libraries. Go and Python work great
together: Go has better performance and parallelism, while Python is
more expressive. Wouldn't it be nice if you could combine the benefits
of Go and Python in one program? This talk shows you how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Why you may want to attend&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Extension modules written in C/C++ or other languages are one of the
major strength Python. Go is a useful language to extend Python. This
talk explains to you how to implement extension modules in Go.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Content of the Talk&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk shows how to use CGO to make Go code available as a C library
and then to use Cython to make this library available as a Python
extension module.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We start by building a wrapper for simple Go code that adds some
numbers and returns the results. This program is our end-to-end
example to demonstrate the steps necessary to create a Python
extension module in Go.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Next, we move to more complex use cases. We look at different ways to
share complex data and to use Python callbacks from Go.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Then, we see how to how to handle Go's Garbage Collector when exposing
with Go Objects.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Finally, the talk goes into the advantages and disadvantages of Go as
an extension language for Python. We also look at some of the
alternative ways to make Go code available in Python.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Recommended Prerequisites&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;To get the most out of the talk, you should know about the difference
between native Python modules and extension modules written in other
languages. Some background on concepts like garbage collection, stack
and heap, and dynamic/shared libraries are beneficial. Knowledge of
the Python C API is not required.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;You do not need to know how to write Go code to follow the talk - the
talk explains all the required Go.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Cython"></category><category term="Go-Lang"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry></feed>