<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_zodb-the-graph-database.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>ZODB: The Graph database for Python Developers.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-python-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Lozinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/zodb-the-graph-database-for-python-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ZODB is a mature graph database written in Python and optimized in
C. Just subclass off of class Persistent Object, and Persistent
Container, and your objects, graphs and applications become persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market for Graph Databases has recently exploded, as evidenced by
over $200Million invested in graph database companies. Most of the graph
databases are written in Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Python developer, you will find much greater productivity
using a graph database written in Python, than one written in statically
bound Java. The major Java databases constrain you to one of several
persistent data types. Persistent Python, supported by the ZODB allows
you to make any Python data structure persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new ZODB Demo makes it very easy to start building your own
applications on top of the ZODB. You can start by customizing the
TreeLeaf, TreeBranch and TreeRoot classes and their templates. You get
CRUD for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo includes traditional relational CRUD, Create, Read, Update, and
Delete. But it also includes the extended graph CRUD. Rename a Leaf or
Branch. Cut and paste leaves or branches, copy and paste leaves or
branches. The talk also demonstrates the soon-to-be released view
historic versions and restore a previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;You can watch the talk video here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;PythonLinks.info/zodb&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And see the slides here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf"&gt;https://pythonlinks.info/presentations/zodbtalk.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="ZODB: The Graph database"></category></entry></feed>