<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Benevolent Designer For Life's Keynote - Designers Make It Go to Eleven</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--benevolent-designer-for-life--39-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benevolent Designer for Life's Keynote: Designers make it go to eleven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Idan Gazit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open-source world is and always has been focused on code; attention
and respect doled out in exchange for patches. As a result, many
open-source projects want for design love but don't know how to secure
it. We scare off potential contributors from the many fields beneath the
aegis of &amp;quot;design&amp;quot;: user experience, user interfaces, usability,
interaction design, information architects, graphic design, typography,
and other roles assumed by the authors of our markup and styling. Django
can be a model citizen among open-source projects in changing these
attitudes and coaxing contributors out of the woodwork -- not just for
the benefit of the framework, but for the constellation of 3rd party
apps which make Django great. Other FOSS communities have made efforts
that we can learn from, and the fight to change perceptions is less
uphill than you might think. This talk will cover: - Misconceptions of
&amp;quot;Design.&amp;quot; What is design, and what do designers do? - A brief trip down
memory lane, and how Django came to be relatively designer- friendly. -
&amp;quot;I don't get it: what is the BDesignFL role?&amp;quot; - Process and tools: How
can Django better engage designers, for core's benefit and for the
benefit of &lt;em&gt;your projects&lt;/em&gt;. How can we help these contributors get over
the &amp;quot;suck&amp;quot; threshold? - What parts of core are ripe for love from
designers? What 3rd party projects?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Idan Gazit</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-05:djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--benevolent-designer-for-life--39-.html</guid><category>design</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2011</category><category>ui</category><category>ux</category></item></channel></rss>