<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_olpc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Brian Thorne - Computer Vision</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/brian-thorne---computer-vision.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Thorne</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/brian-thorne---computer-vision.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Thorne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An introduction to computer vision in Python, from the general concept
to its implementation with some current open-source libraries (opencv,
scipy, pygame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of my presentation is an introduction to computer vision
(CV) and image processing in Python. I will aim to show what is possible
with current libraries, demonstrate their usability, explore their
limitations, and cover elements of best coding practice. Firstly, I will
briefly present the basics, such as video grabbing, image processing and
computer vision algorithms. I will illustrate my presentation with the
Python bindings to the opencv library and show different examples such
as displaying a video image, some filtering algorithms (dilation,
gaussian blur), and how to implement facial recognition. I will describe
after how related tasks can be achieved with other Python tools such as
scipy and pygame. I will show how these three libraries can be used in
conjunction to perform video capturing, image processing and user
interfacing. Finally, I will introduce my basic Python computer vision
framework, which is aimed at inexperienced users, and demonstrate it on
the XO laptop, the inexpensive low-powered sub-notebook distributed as
part of the One Laptop Per Child (OLPC) initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Sound and video are poor. Slides are hard to read.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="kiwipycon"></category><category term="kiwipycon2009"></category><category term="olpc"></category><category term="pygame"></category><category term="scipy"></category><category term="vision"></category></entry><entry><title>Tim McNamara - OLPC XO: Python bringing education to the world's poorest children</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/tim-mcnamara---olpc-xo--python-bringing-education.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim McNamara</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/tim-mcnamara---olpc-xo--python-bringing-education.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OLPC XO: Python bringing education to the world's poorest children&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Tim McNamara&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic will be divided into five different area of 10 minutes each,
with time for questions and discussion. We'll talk about the OLPC
programme, the hardware, the software, the educational theory and how to
get involved NZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In defence of the OLPC XO This section will be a brief overview of
the whole project hopefully with an eye to dispel some rumour and
controversy surrounding the project. There has been several mixed
messages, and I would like to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of the hardware In this section, the talk to move into a
discussion about the overview of the hardware itself. There will be
several machines for the audience to have a look at, and we'll try
and test some of the mesh networking, collaboration and sharing
capabilities that are built into the machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of the software The OLPC XO is run using a Python
environment called Sugar
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sugarlabs.org.nz/"&gt;http://sugarlabs.org.nz&lt;/a&gt;), which
itself is a Fedora Remix. We will talk a little about how an Activity
is built and how to start contributing to the Sugar system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to deploy into schools This segment will go over some of the
theoretical underpinnings of the user interface and Sugar's approach
to things like the directory structure. We'll also explore some of
the tools that teachers and parents can use to progressively
encourage their children to learn about computing and develop
creative and critical thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get involved There are small pockets of XOs around the
country. Learn where they are and how to start improving them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Sound and video are poor. Slides are hard to read.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="kiwipycon"></category><category term="kiwipycon2009"></category><category term="olpc"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConAU 2010: Lightning talks - Saturday</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--lightning-talks---saturday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Amy Maree</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--lightning-talks---saturday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks - Saturday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:00 - Amy Maree: Talking about OLPC XO, Python and Pippy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05:55 - Jurgen Brendel: Jython and writing performance critical parts
in Java.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;09:50 - Dave Claridge: Embedding Python and robots that play soccer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15:10 - Paul Dyson: inflect.py&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:20 - Richard Jones: cocos2d, a python game library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25:40 - Brian Quinlan: Why you probably don't want to work for Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30:50 - Nick Coghlan: Running Python scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;34:55 - Philip: How to introduce Python to a large organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;38:55 - Ryan Kelly: with hacks: re-usable tools for with-statement
hackery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PMC curator notes: Paul Dyson's demo at 18:28 is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone know's Philip's last name (and/or if we spelled his first name
wrong, too), let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category><category term="cocos2d"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="hacks"></category><category term="inflect.py"></category><category term="jython"></category><category term="olpc"></category><category term="pippy"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau2010"></category><category term="robots"></category><category term="scripts"></category><category term="with"></category></entry></feed>