<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_rumba.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The unconventional Introduction to Deep Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/the-unconventional-introduction-to-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Valerio Maggio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/the-unconventional-introduction-to-deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are into Deep Learning, sooner or later, it inevitbly happens
that you’re asked at least once to explain what actually means &lt;strong&gt;Deep
Learning&lt;/strong&gt; , and what’s all the fuss about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, answering this question in a proper way, may vary (and it has
to) depending on the kind of audience you’ve been talking to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are talking to a machine learning experts, you have to
concentrate on what &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; means, for the multiple learning models you
can come up with. Most importarly, you have to convince them that a deep
learning model would work by far better than a more standard and robust
Random Forest or Support Vector Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if your audience is made up of engineers, they
[STRIKEOUT:don’t give a damn..] are definitely more interested in how
you implement your Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) rather than
understanding what are the implications of different &lt;em&gt;activations&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;optimizers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if your audience is made up of data scientists - who are a good
mixture of the previous two, according to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://drewconway.com/zia/2013/3/26/the-data-science-venn-diagram"&gt;Drew
Conway&lt;/a&gt;
- they are more or less interested in both the two aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way, that is the &lt;em&gt;unconventional way&lt;/em&gt;, to explain what Deep
Learning means, is from the perspective of the computational model it
requires to be properly effective. Therefore, you may want to talk about
ANN in terms of matrix multiplications algorithms, running on a (series
of) GPUs in parallel. And this is &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;/strong&gt; the perspecitve I intend
to pursue in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for PyData scientists who are interested in understanding
Deep Learning models from this unconventional perspective, learning what
are the libraries and tools they may leverage for their experiments on
GPUs. Experienced engineers may likely benefit from this talk as well,
learning how they can make their models run fast(er).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Keras"></category><category term="rumba"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="Theano"></category><category term="GPU"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry></feed>