<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Delta Chat, CFFI, pytest and all the Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/delta-chat-cffi-pytest-and-all-the-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delta Chat, a new approach to decentralized messaging, uses Python in
several ways. Delta Chat is a Whatsapp/Telegram-style messenger app
which uses the existing e-mail server network instead of central
servers. There is no address book upload, and no necessity to tie
accounts to mobile numbers. We'll live- demo how &amp;quot;Chat over E-mail&amp;quot;
works, with random audience members, in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll then look into how Python is used for automated testing (with
pytest) against the messenger core library which is exposed through
CFFI. However, the core library will soon be ported to full Rust. Are
there better ways to interface Rust with Python than going through
C-interfaces?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third part we'll introduce first example Chat Bots, written in
Python. Do you want to send an machine-generated system allert to a
sysadmin group? Or safely archive all media that is posted to a family
group? Or have your IoT sensor react to commands or send info? Just do
it without registering a bot to some central cite, or by exposing all
content information to (e. g. Telegram) servers. A Chat Bot only needs
access to a standard IMAP/SMTP account. We'll look at the simple Python
API for writing and testing powerful and versatile Chat bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Delta Chat: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://delta.chat"&gt;https://delta.chat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Core library and Py bindings:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core"&gt;https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Deltabot: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/deltachat/deltabot/"&gt;https://github.com/deltachat/deltabot/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Holger Krekel</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/delta-chat-cffi-pytest-and-all-the-rust.html</guid><category>Development</category><category>Python general</category><category>Rust</category><category>Sensors</category><category>System Administration</category></item><item><title>Become a command line wizard</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/become-a-command-line-wizard.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many modern terminal tools with vastly improved user
experiences as compared to their traditional alternatives. This talk
aims to show off some of those modern terminal tools and compare them
side by side with the traditional ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is not only used by software developers with fancy IDEs but also
by DevOps engineers, administrators, and on remote development machines
where using a GUI is impractical. Therefore, many people are stuck with
a terminal interface only and have to use tools like vim, grep, find,
wc, cloc, less and many others to explore their way around their Python
programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, thanks to the advent of many new and improved tools, we can do
many of the same tasks better, faster and with nicer ergonomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will show off effective use of vim as an IDE with completions
and linting provided by LSP, fd (instead of find) for finding files,
ripgrep (instead of grep) for searching strings, tokei (instead of cloc)
for counting lines of code, bat (instead of cat) for looking at files,
hyperfine for microbenchmarking, httpie (instead of curl) for making
HTTP requests, sd (instead of sed) for text replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk should make terminal work more approachable for all attendees
by showing off how to do some everyday tasks on the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sven-Hendrik Haase</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/become-a-command-line-wizard.html</guid><category>Command-Line</category><category>Linux</category><category>System Administration</category><category>Tooling</category><category>Unix</category></item></channel></rss>