<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Working for FOSS can make you a better programmer: Insights into my Outreachy internship with Fedora</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/working-for-foss-can-make-you-a-better-programmer-insights-into-my-outreachy-internship-with-fedora.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outreachy program offers three-month internships for people from groups
underrepresented in tech. Interns are paid a stipend of $5,500 and have
a $500 travel stipend available to them. Interns work remotely with
mentors from Free and Open Source Software (FOSS) communities on
projects not limited to just programming but also user experience,
documentation, illustration and graphical design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently interning with Fedora under the Outreachy program, where
my task is to is to develop administrative tools for the 389 Directory
Server, an enterprise class LDAP (Lightweight Directory Access Protocol)
server, used in businesses globally to authenticate and identify people.
LDAP is a standard application protocol for accessing and maintaining
distributed directory information services over an Internet Protocol
(IP) network. I am helping Fedora improve the Directory Servers Python
command line tools. In addition to this, the team at Fedora is also
investigating into integrating existing C code with Rust (watch here:
Integrating Rust with existing C) to improve performance and
maintainability. Hence, I am also working on establishing proof of
concept for using Rust instead of C and also using Rust with existing C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with fixing bugs in the Directory Server and it enabled me to
get more understanding about LDAP concepts, since LDAP has a steep
learning curve. My first task was to add the command line support for
automember plugin to the Directory Server. Automembership allows a
static group to act like a dynamic group, for adding new members to the
group. Different automembership definitions create searches that are
automatically run on all new directory entries. The automembership rules
search for and identify matching entries and then explicitly add those
entries as members to the group. I started by added the classes (Auto
Membership Plugin, Auto Member Definition, Auto Member Definitions),
methods and the tests for these classes and methods (Pull Request). Then
I added the support for automember by command line which included
creating, removing, editing and showing the automember definitions. This
included writing the tests as well. By the end of this task, I learnt
about Python decorators, lazy evaluation in Python, using pytest testing
tool and writing command line parser and arguments using the argparse
library. (This will be shown with live coding and screenshots).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on another task which involves building an LRU
cache in Rust which stores C allocated strings and can retrieve them.
This project will be built using the meson build system. I will also
provide tests and asan builds. This task will act as a proof of concept
for investigating if meson can replace autotools as the Directory Server
build system. During this task, I hope to learn about build systems, LRU
caching concept and Rust types and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can deduce from my tasks and the key learnings, doing this
Outreachy internship with Fedora is helping me to stand at the forefront
of technology, learning about LDAP, Python and Rust (polyglot!), which
will definitely enable me to become a better programmer and a
collaborative community member for Fedora. And I hope to inspire other
underrepresented people in tech with my talk about the Outreachy
internship and my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alisha Aneja</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/working-for-foss-can-make-you-a-better-programmer-insights-into-my-outreachy-internship-with-fedora.html</guid><category>open source</category><category>#remote</category><category>#community</category><category>user-groups</category></item><item><title>Python in Africa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</guid><category>conferences</category><category>business</category><category>startup</category><category>beginner</category><category>community</category><category>women</category><category>teamwork</category><category>OpenSource</category><category>social</category><category>pyladies</category><category>education</category><category>Learning environment</category><category>user-groups</category></item></channel></rss>