<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_openhatch.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Get new contributors (and diversity) through outreach</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--get-new-contributors--and-diversity--.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Asheesh Laroia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--get-new-contributors--and-diversity--.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get new contributors (and diversity) through outreach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Asheesh Laroia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups like the Fedora Design Team, Dreamwidth, SF Ruby, and OpenHatch
have discovered the power of outreach to bring in new contributors. In
the past year, SF Ruby grew in numbers as well as in diversity, moving
from 3% women to 18% women. Because most projects need ongoing help,
this talk discusses effective strategies for bringing in contributors
who stick around for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is targeted at anyone involved in an open source project who
wants to find more contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programs like Google Summer of Code often provide excited students who
disappear after a summer's work. Meanwhile, request for help emails on
development lists are typically met with silence. Hackathons create a
flurry of commits, but then we never hear from the participants again.
Expanding your team is possible, and it requires care in terms of
outreach, expectation management, and mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss three major forms of outreach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-on-one check-ins with participants,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periodic drives to bring in new contributors, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-person teaching events. Each one has &amp;quot;do&amp;quot;s and &amp;quot;don't&amp;quot;s associated
with it. This talk digests the experience of effective outreach into
practical strategies that you can re-use within your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="openhatch"></category><category term="outreach"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>