<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_data-mining.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Pandas ecosystem 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/pandas-ecosystem-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc Garcia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/pandas-ecosystem-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pandas is more than 10 years old now. In this time, it became almost a
standard for building data pipelines and perform data analysis in
Python. As the popularity of the project grows, it also grows the number
of projects that depend or interact with pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover this ecosystem of projects around pandas, mainly in
the prespective of scalability and performance. Discussing for example
how projects like Arrow are key for the future of pandas, or how Dask is
overcoming pandas limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first part, the talk will focus on pandas itself, its components,
and its architecture. This will give the required context for a second
part, that will explain related projects, how they interact with pandas,
and what the whole ecosystem can offer to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1613"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1613&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pydata"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="data"></category><category term="pandas"></category></entry><entry><title>A journey into the Chinese language with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/a-journey-into-the-chinese-language-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/a-journey-into-the-chinese-language-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese language includes over 200 radicals used to form over 40
thousands characters that can be combined to create almost 100 thousands
words. Then there are tones, classifiers, homophones, multiple
pronunciations for each character, traditional and simplified variants,
different kind of romanization… it’s no wonder that Chinese is
considered one of the most difficult languages to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However Chinese is actually pretty easy and during this talk you will
learn more about this beautiful language and how I’ve been learning it
with the help of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Human-languages"></category><category term="data-mining"></category><category term="Chinese"></category></entry><entry><title>GPU-accelerated data analysis in Python: a study case in Material Sciences</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/gpu-accelerated-data-analysis-in-python-a-study-case-in-material-sciences.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Di Bernardo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/gpu-accelerated-data-analysis-in-python-a-study-case-in-material-sciences.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Max Planck Computing and Data Facility is engaged in the development
and optimization of algorithms and applications for high performance
computing as well as for data-intensive projects. As programming
language in data science, Python is now used at MPCDF in the scientific
area of “atom probe crystallography” (APT): a Fourier analysis in 3D
space can be simulated in order to reveal composition and
crystallographic structure at the atomic scale of billions APT
experimental data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python data ecosystem has proved to be well suited to this, as it
has grown beyond the confines of single machines to embrace scalability.
The talk aims to describe our approach to scaling across multiple GPUs,
and the role of visualization methods too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data workflow analysis relies on the GPU-accelerated Python software
package PyNX, an open source library which provides fast parallel
computation scattering. The code takes advantage of the high throughput
of GPUs, using the pyCUDA library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploratory data analysis, high productivity and rapid prototyping with
high performance are enabled through Jupyter Notebooks and Python
packages e.g., pandas, matplotlib/plotly. In production stage,
interactive visualization is realized by using standard scientific tool,
e.g. Paraview, an open-source 3D visualization program which requires
Python modules to generate visualization components within VTK files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="GPUComputing"></category><category term="visualization"></category><category term="mathematical-modelling"></category><category term="image-processing"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="scientific-computing"></category><category term="physics"></category><category term="python3"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Python to bring democracy to the A.I. age</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/using-python-to-bring-democracy-to-the-ai-age.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felipe Cabral</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/using-python-to-bring-democracy-to-the-ai-age.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-you-go-full-big-data-at-public-data-and-become-a-citzen"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When you go full Big Data at public data and become a citzen.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience type: developers, data scientists of any level of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a political coup Brazil drowned in scandals and political
disbelief. That was the final straw for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a bot persona who uses Machine Learning to analyze public
spending, launching our own data journalism investigations. As expected
we use the internet publicize our findings and icing on it was to use
Twitter to directly engage the public and politicians under the topic of
suspicious expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come with me and I’ll show some figures from Brazilian corruption, share
some code and cherry-pick the best of our toolbox to deal with public
data and machine learning. I’ll introduce our public dashboard that
makes visualization and browsing government data easy peasy. And surely
we can take a look in some tweets from Rosie, the robot, and how some
politicians are now vociferating with a ROBOT on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you guessed it right: everything is open-source and our mission is
to create a global community to bring democracy to the A.I. age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="agile"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="e-gov"></category><category term="data"></category></entry><entry><title>Sports performance evaluation: from cognitive mechanisms to data-driven algorithms</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/sports-performance-evaluation-from-cognitive-mechanisms-to-data-driven-algorithms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca Pappalardo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/sports-performance-evaluation-from-cognitive-mechanisms-to-data-driven-algorithms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Not everything that counts can be counted, and not everything that
can be counted counts. A. Einstein&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are routinely asked to evaluate the performance of other
individuals, separating success from failure and affecting outcomes from
science to education and sports. Yet, little is known about the aspects
that determine the human perception of performance. How do expert
reviewers, as well as ordinary people, arrive to their evaluations? To
what extent these evaluations are based on objective performance
features? How are they affected by subjective biases or contextual
influences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will answer these fascinating questions focusing on &lt;em&gt;soccer&lt;/em&gt; ,
the most popular sport in the world. Firstly, we will show how machine
learning can accurately reproduce the mechanisms human judges use to
evaluate the performance of soccer players, uncovering limits and
characteristics of the human evaluation process. Second, we design a
Python package that allows, in a completely unsupervised and data-driven
way, to (i) evaluate the quality of a player’s performance and (ii) rank
soccer players based on their performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the talk will show how soccer ratings assigned to
every player of a game by sport-specialized newspapers are associated
with a high- dimensional vector of features extracted by massive data
which describe any quantifiable aspects of soccer games. The talk will
show how, by using Scikit- learn, we can train an &lt;em&gt;artificial judge&lt;/em&gt;
which learns the relation between technical performance and soccer
ratings, hence &lt;em&gt;accurately reproducing&lt;/em&gt; the human evaluation process. By
inspecting the structure of the artificial judge, the talk will show
that the human evaluation criteria follow a simplistic cognitive process
based on a simple heuristic: judges first select a limited number of
features which attract their attention and then rate a performance based
on the presence of noticeable values, i.e., features values far from the
norm that can be easily brought to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the talk will show how to overcome the simplicity of
the human evaluation process presenting &lt;strong&gt;PlayeRank&lt;/strong&gt; , a Python package
which implements an unsupervised data-driven framework to evaluate the
performance of soccer players in the main European leagues. The talk
will show how to use PlayeRank to construct a data-driven ranking of
players and highlight the factors which determine why celebrated
players, like Messi and Cristiano Ronaldo, actually result to be the top
players in the world. The modules composing PlayeRank will be presented,
showing how they allow the user to define the features characterizing a
performance, to detect in an automatic way the relevance of each
player’s action to a game outcome, to detect the role of a player given
his game data, to rate every performance as well as to obtain a final
ranking of all players in Europe. A short demo will be provided during
the talk through a Jupyter notebook, exploiting interactive data
visualization with the Bokeh package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will learn how to use Python to construct evaluation
algorithms entirely based on machine learning and big data, a step
forward to a thorough and objective evaluation of performance which
overcomes the biases and the limitations of human perception of
performance. Just a basic knowledge of Python and of data mining
principles is required for a full understanding of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mathematical-modelling"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="sports-analytics"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning con Python: previsione in real-time della richiesta di energia elettrica</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-previsione-in-real-time-della-richiesta-di-energia-elettrica.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felice Tuosto</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-previsione-in-real-time-della-richiesta-di-energia-elettrica.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nel talk si parlerà di come attraverso il linguaggio Python sia
possibile risolvere un problema reale e complesso relativamente alla
trasmissione di energia elettrica. Verrà spiegato il progetto
&lt;strong&gt;RealtimeLoadForecast&lt;/strong&gt; che è stato sviluppato per un importante TSO
(Transmission System Operator). Si tratta di sistema predittivo che
permette di fornire in tempo reale ogni 15 minuti ed entro 5 minuti, le
previsioni delle serie storiche dei consumi di energia elettrica
relativi a circa 500 nodi elettrici.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si parlerà dei passi che occorre seguire per ottenere da un semplice
prototipo, un sistema &lt;em&gt;ingegnerizzato&lt;/em&gt; che lavori in tempo reale e di
come sono state utilizzate le librerie di Python per l’acquisizione,
manipolazione e processamento dei dati elettrici ed ambientali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saranno descritte alcune tecniche algoritmiche e di Machine Learning per
ottenere dei modelli predittivi capaci di fornire previsioni accurate ma
con tempi di risposta sfidanti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrà mostrato un &lt;em&gt;esempio concreto&lt;/em&gt; di implementazione di un algoritmo
predittivo basato sulla libreria Deep Learning &lt;strong&gt;Keras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per la comprensione del talk non sono necessari particolari requisiti se
non una conoscenza di base di programmazione in Python e di Machine
Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Forecasting"></category><category term="Genetic Algorithms"></category><category term="Keras"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="programming-paradigms"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="threading"></category><category term="realtime"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="mysql"></category><category term="signal-processing"></category><category term="LoadForecasting"></category><category term="cassandra"></category></entry><entry><title>Data mining and integration with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/data-mining-and-integration-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Isaac Vidas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/data-mining-and-integration-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an abundance of data in social media sites (Wikipedia,
Facebook, Instagram, etc.) which can be accessed through web APIs. But
how do we know that the data from the Wikipedia article on &amp;quot;Golden Gate
Bridge&amp;quot; goes along with the data from &amp;quot;Golden Gate Bridge&amp;quot; Facebook
page? This represents an important question about integrating data from
various sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll outline important aspects of structured data mining,
integration and entity resolution methods in a scalable system.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Analysis"></category><category term="data mining"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Mining mit Orange</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/data-mining-mit-orange.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Bresser</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-16:pycon-de-2013/data-mining-mit-orange.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Es wird eine einfache Einführung in das Thema Data Mining gegeben. Dazu
werden anschauliche Beispiele für den Einsatz von Orange gezeigt. Orange
ist ein Open Source Programm, das Data Mining und Datenvisualisierung
durch visuelle Programmierung oder Python Scripting ermöglicht.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="classification"></category><category term="data mining"></category><category term="klassifikation"></category><category term="orange"></category></entry></feed>