<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_bitcoin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Tools to interact with Bitcoin and Ethereum</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/tools-to-interact-with-bitcoin-and-ethereum.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ondrej Sika</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/tools-to-interact-with-bitcoin-and-ethereum.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You probably know Bitcoin. Nowadays, Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies
ecosystem is one of fastest growing industries. Many people build
software on the top of those distributed networks. I'll show you tools
you can use to interact with Bitcoin and Ethereum. From simple stuff
like wallets and transaction to playing with smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Bitcoin"></category><category term="Ethereum"></category><category term="PyCon SK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>_from __future__ import profit</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/_from-__future__-import-profit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-29T10:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-29T10:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>James Campbell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/_from-__future__-import-profit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - a light hearted introduction on how to make $$$ trading Bitcoin with Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent explosion of Bitcoin, Ethereum and other crypto currencies has presented a fantastic opportunity for the small amateur trader. In August 2015, 1 Bitcoin could be bought for $200 and 2 years later as I type this sentence the price has increased to $4211. This talk will explain WHY crypto currencies in particularly are so profitable, and HOW we can take advantage of the situation using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I had no understanding of altcoins or the block chain and had never invested or traded any money in my life. This changed very recently when I set myself the challenge of turning my Raspberry Pi into a profitable trading bot. During some initial research I stumbled upon the world of crypto currency trading and was completely hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested to hear about my experience (and find out whether I've actually made any money) then please come along. No knowledge of trading, bitcoin or anything particularly technical is required.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bitcoin"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Blockchain and Byte-Size Change</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/python-blockchain-and-byte-size-change.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Portia Burton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/python-blockchain-and-byte-size-change.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 keynote by Portia Burton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will answer the question of what is bitcoin and the blockchain and will end with a quick tutorial on how to create a blockchain application in Flask. We will not only make a bitcoin application, but we will also reflect upon the implications of this cutting edge technology to the greater society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin and blockchain technology has been in the news as of late, such as the hard fork of Ethereum to the hack of Bitifnex. This talk will cover the basics of blockchain technology and we will learn how to build an application that accepts bitcoin. Armed with a little knowledge of Flask and REST we will be able to use Python to bridge the gap between current events and technology. As Python developers we will be able to add to the narrative of bitcoin/blockchain technology in a unique and meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bitcoin"></category><category term="blockchain"></category></entry><entry><title>PyOhio 2011: Exchange Digital Money using Bitcoin</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--exchange-digital-money-using-bitcoin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Steele</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-30:pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--exchange-digital-money-using-bitcoin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exchange Digital Money Using Bitcoin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by David Steele&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is described as the first decentralized digital currency. This
talk describes how Bitcoin uses public key encryption, proof-of-work
based logging, and peer-to-peer technology to create a type of money
which can be transferred over the Internet. We'll cover how to use
Python to manage your digital wallet and participate in this new P2P
economy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bitcoin"></category><category term="pyohio"></category><category term="pyohio2011"></category></entry></feed>