<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_dataexploration.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data Visualization in Mixed Reality with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/data-visualization-in-mixed-reality-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Nicanorova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/data-visualization-in-mixed-reality-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Visualization charts are supposed to be our map to information.
However, when making charts, customarily we are just re-sizing lines and
circles based on metrics instead of creating data-driven version of
reality. The contemporary charting techniques have a few shortcomings
(especially when dealing with high-dimensional dataset):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context Reduction: in order to fit a high-dimensional dataset into a
chart one needs to filter/ aggregate/ flatten data which results in
reduction of full context of information. Without context most of the
charts show only a part of the story, that can potentially lead to
data misinterpretation/misunderstanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numeric Thinking: naturally humans have hard time perceiving big
numbers. While data visualization is suppose to help us to
conceptualize large volumes, unless the dataset is carefully
prepared, 2D charts rarely give us the intuitive grasp of magnitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceptual de-humanization: when examining charts it is easy to
forget that we are dealing with activity in real world instead of
lines/bars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augmented/Mixed Reality can potentially solve all of the issues listed
above by presenting an intuitive and interactive environment for data
exploration. Three dimensional space provides conditions to create
complex data stories with more “realistic assets” (beyond lines and
bars). The talk would present the architecture required to create MR
data visualization story with Python (70% of architecture), starting
with drawing 3D assets in a data-driven way and finishing with
deployment on MR devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DataExploration"></category><category term="DataAnalysis"></category><category term="DataVisualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Dai dati alla visualizzazione: la mia prima data pipeline</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dai-dati-alla-visualizzazione-la-mia-prima-data-pipeline.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Riccardo Magliocchetti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/dai-dati-alla-visualizzazione-la-mia-prima-data-pipeline.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Costruire una data pipeline non deve essere per forza complicato. Nel
talk vedremo come si può realizzare una semplice data pipeline usando
Luigi per consumare dati da una API e prepararli per fare esplorazione e
visualizzazione con Superset (AKA Caravel).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DataExploration"></category><category term="superset"></category><category term="DataVisualization"></category><category term="etl"></category><category term="luigi"></category></entry></feed>