<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to ship a Python app to a hundred million desktops</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-ship-a-python-app-to-a-hundred-million-desktops.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is widely used to write scripts and tools, but did you know that
it can also be used to build client-side end-user applications? Crossing
the gap from script to app can be challenging: Join us to learn how to
write modern, high quality desktop apps in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Dropbox, we’ve been fans of Python from the very beginning: we’ll
take you on a tour of our app for Windows/macOS/Linux and share our
“lessons learned” from over 10 years of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll share best practices and techniques for shipping Python code to
hundreds of millions of devices: discover how to maximize security,
improve performance and guarantee stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore the key choices we made and why: learn how we migrated to
Python 3 by simultaneously shipping both versions, or how we use HTML to
power our GUI (a la Electron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll reveal our favorite tools and libraries: learn how we scaled from
a few engineers to over 100 and added support for other programming
languages (like Rust).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The goal of this talk is to share our learnings from using Python on
Windows, macOS and Linux to encourage the use of Python when building
Desktop apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- We also want to recognize the third-party libraries we’ve used (and
their authors) to raise their profile with the overall community.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- We hope this will inspire attendees to write more desktop Python
code, and raise awareness for this use case with the community as a
whole.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We intend to speak to any Python developer/engineer or enthusiast who
makes use of Python in a Desktop environment (or wants to), whether
it’s to make scripts, tools or apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We do not expect knowledge of any specific third-party Python
libraries; in fact, we hope to draw attention to and recognize many
libraries we’ve found useful.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Max Bélanger</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/how-to-ship-a-python-app-to-a-hundred-million-desktops.html</guid><category>Architecture</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Cross-Platform-Development</category><category>Mac OS X</category><category>Windows</category></item></channel></rss>