<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_empathy.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Empathy Maketh an Engineer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-philippines-2019/empathy-maketh-an-engineer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Narendran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-23:pycon-philippines-2019/empathy-maketh-an-engineer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The journey towards becoming a better developer involves in more than just coding. If there is one thing that you want to learn this year to make yourself a better developer, it will be empathy. In this talk, we will see, as a developer how to practice empathy and write code empathetically. Also, we will discuss how empathy driven development will make one a better software craftsman and build great teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="empathy"></category></entry><entry><title>Helping communities &amp; products thrive by fostering empathy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sasha Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a fundamental part of human interaction. When we communicate
by email or at conferences, or indirectly, when we create products,
events, or do a talk. However, our understanding of other people is full
of error, and worse, bias. This can lead us to make communities and
products that work poorly for people that are different from ourselves,
introduce confusion and misunderstanding, exclude people
unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our communities are an opportunity to learn as well. To embrace
our diversity, and expand our understanding of other people’s worlds. To
gain understanding of other people’s situations, experiences and
emotions, which can be dramatically different to ours. And how we can
use this to create both products and communities which work great not
only for ourselves, but also those that we more easily forget about. As
creators in tech we have such tremendous power to create change, but
merely our best intentions will not be enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how and why we sometimes have such difficulty to
understand others, and how others can have difficulty to understand us.
We’ll talk about why other people’s experiences, emotion and perceptions
can be so different. Both for the world as a whole, but also with the
speaker’s personal experiences. Finally, we’ll cover specific ways for
us to understand others better, and associated pitfalls, to make our
communities and products happy, inviting and supportive places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="empathy"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>One weird trick to becoming a better software developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/one-weird-trick-to-becoming-a-better-software-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Esther Nam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/one-weird-trick-to-becoming-a-better-software-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of us who have worked in software development for longer than a few years probably feel we have an intuitive sense of what a great developer is. Some traits come more easily to mind than others when it comes to identifying a great developer. In this talk we will take a slightly different approach to evaluating software development best practices, and identify one underrated skill common to great software developers: empathy. I hope to demonstrate that cognitive and emotional empathy skills are critical to good software development. We will explore ways to cultivate this trait in order to become better developers, both for our own sakes and for the sake of the teams in which we work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="empathy"></category></entry></feed>