<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Traversing the land of graph computing and databases</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/traversing-the-land-of-graph-computing-and-databases.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphs have long held a special place in the computer science’s history
(and codebases). With the advent of a new wave of the information age
characterized by a greater emphasis on linked data, graph computing and
databases have risen to prominence. Be it enterprise knowledge graphs or
graph-based analytics, there are a great number of potential
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reap the benefits of graph databases and computing, one needs to
understand the basics as well as current technical landscape and
offerings. Also, it’s important to understand if a graph-based approach
suits your problem. This talk will touch upon these points. Be prepared
to learn some graph fundamentals and witness a live demo using Neo4j, a
popular graph database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soft pre-requisites include familiarity with Python and experience
working with a SQL or NoSQL database. There are no hard pre-requisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1682"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1682&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Akash Tandon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/traversing-the-land-of-graph-computing-and-databases.html</guid><category>nosql</category><category>graph</category><category>analytics</category><category>databases</category><category>neo4j</category><category>datascience</category><category>graphdatabase</category></item><item><title>Unveiling the potential of graph databases with Python and Neo4j</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/unveiling-the-potential-of-graph-databases-with-python-and-neo4j.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time we are dealing with data coming from the real world, big and
not so big, you know that usually 80% of the time is needed to clean,
prepare and arrange them. We can then spend the other 20% of the time
enjoying our beloved data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing that you may know less is that in the last years, the Neo4j
graph database went into the light of being the “right” place to store
data, thanks to its capacity of direct modelling relations among data,
its high availability and its easy, fast and clean query language
Cypher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’m going to show you some tips to set up in the right way
your data using Pandas, in order to proper model and import them into
Neo4j. A Neo4j Python driver is available to easily import Cypher
queries embedded in Python code. Still, the py2neo package allows
building and querying your database right within your favourite snake
command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget about “tall as teen” SQL queries here; thanks to Pandas, Python
and Cypher modelling, loading and query your database is going to be
really straightforward. After this talk, you’ll can’t wait to give Neo4j
a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: a little knowledge of Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fabio Lamanna</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/unveiling-the-potential-of-graph-databases-with-python-and-neo4j.html</guid><category>database</category><category>graph</category><category>storage</category><category>neo4j</category><category>data</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Graph Databases: Talking about your Data Relationships with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/graph-databases-talking-about-your-data-relationships-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered how many relationships you have in your virtual life? Every friend or page liked on Facebook, each connection in LinkedIn or Twitter account followed is a new relationship not only between two people, but also between their data. In Brazil only, we have 160 millions Facebook users. How can we represent and manipulate all these relationships? Graph Databases are storage systems that use graph structure (nodes and edges) to represent and store data in a semantic way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will begin approaching the challenge in representing relationships in Relational Databases and introducing a more friendly solution using graph. The definition of Graph Database, its pros and cons and some available tools (Neo4J, OrientDB and TitanDB) will be shown during the presentation, as well as how these tools can be integrated with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicolle Cysneiros</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/graph-databases-talking-about-your-data-relationships-with-python.html</guid><category>graph</category></item><item><title>Analisi dati e grafici con Genropy e Pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/analisi-dati-e-grafici-con-genropy-e-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
offre ad utenti e sviluppatori un ambiente di lavoro molto comodo per il
caricamento e la gestione dei dati. In questo talk parleremo degli
strumenti messi a disposizione per l’analisi dei dati e la
rappresentazione grafica, tabellare e in dashboard. Parleremo in
particolare dell’integrazione con Pandas e di come sia facile anche per
un utente non particolarmente esperto generare pivot table, e creare
colonne calcolate e mostrare i risultati come grafici.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Francesco Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/analisi-dati-e-grafici-con-genropy-e-pandas.html</guid><category>genropy</category><category>webapp</category><category>pandas</category><category>web-development</category><category>graph</category></item></channel></rss>