<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_puppet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Continuous Delivery starts at your Development Environment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/continuous-delivery-starts-at-your-development-environment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Bittner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/continuous-delivery-starts-at-your-development-environment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery is the automation of our deployment and QA, isn’t
it? The industrialized software production chain that solves all our
problems. Well, kind of. It’s more than that. Because: You still have
pain when …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You bring new developers on board (e.g. for installing Docker and
friends, IDEs and command line tools).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your development machine behaves weird or needs an upgrade. (Can you
simply re-install it and continue working without losing a day or a
week of productivity?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to explain to your colleagues, or even convince them, how to
configure which of their tools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone turns to you (or your admin wizard) when there are troubles
to get some tools or projects running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks explains how to bootstrap a super-efficient startup, SMB, or
just any development team that needs a development infrastructure.
You’ll see a demo of The Foreman, Puppet, Ansible and optionally FreeIPA
and virtualization technology, which gets you from zero to 100 in just a
few hours. This talk explains how you do infrastructure like software
development. Everything under control. Everything under version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join the show, and take home the recipe that tells you how to step
up the next level of Continuous Delivery! - If you’re a beginner fear
not: this talk starts with an introduction to CI/CD and brings you up to
speed quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 22 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="continuous-delivery"></category><category term="agile"></category><category term="ansible"></category><category term="puppet"></category><category term="free-software"></category><category term="FreeIPA"></category><category term="infrastructure-as-code"></category></entry><entry><title>How to maintain big app stacks without losing your mind</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2011/how-to-maintain-big-app-stacks-without-losing-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dylan Jay</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-08-22:pycon-au-2011/how-to-maintain-big-app-stacks-without-losing-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;zc.buildout is a powerful build/configure/deployment tool for creating
applications from multiple parts, some not python. It's perfect for
sharing a development environment or deploy applications to many hosts.
This tutorial will cover basic concepts, similarity to other tools such
as virtual-env, puppet etc as well as practical examples. zc.buildout
has successful been used with web applications such as Plone, django and
pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deploy"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="puppet"></category><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="zc.buildout"></category></entry><entry><title>Von der Entwicklung bis zum Deployment mit standardisierten und konfigurierbaren Laufzeitumgebungen</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/von-der-entwicklung-bis-zum-deployment-mit-standa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juergen Schackmann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-15:pycon-de-2013/von-der-entwicklung-bis-zum-deployment-mit-standa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Es wird gezeigt, wie Laufzeitumgebungen (Betriebssystem, Services wie
Datenbank oder Webserver, Python, Applikation) standardisiert
konfiguriert und automatisiert erzeugt werden können. Somit wird
sichergestellt, dass eine Applikation immer in definierten und
weitgehend identischen Umgebungen ausgeführt wird - unabhängig von den
verschiedenen Phasen des Lebenszyklus (Entwicklung, Test, Produktion
etc.) und persönlichen Präferenzen und Know-how der involvierten
Personen. Hierfür eingesetzt werden: Vagrant, Virtualbox,Puppet,
Virtualenv.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bootstrapping"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="puppet"></category><category term="vagrant"></category><category term="virtualenv"></category></entry><entry><title>Dependency management with Puppet</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--dependency-management-with-puppet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Crowley</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--dependency-management-with-puppet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dependency management with Puppet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Richard Crowley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puppet is a configuration management tool that we'll learn to use the
easy way. We'll introduce the Puppet language and the concept of
resources like packages, files, shell commands, and more. We'll use
Puppet to build our dev environment and deploy it to production servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've all been there: religiously following the steps in some blog post
for the 47th time trying to setup a shiny new server. We thought we'd
improved the situation when we copied our Bash history into doit.sh and
committed it. Then along came Pip and requirements.txt files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where most of us are today. Pip can only manage Python packages
so much of our servers' behavior is left to Lady Luck. Puppet gives us
the power to efficiently and confidently specify everything our program
needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll start at square one and the concept of resources, the basic unit
of configuration management. We'll learn the Puppet language's resource
syntax. We'll talk about obvious resource types like packages and files
plus less obvious types like shell commands, users, groups, and daemons.
We'll compose resources into larger ones, declare dependencies between
resources, and accommodate differences between OS X and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Puppet manifests can satisfy our program's dependencies on demand,
making them ideal parts of the deploy process. We'll walk through how
Puppet is used to build production environments both through tools such
as Fabric and Puppet's traditional client-server mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependency hell doesn't have to be your reality. Consistent, reliable
environments can be had with Puppet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="dependencies"></category><category term="puppet"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>