<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - IndranilGhosh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_indranilghosh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Introducing Lambda Calculus with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/introducing-lambda-calculus-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/introducing-lambda-calculus-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indranil Ghosh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be focusing on untyped lambda calculus and start by the simple definition of a function, that can be implemented with Python lambda. We will then discuss the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;abstraction&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;application&lt;/strong&gt; in lambda calculus and then move …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indranil Ghosh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/AL8WB3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be focusing on untyped lambda calculus and start by the simple definition of a function, that can be implemented with Python lambda. We will then discuss the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;abstraction&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;application&lt;/strong&gt; in lambda calculus and then move on to understand what a &lt;strong&gt;substitution&lt;/strong&gt; is and how can these be implemented in Python. We will finally study some combinators which are the basic building blocks of combinatory logic, before ending with encoding datatypes in lambda calculus and implementing the same with Python lambda. Datatypes we will be discussing are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boolean values like TRUE and FALSE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical operators like AND, OR and NOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Church Numerals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Sep  5 14:40:00 2020 at Python 2&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2020"></category><category term="IndranilGhosh"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConAU"></category><category term="PyConline"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Football (soccer) data analysis: A pedagogic introduction</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/football-soccer-data-analysis-a-pedagogic-introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Indranil Ghosh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/football-soccer-data-analysis-a-pedagogic-introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Indranil Ghosh) Nowadays data is the key to solving challenges in most fields, say astronomy, applied mathematics, health care, or even sports. Data is everywhere and it is super beneficial to leverage these data and build models for making sense out of them and telling stories. The field of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Indranil Ghosh) Nowadays data is the key to solving challenges in most fields, say astronomy, applied mathematics, health care, or even sports. Data is everywhere and it is super beneficial to leverage these data and build models for making sense out of them and telling stories. The field of sports, especially football (soccer), is enriched by data analysis that makes us understand the game better and predict outcomes. Many people want to delve deep into football (soccer) data analysis and get their hands dirty. This talk is to help them do so by pedagogically introducing them to the introductory analytical methodologies to overcome the initial barriers of the field and start working with data analyses and visualizations on football data to deduce interesting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/PJWQZQ/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/PJWQZQ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Sep 12 02:45:00 2021 at Backup Speakers&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="IndranilGhosh"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry></feed>