<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_class.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Machine Learning Techniques for Class Imbalances &amp; Adversaries</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/machine-learning-techniques-for-class-imbalances-adversaries.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brendan Herger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-09:pydata-dc-2016/machine-learning-techniques-for-class-imbalances-adversaries.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many areas of applied Machine Learning which require models optimized for rare occurrences (i.e. class imbalance), as well as users actively attempting to subvert the system (i.e. adversaries).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will guide the audience through multiple published techniques which specifically attempt to address these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Data Innovation Lab at Capital One has explored more advanced modeling techniques for class imbalance &amp;amp; adversarial actors. Our use case has allowed us to survey the many related fields which deal with these issues, and attempt many of the suggested modeling techniques. Additionally, we have introduce a few novel variations of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an introduction to the problem space, a brief overview of the modeling frameworks we've chosen to work with, a brief overview of our approaches, a discussion of lessons learned, and our proposed future work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approaches discussed will include ensemble models, deep learning, genetic algorithms, outlier detection via dimensionally reduction (PCA and neural network auto-encoders), time-decay weighting, and Synthetic Minority Over-sampling Technique (SMOTE sampling).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="class"></category><category term="learning"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Django in Depth</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--django-in-depth.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Bennett</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--django-in-depth.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django In Depth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by James Bennett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most books, tutorials and other documentation for Django take a
high-level approach to its components and APIs, and so barely scratch
the surface of the framework. In this tutorial, however, we'll take a
detailed look under the hood, covering everything from the guts of the
ORM to the innards of the template system to how the admin interface
really works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you're the newest of newbies or the most seasoned of application
developers, you'll come away with a deeper knowledge of Django, and a
plethora of new tips and tricks you can use in your own applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intended Audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning to intermediate users of the Django web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Class Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction: going beyond Django's documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the hood of the ORM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forms and validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the template system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Django processes requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding the view layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The admin interface, inside and out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Cam frezz from time to time]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="class"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category></entry></feed>