<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_bokeh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Bokeh: Using python for interactive data visualization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/bokeh-using-python-for-interactive-data-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ernesto Arbitrio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/bokeh-using-python-for-interactive-data-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is an interactive visualization library that targets modern web
browsers for presentation. Its goal is to provide elegant, concise
construction of novel graphics in the style of D3.js, and to extend this
capability with high- performance interactivity over very large or
streaming datasets. In this talk, you will learn to use Bokeh to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create simple interactive plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;annotate and styling the plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using bokeh plots in web pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;link interactive visualizations to a running python instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stream data to plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using Datashader to view and interact with large datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization is key to understanding the information contained in
data. The interactivity provide a valuable means for engineers, data
journalist, and scientist to explore their data. This talk will
introduce ( &lt;em&gt;using also some code example&lt;/em&gt; ) the audience to the basics
of using Bokeh, demonstrate different aspects of the library, and teach
how to deal with data formats ( &lt;em&gt;pandas&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;numpy&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;bokeh Column Data
Source&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge required: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;python3&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas basics&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;numpy bascis&lt;/tt&gt;,
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;data mining&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;jupyter notebook&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some visualization examples refers
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/docs/gallery.html#gallery"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="plot"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="DataVisualization"></category><category term="dataminig"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Visualization with Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-indy-2018/data-visualization-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Alexander</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-12:pydata-indy-2018/data-visualization-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to create interactive charts and graphs without writing any JavaScript. We'll use Python to generate simple interactive graphs and plots within Jupyter notebooks, and embedded in a running Django site. I'll show examples of streaming data to a Bokeh instance, and interactively intuit about a large dataset using Datashader.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Science &amp; Data Visualization in Python. How to harness power of Python for social good?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Radovan Kavicky</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python as an Open Data Science tool offers many libraries for data visualization and I will show you how to use and combine the best. I strongly believe that power of data is not only in the information &amp;amp; insight that data can provide us, Data is and can be really beautiful and can not only transform our perception but also the world that we all live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I will primarily focus on answering/offer the answer to these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why we need data science and why more and more people should be really interested in analyzing data and data visualization? (motivation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is data science and how to start doing it in Python? (introduction of procedures, tools, most popular IDE-s for Python, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tools for data analysis and data visualization Python offers? (in each stage of analysis the best libraries will be shown for the specific purpose; as for data visualization we will focus particularly on Bokeh, Seaborn, Plotly and use of Jupyter Notebook and Plotly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to 'unlock' the insight hidden in data through Python and how to use it to transform not only public administration or business, but ultimately the transformation of the whole society and economy towards the insight &amp;amp; knowledge based? (potential of data science)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Data, Open Government Partnership, Open Public Administration &amp;amp; all the advantages of Open Data Science &amp;amp; Python. Data-Driven Approach. Everywhere. Now. (the end of talk +vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="PyData"></category><category term="PyDataBLN"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="PyDataBA"></category><category term="PyDataBratislava"></category><category term="talk"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category><category term="Social Good"></category><category term="datascience"></category><category term="jupyter"></category><category term="open science"></category><category term="open data science"></category><category term="DataVisualization"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="analysis"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="data wrangling"></category><category term="jupyter notebook"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="Open Data"></category><category term="Citizen Data Science"></category></entry><entry><title>Interactive Data Visualization with HoloViews &amp; Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/interactive-data-visualization-with-holoviews-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jean-Luc Stevens</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-04:scipy-2017/interactive-data-visualization-with-holoviews-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are audio issues with this video that cannot be fixed. We recommend listening to the tutorial without headphones to minimize the buzzing sound.
Tutorial information may be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/"&gt;https://scipy2017.scipy.org/ehome/220975/493423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualization represents a major bottleneck in scientific research, engineering, data science, and data analytics. The tools in the Python scientific ecosystem make it very simple to do many of the tasks required, but building visualizations to help understand complex patterns and relationships in your data still typically involves a large amount of custom coding for every new type of plot. Writing long and detailed scripts for plotting slows down the process of exploration and reporting, while the difficulty involved means that many important observations and discoveries are missed due to inadequate visualizations. The complexity of the resulting plotting code makes it difficult to rapidly build sophisticated, interactive visualizations that can quickly reveal the underlying structure of the data, and once such complex plotting scripts have been created they can be a major impediment to future understanding, reproduction, and modification of the research process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will learn how to approach the problem of interactive visualization declaratively. Using the HoloViews library, you can annotate your data and store it in general-purpose containers that will be instantly visualizable. The declarative objects in HoloViews wrap your data to make it incredibly easy to visualize how different sets of data relate to each other, using subfigures, animations, interactive widgets and custom interactions. This flexibility has made HoloViews the chosen future replacement for the high-level Bokeh Charts API and works particularly well with IPython/Jupyter notebooks, where you can immediately see the output from selecting, combining, slicing, or sampling these objects. Each of these operations generates a different type of visualization, that can be flexibly extended even to complex dashboards deployed using the Bokeh server or Jupyter dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core design principle of HoloViews is to make it simple to create complex plot layouts and interactivity by applying compositional operations to a small number of elements and containers. Since HoloViews separates the declaration of the data from the precise visual details of the plotting code, the same HoloViews objects can be rendered using matplotlib for publication-quality plots, or bokeh for interactive use. Overall, this means the user can focus on &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; to plot before worrying about &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; exactly it should be displayed, providing a huge boost in productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="HoloViews"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Networks meet Finance in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/networks-meet-finance-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Vaz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/networks-meet-finance-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will talk about network models in finance, and walk through real data and very visual examples using the pydata toolset - pandas, bokeh, pandas, networkx, ipywidgets. Special focus will be given to correlation networks, with applications to market characterization and portfolio risk management (as done in Pozzi 2013) using the latest available market data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of the 2008 Lehman and the subsequent European debt crisis, it became clear that both financial industry and regulators had underestimated the degree of interconnectedness and interdependency across financial assets and institutions. This type of information is especially well represented by network models, which had first gained popularity in computer science, biology and social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of network models in finance is already providing insight into the structure of the financial world and the economy. Network models are proving to be useful tools for providing early-warning signals of systemic risk (e.g. Squartini 2013), measuring liquidity and concentration risk, identifying sectors from time-series correlations (e.g. Fenn 2011) as well as insights into finding diversified baskets of assets in the classical investment framework (e.g. Pozzi 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will provide an overview of some of the aforementioned work, and walk through (real data) examples using the pydata toolset. Special focus will be given to the study of correlation networks, with applications to portfolio risk management as in (Pozzi 2013) using the latest available market data. The examples make heavy use of pandas, bokeh, pandas, networkx, ipywidgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pandas"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="networkx"></category><category term="ipywidgets"></category></entry><entry><title>¡Eureka! (Python y ciencia)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyday-galicia-2016/eureka-python-y-ciencia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Sánchez de León Peque</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pyday-galicia-2016/eureka-python-y-ciencia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En esta charla se plantea una pregunta de física básica que se resolverá científicamente con ingenio, mátemáticas y python, aprovechando para (de una manera amena) ver librerías habituales en el entorno científico como sympy, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, bokeh, numba, pandas y sklearn.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyday"></category><category term="sympy"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="scipy"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="numba"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to large scale data analytics and interactive visualization</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2014/introduction-to-large-scale-data-analytics-and-interactive-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christine Doig</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-06:pycon-es-2014/introduction-to-large-scale-data-analytics-and-interactive-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NumPy, Pandas y Matplotlib, entre otros, han revolucionado el procesamiento, manipulación y visualización de datos en Python. ¿Pero, qué hacemos cuando nuestro dataset es demasiado grande para caber en la memoria de nuestro ordenador? ¿Usar una base de datos como Postgres o MongoDB, almacenar en disco con PyTables o BColz, o usar sistemas distribuidos como Hadoop o Spark?Cada una de estas opciones tiene sus ventajas e inconvenientes. Aprender cada una de estas herramientas consume tiempo que podría estar empleándose en el análisis de los datos en sí. La librería Blaze ofrece una interfaz común para una variedad de backends y abstracciones para el procesamiento y la migración de datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por otro lado, ¿cómo visualizamos nuestro dataset cuando tenemos más individuos que píxeles tiene nuestra pantalla? Bokeh es una librería para la visualización interactiva de datos en el navegador al estilo de D3.js en Python, que incluye la funcionalidad de Abstract Rendering para estos casos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La charla consistirá en una introducción al análisis y visualización de large datasets, cómo las librerías Blaze and Bokeh nos pueden facilitar el trabajo y un ejemplo práctico con un dataset de tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Blaze"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Taller - Introducción a visualizaciones interactivas con Bokeh</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/taller-introduccion-a-visualizaciones-interactivas-con-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Vidal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/taller-introduccion-a-visualizaciones-interactivas-con-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt; ) es una librería de visualización de datos con una interfaz concisa y elegante que permite la construcción de gráficos preparados para la web y con interactividad out-of-the-box y sencilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diseña avanzados dashboards en Python para un navegador web sin escribir ni una línea de código de Javascript (pero si quieres puedes ;P)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactividad cliente-side, cliente-servidor, streaming, big data... Simplemente Bokeh! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="workshop"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Bokeh for Data Storytelling</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2015/bokeh-for-data-storytelling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-05:euroscipy-2015/bokeh-for-data-storytelling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bokeh visualization library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source project. This talk will describe Bokeh and show how it can enable domain experts to easily create novel and powerful visualizations that extract insight from remote, possibly large data sets, to be published to the web for others to explore and interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Bokeh: Interactive Visualizations in the Browser</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a Python visualization library for large datasets that natively
uses the latest web technologies. Its goal is to provide concise
construction of novel graphics, while delivering high-performance
interactivity over large data to thin clients. This talk will cover the
motivation and architecture behind Bokeh, demonstrate interesting uses
and capability, and discuss future plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With support from the DARPA XDATA Initiative, and contributions from
community members, the Bokeh visualization library
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source
project with heavy interest and following on GitHub
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ContinuumIO/bokeh"&gt;https://github.com/ContinuumIO/bokeh&lt;/a&gt;). The principal goals of Bokeh are
to provide capability to developers and domain experts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily create novel and powerful visualizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that extract insight from remote, possibly large data sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published to the web for others to explore and interact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe how the architecture of Bokeh enables these
goals, and demonstrate how it can be leveraged by anyone using python
for analysis to visualize and present their work. We will talk about
current development and future plans, including a brief discussion of
Joseph Cottam's exciting academic work on abstract rendering for large
data sets that is going into Bokeh
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/JosephCottam/AbstractRendering"&gt;https://github.com/JosephCottam/AbstractRendering&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="vis"></category></entry></feed>