<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_deep-learning-artificial-intelligence.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Build text classification models ( CBOW and Skip-gram) with FastText in python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/build-text-classification-models-cbow-and-skip-gram-with-fasttext-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kajal Puri</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/build-text-classification-models-cbow-and-skip-gram-with-fasttext-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;FastText has been open-sourced by Facebook in 2016 and with its release,
it became the fastest and most accurate library in Python for text
classification and word representation. It is to be seen as a substitute
for gensim package's word2vec. It includes the implementation of two
extremely important methodologies in NLP i.e Continuous Bag of Words and
Skip-gram model. Fasttext performs exceptionally well with supervised as
well as unsupervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will be divided in following four segments :&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>From exploration to deployment - combining PyTorch and TensorFlow for Deep Learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/from-exploration-to-deployment-combining-pytorch-and-tensorflow-for-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marcel Kurovski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/from-exploration-to-deployment-combining-pytorch-and-tensorflow-for-deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the many deep learning frameworks out in the wild few have
achieved widespread adoption. Two of them are TensorFlow and PyTorch.
Where PyTorch relies on a dynamic computation graph TensorFlow goes for
a static graph. Where TensorFlow shows greater adoption and additional
useful extensions with TensorFlow Serving and TensorBoard, Pytorch
proves useful trough its easy and more pythonic API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data scientists are confronted with explorative challenges, but also
need to be aware of model deployment and production. Do we need to
single out frameworks until we end up with the only one or is there a
case for joint usage of two deep learning frameworks? Can we leverage
the strengths of the frameworks for different tasks along the path from
exploration to production?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I want to present a case combining the benefits of PyTorch
and TensorFlow using the first for explorative and latter for deployment
tasks. Therefore, I will choose a common deep learning challenge and
discuss the strengths and weaknesses of both frameworks along a demo
that brings a model from development into production.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Satellite data is for everyone: insights into modern remote sensing research with open data and Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/satellite-data-is-for-everyone-insights-into-modern-remote-sensing-research-with-open-data-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felix M. Riese</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/satellite-data-is-for-everyone-insights-into-modern-remote-sensing-research-with-open-data-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The largest earth observation programme Copernicus
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://copernicus.eu"&gt;http://copernicus.eu&lt;/a&gt;) makes it possible to perform terrestrial
observations providing data for all kinds of purposes. One important
objective is to monitor the land-use and land-cover changes with the
Sentinel-2 satellite mission. These satellites measure the sun
reflectance on the earth surface with multispectral cameras (13 channels
between 440 nm to 2190 nm). Machine learning techniques like
convolutional neural networks (CNN) are able to learn the link between
the satellite image (spectrum) and the ground truth (land use class). In
this talk, we give an overview about the state-of-the-art land-use
classification with CNNs based on an open dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EuroSAT benchmark dataset (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://madm.dfki.de/downloads"&gt;http://madm.dfki.de/downloads&lt;/a&gt;) is freely
provided by German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI).
It consists of 27.000 image patches for ten different land use/cover
classes, e.g. industrial and residential areas, different crop and
vegetation types and forests. All samples have 64 by 64 pixel dimension
and include either only the RGB images or all 13 bands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use different out-of-box CNNs for the Keras deep learning
library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://keras.io/"&gt;https://keras.io/&lt;/a&gt;). All networks are either included in Keras
itself or are available from Github repositories. We will show the
process of transfer learning for the RGB datasets. Furthermore, the
minimal changes required to apply commonly used CNNs to multispectral
data are demonstrated. Thus, the interested audience will be able to
perform their own classification of remote sensing data within a very
short time. Results of different network structures are visually
compared. Especially the differences of transfer learning and learning
from scratch are demonstrated. This also includes the amount of
necessary training epochs, progress of training and validation error and
visual comparison of the results of the trained networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we give a quick overview about the current research topics
including recurrent neural networks for spatio-temporal land-use
classification and further applications of multi- and hyperspectral
data, e.g. for the estimation of water parameters and soil
characteristics. Additionally, we provide links to the code and dataset
used in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Computer Vision"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Science"></category></entry><entry><title>How to teach space invaders to your computer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/how-to-teach-space-invaders-to-your-computer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Wölfle</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/how-to-teach-space-invaders-to-your-computer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First things first: playing good old Atari games might be cool but why
should I write a program for doing it? Well teaching a computer to play
a game means teaching it to develop strategies and use foresight
planning to solve a certain problem. The tools you gather while solving
i.e. space invaders are the same you may use to solve any problem which
requires a sequential set of decisions in order to find an optimal
solution to some problem, like i.e. controlling a robot that collects
garbage. Furthermore, there is a lot of scientific research on
reinforcement learning that focuses on solving Atari games which makes
it a good starting point, as large amounts of publications and open
source code already exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to expect from this talk? At first there will be a very short
introduction to reinforcement learning theory, just the very basics,
common applications and some references for further reading. Next points
are, how to run Atari games from inside python for a learning task (with
OpenAI's gym), and where to find an algorithm for the actual learning
problem. Finally it will be shown how to build it all together in a
jupyter notebook and let the algorithm play the game. Et voilà that's
your computer beating you in space invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Science"></category></entry><entry><title>Satellite Image Segmentation Photovoltaic Potential Estimation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/satellite-image-segmentation-photovoltaic-potential-estimation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johannes Oos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/satellite-image-segmentation-photovoltaic-potential-estimation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The used technologies are python based and include: MongoDB tensorflow
Flask google.cloud python API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dataset of labelled satellite images is created. Several networks are
trained and tested on this dataset. The network is deployed on a
production server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the classification/segmentaion are used to feed python
based photovotlaic simulation libaries. The output is displayed and the
results (the potential) evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Computer Vision"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Science"></category></entry><entry><title>Experiences from applying Convolutional Neural Networks for classifying 2D sensor data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/experiences-from-applying-convolutional-neural-networks-for-classifying-2d-sensor-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Matthias Peussner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/experiences-from-applying-convolutional-neural-networks-for-classifying-2d-sensor-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When being the first in your company to apply a deep learning algorithm
on your data you often have to overcome several obstacles. One challenge
is to understand your data and to form a training and test dataset.
Another one is to get your algorithms and its performance accepted and
integrated in your existing processing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convolutional Neural Networks have become a standard tool in processing
image data. They have shown to reach human-level classification
performance on some object recognition tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will present my experiences in getting started using a
convolutional neural network for classification of 2D sensor data. I
will point out the importance of understanding your data and give hints
of how to select your train and test datasets according to the
requirements. Furthermore, I will show how to get a feature extractor
out of the classifier and how to visualize it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Computer Vision"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Germany's next topic model</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/germanys-next-topic-model.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Mayer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/germanys-next-topic-model.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identifying topic models for user generated content like hotel reviews
turns out to be difficult with the standard approach of LDA (Latent
Dirichlet Allocation; Blei et al., 2003). Hotel review texts usually
don't differ as much in the topics that are covered as is typical with
other genres such as Wikipedia or newsgroup articles where there is
commonly only a very small set of topics present in each document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, we developed our own approach to topic modeling that is
especially tailored to non-edited texts like hotel reviews. The approach
can be divided into three major steps. First, using the concept of
second-order cooccurrences we define a contextual similarity score that
enables us to identify words that are similar with respect to certain
topics. This score allows us to build up a topic network where nodes are
words and edges the contextual similarity between the words. With the
help of algorithms from graph theory, like the Infomap algorithm
(Rosvall and Bergstrom, 2008), we are able to detect clusters of highly
connected words that can be identified as topics in our review texts. In
a further step, we use these clusters and the respective words to get a
topic similarity score for each word in the network. In other words, we
transform a hard clustering of words into topics into a probability
score of how likely a certain word belongs to a given topic/cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is structured as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References: David M. Blei, Andrew Y. Ng, Michael I. Jordan: Latent
dirichlet allocation. In: Journal of Machine Learning Research, Jg. 3
(2003), S. 993–1022, ISSN 1532-4435 M. Rosvall and C. T. Bergstrom, Maps
of information flow reveal community structure in complex networks, PNAS
105, 1118 (2008) &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0706851105"&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0706851105&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.0609"&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.0609&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Networks"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Visualisation"></category></entry><entry><title>reticulate: R interface to Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/reticulate-r-interface-to-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jens Bruno Wittek</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/reticulate-r-interface-to-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and R are the preferred languages for data science. In 2018,
RStudio introduced its package reticulate and clearly demonstrates that
it favours to join forces. Both languages have strengths and weaknesses.
Tools to combine the strengths will enable easier collaboration in
projects and more possibilities to succeed. Using Python from R gives R
users wider access to functions and makes it easier for Python beginners
to just run scripts and being able to collaborate in Python projects.
The talk will show the possibilities of reticulate: The main part starts
with demonstrating the Python interpreter within R. It will show how to
source Python scripts as well as install and import modules. Then it
will deal with the most important types of Python objects, how they are
represented in R and how to further manipulate them. Thereby, a special
focus is on using Python for data science. In addition, it will be
presented how Conda environments can be created and used from R. A
further application will be the creation of reports with Markdown and
LaTeX where R and Python can be used within one document and share
objects. A last topic is about showing the possibilities for easier
development in RStudio (help regarding Python functions, auto
completion).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="NLP"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="Visualisation"></category></entry></feed>