<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_data-scientist.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Addressing the Scarcity of Data Scientist</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/addressing-the-scarcity-of-data-scientist.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joe Gartner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/addressing-the-scarcity-of-data-scientist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many individuals who have the job title data scientist have Ph.D.s in quantitative research such as Physics, Computer Science, and Statistics, however, the demand for analytic talent is much larger than industries ability to keep up. This talk addresses the role of immersive programs in filling the skills gap.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="Data Science"></category></entry><entry><title>Predicting Human Activity using Time Series Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/predicting-human-activity-using-time-series-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Akul Mehra</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/predicting-human-activity-using-time-series-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time series is referred to as sequence of data points measured over
successive intervals of time. Time series analysis is performed to
extract meaningful statistics and characteristics of the data. For
example, this analysis can be used to predict future based on the past
events. Such use cases of this analysis are stock market prediction,
weather prediction and web traffic prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll be understanding the basics and how to perform time
series analysis and machine learning for a given dataset. For this talk,
we’ll be using the UCI Human Activity Recognition (HAR) Data Set to
classify a given activity performed by the human as one of the following
activities: Walking, Sitting, Standing or Laying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk would be intermediate level and basics of Python and Pandas are
required. Understanding of Machine Learning algorithms and signal
processing would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1576"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1576&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="TimeSeriesAnalysis"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="machine-language"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="data-exploration"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="MachineLearning"></category><category term="TimeSeries"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="DataEngineering"></category></entry><entry><title>Practical Machine Learning with Python and scikit-learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/practical-machine-learning-with-python-and-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Grandi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/practical-machine-learning-with-python-and-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A tutorial for intermediate Python developers with none or little
knowledge about Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After presenting an existing dataset and giving a bit of context about
the problem, I will show step by step how to analyse it, train a
supervised classification model, optimise it and make predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the tutorial we will make use of the following libraries and
tools: pandas, jupyter, matplotlib, numpy, scikit-learn, scipy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if it won’t be possible to follow each singular attendee, it’s
strongly suggested to have a laptop ready with Python 3 installed and a
virtual environment properly configured and ready to be used. In this
way attendees will have the possibility to try the shown code and
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;domenica 22 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category></entry><entry><title>How to make your model happy again</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/how-to-make-your-model-happy-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessia Marcolini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/how-to-make-your-model-happy-again.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays ‘build and run’ a predictive model is a quite easy task, thanks
to frameworks that simplify things and set good defaults for you (i.e.
Keras).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do you &lt;em&gt;effectively&lt;/em&gt; train a model, in order to gain better
performance or to get your results faster? Do you feel frustrated every
time you need to set and then tune the network’s hyperparameters, too?
Don’t worry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will share some practical tips&amp;amp;tricks (such as Model
Ensembling and learning rate schedulers) and relative examples, derived
from my personal experience or from literature, with the aim to improve
neural networks capabilities and to get the convergence faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at data scientists or everyone passionate about this
topic who wants to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gently inspired by Practical Deep Learning for Coders Part 1 v2 of
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fast.ai"&gt;fast.ai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="neural network"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling your Data infrastructure</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/scaling-your-data-infrastructure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Barra</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/scaling-your-data-infrastructure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This talk aims to answer a few questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you do when you need to move your model from your laptop to
production?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;big data == I need to use JVM&lt;/tt&gt; the right assumption?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I put my jupyter notebook in production?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you apply the best software engineering practices (testing and
ci for example) inside your data science process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you “decouple” your data scientists, developers and devops
teams?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you guarantee the reproducibility of your models?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you scale your training process when does not fit in memory
anymore?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you serve your models and provide an easy rollback system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Data Science workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scaling is not just a matter of the size of your Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scaling when the size of your Data matters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDS, Dockerized Data Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassiny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll share my experience highlighting some of the challenges I faced and
the solutions I came up to answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this presentation I will mention libraries like jupyter, atom,
scikit- learn, dask, ray, parquet, arrow and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principles and best practices I will share are something that you
can apply, more or less easily, if you are running or in the process to
run a production system based on the Python stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on (my) best practices to run the Python Data stack
together and I will also talk about Cassiny, an open source project I
started, that aims to simplify your life if you want to use a completely
Python based solution in your data science workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 20 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="CloudComputing"></category><category term="pydata"></category><category term="#lessonslearned"></category><category term="Big-Data"></category><category term="S3"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="#amicodialessia"></category><category term="java"></category><category term="docker"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>E.T. chiama Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/et-chiama-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Davide Corio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/et-chiama-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All’osservatorio astronomico della Val Pellice in provincia di Torino,
le attività amministrative, didattiche, divulgative e scientifiche non
mancano di certo. L’osservatorio, gestito dall’&lt;a class="reference external" href="http:/osservatoriourania.it"&gt;Associazione Astrofili
Urania&lt;/a&gt;, dispone di diversi telescopi
ottici, di un planetario, di una biblioteca, di una sala
corsi/conferenze e di un radio telescopio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python è spesso un filo conduttore nel mondo scientifico e non solo, e a
prova di questo fatto vogliamo mostrarvi come lo usiamo noi
all’osservatorio. Mostreremo come Python viene usato per l’elaborazione
dei dati provenienti dal radio telescopio, che scruta il cielo alla
ricerca di segnali provenienti da esopianeti ed inviati potenzialmente
da altre forme di vita intelligente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altri cenni riguarderanno l’utilizzo di software basati su Python (come
Odoo) per la gestione di associazioni come la nostra.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pydata"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="data-logging"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="Odoo"></category><category term="astronomy"></category></entry><entry><title>Jupyter: if you don't use it yet you're doing wrong</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/jupyter-if-you-dont-use-it-yet-youre-doing-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Barra</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/jupyter-if-you-dont-use-it-yet-youre-doing-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard about Jupyter Notebook ? It’s like Python REPL on
steroids !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce the Jupyter project, the libraries behind
this project and how you can use Jupyter Notebook for a lot of
activities like fast prototyping, data science, education and so on !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be an introduction, Beginners are welcome !&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="iPython"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning con Python: previsione in real-time della richiesta di energia elettrica</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-previsione-in-real-time-della-richiesta-di-energia-elettrica.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felice Tuosto</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/machine-learning-con-python-previsione-in-real-time-della-richiesta-di-energia-elettrica.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nel talk si parlerà di come attraverso il linguaggio Python sia
possibile risolvere un problema reale e complesso relativamente alla
trasmissione di energia elettrica. Verrà spiegato il progetto
&lt;strong&gt;RealtimeLoadForecast&lt;/strong&gt; che è stato sviluppato per un importante TSO
(Transmission System Operator). Si tratta di sistema predittivo che
permette di fornire in tempo reale ogni 15 minuti ed entro 5 minuti, le
previsioni delle serie storiche dei consumi di energia elettrica
relativi a circa 500 nodi elettrici.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si parlerà dei passi che occorre seguire per ottenere da un semplice
prototipo, un sistema &lt;em&gt;ingegnerizzato&lt;/em&gt; che lavori in tempo reale e di
come sono state utilizzate le librerie di Python per l’acquisizione,
manipolazione e processamento dei dati elettrici ed ambientali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saranno descritte alcune tecniche algoritmiche e di Machine Learning per
ottenere dei modelli predittivi capaci di fornire previsioni accurate ma
con tempi di risposta sfidanti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrà mostrato un &lt;em&gt;esempio concreto&lt;/em&gt; di implementazione di un algoritmo
predittivo basato sulla libreria Deep Learning &lt;strong&gt;Keras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per la comprensione del talk non sono necessari particolari requisiti se
non una conoscenza di base di programmazione in Python e di Machine
Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Forecasting"></category><category term="Genetic Algorithms"></category><category term="Keras"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="programming-paradigms"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="threading"></category><category term="realtime"></category><category term="Data-Scientist"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="mysql"></category><category term="signal-processing"></category><category term="LoadForecasting"></category><category term="cassandra"></category></entry></feed>