<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_chatbot.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Rasa: open source conversational AI to build next generation chatbots</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/rasa-open-source-conversational-ai-to-build-next-generation-chatbots.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Joey Faulkner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/rasa-open-source-conversational-ai-to-build-next-generation-chatbots.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joey Faulkner&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;JoeyMFaulkner)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD student in machine learning/astronomy, and an AI researcher at Rasa. We make open source libraries for conversational AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon you will primarily communicate with your computer through conversation. At Rasa, we believe that this revolution in user experience should be available to everyone. In this spirit we have developed open source tools that use machine learning to make chatbots in a developer-friendly interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revolution-in-waiting for user experience is conversational AI, and this revolution should be available to everyone. The ability to communicate with your computer via a fulfilling and useful conversation will change the way we approach user interaction. Recent advances in machine learning have made this goal not only possible to reach, but possible to bring to the developer community at large. At Rasa we have developed a set of open-source Python libraries which can comprehend natural language and handle complex, interesting conversations. We utilise deep learning to bypass existing rigid conversational norms (state machines, if/else statements, etc.) and allow developers to make awesome bots simply by talking to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="open source"></category><category term="chatbot"></category><category term="natural language"></category><category term="ai"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Messenger chat with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/messenger-chat-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Akos Hochrein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/messenger-chat-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatbots are getting more and more in mainstream product development. In this talk, I would like to show you how to setup a one on the Facebook Messenger platform using Python and Heroku, so you can get started right away!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="chatbot"></category></entry><entry><title>DeepCare Chatbot - Generating answers to customers using Deep Learning and NLP</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-barcelona-2017/deepcare-chatbot-generating-answers-to-customers-using-deep-learning-and-nlp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-20T15:45:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-20T15:45:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Pascal van Kooten</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-20:pydata-barcelona-2017/deepcare-chatbot-generating-answers-to-customers-using-deep-learning-and-nlp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DeepCare chatbot is capable of learning to answer customer questions. Using a hybrid approach of NLP and Deep Learning, it tries to combat logical fallacies that occur in pure deep learning bots, while still coming up with unique answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, it uses a sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) long-short-term-memory LSTM deep learning model to capture intricacies in questions. As organisations cannot afford a bot making logical mistakes, verification through NLP is used. This two-step model prevents the downside of &amp;quot;no control&amp;quot; on deep learning, as well as the too static nature of classical rule based NLP models, and thus enables potentially higher quality answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A live demo will be available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://deepcare.online"&gt;http://deepcare.online&lt;/a&gt; on the day of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="chatbot"></category><category term="nlp"></category><category term="deep learning"></category></entry><entry><title>There's Hope for Chatbots</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/theres-hope-for-chatbots.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hobson Lane</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/theres-hope-for-chatbots.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Hobson Lane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermediate python developers will learn how to build a chatbot engine that identifies bullying in chatrooms. Studies show that most free-for-all social networks (Twitter, Facebook, Twitch, Slack) unintentionally make us less kind and supportive. But there's Hope. At Hopester we've built an open source chatbot engine with an open API called Hope. We'll show you how to add Hope to your chat channels or build your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="chatbot"></category></entry><entry><title>"It's about time to take your medication!" or how to write a friendly reminder bot ;-)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/its-about-time-to-take-your-medication-or-how-to-write-a-friendly-reminder-bot-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Florian Wilhelm</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-05:europython-2015/its-about-time-to-take-your-medication-or-how-to-write-a-friendly-reminder-bot-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Florian Wilhelm - &amp;quot;It's about time to take your medication!&amp;quot; or how to write a friendly reminder bot ;-)
[EuroPython 2015]
[24 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author  shows how to use the [SleekXMPP][1] library in order to
write a small chatbot that connects to Google Hangouts and reminds you
or someone else to take medication for instance.  The secure and
recommended OAuth2  protocol is used to authorize the bot application
in the [Google Developers Console][2]  in order to access the Google+
Hangouts API. The author will elaborate then on how to use an event-
driven library to write a bot that sends scheduled messages, waits for
a proper reply and repeats the question if need be. Thereby, a primer
on event-driven architectures will be given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sleekxmpp.readthedocs.org/"&gt;http://sleekxmpp.readthedocs.org/&lt;/a&gt;
[2]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://console.developers.google.com/"&gt;https://console.developers.google.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="SleekXMPP"></category><category term="chatbot"></category></entry></feed>