<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vim your Python, Python your Vim</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/vim-your-python-python-your-vim.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you use to write source code, docs, books or e-mails? Single
brain, single pair of hands, single keyboard, but a different keyboard
layout for each language and a different text editor for each purpose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you use an IDE to work on Python code, then switch to an e-mail
client to write a message, then open a different editor to work on the
documentation and finally ssh to a remote server to edit a configuration
file? Do you switch languages frequently or are your colleagues named
Müller, François, Muñoz or even Šedivý?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you how I am happily typing in several languages on a single
standard US keyboard layout and why my CapsLock became so useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you how I use a single editor on all my machines to produce
all sorts of text, especially Python code with a few useful plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you my own plugin written in Python to hack my e-mails far
beyond imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 20 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miroslav Šedivý</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/vim-your-python-python-your-vim.html</guid><category>neovim</category><category>vim</category><category>editor</category><category>keyboard</category><category>internationalization</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>ZimboPy: Empowering Zimbabwean Girls As Change Makers</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZimboPy is an organic, on-the-ground effort by a local non-profit
organization and Python developers in the Harare software development
community to advance the cause of women in technology in Zimbabwe. The
program operates in community centers, universities, high schools and
tech hubs to make programming accessible to girls regardless of their
socio-economic status. Upon initially joining a ZimboPy club, many of
the girls would have never used a computer before, let alone code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Zimbabwe, only 17% of computer science undergraduate majors are
women, and in the developing world, women make up less than 20% of the
information and technology workforce. ZimboPy exists to empower
Zimbabwean girls with the skills and confidence necessary to not only
enter the local tech industry, but to lead it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to learning to code, ZimboPy club members also join a global
network of women in technology that are working to tackle social
challenges through human-centered design and computer science. ZimboPy’s
mentorship program invites experienced women developers, mainly from the
United States and Europe, to help Zimbabwean girls address local
problems which can be solved with technology, such as clean water and
e-commerce solutions for small shops in towns and villages. Mentors will
travel to Zimbabwe and work with girls as they develop a plan for their
applications and pair-program with them, answering questions and
providing feedback along the way. To ensure that the girls are
successful, mentors will continue to work with their groups even after
leaving the country through weekly video conferences and email feedback.
Overall, ZimboPy looks forward to changing Zimbabwe’s future through
creativity, collaboration and the power of Python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marlene Mhangami</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/zimbopy-empowering-zimbabwean-girls-as-change-makers.html</guid><category>internationalization</category><category>School</category><category>Learning</category><category>problem solving</category></item><item><title>A Gringo's Guide to Internationalization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2012/a-gringos-guide-to-internationalization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming from a speaker who escaped a notion to &amp;quot;why would we need to
translate?&amp;quot; this talk aims to show what actually goes into translating a
website or app using Django's Internationalization tools. Covered will
be an overview of batteries included, best practices and anti-patterns
in using them, and some third party tools to help make your life
escaping the myth of a Lingua Franca easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's often a bubble in the English-speaking programming world that
the entire internet runs on English. Our Top-level domains are shortened
english words. Our programming languages--Python in particular--try to
emulate English words and grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firmly in place in this world for many years, my first attempt to
translate a pre-existing site came with a high sticker shock of nuanced
difficulty. This talk covers all the lessons I learned in taking a
fully-fleshed web app with no translation (and a programmer with no
translation experience) to being completely translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talk-overview"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Talk Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Translation&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of gettext&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief history of a translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add gettext calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;django-admin.py&lt;/span&gt; makemessages&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship po file to translation service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive file back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gettext vs gettext_lazy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batteries Included&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gettext Python calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Middleware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;template tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trans vs. blocktrans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-patterns of the battery included use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heavy whitespace in blocktrans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monster-sized translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best laid plans of mice and men...&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems that get in the way of A history of a translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realize half the site is still untranslated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit out the translations you already had translated to avoid
re-curring costs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have the product adjust so two words change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realize common text that's in the database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fin?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patterns and tools to help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;poxx.py&lt;/tt&gt; and the idea of a 'canonical' po file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;dbgettext&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wholly-translated template files (translate_include,
trans_render)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Translation Technique&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While undocumented, translation backend is pretty darn flexible
and the source code is a treasure trove to make 'impossible' use
cases not too bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of how the translation service works behind the scenes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;_translation&lt;/tt&gt; thread local&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merged translations (root-&amp;gt;app-&amp;gt;default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sessions vs. Accept-Language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Middleware and Context processors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example of advanced translation code: Multi-tenancy translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translating some sites, not translating others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translating Site A one way, Site B another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using an English translation for duct-tape and profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Django's i18n sucks.&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the vein of the &amp;quot;Django Sucks&amp;quot; Key note. It doesn't really, but
it could use some changes--from minor to major.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why .po Files are archaic and limited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What we can do to improve for 1.5 and beyond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Burch</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-04:djangocon-us-2012/a-gringos-guide-to-internationalization.html</guid><category>django</category><category>internationalization</category></item><item><title>JSON data + RML template = PDF report</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/json-data-rml-template-pdf-report.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Stefano Cotta Ramusino - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main problem with reports generated in Python is how to separate the
content from the style using ReportLab library, because all informations
should be saved in a single source file that, by example, is impossible
to understand for your graphic designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the solution: just modularizes all components you need and identify
simple container formats for your data input (JSON) and document
template (ReportLab RML).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with the power of Genshi and XInclude we will create dynamic
templates that include specific snippets (e.g., to generate on the fly a
decent graph with matplotlib or cairoplot to fill some lacks of
ReportLab) and we will detach the stylesheet from the template
structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at the end you can also have the internationalization service in the
PDF report generation!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stefano Cotta Ramusino</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/json-data-rml-template-pdf-report.html</guid><category>internationalization</category><category>json</category><category>matplotlib</category></item><item><title>Internationalizing your Django project (#74)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--internationalizing-your-django-projec.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internationalizing your Django project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Matt Croydon (Mediaphormedia)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internationalizing your Django application isn't as hard as it sounds.
This session introduces the topic of internationalization and walks
through what it takes to use Django's internationalization tools,
including how to mark models, views, and templates for translation and
how to enable internationalization in your application. We will also
step through localizing your application in a new language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matt Croydon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--internationalizing-your-django-projec.html</guid><category>i18n</category><category>internationalization</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category></item></channel></rss>