<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_beeware.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Build Native Mobile Apps with Python and BeeWare</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/python-frederick/build-native-mobile-apps-with-python-and-beeware.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bob Marchese</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-11:python-frederick/build-native-mobile-apps-with-python-and-beeware.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the October 2018 Python Frederick event, Bob showed the group how we can build native mobile applications that are written completely in Python using the BeeWare suite of tools&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="beeware"></category><category term="mobile"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a cross-platform native app with BeeWare</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/building-a-cross-platform-native-app-with-beeware.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Russell Keith-Magee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/building-a-cross-platform-native-app-with-beeware.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to write a GUI application you can run on your laptop? What about an app that you can run on your phone? Historically, these have been difficult to achieve with Python, and impossible to achieve without learning a different API for each platform. But no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeeWare is a collection of tools and libraries that allows you to build cross-platform native GUI applications in pure Python, targeting desktop, mobile and web platforms. In this talk, you'll be introduced to the BeeWare suite of tools and libraries, and see how you can use them to develop, from scratch, a GUI ChatBot application that can be deployed as a standalone desktop application, a mobile phone application, and a single page webapp - without making any changes to the application's codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="beeware"></category><category term="cross-platform"></category><category term="gui"></category></entry></feed>