<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_windows.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building Data-Driven Client Relationship Management in Banking with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/building-data-driven-client-relationship-management-in-banking-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Hughes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/building-data-driven-client-relationship-management-in-banking-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a case study that documents how a small data science team in a
big bank took on the challenge to transform a fragmented sales process
into a data-driven one using Python and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk outlines the various ways Python has been instrumental in
delivering a production solution that serves advisers and relationship
manager on a continuous basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The Challenge&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- A bank has many clients with diverse needs and cost pressures mean
fewer advisers resulting in reduced client coverage.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Multiple sales channels and mixed service levels meant sales
processes were uncoordinated and driven by heuristics and often very
subjective.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- And... Excel sheets everywhere!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Solution&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Go data-driven!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Learn from clients and understand product usage&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Empower and inform advisers and call centre agents&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Build a front-to-back sales process (no more Excels!)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How? With Python!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The Python Bits&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Scikit learn machine learning pipelines that implement two distinct
approaches to product affinity in banking and wealth management&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- SQL Alchemy based API for data engineering and rapid prototyping of
analytics&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Pandas and Jupyter for development and collaboration&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Luigi pipeline for daily processing of millions of transactions and
engineering features&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Extracting features from text with NLP (Spacy)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Delivering machine learning interpretability in production, e.g.
with Random Forests and treeinterpreter&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- A Python module that we built with all the reusable bits: building
training and prediction datasets, developing pipelines, generating
monitoring data and enabling explainability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Business Cases"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category><category term="Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)"></category><category term="Windows"></category></entry><entry><title>How to ship a Python app to a hundred million desktops</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-ship-a-python-app-to-a-hundred-million-desktops.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Max Bélanger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/how-to-ship-a-python-app-to-a-hundred-million-desktops.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is widely used to write scripts and tools, but did you know that
it can also be used to build client-side end-user applications? Crossing
the gap from script to app can be challenging: Join us to learn how to
write modern, high quality desktop apps in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Dropbox, we’ve been fans of Python from the very beginning: we’ll
take you on a tour of our app for Windows/macOS/Linux and share our
“lessons learned” from over 10 years of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll share best practices and techniques for shipping Python code to
hundreds of millions of devices: discover how to maximize security,
improve performance and guarantee stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore the key choices we made and why: learn how we migrated to
Python 3 by simultaneously shipping both versions, or how we use HTML to
power our GUI (a la Electron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll reveal our favorite tools and libraries: learn how we scaled from
a few engineers to over 100 and added support for other programming
languages (like Rust).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The goal of this talk is to share our learnings from using Python on
Windows, macOS and Linux to encourage the use of Python when building
Desktop apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- We also want to recognize the third-party libraries we’ve used (and
their authors) to raise their profile with the overall community.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- We hope this will inspire attendees to write more desktop Python
code, and raise awareness for this use case with the community as a
whole.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We intend to speak to any Python developer/engineer or enthusiast who
makes use of Python in a Desktop environment (or wants to), whether
it’s to make scripts, tools or apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We do not expect knowledge of any specific third-party Python
libraries; in fact, we hope to draw attention to and recognize many
libraries we’ve found useful.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Cross-Platform-Development"></category><category term="Mac OS X"></category><category term="Windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Basta problemi con tensorflow usando Docker &amp; Nvidia Docker</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/basta-problemi-con-tensorflow-usando-docker-nvidia-docker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicola Landro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/basta-problemi-con-tensorflow-usando-docker-nvidia-docker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Di sicuro vi sarà capitato che condividendo o effettuando un progetto
tensorflow questo non funzioni correttamente. Soprattutto non riesco a
far scalare la mia app perchè non ho abbastanza macchine con GPU e
eseguire lo scale su macchine con solo CPU è costoso per poi ottenere
scarsi benefici. La soluzione è utilizzare Docker e Nvidia Docker.
Vedremo perchè Docker è migliore di una macchina virtuale e come
cambiano le prestazioni rispetto ad andare direttamente sulla macchina.
Vedremo trucchi su come strutturare dei docker-compose file senza
duplicazione per poter sviluppare agilmente sia con GPU che senza, poter
effettuare un deploy con tranquillità e poter scalare facilmente anche
senza GPU. Slide Link: &amp;lt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.slideshare.net/NicolaLandro/basta"&gt;https://www.slideshare.net/NicolaLandro/basta&lt;/a&gt;-
problemicontensorflowusandodockernvidiadocker&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1528"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="OSX"></category><category term="windows"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="cuda"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category><category term="docker"></category></entry><entry><title>Python on Windows is Okay, Actually</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/python-on-windows-is-okay-actually.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steve Dower</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/python-on-windows-is-okay-actually.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packages that won't install, encodings that don't work, installers that ask too many questions, and having to own a PC are all great reasons to just ignore Windows. Or they would be, if they were true. Despite community perception, more than half of Python usage still happens on Windows, including web development, system administration, and data science, just like on Linux and Mac. And for the most part, Python works the same regardless of what operating system you happen to be using. Still, many library developers will unnecessarily exclude half of their potential audience by not even attempting to be compatible. This session will walk through the things to be aware of when creating cross-platform libraries. From simple things like using pathlib rather than bytestrings, through to all the ways you can get builds and tests running on Windows for free, by the end of this session you will have a checklist of easy tasks for your project that will really enable the whole Python world to benefit from your work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Python for hackers and Penetration testing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-for-hackers-and-penetration-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Oltjano Terpollari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/python-for-hackers-and-penetration-testing.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="sqlmap"></category><category term="subnet"></category><category term="set"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="zip"></category><category term="whitehat"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="windows"></category><category term="sysadmin"></category><category term="ssh"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="hacking"></category><category term="pythonscripts"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="socket"></category></entry><entry><title>Pacchettizzare applicazioni python in un singolo file binario</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/pacchettizzare-applicazioni-python-in-un-singolo-file-binario.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriele Franch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/pacchettizzare-applicazioni-python-in-un-singolo-file-binario.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uno dei pochi svantaggi di python è la difficoltà di distribuire
applicazioni stand alone binarie sviluppate in python. In questa talk
mostreremo come è possibile pachettizzare applicazioni python generando
un singolo file eseguibile per ciascuna piattaforma desktop: windows,
linux e mac. Partiremo da un semplice hello world, fino ad arrivare ad
applicazioni sempre più complesse. Verranno introdotti i tool a
disposizione per python per la combinazione di più file in un unico
script (stickytape), l’offuscamento e la minificazione (pyminifier,
Nuitka), la compilazione in un singolo file (PyInstaller, cx_Freeze).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisiti&lt;/strong&gt; : Conoscenza base di python e virtualenv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;domenica 22 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="windows"></category><category term="OSX"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="PyQt"></category><category term="interpreter"></category></entry><entry><title>Python + Windows, like a boss</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-windows-like-a-boss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicola Iarocci</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/python-windows-like-a-boss.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically, Python coding on Windows has been kind of troublesome, but
not anymore. Since a couple of years ago it is possible write awesome
quality Python code with Visual Studio. This is good news for Python
developers of all levels, because Visual Studio offers and incredible
set of tools to enhance all the stages of product development: from
managing virtual environments and handling package management, to
writing and refactoring code, up to testing &amp;amp; debugging - all of that
for free. In this talk I will demo how you can use PTVS to boost your
Python development on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="windows"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="IDE"></category></entry><entry><title>Experiences making CPU-bound tasks run much faster</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/experiences-making-cpu-bound-tasks-run-much-faste.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Ozsvald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/experiences-making-cpu-bound-tasks-run-much-faste.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Ian Ozsvald - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Margherita &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;UPDATE - post-event I've created a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ianozsvald.com/2011/06/29/high-performance-python-tutorial-v0-1%20-from-my-4-hour-tutorial-at-europython-2011/"&gt;49 page PDF write-
up&lt;/a&gt;
which summarises the 4 hour tutorial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-time R&amp;amp;D consultant I'm often working to make slow,
experimental code run faster for tasks like physics simulation, flood
modeling and natural language processing. Python allows a smooth
progression from rough-and-ready (but slow) algorithms through to finely
tuned tasks that efficiently use as much CPU power as you can bring to
bear. Speed-ups of 10-500* can be expected for the Mandelbrot code
we'll use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll cover a set of libraries that make CPU-bound tasks run
much faster. We'll begin with a look at profiling using RunSnakeRun and
line_profiler to identify our bottleneck. We'll take a look at slow
algorithms in Python and how they can run faster using numpy and
numexpr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we'll cover the use of multiprocessing to utilise multiple CPU
cores along with Cython or ShedSkin to easily use C code in a friendly
Python wrapper. Multiprocessing on a quad-core system can often provide
a 4* speed-up for the right tasks. Next parallelpython will let us run
our code on a network of machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we'll look at pyCUDA to utilise an NVIDIA GPU. CUDA can give the
best improvements for mathematical problems (over 100* on the right
tasks) but works on a narrower set of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it'll work: The tutorial will be hands on, you'll be converting
example files from normal Python to faster variants using the tools
below. All of it is optional, you'll get the most benefit by having
everything installed. We'll work in groups and open discussion is
encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE - you are expected to have all these tools installed &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the
tutorial (if you don't, you might find it hard to follow what's going
on!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be using Python 2.7.1 on a Macbook (Snow Leopard). All of these
tools run on Windows and Linux, as long as your versions are fairly
recent everything should run just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My versions (roughly ordered by importance):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2.7.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RunSnakeRun 2.0.1b6 (with wxPython 2.8.12.0 Unicode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;line_profiler (1.0b2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cython 0.14.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ShedSkin 0.7.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numpy 1.5.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numexpr 1.4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ParallelPython 1.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pyCUDA HEAD from git as of 14th June 2011 (with CUDA 4.0 drivers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyPy 1.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some background reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ianozsvald.com/2010/07/14/22937-faster-python-math-using-pycuda/"&gt;http://ianozsvald.com/2010/07/14/22937-faster-python-math-using-pycuda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ianozsvald.com/2008/11/17/making-python-math-196-faster-with-shedskin/"&gt;http://ianozsvald.com/2008/11/17/making-python-math-196-faster-with-shedskin/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="cython"></category><category term="git"></category><category term="multiprocessing"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="nvidia"></category><category term="profiling"></category><category term="pycuda"></category><category term="runsnakerun"></category><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="windows"></category><category term="wxpython"></category></entry><entry><title>PyCon 2009: How I Distribute Python applications on Windows - py2exe and InnoSetup (#108)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--how-i-distribute-python-applications-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-02-17:pycon-us-2009/pycon-2009--how-i-distribute-python-applications-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many deployment options for Python code. I'll share what has
worked well for me on Windows, packaging command line tools and services
using py2exe and InnoSetup. I'll demonstrate a simple build script which
creates windows binaries and an InnoSetup installer in one step. In
addition, I'll go over common errors which come up when using py2exe and
hints on troubleshooting them. This is a short talk, so there will be a
follow-up Open Space session to share experience and help each other
solve distribution problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="innosetup"></category><category term="py2exe"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2009"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry></feed>