<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>I Code Life – is DNA the next coding language?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2018/i-code-life-is-dna-the-next-coding-language.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next generation of Genetic Engineering is the ability to design and make synthetic genes - the DNA of all living organisms. This is used across multiple industries, like pharma, agriculture, chemical production and even data storage. Twist Bioscience developed disruptive technology to synthesize DNA and its Israel R&amp;amp;D center develops software tools to design and debug DNA sequences by its customers. Yogev will describe the challenges, technology and application of the next generation of Genetic engineering, led by Nano-technology and Software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yogev Debbi</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-04:pycon-israel-2018/i-code-life-is-dna-the-next-coding-language.html</guid><category>DNA</category></item><item><title>Rapid Python used on Big Data to Discover Human Genetic Variation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--rapid-python-used-on-big-data-to-disc.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rapid Python used on Big Data to Discover Human Genetic Variation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Deniz Kural&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advances in genome sequencing has enabled large-scale projects such as
the 1000 Genomes Project to sequence genomes across diverse populations
around the world, resulting in very large data sets. I use Python for
rapid development of algorithms for processing &amp;amp; analyzing genomes and
discovering thousands of new variants, including &amp;quot;Mobile Elements&amp;quot; that
copy&amp;amp;paste; themselves across the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in high-throughput sequencing now enables accurate
sequencing human genomes at a low cost &amp;amp; high speed. This technology is
now used to initiate projects involving large-scale sequencing of many
genomes. The 1000 Genomes project aims to sequence 2500 genomes across
27 world populations, and has initially completed its Pilot phase. The
aim of the project is to discover &amp;amp; characterize novel variants. These
variants enable association studies that investigate the link between
genomic variation &amp;amp; phenotypes, including disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A class of variants, known as &amp;quot;Structural Variants&amp;quot; represent a
heterogenous class of larger variants, such as inversions, duplications,
deletions, and various kinds of insertions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Python to for rapid development of algorithms to process, analyze,
and annotate very large data sets. In particular, I focus on Mobile
Elements, pieces of DNA that copy&amp;amp;paste; across the genome. These
elements constitute roughly half of the genome, whereas protein-coding
genes account for roughly 1.5 % of the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss distributed computing, genomics, and big data within the
context of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deniz Kural</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--rapid-python-used-on-big-data-to-disc.html</guid><category>bigdata</category><category>casestudy</category><category>dna</category><category>genomes</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item></channel></rss>