<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lightning talk 09 - Intro to JupyterHub and BinderHub</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2019/lightning-talk-09-intro-to-jupyterhub-and-binderhub.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erik Sundell</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-31:pycon-se-2019/lightning-talk-09-intro-to-jupyterhub-and-binderhub.html</guid><category>lightning talk</category><category>jupyterhub</category><category>binderhub</category></item><item><title>Building an interactive training environment using JupyterHub</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2019/building-an-interactive-training-environment-using-jupyterhub.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;JupyterHub is used to run and manage Jupyter notebook instances for multiple users at the same time. Did you know though that you can use JupyterHub to spawn applications other than Jupyter notebooks? Come see how JupyterHub was used to create a multi user interactive training environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Graham Dumpleton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-24:kiwi-pycon-2019/building-an-interactive-training-environment-using-jupyterhub.html</guid><category>jupyterhub</category></item><item><title>Democratizing Distributed Computing with Dask and JupyterHub</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/democratizing-distributed-computing-with-dask-and-jupyterhub.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use JupyterHub, XArray, Dask, and Kubernetes to build a cloud-based system to enable scientists to analyze and manage large datasets.  We use this in practice to serve a broad community of atmospheric and climate scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atmospheric and climate scientists analyze large volumes of observational and simulated data to better understand our planet.  They have historically used tools like NumPy and SciPy along with Jupyter notebooks to combine efficient computation with accessibility.  However, as datasets increase in size and collaboration extends to new populations of scientists these tools begin to feel their age.  In this talk we use more recent libraries to build a modern deployment for academic scientists.  In particular we use the following tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dask:&lt;/strong&gt; to parallelize and scale NumPy computations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XArray&lt;/strong&gt;: as a self-discribing data model and tool kit for labeled and index arrays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JupyterLab:&lt;/strong&gt; to enable more APIs for users beyond the classic notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JupyterHub:&lt;/strong&gt; to manage users and maintain environments for a new population of cloud-friendly users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes:&lt;/strong&gt; to manage everything and deploy easily on cloud hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus less on how these libraries work and will instead be a case study of using them together in an operational setting.  During the talk we will build up and deploy a running system that the audience can then use to access distributed computing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matthew Rocklin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/democratizing-distributed-computing-with-dask-and-jupyterhub.html</guid><category>jupyterhub</category><category>xarray</category><category>dask</category><category>kubernetes</category></item><item><title>STEAM Workshops using Jupyter Notebooks, JupyterHub, and Binder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/steam-workshops-using-jupyter-notebooks-jupyterhub-and-binder.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Middle School and High School students can learn by doing. Jupyter Notebooks and the rich Python ecosystem with libraries on a variety of topics can engage many learners of the sciences and humanities. Interactive content, using Jupyter Widgets and visualization libraries, put the student in charge of manipulating content and extending their learning. Giving students engaging content in familiar subjects encourages them to develop and use computational skills to build upon their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difficulty of teaching workshops is access to computers and the ability to install software on those systems. This talk will demonstrate how a workshop organizer or teacher can deploy JupyterHub easily for a class using the Zero to JupyterHub Guide, Kubernetes, and Cloud Services. Even if students only have access to smartphones, tablets, or shared computers, a workshop can be held using Binder which allows a notebook environment to be served at the click of a button to any modern web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carol Willing</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/steam-workshops-using-jupyter-notebooks-jupyterhub-and-binder.html</guid><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>jupyterhub</category><category>binder</category></item><item><title>Integrating Jupyter Notebooks into your Infrastructure</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/integrating-jupyter-notebooks-into-your-infrastructure.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Florian Rhiem&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;FlorianRhiem)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florian Rhiem is a scientific software developer at Forschungszentrum Jülich in the Scientific IT-Systems department of Peter Grünberg Institute / Jülich Centre for Neutron Science. In 2014, he finished his master's thesis on visualization of multidimensional functions and graduated as Master of Science in Technomathematics. He works with Python and C, mostly focusing on 3D visualization software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks combine executable code and rich text elements in a web application. In this talk you will learn how a custom JupyterHub installation can be used to integrate Jupyter Notebooks into your infrastructure, including existing authentication methods and custom software distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter Notebooks allow you to create and share interactive documents containing both rich text and executable code. As researchers, you can write Notebooks that allow your readers to reproduce your results on their own. As data scientists, you can use interactive visualizations to explore and analyze data sets directly in your browser. With official support for Python, Julia and R and community support for programming languages ranging from Fortran to JavaScript, Jupyter can be used in a wide variety of workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you will learn how a custom JupyterHub installation has been used to seamlessly integrate Jupyter Notebooks into the existing infrastructure at the Jülich Centre for Neutron Science and the Peter Grünberg Institute. After introducing JupyterHub and its components, the presentation will show how each can be customized to use already existing resources and services, such as LDAP authentication, NFS-based storage and custom software distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Florian Rhiem</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/integrating-jupyter-notebooks-into-your-infrastructure.html</guid><category>jupyterhub</category><category>jupyter</category><category>use-case</category></item><item><title>JupyterHub as an Interactive Supercomputing Gateway</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/jupyterhub-as-an-interactive-supercomputing-gateway-scipy-2016-michael-milligan.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Minnesota Supercomputing Institute we are exploring ways to provide the immediacy and flexibility of interactive computing within the batch-scheduled, tightly controlled world of traditional cluster supercomputing. As Jupyter Notebook has gained in popularity, the steps needed to use it within such an environment have proven to be a barrier to entry even as increasingly powerful Python tools have developed to take advantage of large computational resources. JupyterHub to the rescue! Except out of the box, it doesn't know anything about resource types, job submission, and so on. We developed BatchSpawner and friends as a general JupyterHub backend for batch-scheduled environments. In this talk I will walk through how we have deployed JupyterHub to provide a user-friendly gateway to interactive supercomputing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Milligan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/jupyterhub-as-an-interactive-supercomputing-gateway-scipy-2016-michael-milligan.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>hpc</category><category>jupyterhub</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>supercomputing</category></item></channel></rss>