<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_leadership.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to Become a Kickass Team Lead 101</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/how-to-become-a-kickass-team-lead-101.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ahmad Alhour</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/how-to-become-a-kickass-team-lead-101.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Title: How to Become a Kickass Team Lead 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience Level: Beginner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SUMMARY&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most engineers who get promoted to the role of a team lead, tech lead or
lead developer (regardless of the wording of the title) feel like they
were thrown in cold waters as they, most probably, lack prior training
or education on the subject matter. Most of us that survive and actually
get to like the new role and arrive at really good results, manage to
educate themselves on the skills and habits required to become an
effective team leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will cover the most important lessons about being an
effective team lead without any previous knowledge about the subject.
This is a practical talk and the audience will walk away with a lot of
material and advice to upgrade their engineering leadership game, as
well as a recommended set of resources for further study. The talk is
primarily focused on developing leadership skills and is tailored
towards engineers and software teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals are: - How to develop practical leadership skills for
your day-to-day job - Understand the core components of leadership: ATM
(Ability, Team, Mission) - How to build teamwork on a foundation of
trust - How to overcome the main dysfunctions to look in order to
tighten up your team - Increase your awareness of the main anti-patterns
that team leads end up doing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1668"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1668&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="management"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="leadership"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="tech-lead"></category><category term="education"></category></entry></feed>