<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - AutoML</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_automl.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>AutoGluon - AutoML for Tabular, Multimodal and Time Series Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/autogluon-automl-for-tabular-multimodal-and-time-series-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Caner Turkmen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/autogluon-automl-for-tabular-multimodal-and-time-series-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AutoML, or automated machine learning, offers the promise of transforming raw data into accurate predictions with minimal human intervention, expertise, and manual experimentation. In this talk, we will introduce AutoGluon, a cutting-edge toolkit that enables AutoML for tabular, multimodal and time series data. AutoGluon emphasizes usability, enabling a wide …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AutoML, or automated machine learning, offers the promise of transforming raw data into accurate predictions with minimal human intervention, expertise, and manual experimentation. In this talk, we will introduce AutoGluon, a cutting-edge toolkit that enables AutoML for tabular, multimodal and time series data. AutoGluon emphasizes usability, enabling a wide variety of tasks from regression to time series forecasting and image classification through a unified and intuitive API. We will specifically focus on tasks on tabular and time series tasks where AutoGluon is the current state-of-the-art, and demonstrate how AutoGluon can be used to achieve competitive performance on tabular and time series competition data sets. We will also discuss the techniques used to automatically build and train these models, peeking under the hood of AutoGluon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyData Berlin 2023"></category><category term="AutoGluon"></category><category term="AutoML"></category></entry></feed>