<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_diversity.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>10 Years In Industry as a Minority Developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2019/10-years-in-industry-as-a-minority-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica Ross McKinnie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-13:pytexas-2019/10-years-in-industry-as-a-minority-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder what it’s like being visibly different in tech, whether female or minority, or heaven forbid, both? Find out in this talk! #9 will shock you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Inclusion"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Culture"></category></entry><entry><title>Are women underrepresented in the High Performance Computing (HPC) community?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/are-women-underrepresented-in-the-high-performance-computing-hpc-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Athina Frantzana</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/are-women-underrepresented-in-the-high-performance-computing-hpc-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This study is the first attempt to understand the current gender
demographics of the HPC community, and identify potential reasons and
ways to tackle the gender imbalance. By listening to the people who
constitute the community, the study offers a guideline on what the HPC
community should focus on in order to become more attractive, accessible
and useful to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Diversity"></category></entry><entry><title>AfroPython: empoderando a la población negra usando Python en Brasil</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/afropython-empoderando-a-la-poblacion-negra-usando-python-en-brasil.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felipe de Morais</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-us-2019/afropython-empoderando-a-la-poblacion-negra-usando-python-en-brasil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Más que 50% de la población de Brasil son negros pero este numero no está representado en Tecnología. Brasil es el segundo país con más personas negras en el mundo, solo detrás de Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de esta charla es compartir una iniciativa creada en Brasil para incluir y empoderar las personas negras con a través de la tecnología.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="afropython"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Girls Italia: entrare in contatto con le donne tecnologiche, davvero</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/django-girls-italia-entrare-in-contatto-con-le-donne-tecnologiche-davvero.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Laura Bartoli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/django-girls-italia-entrare-in-contatto-con-le-donne-tecnologiche-davvero.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parlare di inclusività e tematiche di genere è ormai una moda.
Affrontare il tema donne che lavorano nell’industria IT con toni
tragici, come si trattasse di esseri mitologici, lo è ancora di più.
Come passare oltre il “velo di Maya” e bypassare la disinformazione?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nel 2015 insieme alla community Python Italiana abbiamo gettato le basi
per portare in Italia Django Girls, workshop nato per contribuire a
colmare quel gender gap di cui si parla tanto. In tre anni di “duro
lavoro” come organizzatrice di laboratori in Italia, sono entrata in
contatto con oltre 400 donne appassionate di tecnologia: studentesse di
ingegneria informatica, architetti, insegnanti, casalinghe, web
desinger. E anche con sviluppatori pronti a supportare la causa ( sì,
potete essere una “Django Girl” anche se avete la barba) che hanno
contribuito a far crescere la community con il loro entusiasmo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;45 minuti per conoscere la mission Django Girls, entrare in contatto con
la community italiana e per sfatare i falsi miti. Un talk entry level
per tutti, per chi è interessato a portare il progetto nella propria
città, per chi vorrebbe fare il coach e per chi semplicemente vorrebbe
sapere di più sull’iniziativa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="women"></category><category term="inclusion"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Helping communities &amp; products thrive by fostering empathy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sasha Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a fundamental part of human interaction. When we communicate
by email or at conferences, or indirectly, when we create products,
events, or do a talk. However, our understanding of other people is full
of error, and worse, bias. This can lead us to make communities and
products that work poorly for people that are different from ourselves,
introduce confusion and misunderstanding, exclude people
unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our communities are an opportunity to learn as well. To embrace
our diversity, and expand our understanding of other people’s worlds. To
gain understanding of other people’s situations, experiences and
emotions, which can be dramatically different to ours. And how we can
use this to create both products and communities which work great not
only for ourselves, but also those that we more easily forget about. As
creators in tech we have such tremendous power to create change, but
merely our best intentions will not be enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how and why we sometimes have such difficulty to
understand others, and how others can have difficulty to understand us.
We’ll talk about why other people’s experiences, emotion and perceptions
can be so different. Both for the world as a whole, but also with the
speaker’s personal experiences. Finally, we’ll cover specific ways for
us to understand others better, and associated pitfalls, to make our
communities and products happy, inviting and supportive places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="empathy"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Programação além de código</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/caipyra-2016/programacao-alem-de-codigo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leticia Portella</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:caipyra-2016/programacao-alem-de-codigo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra da Letícia Portella no Caipyra 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programação além de código&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/leportella/programacao-alem-do-codigo-comunidade-e-mulheres-na-tecnologia"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/leportella/programacao-alem-do-codigo-comunidade-e-mulheres-na-tecnologia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Is it too late to learn how to program and how being a developer changed my life</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/is-it-too-late-to-learn-how-to-program-and-how-being-a-developer-changed-my-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alicia Carr</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/is-it-too-late-to-learn-how-to-program-and-how-being-a-developer-changed-my-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How I became a developer in my 50th. the challenges, the assumption and
the victories and how women are not being recognized as an important
part of the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How and why I wanted to be an iOS mobile developer at the age of 51.
Some people want to believe that people my age are out of touch with
technology and as a woman, I have seen the best and the worst in the
tech community but I also now that there is a solution at the end of the
rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the boom in use of smartphones, we have seen a corresponding growth
in numbers of available apps, some of which are being leveraged for
social change. What people don’t know is 70% of women are more active on
our mobile device than men, women are more active with social media,
shopping, photo apps, are more connected to entertainers and play more
games on their smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said we the tech community need to open up our arm and
embrace the change and think about how women in tech can change the way
we see and create apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="android"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Diversity Panel: experience and discussion from all over the world</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alicia Carr</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion table about Diversity in all its hues with organizers and
experts from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="panel"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Girls</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2016/pycaribbean-2016-django-girls-ola-sitarska.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ola Sitarska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-20:pycaribbean-2016/pycaribbean-2016-django-girls-ola-sitarska.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="keynote"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="django girls"></category><category term="diversity"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a More Inclusive Python Community Culture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kojo Idrissa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groups that are more diverse are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/#q=diverse+%22problem+solving%22"&gt;better at solving
problems&lt;/a&gt;
than more homogenous groups. An inclusive group culture maximizes the
odds of attracting and retaining skills &amp;amp; personalities needed to
thrive. The Python community has a pretty good track record on issues
related to inclusion. So, how can you help continue that trend,
especially in your local community? I'll start with a brief &lt;em&gt;WHY&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;WHAT&lt;/em&gt; of Inclusion, but most of this talk focuses on &lt;strong&gt;HOW&lt;/strong&gt; to help
your local corner of the Python community be as Inclusive as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="inclusion"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Culture"></category></entry><entry><title>Diversity as a Dependency</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/diversity-as-a-dependency.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Ravenscroft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/diversity-as-a-dependency.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Anna Ravenscroft - 20 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PSF recently adopted a diversity statement. While some argue that we
should do this just because it's &amp;quot;the right thing to do&amp;quot;, others
question why we, as a technical community, should even worry about
diversity. This talk addresses the diversity question, not in moralistic
or ethical terms, but in pragmatic ones. Studies on creativity and
productivity demonstrate the potential benefits of diversity for the
Python community. Making Python the best language it can be is not
merely helped by increasing diversity, but may be dependent on
diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="psf"></category></entry><entry><title>Diversity in Tech: Improving our Toolset</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--diversity-in-tech--improving-our-tool.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Leech</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--diversity-in-tech--improving-our-tool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity in Tech: Improving our Toolset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jennifer Leech&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities allow more diversity, they draw from a larger talent
pool, challenge each other more, and hit a higher bar in terms of
ingenuity and work-product. However questions surrounding diversity
often seem under- examined. What are the effects of diversity in the
community, or lack thereof? I intend to approach this topic from an
accessible and entertaining, yet analytical perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year there was a photo of Kate Moss shown during a PyCon
presentation which raised debate as to its appropriateness. This debate
brought up some interesting questions - but what I found most
interesting was that while it elicited strong opinions, the issue seemed
to be somewhat unexamined. This event sparked a desire for deeper
analysis on this topic in a more focussed setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I intend to address some of the core principles underlying
this debate. Discussion will include the following questions: Where does
responsibility lie in understanding these issues? What are the effects
of failing to do so? What are the effects of diversity in the community,
or lack thereof? What do we lose by being more homogenous or more
diverse? Gain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities allow more diversity, they draw from a larger talent
pool, challenge each other more, and hit a higher bar in terms of
ingenuity and work-product. However, diversity requires awareness and
tolerance on both the part of the dominant culture and on the part of
the new arrivals to smooth the inevitable rough edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to approach this topic from an accessible, inclusive and
entertaining, yet analytical perspective. The broader intent is to raise
the level of understanding and community discourse on this topic. It is
odd that diversity can so dramatically affect our lives and communities
and yet be unexamined, particularly in a community so highly intelligent
and educated as that which populates the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry><entry><title>Get new contributors (and diversity) through outreach</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--get-new-contributors--and-diversity--.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Asheesh Laroia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--get-new-contributors--and-diversity--.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get new contributors (and diversity) through outreach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Asheesh Laroia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups like the Fedora Design Team, Dreamwidth, SF Ruby, and OpenHatch
have discovered the power of outreach to bring in new contributors. In
the past year, SF Ruby grew in numbers as well as in diversity, moving
from 3% women to 18% women. Because most projects need ongoing help,
this talk discusses effective strategies for bringing in contributors
who stick around for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is targeted at anyone involved in an open source project who
wants to find more contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programs like Google Summer of Code often provide excited students who
disappear after a summer's work. Meanwhile, request for help emails on
development lists are typically met with silence. Hackathons create a
flurry of commits, but then we never hear from the participants again.
Expanding your team is possible, and it requires care in terms of
outreach, expectation management, and mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss three major forms of outreach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-on-one check-ins with participants,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periodic drives to bring in new contributors, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-person teaching events. Each one has &amp;quot;do&amp;quot;s and &amp;quot;don't&amp;quot;s associated
with it. This talk digests the experience of effective outreach into
practical strategies that you can re-use within your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="openhatch"></category><category term="outreach"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>