<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_gettinginvolved.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The Development of Python and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--the-development-of-python-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--the-development-of-python-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Development of Python and You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Curtin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an inside look at what it takes to work on CPython, from getting
setup with the source and navigating the bug tracker, to the best
practices for having your work accepted. We'll find, categorize, and fix
an issue in Python to get you started. This talk is ideal for those who
are new to open source projects or are interested in the Python
development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People from all backgrounds, users of all platforms, and developers of
all levels are necessary in the development of Python. From writing code
to documentation, it takes all kinds of people to make an impact. If
you've used Python, we need you, and what better place to get involved
than at PyCon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010 saw a rise in the number of contributors to CPython, and the PSF
stepped in to support the efforts of those wanting to get involved. Are
you up for the challenge? This talk dives right into what it takes to
get involved, covering the who, what, where, when, and why of Python
development, going through the whole process live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference is over, stick around with the CPython crew and
hack away!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="coredev"></category><category term="cpython"></category><category term="development"></category><category term="gettinginvolved"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>