<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - RESTful</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GraphQL in Python 🍓</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/graphql-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years GraphQL has gained much traction, but what’s the
state of GraphQL in Python. This talk describes what GraphQL is, why it
has been created and the current state of GraphQL libraries in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a short history of GraphQL, some examples of what makes it
shine and why it can be preferred to REST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also analyse the current state of GraphQL in Python, having a
brief overview of the current libraries and then having an in-depth look
at Strawberry a new library based on dataclasses that makes it easy to
create GraphQl APIs in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/graphql-in-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Django</category><category>RESTful</category><category>Web</category><category>Web General</category><category>Web Servers and MicroFWs</category></item><item><title>API-schema-based testing with schemathesis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/api-schema-based-testing-with-schemathesis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automatically generate test-cases based on your API-schemas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal with this talk is to introduce the audience to property-based testing for API’s using schemas to automatically generate test scenarios, enabling them to write more powerful tests faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will focus on a subset of the field of property-based testing where we focus on testing by automatically generating properties and test strategies from the API Schemas that we often already have. These tests ensure that our APIs conform to their specified schema and enables us to write a much larger amount of tests in less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will focus on the schemathesis library which leverages the strong hypothesis library as well as the hypothesis-JSONSchema extension strategies, and will in the future also support GraphQL via the hypothesis-graphql strategies. I’m a contributor to schemathesis and currently working on the future GraphQL support with schemathesis creator, Dmitry Dygalo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also compare it with its predecessor “swagger-conformance”, pure property-based testing through hypothesis, schema strategies with hypothesis-graphql and hypothesis-jsonschema, and discuss their advantages and disadvantages. I will also briefly talk about “QuickREST: Property-based Test Generation of OpenAPI-Described RESTful APIs” (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.09686"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.09686&lt;/a&gt;), the research paper that’s part of the inspiration for these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By focusing on property-based test generation using schemas we already have, I will show that a field like property-based testing, which can seem quite daunting at first, actually can have a low barrier to entry while yielding large amounts of value in return and is useful for most common web projects today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will show how formal schemas for APIs can and will continue to provide additional value outside the scope of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Hultnér</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/api-schema-based-testing-with-schemathesis.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>APIs</category><category>RESTful</category><category>Test Libraries (pytest/nose/...)</category><category>Testing</category><category>Web Servers and MicroFWs (Flask/Tornado/Nginx/...)</category></item><item><title>Overcoming access control in web APIs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/overcoming-access-control-in-web-apis.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to address security concerns using Sanic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, you've developed a great web API. Awesome, you are about to deploy it. But, how do you secure it and manage access?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about different approaches to securing a web API whether it is meant for third-party integrations or driving a modern single-page application. Not all APIs are the same, so we will explore different considerations to make when crafting a solution to handle token-based authentication, and scoping to define access levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the core developers of the async web framework Sanic, I will primarily focus on authentication and authorization tools inside Sanic to showcase how to address these issues. However, the concepts should be broadly applicable enough to take back and apply to any web API. The goal is to learn the hot spots, and identify strategies to overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core take aways will include:
- how to implement various JWT strategies;
- best practices for storing JWTs on a browser; and
- controlling access privileges using structured scopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time permitting, we will even discuss some tools to be used to help ease the anxiety and make security more approachable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Hopkins</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/overcoming-access-control-in-web-apis.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>APIs</category><category>Authentication</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>RESTful</category><category>Web</category></item><item><title>ScanAPI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/scanapi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automated Integration Testing and Live Documentation for your API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current IT scenario, the use of APIs is, without question, widely vast, popular, and significant. It seems at least prudent to ensure they are working properly, as expected. To guarantee the quality of the data that is being consumed or used. To ensure that communication between services is occurring as expected. To ensure the system does, in fact, what it should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ScanAPI is an open-source library that was created to solve all these points. ScanAPI provides an easy way to create integration tests for REST APIs via configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three main reasons that led me to the creation of this library were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be a firefighter in a scenario where most of the reported bugs were directly related to some API contract being broken or some endpoint having a behavior different from that expected by the consumer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To need to deal with APIs with outdated or mistaken documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To need to debug an endpoint in the middle of a &amp;quot;chain&amp;quot; of other endpoints. Where I needed to recreate a state that depends on the action of other endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a fictitious example: debug an endpoint to reserve seats on an airplane, which depends directly on the previous call of an endpoint for user registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ScanAPI is open-source and written in Python. However, it can be used in APIs created in any other programming language, since the tests provided by it are integration tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ScanAPI you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use environment variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chaining requests - making a request from a result of previous responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide sensitive information of the requests and responses in the generated report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write Python code - if you want, it's not necessary :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics I intend to address in this talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation to create the library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What problems the library solves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to test an API using a ScanAPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the documentation generated by ScanAPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of how it is implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where it is currently being used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Link: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/scanapi/scanapi"&gt;https://github.com/scanapi/scanapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:
- Python
- REST APIs
- Integration tests&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Camila Maia</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/scanapi.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>APIs</category><category>Open-Source</category><category>RESTful</category><category>Test Libraries (pytest/nose/...)</category><category>Testing</category></item></channel></rss>