<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_text-analysis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to turn Wikipedia into a Quiz Game</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/how-to-turn-wikipedia-into-a-quiz-game.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Cappelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/how-to-turn-wikipedia-into-a-quiz-game.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiz games let people test their knowledge through multi-choice
questions. Unfortunately, generating such questions can be very
time-consuming and it is typically done manually. In this talk we
will present a pipeline to automatically generate quiz games starting
from generic knowledge (e.g. Wikipedia). The pipeline consists of the
following components: (i) a parser to retrieve text from Wikipedia
pages, (ii) a Natural Language Processing module (based on the Google
Natural Language API) to extract information about syntax, entities
and relations, (iii) a Natural Language Generation module to generate
test questions and correct answers, and finally (iv) a domain-aware
module that uses domain-specific knowledge to generate wrong answers
(i.e. distractors). Every module is written in Python and it is based
on either available libraries or Cloud services (e.g., Google Natural
Language).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: basic knowledge of python, minimal understanding
of text syntactic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="nlp"></category><category term="AI"></category><category term="games"></category><category term="computational-linguistics"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="text-analysis"></category><category term="google-cloud"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category><category term="linked-data"></category></entry><entry><title>Word Embeddings for Natural Language Processing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/word-embeddings-for-natural-language-processing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Bonzanini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/word-embeddings-for-natural-language-processing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Word embeddings are a family of Natural Language Processing (NLP)
algorithms where words are mapped to vectors in low-dimensional space.
The interest around word embeddings has been on the rise in the past few
years, because these techniques have been driving important improvements
in many NLP applications like text classification, sentiment analysis or
machine translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll describe the intuitions behind this family of
algorithms, we’ll explore some of the Python tools that allow us to
implement modern NLP applications and we’ll conclude with some practical
considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="nlp"></category><category term="text-analysis"></category><category term="pydata"></category></entry></feed>