<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Multi-modal classification with PyTorch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/multi-modal-classification-with-pytorch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent work by Kiela et al. (2018) reveals that image and text
multi-modal classification models far outperform both text- and
image-only models. This talk will review work that extends Kiela et
al.’s (2018) research by determining if accuracy in classification may
be increased by the implementation of transfer learning in language
processing. The performance of the model over a MM-IMDb (Arevalo et al.
2017) dataset is analyzed and compared to the baseline provided by Kiela
et al. (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is implemented with PyTorch and the goal of the talk will be to
review details of the implementation, and performance of the model as
compared to that recorded in Kiela et al. (2018). Attendees of this talk
should have a basic familiarity with neural nets developed in PyTorch
for the purposes of NLP and computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References: Arevalo, J., Solorio, T., Montes-y-Gómez, M., &amp;amp; González, F.
A. 2017. Gated multimodal units for information fusion. arXiv preprint
arXiv:1702.01992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiela, Douwe, Edouard Grave, Armand Joulin, and Tomas Mikolov. 2018.
Efficient large-scale multi-modal classification. arXiv preprint
arXiv:1802.02892.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1754"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1754&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jennifer Seale</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/multi-modal-classification-with-pytorch.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>computer-vision</category></item><item><title>GPU-accelerated data analysis in Python: a study case in Material Sciences</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/gpu-accelerated-data-analysis-in-python-a-study-case-in-material-sciences.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Max Planck Computing and Data Facility is engaged in the development
and optimization of algorithms and applications for high performance
computing as well as for data-intensive projects. As programming
language in data science, Python is now used at MPCDF in the scientific
area of “atom probe crystallography” (APT): a Fourier analysis in 3D
space can be simulated in order to reveal composition and
crystallographic structure at the atomic scale of billions APT
experimental data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python data ecosystem has proved to be well suited to this, as it
has grown beyond the confines of single machines to embrace scalability.
The talk aims to describe our approach to scaling across multiple GPUs,
and the role of visualization methods too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data workflow analysis relies on the GPU-accelerated Python software
package PyNX, an open source library which provides fast parallel
computation scattering. The code takes advantage of the high throughput
of GPUs, using the pyCUDA library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploratory data analysis, high productivity and rapid prototyping with
high performance are enabled through Jupyter Notebooks and Python
packages e.g., pandas, matplotlib/plotly. In production stage,
interactive visualization is realized by using standard scientific tool,
e.g. Paraview, an open-source 3D visualization program which requires
Python modules to generate visualization components within VTK files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giuseppe Di Bernardo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/gpu-accelerated-data-analysis-in-python-a-study-case-in-material-sciences.html</guid><category>GPUComputing</category><category>visualization</category><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>image-processing</category><category>bigdata</category><category>matplotlib</category><category>analytics</category><category>data-visualization</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>Data Mining</category><category>scientific-computing</category><category>physics</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Sports performance evaluation: from cognitive mechanisms to data-driven algorithms</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/sports-performance-evaluation-from-cognitive-mechanisms-to-data-driven-algorithms.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Not everything that counts can be counted, and not everything that
can be counted counts. A. Einstein&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are routinely asked to evaluate the performance of other
individuals, separating success from failure and affecting outcomes from
science to education and sports. Yet, little is known about the aspects
that determine the human perception of performance. How do expert
reviewers, as well as ordinary people, arrive to their evaluations? To
what extent these evaluations are based on objective performance
features? How are they affected by subjective biases or contextual
influences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will answer these fascinating questions focusing on &lt;em&gt;soccer&lt;/em&gt; ,
the most popular sport in the world. Firstly, we will show how machine
learning can accurately reproduce the mechanisms human judges use to
evaluate the performance of soccer players, uncovering limits and
characteristics of the human evaluation process. Second, we design a
Python package that allows, in a completely unsupervised and data-driven
way, to (i) evaluate the quality of a player’s performance and (ii) rank
soccer players based on their performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the talk will show how soccer ratings assigned to
every player of a game by sport-specialized newspapers are associated
with a high- dimensional vector of features extracted by massive data
which describe any quantifiable aspects of soccer games. The talk will
show how, by using Scikit- learn, we can train an &lt;em&gt;artificial judge&lt;/em&gt;
which learns the relation between technical performance and soccer
ratings, hence &lt;em&gt;accurately reproducing&lt;/em&gt; the human evaluation process. By
inspecting the structure of the artificial judge, the talk will show
that the human evaluation criteria follow a simplistic cognitive process
based on a simple heuristic: judges first select a limited number of
features which attract their attention and then rate a performance based
on the presence of noticeable values, i.e., features values far from the
norm that can be easily brought to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the talk will show how to overcome the simplicity of
the human evaluation process presenting &lt;strong&gt;PlayeRank&lt;/strong&gt; , a Python package
which implements an unsupervised data-driven framework to evaluate the
performance of soccer players in the main European leagues. The talk
will show how to use PlayeRank to construct a data-driven ranking of
players and highlight the factors which determine why celebrated
players, like Messi and Cristiano Ronaldo, actually result to be the top
players in the world. The modules composing PlayeRank will be presented,
showing how they allow the user to define the features characterizing a
performance, to detect in an automatic way the relevance of each
player’s action to a game outcome, to detect the role of a player given
his game data, to rate every performance as well as to obtain a final
ranking of all players in Europe. A short demo will be provided during
the talk through a Jupyter notebook, exploiting interactive data
visualization with the Bokeh package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will learn how to use Python to construct evaluation
algorithms entirely based on machine learning and big data, a step
forward to a thorough and objective evaluation of performance which
overcomes the biases and the limitations of human perception of
performance. Just a basic knowledge of Python and of data mining
principles is required for a full understanding of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luca Pappalardo</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/sports-performance-evaluation-from-cognitive-mechanisms-to-data-driven-algorithms.html</guid><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>Python</category><category>bigdata</category><category>sports-analytics</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>analytics</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Data Mining</category><category>sklearn</category></item><item><title>Tensor decomposition with Python: Learning structures from multidimensional data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/tensor-decomposition-with-python-learning-structures-from-multidimensional-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many problems in signal processing and machine learning generate massive
amounts of multidimensional data. Data sources from sensor networks and
Internet-of-Things applications promise a wealth of interaction data
that can be naturally represented as tensors. Tensor decompositions have
gained a steadily increasing popularity in data mining and machine
learning, with applications in psychometrics, chemometrics, signal
processing, computer vision, neuroscience, graph analysis, and more. For
example, time-varying social networks collected from wearable proximity
sensors can be represented as 3-way tensors, and tensor decomposition
can be used to extract community structures with their structural and
temporal signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current standard framework for working with tensors, however, is
Matlab. We will show how tensor decompositions can be carried out using
Python, how to obtain latent components and how they can be interpreted,
and what are some applications of this technique in the academy and
industry. We will see a use case where a Python implementation of tensor
decomposition is applied to a dataset that describes face-to-face social
interactions of people, collected using the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sociopatterns.org/"&gt;SocioPatterns&lt;/a&gt; platform. This
platform was deployed in different settings such as conferences, schools
and hospitals, in order to support mathematical modelling and simulation
of airborne infectious diseases. Tensor decomposition has been used in
these scenarios to solve different types of problems: it is used for
data cleaning, where time-varying graph anomalies can be identified and
removed from data; it have been also used to assess the impact of
face-to-face interactions in the spreading of diseases. These examples
show the potential of this technique in data mining and machine learning
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">André Panisson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/tensor-decomposition-with-python-learning-structures-from-multidimensional-data.html</guid><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>datamining</category><category>machine-learning</category></item><item><title>Validazione e decodifica di file XML con Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/validazione-e-decodifica-di-file-xml-con-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Per la schematizzazione di documenti XML sono disponibili diversi
standard, tra questi XML Schema. La prima problematica è quella di poter
validare file XML secondo il loro rispettivo schema. Un’altra esigenza è
la conversione dell’XML in strutture dati in cui siano valorizzati i
tipi base definiti nello schema e la struttura nidificata in cui sono
inseriti, similmente a quello che è già reso disponibile per JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ambito scientifico, nell’ambito delle attività del progetto europeo
MaX (Materials design at the Exascale), per semplificare l’interscambio
di dati dati XML tra diversi software di simulazione, si è deciso di
adottare un approccio unitario e sistematico alla validazione e alla
decodifica dei dati XML prodotti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pertanto è in fase di sviluppo una nuova libreria (xmlschema), basata
sulla libreria standard ElementTree di Python, che permette di validare
e decodificare dati XML con schemi XSD. La decodifica di un documento
XML produce un dizionario nidificato con i valori terminali appartenenti
ai corrispondenti tipi elementari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nella presentazione parlerei delle problematiche degli schemi XSD,
dell’ambito scientifico in cui è stata sviluppata la libreria e della
struttura della libreria stessa, illustrando e magari raccogliendo
qualche idea per migliorarla.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Davide Brunato</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/validazione-e-decodifica-di-file-xml-con-python.html</guid><category>xml</category><category>mathematical-modelling</category><category>encoding</category><category>Python</category><category>simulation</category><category>validation</category><category>physics</category><category>metadata</category></item></channel></rss>