<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_community.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>10 Years In Industry as a Minority Developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2019/10-years-in-industry-as-a-minority-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica Ross McKinnie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-13:pytexas-2019/10-years-in-industry-as-a-minority-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder what it’s like being visibly different in tech, whether female or minority, or heaven forbid, both? Find out in this talk! #9 will shock you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Inclusion"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Culture"></category></entry><entry><title>A Day Has Only 24±1 Hours</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/a-day-has-only-24-1-hours.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miroslav Šedivý</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/a-day-has-only-24-1-hours.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the last Sunday of October you may get “one more hour of sleep” but
as well may spend much more time debugging code dealing with the time
zones, daylight saving time shifts and datetime stuff in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll look at a few pitfalls you may encounter when working with
datetimes in Python. We'll dissect the pytz library, explain why it
contains over 500 individual time zones while focusing on the 63 entries
in Europe. We'll also find the reason why pytz is not part of the
standard Python, why it gets updated so often and why even that won't
solve all your problems. Do you know what happens after 2021 when the EU
stops DST switching?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two centuries of short-sighted propaganda and long-term chaos in
forty-five minutes. Maybe that will make you want to avoid time zones in
your code altogether!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Python general"></category><category term="failures/mistakes"></category></entry><entry><title>EPS General Assembly 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/eps-general-assembly-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Andre Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/eps-general-assembly-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where the EuroPython Society (EPS) board gives its reports,
resolutions are passed and the EPS members can vote in a new EPS board.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category><category term="EPS"></category><category term="EuroPython"></category><category term="EuroPython Society (EPS)"></category></entry><entry><title>EuroPython 2020: Help us build the next edition!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/europython-2020-help-us-build-the-next-edition.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Andre Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/europython-2020-help-us-build-the-next-edition.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need help with organizing and running EuroPython 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will explain how the EuroPython workgroup model
works and where you could help.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category><category term="EuroPython"></category><category term="EuroPython Society (EPS)"></category></entry><entry><title>Python 1994</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/python-1994.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Everitt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/python-1994.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Come for the language, stay for the community.” The Python community
started in 1994 at a NIST workshop in Maryland. What was the world of
Python like in its first years? Did we have any clue whatsoever? A
joke-focused tour of early Python, heavy on question-and-answer.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>Do we have a diversity problem in Python community?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/do-we-have-a-diversity-problem-in-python-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cheuk Ho</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/do-we-have-a-diversity-problem-in-python-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversity statement quoted as follows: “The Python Software
Foundation and the global Python community welcome and encourage
participation by everyone. Our community is based on mutual respect,
tolerance, and encouragement, and we are working to help each other live
up to these principles. We want our community to be more diverse:
whoever you are, and whatever your background, we welcome you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversity, big deal! As an active members and event organisers (and also
on the minority side of the gender) in the Python community, we have
alway been concern by the question of: Do we truly have a problem in
diversity? Especially, gender diversity. We would like to find out the
truth, by data science, and see if we can find a clue why and how we can
fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will show the research others did regarding the representation
of women in the R and Python communities [1]. Then, we will show the
research that we did based on our experience and statistic. Including
static analysis of the speakers diversity (regarding gender) at major
PyCon and PyData conferences. Finally, as we all care about diversity
and want improvements, we would like to find out the reason and what we
can do about it. We would propose what we, the minorities and allies,
could do against this seemingly unbalance situation and make the
community better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for all that who cares about diversity in our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://reshamas.github.io/why-women-are-flourishing-in-r-community-but"&gt;https://reshamas.github.io/why-women-are-flourishing-in-r-community-but&lt;/a&gt;-
lagging-in-python/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: slides at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slides.com/cheukting_ho/do-we-have-a-diversity"&gt;https://slides.com/cheukting_ho/do-we-have-a-diversity&lt;/a&gt;-
problem-in-python-community&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category><category term="Conferences and Meet-Ups"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Static Analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>Why You Should Pursue Public Speaking and How to Get There</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/why-you-should-pursue-public-speaking-and-how-to-get-there.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yenny Cheung</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/why-you-should-pursue-public-speaking-and-how-to-get-there.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear of public speaking is the most common of all phobias. Want to speak
confidently in front of the crowd? This talk shares tips on how to
overcome the fear, and ways to get started. You will be prepared to
brace presenting from a team meeting to a conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Become a Kickass Team Lead 101</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/how-to-become-a-kickass-team-lead-101.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ahmad Alhour</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/how-to-become-a-kickass-team-lead-101.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Title: How to Become a Kickass Team Lead 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience Level: Beginner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SUMMARY&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most engineers who get promoted to the role of a team lead, tech lead or
lead developer (regardless of the wording of the title) feel like they
were thrown in cold waters as they, most probably, lack prior training
or education on the subject matter. Most of us that survive and actually
get to like the new role and arrive at really good results, manage to
educate themselves on the skills and habits required to become an
effective team leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will cover the most important lessons about being an
effective team lead without any previous knowledge about the subject.
This is a practical talk and the audience will walk away with a lot of
material and advice to upgrade their engineering leadership game, as
well as a recommended set of resources for further study. The talk is
primarily focused on developing leadership skills and is tailored
towards engineers and software teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals are: - How to develop practical leadership skills for
your day-to-day job - Understand the core components of leadership: ATM
(Ability, Team, Mission) - How to build teamwork on a foundation of
trust - How to overcome the main dysfunctions to look in order to
tighten up your team - Increase your awareness of the main anti-patterns
that team leads end up doing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1668"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1668&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="management"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="leadership"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="tech-lead"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>Back to the Future!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-philippines-2019/back-to-the-future.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Beng Keat Liew</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-23:pycon-philippines-2019/back-to-the-future.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will present the state of affairs with PyCon's and Python communities around the region. We will also 'jump back' into history with PyCon APAC and derive the common lessons learned and insights and wishes for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>Costruisci la tua piattaforma open-source di video-sharing in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/costruisci-la-tua-piattaforma-open-source-di-video-sharing-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Simone Orsi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/costruisci-la-tua-piattaforma-open-source-di-video-sharing-in-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="video"></category><category term="sharing"></category><category term="youtube"></category><category term="open-source"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>OpenStack: A python based IaaS provider</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/openstack-a-python-based-iaas-provider.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Flavio Percoco</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/openstack-a-python-based-iaas-provider.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="scm"></category><category term="cloud"></category><category term="gerrit"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Creating an inclusive corporate culture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/creating-an-inclusive-corporate-culture.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yenny Cheung</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/creating-an-inclusive-corporate-culture.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having a tech career as a minority is challenging. It could mean being
the only one to speak against the popular opinion, or becoming more
visible to get the same level of recognition. What can we do on the
corporate level to make sure everyone feels welcome and retain these
talents? Creating an inclusive corporate culture helps us achieve just
that. This talk shares concrete steps that employees and employers can
take to improve minorities in tech’s sense of belonging and engagement:&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Business &amp; Start-Ups"></category><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>How to make your (digital) Communication strong &amp; future ready</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/how-to-make-your-digital-communication-strong-future-ready.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Simon Daubermann</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/how-to-make-your-digital-communication-strong-future-ready.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your business is all set up and ready. You want to enter the market with
a new product or service. As digital communication evolves, brands and
companies are constantly facing new challenges. The ways of providing
information and interacting become more and more multi-layered and
complex. A well-defined communicative base can serve as a corrective
that prevents technology from becoming self-serving.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Business &amp; Start-Ups"></category><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>Python on the blockchain: Triumphs and tribulations in a crypto startup</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/python-on-the-blockchain-triumphs-and-tribulations-in-a-crypto-startup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Danny McDonald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/python-on-the-blockchain-triumphs-and-tribulations-in-a-crypto-startup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many cryptographic components of blockchain protocols can be
extremely complex, blockchain systems themselves are relatively easy to
understand when viewed from a distance. To take the example of Bitcoin,
users store digital currency in hardware or software wallets, and use
private keys to sign and broadcast transactions. Broadcasted
transactions are grouped together into a block through a cryptographic
process known as mining, with miners rewarded through the collection of
transaction fees and the issuance of new coins. The mined block of
transactions is appended to the existing chain, and verified by a global
network of nodes. This process repeats in perpetuity, with each newly
added block adding to the trustedness and security of data stored on the
chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased interest in and demand for cryptocurrencies has brought about
a need for places where digital assets can easily be bought, sold or
traded. Our platform, Bitpanda, accomplishes this with a backend written
in Python, and relying heavily on Django and MySQL databases. In our
presentation, we begin by providing a brief overview of how blockchains
work. Following this, we describe the Python architecture that (e.g.)
generates cryptocurrency wallets, builds, signs and sends transactions,
and monitors blockchains for new, relevant data. Key challenges,
solutions and failures encountered during the development of the system,
and growth of our team, are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout our talk, we also highlight a number of broader social
implications of blockchains, and our work with them. More specifically,
we describe the need for open-innovation based approaches to blockchain
development, the value of open-source within the blockchain community,
and the current lack of critical discourse surrounding the potential
uses of blockchains as mechanisms of surveillance and control.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Business &amp; Start-Ups"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="Infrastructure"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>What's new in Python 3.7?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/whats-new-in-python-37.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephane Wirtel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/whats-new-in-python-37.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scheduled for release in mid-June after the conference, Python 3.7 is
shaping up to be a feature-packed release! This talk will cover all the
new features of Python 3.7, including the Data Classes and the Context
Variables for the asynchronous programming with asyncio.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="DevOps"></category></entry><entry><title>Binder - lowering the bar to sharing interactive software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/binder-lowering-the-bar-to-sharing-interactive-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tim Head</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/binder-lowering-the-bar-to-sharing-interactive-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Binder project drastically lowers the bar to sharing and re-using
software. As a user wanting to try out someone else’s work I only have
to click a single link. As the author preparing a binder-ready project
is much easier than having to support many different platforms and for
many projects involves little additional work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce the audience to the concepts and ideas
behind the Binder project. I will showcase examples from the community
to illustrate use-cases and show off the power of Binder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three pieces of software power Binder:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://repo2docker.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;repo2docker&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;BinderHub&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/stable/"&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt;. Using an
example repository I will go through the steps required to make a
repository binder- ready and what happens when a user launches it. At
each step I will illustrate the role that each of the three software
components play and how they interact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binder is a project created by its community. I will present pathways
for getting involved with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap up I will highlight plans for future developments and features
of Binder.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Community"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="DevOps"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="Science"></category><category term="Web"></category></entry><entry><title>CPython loves your Pull Requests</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/cpython-loves-your-pull-requests.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stéphane Wirtel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/cpython-loves-your-pull-requests.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="description"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPython, what’s CPython. CPython is the official implementation of
Python, written in C. And it’s not just a implementation, it is a group
of volunteers and where they daily work on the project but there is no
many active contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I would like to prove to you than you can become an active
contributor of CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core developers of CPython need your help, for example, with the
review of some patches, you can comment a patch or try to reproduce a
bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, when you wanted to contribute to CPython, you had to use
the bug tracker interface and send a patch, this patch was reviewed if
you were lucky and after commented etc…. but this process was really
long and time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with the new process based on GitHub and Git, you can create a new
branch on your local repository and just send a Pull Request. The Pull
Request is just awesome, it will be reviewed really quickly, we will
comment your Pull Request and if the code is correct and the tests pass,
then you PR will be merged in CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love and need your Pull Requests for CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="audience"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Audience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For new comers to CPython and the future contributors and of course for
the regular contributors and core-dev of CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this migration to GitHub, I will show the work done by the
migration team, the benefits of this migration and the new
tools/workflow. Few tools have been developed to help the core-dev. For
example, Miss Islington has been developed for an automatic back-port of
a branch from Python ‘master’ to Python 3.6 or 3.5, just with a “label”
on the Pull Request&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will show some stats about the contributors and the contributions on
the CPython project. For example, in November 2017, 4207 pull requests
from the community since the migration in Feb 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is explained with a story “Once upon a time” and with humour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="outline"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Outline&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;small history about the beginning of Python, the status and the
challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Former workflows, former tools:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the CLA (PSF Contributor Agreement)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the bug tracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patch review with the Rietveld tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;typical workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conclusion: We have an issue for the new comers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New workflow, new tools&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git, why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github, why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web interface, Pull Requests, Dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REST API, GraphQL API for the statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation with Travis, AppVeyor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Bots: Bedevere, Miss Islington, “The Knights who say ni!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New tool: Blurb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison between the former and new workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistics (between Feb 2017, and Nov 2017)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Pull Requests (4204)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Contributors (586) vs Core Dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge time, Top, Average, etc….&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="additional-notes"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Additional notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk has been presented at PyCon Canada in November 2017 at
Montreal in front of two core-devs of Python, Brett Cannon and Mariatta
Wijaya. Also reviewed by Victor Stinner core-dev python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk has been shared on the python-dev mailing list by Victor
Stinner:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-dev/2017-December/151051.html"&gt;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-dev/2017-December/151051.html&lt;/a&gt;
because the statistics were interesting for the core-dev.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation at PyCon Canada 2017: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2017.pycon.ca/schedule/4/"&gt;https://2017.pycon.ca/schedule/4/&lt;/a&gt;
Slides:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/matrixise/cpython-loves-your-pull-requests"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/matrixise/cpython-loves-your-pull-requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience, speaker at PyCon Canada 2015, 2016 and 2017 Python FOSDEM
2013, 2014, 2015 and 2017 PyCon Ireland 2015, 2016, and 2017 PyCon
France 2012, 2014, 2016, 2017 PyCon UK 2015 EuroPython 2015, 2016 and
2017. Montreal Python September 2015 and November 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizer of Python FOSDEM (+- 600 people) in Belgium Co-Organizer of
EuroPython 2015, 2016 and 2017 (as member of the Web workgroup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow Member of the Python Software Foundation since 2013 Member of the
Fellow Workgroup for the PSF Member of the Marketing Workgroup for the
PSF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, contributor of CPython, mainly on Devguide and sometimes on
the main repository with some fixes, new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my contribution to the migration of Python.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/2017-February/004220.html"&gt;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/2017-February/004220.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others presentations where I explain the interpreter and the bytecode of
Python &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/matrixise/architecture-of-cpython-part-1"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/matrixise/architecture-of-cpython-part-1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/matrixise/exploring-our-python-interpreter"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/matrixise/exploring-our-python-interpreter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="statistics"></category><category term="core-programming"></category><category term="CPython"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="github"></category><category term="git"></category></entry><entry><title>Helping communities &amp; products thrive by fostering empathy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sasha Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a fundamental part of human interaction. When we communicate
by email or at conferences, or indirectly, when we create products,
events, or do a talk. However, our understanding of other people is full
of error, and worse, bias. This can lead us to make communities and
products that work poorly for people that are different from ourselves,
introduce confusion and misunderstanding, exclude people
unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our communities are an opportunity to learn as well. To embrace
our diversity, and expand our understanding of other people’s worlds. To
gain understanding of other people’s situations, experiences and
emotions, which can be dramatically different to ours. And how we can
use this to create both products and communities which work great not
only for ourselves, but also those that we more easily forget about. As
creators in tech we have such tremendous power to create change, but
merely our best intentions will not be enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how and why we sometimes have such difficulty to
understand others, and how others can have difficulty to understand us.
We’ll talk about why other people’s experiences, emotion and perceptions
can be so different. Both for the world as a whole, but also with the
speaker’s personal experiences. Finally, we’ll cover specific ways for
us to understand others better, and associated pitfalls, to make our
communities and products happy, inviting and supportive places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="empathy"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Panino Digitale: una applicazione pratica di educazione creativa</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/panino-digitale-una-applicazione-pratica-di-educazione-creativa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mauro Angioni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/panino-digitale-una-applicazione-pratica-di-educazione-creativa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’istruzione tecnica è stata introdotta ai tempi della rivoluzione
industriale anche in funzione della necessità di avere operai
specializzati, una volta formato l’operaio svolgeva pressoché la stessa
mansione per tutta la vita. Dalla Rivoluzione Industriale a oggi, il
lavoro si è evoluto in modo considerevole. Tuttavia, queste grandi
trasformazioni del passato sono state graduali, mentre oggi i
cambiamenti sono repentini, trasversali e dirompenti. La formazione
scolastica è rimasta ancorata a schemi tradizionali. Il fine ultimo
della scuola dovrebbe essere quello di fare uscire ragazzi
intraprendenti e capaci di trarre soddisfazione dallo stesso
apprendimento, e le esperienze di alternanza scuola-lavoro nelle aziende
assumono un ruolo importante per la loro formazione, per le soft skill,
per mantenere alto l’interesse, per rendere lo studente protagonista e
consapevole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa è la storia di un gruppo di studenti di un istituto tecnico
superiore, appassionati di Python e provenienti da esperienze di
alternanza e di partecipazione alle conferenze di comunità, che hanno
immaginato di sviluppare autonomamente Panino Digitale, un’applicazione
basata sul framework Django, con cui gli studenti possano prenotare il
panino al bar della scuola. Per realizzarla concretamente, hanno
coinvolto i loro docenti, condiviso l’idea con la loro comunità
scolastica, raccolto nuovi contributori tra i loro compagni, e chiesto
supporto, affiancamento e strumenti alla community Python e ai suoi
membri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="istruzione"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Working for FOSS can make you a better programmer: Insights into my Outreachy internship with Fedora</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/working-for-foss-can-make-you-a-better-programmer-insights-into-my-outreachy-internship-with-fedora.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alisha Aneja</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/working-for-foss-can-make-you-a-better-programmer-insights-into-my-outreachy-internship-with-fedora.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outreachy program offers three-month internships for people from groups
underrepresented in tech. Interns are paid a stipend of $5,500 and have
a $500 travel stipend available to them. Interns work remotely with
mentors from Free and Open Source Software (FOSS) communities on
projects not limited to just programming but also user experience,
documentation, illustration and graphical design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently interning with Fedora under the Outreachy program, where
my task is to is to develop administrative tools for the 389 Directory
Server, an enterprise class LDAP (Lightweight Directory Access Protocol)
server, used in businesses globally to authenticate and identify people.
LDAP is a standard application protocol for accessing and maintaining
distributed directory information services over an Internet Protocol
(IP) network. I am helping Fedora improve the Directory Servers Python
command line tools. In addition to this, the team at Fedora is also
investigating into integrating existing C code with Rust (watch here:
Integrating Rust with existing C) to improve performance and
maintainability. Hence, I am also working on establishing proof of
concept for using Rust instead of C and also using Rust with existing C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with fixing bugs in the Directory Server and it enabled me to
get more understanding about LDAP concepts, since LDAP has a steep
learning curve. My first task was to add the command line support for
automember plugin to the Directory Server. Automembership allows a
static group to act like a dynamic group, for adding new members to the
group. Different automembership definitions create searches that are
automatically run on all new directory entries. The automembership rules
search for and identify matching entries and then explicitly add those
entries as members to the group. I started by added the classes (Auto
Membership Plugin, Auto Member Definition, Auto Member Definitions),
methods and the tests for these classes and methods (Pull Request). Then
I added the support for automember by command line which included
creating, removing, editing and showing the automember definitions. This
included writing the tests as well. By the end of this task, I learnt
about Python decorators, lazy evaluation in Python, using pytest testing
tool and writing command line parser and arguments using the argparse
library. (This will be shown with live coding and screenshots).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on another task which involves building an LRU
cache in Rust which stores C allocated strings and can retrieve them.
This project will be built using the meson build system. I will also
provide tests and asan builds. This task will act as a proof of concept
for investigating if meson can replace autotools as the Directory Server
build system. During this task, I hope to learn about build systems, LRU
caching concept and Rust types and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can deduce from my tasks and the key learnings, doing this
Outreachy internship with Fedora is helping me to stand at the forefront
of technology, learning about LDAP, Python and Rust (polyglot!), which
will definitely enable me to become a better programmer and a
collaborative community member for Fedora. And I hope to inspire other
underrepresented people in tech with my talk about the Outreachy
internship and my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="open source"></category><category term="#remote"></category><category term="#community"></category><category term="user-groups"></category></entry><entry><title>Pythonコミュニティが私に与えてくれたもの</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2012/pythonkomiyuniteigasi-niyu-etekuretamono.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>栗毛野 友美</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-16:pycon-japan-2012/pythonkomiyuniteigasi-niyu-etekuretamono.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;昨年PyCon JPに参加した事を契機に、コミュニティ活動に参加だけでなく企画をするようになりました。どこにでもいる普通の非PythonエンジニアがPyCon JPに参加した事をきっかけに得た事や変化した事、コミュニティの歩き方についてお話しします。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon jp"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="pythoncommunity"></category></entry><entry><title>Setting Expectations for Open Source Participation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2018/setting-expectations-for-open-source-participation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brett Cannon</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-01-22:pycascades-2018/setting-expectations-for-open-source-participation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Burn-out is common in open source due to a misunderstanding of what users, contributors, and maintainers should expect from each other. This talk will set out to help everyone set reasonable expectations of each other in order to make open source pleasant for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Keeping up with the pace of a fast growing community without dying</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Flavio Percoco</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/keeping-up-with-the-pace-of-a-fast-growing-community-without-dying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;New open source communities are born everyday. Some of them are meant to
last long and some others aren’t. There’s a moment in every community
where it needs to outgrow itself, expand its limits and aim way higher
than ever. This is no necesarily related to its goals but the ecosystem
it needs to stay alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a community has gone beyond its limits, the community members,
consumers and leaders will have to keep up with its pace. How do we help
it to remain sane? How do we keep our goals on track while allowing for
further growth? How do we allow it to keep expanding without further
damaging the community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all questions we ask ourselves everyday in the OpenStack
community and that we’ve managed to work on without killing ourselves on
the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="open-source"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Growing a Python community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about people, not tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share one recipe of building a community from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reveals hands-on experience about the organisational journey,
including insider details and financial questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is packed into the story, how one year ago a tempting
idea of making a little Python conference in Munich was born. Six month
later, with poor German skills, no business network and mostly foreign
crew a little idea was converted into PyCon.DE. This conference had a
noticeable Italian flavour, and it’s time to tell why.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="humor"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="beer"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>Don't try to look smart. Be smart</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Flavio Percoco</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/dont-try-to-look-smart-be-smart.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The technology industry is growing and already huge. The number of
humans in this industry and the number of areas they can work on are
overwhelming. The number of opportunities often don’t seem as many for
an industry that big, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how long you’ve been in this industry, you often feel
overwhelmed, unfocused, demotivated by the size of the industry, the
uncertainty it generates and the urge of doing something others consider
important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this talk, the audience will learn how to grow in an industry
that is often blasted with intellectual appearances, quantity over
quality and unstoppable, constant, changes. The talk provides tips to
cope with large communities and fields as well as experiences and
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Growth"></category><category term="community"></category></entry><entry><title>Genropy: 10 anni di sviluppo di un framework italiano</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giovanni Porcari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
consente allo sviluppatore di scrivere applicazioni complesse in tempi
brevissimi. Lo scopo del framework è di mettere a disposizione un
potente costruttore di GUI web, un ORM molto facile, veloce ed intivo ed
una serie di component che rendono possibile costruire la propria
applicazione in poche righe di codice. A questo si aggiungono tools di
amministrazione per la gestione di permessi, grafici, gestione del
workflow, gestore di stampe e molti altri che fanno di Genropy
un’ambiente usabile immediatamente in produzione anche in situazioni
complesse e critiche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abbiamo cominciato a scrivere Genropy nel 2005 e durante il primo Pycon
qui a Firenze nel 2007, abbiamo ne abbiamo mostrato la primissima
versione. Da allora, ogni edizione di Pycon è stata l’occasione per
presentare le nuove features e cercare di diffondere la copnoscenza di
questo framework . A distanza di 10 anni possiamo dire che esiste una
minuscola ma molto attiva community che utilizza Genropy come strumento
quotidiano per scrivere le proprie applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk vorremmo raccontarvi questa avventura, e darvi modo di
conoscere meglio Genropy e di capire se può essere anche per voi il
vostro nuovo modo di scriverre applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="genropy"></category><category term="gui"></category><category term="web-development"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Africa</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Makarudze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="startup"></category><category term="beginner"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="women"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="pyladies"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="Learning environment"></category><category term="user-groups"></category></entry><entry><title>Care and feeding of Pythons</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/care-and-feeding-of-pythons.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ewa Jodlowska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/care-and-feeding-of-pythons.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python Software Foundation was founded in an open source culture with a focus on volunteer work. As the Python ecosystem has grown, so have the volunteer efforts. However, some jobs are of a scale where they can’t reasonably be asked of a volunteer. The PSF also has an important role in financially supporting the Python community. In this keynote, we’ll see how the Python community is growing, what new challenges that brings, and how we can sustainably address them, so that the PSF can continue its mission to grow and nurture our community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Culture"></category><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a More Inclusive Python Community Culture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kojo Idrissa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groups that are more diverse are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/#q=diverse+%22problem+solving%22"&gt;better at solving
problems&lt;/a&gt;
than more homogenous groups. An inclusive group culture maximizes the
odds of attracting and retaining skills &amp;amp; personalities needed to
thrive. The Python community has a pretty good track record on issues
related to inclusion. So, how can you help continue that trend,
especially in your local community? I'll start with a brief &lt;em&gt;WHY&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;WHAT&lt;/em&gt; of Inclusion, but most of this talk focuses on &lt;strong&gt;HOW&lt;/strong&gt; to help
your local corner of the Python community be as Inclusive as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="inclusion"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Culture"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote - David Eaves</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--keynote---david-eaves.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-05:djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--keynote---david-eaves.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keynote - David Eaves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David talks about community management in open source communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="communitymanagement"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2011"></category><category term="eaves"></category><category term="management"></category></entry><entry><title>A Python Takeover</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/a-python-takeover.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Ramm-Christensen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/a-python-takeover.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Mark Ramm-Christensen - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I started working on SourceForge with a couple of python
developers. Back then the site was written in PHP and was in some ways
buried in technical debt. Everything is different today, we have a
complete set of tools for Ticket tracking, Wiki documents, Git,
Mercurial, Subversion, and IRC - all written in Python, and now released
as open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how the amazing libraries, tools, and talent in the
Python web community has radically changed an established company, and
allowed us to reinvent sourceforge.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will go over our tech stack, talk about the libraries we used,
the way we solved scalability, internationalization, and performance
issues issues. Ultimately we know that without python, we could not have
built a flexible plugin based system, and gotten permission from
management to open source it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="python,"></category><category term="sourceforge"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>sqlmap - security development in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlmap-security-development-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miroslav Stampar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/sqlmap-security-development-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Miroslav Stampar - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;sqlmap&amp;quot; is one of the largest, widely used and most active Python
projects in the IT security community (more than 2000 commits in one
year period with community of over 100 active testers). It combines it's
developers' strong security knowledge together with analytical,
mathematical and Python development skills to provide IT professionals
with vibrant features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk would be consisted of several parts: short introduction to project
and developers, developing and testing environment, programming cycle,
program's workflow, technologies used, common pitfalls and how we've
circumvent them, usage of mathematical models, optimizations, project's
future goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The significant part of this talk would be the immediate insight into
the developing process of probably the world's most advanced open-source
Python IT security project today.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="testing"></category></entry><entry><title>The London Python Code Dojo - an Education in Developer Education</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/the-london-python-code-dojo-an-education-in-dev.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicholas Tollervey</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/the-london-python-code-dojo-an-education-in-dev.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Nicholas Tollervey - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The London Python Code Dojo is a community organised monthly meeting for
Python programmers in the UK. Variously described as social coding,
developer training, &amp;quot;Scrapheap Challenge&amp;quot; for Pythonistas and &amp;quot;I didn't
learn coding like this when I was a lad&amp;quot;, we've forked the traditional
code-dojo format and turned it into something very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain and explore what happens in the dojo, how it's
organised and why various changes were made to the classic dojo format.
Reference will also be made to influences from music education and
philosophy of education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, by the end of the talk you'll all want to go organise a dojo!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Plumbing with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/data-plumbing-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pavlos Christoforou</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/data-plumbing-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Pavlos Christoforou - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Point Nine provides operations outsourcing and support to large and
complex financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our day to day responsibilities we are required to process
our client's trading activity which generally involves receiving data in
various formats and through various protocols, apply transformations,
validations and enrichment processes and distribute the resulting data
to various third parties, in short Data Plumbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to introduce the audience to the (vast) field
of financial data processing which we believe presents a tremendous
opportunity for python and it's community and provide a brief overview
of Point Nine's deployment of Python as the main framework for all data
plumbing activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="framework"></category><category term="processing"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting ready for PostgreSQL 9.1</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/getting-ready-for-postgresql-91.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriele Bartolini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/getting-ready-for-postgresql-91.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Gabriele Bartolini,Harald Armin Massa,Marco Nenciarini
- 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza Napoli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL is an advanced, versatile open-source database management
system that integrates perfectly with Python. It is developed by a very
active international community and is distributed under the BSD-like
PostgreSQL License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise-class features (including SQL standard compliance, ACID
transactions, disaster recovery, high availability, replication,
partitioning and general extensibility) make PostgreSQL suitable for
business critical environments seeking to reduce the TCO of their
database solutions without altering their functional needs. PostgreSQL
9.0, released in September 2010, was the first version of PostgreSQL
with Hot Standby, a built-in master/slave replication mechanism.
Asynchronous replication through the standard and consolidated log
shipping technique (previously used with Warm Standby for high
availability) has been enhanced with streaming replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 9.1, expected to be out later in 2011, will add synchronous
replication to PostgreSQL, making it the first DBMS that allows
developers and users to control the replication strategy at
transactional granularity. Come to the talk and discover all the major
new features of PostgreSQL 9.1, including extensions management,
writable common table expressions (WCTE), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="asynchronous"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="distributed"></category><category term="extensions"></category><category term="partitioning"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="replication"></category></entry><entry><title>Programmazione MapReduce in Python con Pydoop</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/programmazione-mapreduce-in-python-con-pydoop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Simone Leo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/programmazione-mapreduce-in-python-con-pydoop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Simone Leo - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Italiana Big Mac &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hadoop è la principale implementazione open source di MapReduce, il
paradigma di calcolo distribuito su larga scala di Google. L'API nativa
di Hadoop è in Java e le opzioni built-in per la programmazione in
Python - Streaming e Jython - presentano diversi inconvenienti: la prima
consente di accedere solo a un piccolo sottoinsieme delle funzionalità
di Hadoop, mentre la seconda ha tutte le limitazioni di Jython rispetto
a CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydoop.sourceforge.net"&gt;Pydoop&lt;/a&gt; è un'API per Hadoop che rende
disponibile buona parte delle funzionalità di Hadoop al programmatore
Python, consentendo lo sviluppo in CPython. I suoi moduli di base sono
wrapper Boost.Python per l'interfaccia C/C++ di Hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk consiste in un tutorial su MapReduce/Hadoop e in una
presentazione dell'API Pydoop, con l'obiettivo principale di avvicinare
le community di Hadoop e Python. Può essere utile, anche se non
strettamente necessaria, una conoscenza di base della programmazione
distribuita.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="hadoop"></category><category term="java"></category><category term="jython"></category><category term="mapreduce"></category><category term="python,"></category><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Python for High Performance and Scientific Computing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/python-for-high-performance-and-scientific-comput.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Schreiber</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/python-for-high-performance-and-scientific-comput.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Andreas Schreiber - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an accepted high-level scripting language with a growing
community in academia and industry. It is used in a lot of scientific
applications in many different scientific fields and in more and more
industries, for example, in engineering or life science). In all fields,
the use of Python for high- performance and parallel computing is
increasing. Several organizations and companies are providing tools or
support for Python development. This includes libraries for scientific
computing, parallel computing, and MPI. Python is also used on many core
architectures and GPUs, for which specific Python interpreters are being
developed. A related topic is the performance of the various interpreter
and compiler implementations for Python. The talk gives an overview of
Python’s use in HPC and Scientific Computing and gives information on
many topics, such as Python on massively parallel systems, GPU
programming with Python, scientific libraries in Python, and Python
interpreter performance issues. The talk will include examples for
scientific codes and applications from many domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/k94rC4"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="engineering"></category><category term="gpu"></category><category term="hpc"></category><category term="interpreters"></category><category term="parallel"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="python,"></category><category term="scientific"></category></entry><entry><title>The development process of Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/the-development-process-of-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ezio Melotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/the-development-process-of-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Ezio Melotti - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an open source language, where everyone can contribute, and
thanks to Mercurial now it's even easier. With this talk I want to
unveil what happens &amp;quot;behind the scenes&amp;quot; of CPython and how you can get
involved and be part of the open source community that allows Python to
be one of the most popular programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the workflow of the CPython development;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to get a clone of Python;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use Mercurial to do all the most common operations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the structure of the main CPython repository;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what other are repositories are used;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use the bug tracker to report and find bugs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use remote Mercurial repos to contribute code;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what tools are used;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to get in touch with the core developers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are the plans for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="contribute"></category><category term="cpython"></category><category term="mercurial"></category><category term="workflow"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConAU 2010: GLAMkit: a harder, better, faster, stronger way to write reusable Django code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--glamkit--a-harder--better--faster--.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Greg Turner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--glamkit--a-harder--better--faster--.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GLAMkit: a harder, better, faster, stronger way to write reusable Django
code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Dr. Greg Turner (the Interaction Consortium)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our web development work for Galleries, Libraries, Archives
and Museums (the so-called GLAM sector), we have open-sourced the common
tools and design patterns that we have developed as a web framework
called GLAMkit (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://glamkit.org/"&gt;http://glamkit.org/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLAMkit is based on Django, and is inspired by its design philosophy of
several apps which implement specific features. However, by looking at
the successes and challenges faced by other CMSes and collections of
apps such as Pinax, we have taken the philosophy a stage futher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than being a collection of Django apps, we have constructed
GLAMkit as a collection of optional and reusable Django 'toolkits' for
implementing common features. We leave the implementation details - the
things that Django already does brilliantly - to the application
developers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will present the history of GLAMkit's development, with
particular focus on how our approach to reusability came about, and some
examples of that approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="advocacy"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau2010"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Weiterentwicklung der PyCon DE Konferenzreihe</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/weiterentwicklung-der-pycon-de-konferenzreihe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-André Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-11-01:pycon-de-2012/weiterentwicklung-der-pycon-de-konferenzreihe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die PyCon DE Konferenzreihe wurde 2010 von einer Gruppe interessierter
Python Nutzer angestoßen und dann über eine Community Abstimmung in den
Jahren 2011 und 2012 an die Python User Group Leipzig vergeben. In
diesem Vortrag soll kurz auf die Entstehungsgeschichte eingegangen
werden und dann in Zusammenarbeit mit den Zuhörern das Konzept der Reihe
weiterentwickelt werden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Vortrag wird interaktiv gestaltet werden. Nach der kurzen Einführung
steht die Diskussion mit der Community und ggf. auch Abstimmung über
Vorschläge im Vordergrund. Die Resultate der Diskussionen sollen dann in
die Konzeption für die PyCon DE 2013 und 2014 einfließen.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="interaktion"></category><category term="konferenz"></category><category term="konzept"></category><category term="pycon de"></category></entry><entry><title>Python verbindet - Der Python Software Verband e.V. in 20 Minuten</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/python-verbindet-der-python-software-verband-e.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Müller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-15:pycon-de-2013/python-verbindet-der-python-software-verband-e.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der Python Software Verband (PySV) ist als eingetragener Verein in
Deutschland organisiert, und versteht sich als Support-Organ der
gesamten deutschsprachigen Python-Community. 2011 hat sich der PySV
langsam aber sicher organisatorisch aus dem früheren DZUG e.V., der
bereits vollständig aus Python Enthusiasten bestand, emanzipiert und
seine Neustrukturierung im letzten Jahr weitgehend abgeschlossen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die wichtigsten Mittel zur Unterstützung der Community sind u. a. unsere
aktiven Mitglieder und die PySV-Website als zentraler Anlaufpunkt und
der neue Usergruppen-Hub. Der PySV unterstützte und organisierte bereits
die Python-Konferenzen PyCon.DE 2011 und 2012 als verantwortlicher
Partner mit. Auch die PyCon.DE 2013 wird er in enger Zusammenarbeit mit
der Kölner PyCologne Usergroup und dem DLR ermöglichen. In den Jahren
2014 und 2015 wird der PySV sogar Mitausrichter der EuroPython – der
größten europäsichen Python-Konferenz – sein. Die Berliner Usergroup mit
dem PySV im Rücken konnte sich in der Bewerbung durchsetzen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auch kleinere, aber deswegen nicht unwichtigere Events unterstützt der
PySV. Neben dem mittlerweile schon traditionellen PythonCamp in Köln
sind das verschiedene Python-Sprints und u.A. der World Plone Day an
mehreren Orten. Auf Messen wie der CeBIT, der überregionalen FrOSCon
Konferenz und den Berliner und Chemnitzer Linuxtagen und dem Linuxtag in
Berlin sorgt der Verband dafür, dass Python regelmäßig präsent ist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der gemeinsam neu entwickelte Programmierwettbewerb nimmt Formen an.
Studenten erhalten vom PySV Unterstützung für die Teilnahme an der
EuroSciPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wie der Verband der Community helfen kann, wird mit allen, die mithelfen
wollen, gemeinsam erarbeitet. Er bietet organisatorische, finanzielle
und technische Hilfe für Usergruppen, Sprints und Workshops mit
Python-Bezug. Alle Python-Enthusiasten sind eingeladen im Verein aktiv
mitzuarbeiten. Neue Ideen und Verbesserungsvorschläge sind immer gern
gesehen. Unsere Grundregel lautet: “Soviel Unterstüzung wie möglich, so
wenig Reglementierung wie möglich.”&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="pysv"></category><category term="verband"></category></entry><entry><title>Diversity as a Dependency (#49)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--diversity-as-a-dependency---49.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna M Ravenscroft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--diversity-as-a-dependency---49.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity as a Dependency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Anna M Ravenscroft (PSF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PSF recently adopted a diversity statement. While some argue that we
should do this just because it's &amp;quot;the right thing to do&amp;quot;, others
question why we, as a technical community, should even worry about
diversity. This talk addresses the diversity question, not in moralistic
or ethical terms, but in pragmatic ones. Studies on creativity and
productivity demonstrate the potential benefits of diversity for the
Python community. Making Python the best language it can be is not
merely helped by increasing diversity, but may be dependent on
diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="psf"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category></entry><entry><title>Think Globally, Hack Locally - Teaching Python in Your Community (#122)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--think-globally--hack-locally---teachi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Leigh Honeywell</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--think-globally--hack-locally---teachi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think Globally, Hack Locally - Teaching Python in Your Community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Leigh Honeywell (HackLab.TO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For over a year, HackLabTO (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hacklab.to/"&gt;http://hacklab.to&lt;/a&gt;),
a hackerspace in Toronto, has been the home of an informal Python class
/ hack night every Thursday evening. Our participants represent a
diverse cross- section of the lab's community, and include everyone from
complete beginners who hadn't written code since BASIC in high school,
to seasoned veterans. Come hear about our successes and failures, and
learn how to start such an event in your local community.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="teaching"></category></entry><entry><title>Small acts make great revolutions: crafting Python and Open Source communities in Rio de Janeiro (#78)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/small-acts-make-great-revolutions-crafting-pytho.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guilherme Chapiewski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/small-acts-make-great-revolutions-crafting-pytho.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Small acts make great revolutions: crafting Python and Open Source
communities in Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Guilherme Chapiewski; Henrique Bastos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we are Python lovers, we at PythOnRio (Python's Rio de
Janeiro users group) strongly believe in differences. Programming
languages and technologies are not religions. Why do we have to compete
against each other when we can take advantage of diversity by sharing
our knowledge and learning to use the best tools for each job? By
promoting this thinking we are gathering people from many different open
source communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's our main recipe for the success of initiatives like Coding Dojo
Rio, PythOnCampus, Dev in Rio, #horaextra and many other social meetings
where we have gathered some of the smartest people in Rio's software
development community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this philosophy, Rio de Janeiro communities are growing and
starting to jell - they are becoming so strongly knit that the whole is
greater than the sum of the parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we would like to share not only our &amp;quot;methods&amp;quot; and
&amp;quot;formulas&amp;quot;, but the values and experiences that are leading us to build
a strong and active community while having lots of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="pythonrio"></category></entry><entry><title>Montreal-Python -- Lessons Learned from Bootstraping a Python Community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--montreal-python----lessons-learned-fr.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yannick Gingras</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--montreal-python----lessons-learned-fr.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montréal-Python is a user-group formed in 2007. It has since then grown
into a thriving community with code sprint and regular meetings
attracting over 50 attendees. This talk will present history of the
group and will highlight the key factors behind its success with the
hope to inspire others to replicate that accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will first walk the audience through the factors inherent to
Montréal itself and how it affected other user groups before
Montréal-Python. These groups inspired us to get a group of Python
hackers started the presentation will show how we were able to leverage
on the success of other user groups to bring our young community
forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various stages of our growth will be presented along with insights
on how we managed to find speakers and venues at each point. The
presentation will then go through an overview of our current activities,
sharing in the process how effective they are in engaging the community.
Our plans for the next few years will be presented then a summary will
provide advice to anyone who would like to get started organizing a
local Python user group.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="growth"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="usergroups"></category></entry></feed>