<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_freeipa.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Continuous Delivery starts at your Development Environment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/continuous-delivery-starts-at-your-development-environment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Bittner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/continuous-delivery-starts-at-your-development-environment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery is the automation of our deployment and QA, isn’t
it? The industrialized software production chain that solves all our
problems. Well, kind of. It’s more than that. Because: You still have
pain when …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You bring new developers on board (e.g. for installing Docker and
friends, IDEs and command line tools).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your development machine behaves weird or needs an upgrade. (Can you
simply re-install it and continue working without losing a day or a
week of productivity?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to explain to your colleagues, or even convince them, how to
configure which of their tools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone turns to you (or your admin wizard) when there are troubles
to get some tools or projects running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talks explains how to bootstrap a super-efficient startup, SMB, or
just any development team that needs a development infrastructure.
You’ll see a demo of The Foreman, Puppet, Ansible and optionally FreeIPA
and virtualization technology, which gets you from zero to 100 in just a
few hours. This talk explains how you do infrastructure like software
development. Everything under control. Everything under version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join the show, and take home the recipe that tells you how to step
up the next level of Continuous Delivery! - If you’re a beginner fear
not: this talk starts with an introduction to CI/CD and brings you up to
speed quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 22 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="continuous-delivery"></category><category term="agile"></category><category term="ansible"></category><category term="puppet"></category><category term="free-software"></category><category term="FreeIPA"></category><category term="infrastructure-as-code"></category></entry><entry><title>How to become enterprise-friendly with free software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-finland-2015/how-to-become-enterprise-friendly-with-free-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bokovoy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-19:pycon-finland-2015/how-to-become-enterprise-friendly-with-free-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland 2015
Alexander Bokovoy - How to become enterprise-friendly with free software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to enable single sign-on in your web applications and allow Kerberos logins in an enterprise next to you to work? This talk covers recent developments in FreeIPA, SSSD, and Ipsilon projects that allow application developers to integrate with traditional corporate infrastructure with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the author:  I'm Principal Software Engineer at Red Hat, working on FreeIPA, Samba, SSSD, Kerberos, and many other things. FreeIPA is a free software infrastructure project doing to Linux and other POSIX-compatible operating systems what Active Directory is for Windows environment. FreeIPA is written in Python and C.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="FreeIPA"></category><category term="SSSD"></category><category term="Ipsilon"></category></entry></feed>