<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_finance.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Why Python is huge in finance?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2019/why-python-is-huge-in-finance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Roos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-31:pycon-se-2019/why-python-is-huge-in-finance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is huge in finance, from banks to hedge-funds to day-traders; it is often the go-to tool to get things done. This talk dives into 'why?'. First looking at several areas where Python is big, what kind of work is involved, and the challenges for developers? Then at what libraries/language aspects make Python particularly suited. Pandas gets particular attention as it is incredibly useful and can make you super productive. We finish up with a demo of how you can use Monte Carlo techniques to build a mini stock market simulation and test out your own trading ideas. After the talk, you should have a better feel for what it's like working with Python in finance and also a good set of starting point if you want to start experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="finance"></category></entry><entry><title>Deep learning: the final frontier for time series analysis and signal processing?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-the-final-frontier-for-time-series-analysis-and-signal-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexandr Honchar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-the-final-frontier-for-time-series-analysis-and-signal-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep neural networks are becoming irreplaceable for analyzing most kinds
of data that humans supposed to exceed in - images, video, sounds,
texts. They can not only predict something based on some input but also
generate new images or sounds. Meanwhile, we are forgetting about
another very important source of data - signals (or time series, which
will be interchangeably here), that gets less hype in public but
benefits a lot from applying deep learning comparing to classical
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will review what are sources of time series and what
business goals are we solving while analyzing them, what are “old” tools
for analysis and how deep neural nets overcome them, we will learn the
latest trends and ruin some myths and, moreover, we will see how
generative models can be applied to the signal processing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, you’ll be able to boost your current solutions in
signal processing or time series analysis with deep learning. It will be
also interesting for practitioners in other areas, like computer vision
or NLP since we will discuss some concepts that are widely applicable.
Previous experience with time series is not required, but some
theoretical or practical experience with machine learning and/or neural
networks is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1716"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="biomedical-data-science"></category><category term="TimeSeries"></category><category term="signal-processing"></category><category term="neural network"></category><category term="finance"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Python Has Taken Over Finance</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/why-python-has-taken-over-finance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yves Hilpisch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/why-python-has-taken-over-finance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yves Hilpisch (&amp;#64;dyjh)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, the finance field was dominated by compiled languages, such as C or C++, since they were considered to be the right choice for the implementation of computationally demanding algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, Python and its fast growing eco-system of (data analysis) packages have made it today's language of choice for the financial industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk illustrates, based on some simple examples, the benefits of working with a high level programming language, such as Python, for the tasks at hand in finance. The examples illustrate that really concise Python code can achieve high performance results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="algorithms"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="finance"></category><category term="python"></category></entry></feed>