<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>pomegranate Fast and Flexible Probabilistic Modeling in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2017/pomegranate-fast-and-flexible-probabilistic-modeling-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;pomegranate is a python package that extends the ideas behind scikit-learn to probabilistic models such as mixtures, Bayesian networks, and hidden Markov models. pomegranate is built to be modular by separating out the probability distributions from the models themselves, allowing both arbitrary distributions to be used for any model, and making the modeling of different features with different distributions a breeze. pomegranate was built with large quantities of data in mind, supporting both an out-of-core API for when your data doesn't fit in memory, built-in multi-threaded parallelism made possibly by releasing the GIL, and most recently GPU support for large Gaussian models. This talk will be an overview of the most important features behind pomegranate and motivate the concept of probabilistic modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Schreiber</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-07-17:scipy-2017/pomegranate-fast-and-flexible-probabilistic-modeling-in-python.html</guid><category>pomegranate</category></item><item><title>The Duct Tape of Heroes: Bayes Rule</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/the-duct-tape-of-heroes-bayes-rule.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will give many examples of when Bayes rule will help you in your day to day work. I'll quickly show many examples of bayesian statistical thinking in action; the pleasure of inference, probabilistic graphs, model selection, feature generation, even operations research! I'll finish with a dataset from Heroes of the Storm and I'll show why Bayesian models can outperform randomforests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is made up of the following examples;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;basic disease example: what is the value of adding an extra test to a patient
give an example of an inference task that is very hard to do properly without bayesian thinking
creating simple probibalistic models with pandas and showing how they are robust against missing data. I will also demo pomegranate, a new probabilistic programming tool for python.
show how you can use bayes rule to pick models
demo a bayesian probablistic approach to finding overpowered characters in the Heroes of the Storm video game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://koaning.io/theme/notebooks/bayes.pdf"&gt;http://koaning.io/theme/notebooks/bayes.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vincent Warmerdam</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/the-duct-tape-of-heroes-bayes-rule.html</guid><category>pomegranate</category><category>bayes</category></item></channel></rss>