<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Delta Chat, CFFI, pytest and all the Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/delta-chat-cffi-pytest-and-all-the-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delta Chat, a new approach to decentralized messaging, uses Python in
several ways. Delta Chat is a Whatsapp/Telegram-style messenger app
which uses the existing e-mail server network instead of central
servers. There is no address book upload, and no necessity to tie
accounts to mobile numbers. We'll live- demo how &amp;quot;Chat over E-mail&amp;quot;
works, with random audience members, in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll then look into how Python is used for automated testing (with
pytest) against the messenger core library which is exposed through
CFFI. However, the core library will soon be ported to full Rust. Are
there better ways to interface Rust with Python than going through
C-interfaces?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third part we'll introduce first example Chat Bots, written in
Python. Do you want to send an machine-generated system allert to a
sysadmin group? Or safely archive all media that is posted to a family
group? Or have your IoT sensor react to commands or send info? Just do
it without registering a bot to some central cite, or by exposing all
content information to (e. g. Telegram) servers. A Chat Bot only needs
access to a standard IMAP/SMTP account. We'll look at the simple Python
API for writing and testing powerful and versatile Chat bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Delta Chat: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://delta.chat"&gt;https://delta.chat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Core library and Py bindings:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core"&gt;https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Deltabot: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/deltachat/deltabot/"&gt;https://github.com/deltachat/deltabot/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Holger Krekel</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:/europython-2019/delta-chat-cffi-pytest-and-all-the-rust.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Development</category><category>Python general</category><category>Rust</category><category>Sensors</category><category>System Administration</category></item><item><title>Python vs Rust for Simulation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/python-vs-rust-for-simulation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Both Python and Rust are getting more and more popularity. Although it
is unfair to compare them directly, this talk aims to provide a clear
comparison with a pre-defined criteria applied to a specific use-case.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Writing a simulation engine is very similar to writing a game engine
and requires certain features from a language or framework.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Possible comparison criteria:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. Performance&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. Simplicity&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3. Amount of code necessary for a MVP&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4. Utilities: docs, tests, profile&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;5. Compatibility&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Tl;dr&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Do I want to go back to Python after Rust? Maybe+)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alisa Dammer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:/europython-2019/python-vs-rust-for-simulation.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Development</category><category>Rust</category><category>python</category></item><item><title>Extending Python with Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/extending-python-with-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction and a hands-on demo of writing Python extension in Rust&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a rising star of the programming language world. I'd like to discuss it from a Python developer perspective. Obviously, Rust is not a replacement for Python, but in case you're seeking better performance it may be a good idea to build an extension. This is safer and arguably easier to do in Rust than in C.
In this talk we will take a look at existing crates that provide interface to Python and see how easy it is to use them.
Then we go through the demo and see it in action.
Run some benchmarks against pure Python and also Cython.
Write a Dockerfile to build it all together.
Discuss CI/CD for mixed Rust/Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mikhail Medvedev</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/extending-python-with-rust.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>All Other Programming Languages</category><category>Compiler and Interpreters</category><category>Deployment/Continuous Integration and Delivery</category><category>Docker</category><category>Rust</category></item><item><title>Rusty Python - A Case Study</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/rusty-python-a-case-study.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a very expressive and powerful language, but it is not always the fastest option for performance-critical parts of an application. Rust, on the other hand, is known for its lightning-fast runtime and low-level control, making it an attractive option for speeding up performance-sensitive portions of Python programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will present a case study of using Rust to speed up a critical component of a Python application. We will cover the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of Rust and its benefits for Python developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profiling and identifying performance bottlenecks in Python application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing a solution in Rust and integrating it with the Python application using PyO3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measuring the performance improvements and comparing them to other optimization techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will learn about the potential for using Rust to boost the performance of their Python programs and how to go about doing so in their own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Robin Raymond</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/rusty-python-a-case-study.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Rust</category></item><item><title>Specifying behavior with Protocols, Typeclasses or Traits. Who wears it better?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2023/specifying-behavior-with-protocols-typeclasses-or-traits-who-wears-it-better.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore the use of Python's typing.Protocol, Scala's Typeclasses, and Rust's Traits.
They all offer a very powerful &amp;amp; elegant mechanism for abstracting over various concepts (such as Serialization) in a modular manner.
We will compare and contrast the syntax and implementation of these constructs in each language and discuss their strengths and weaknesses. We will also look at real-world examples of how these features are used in each language to specify behavior, and consider differences in terms of type system expressiveness and effectiveness. By the end of the talk, attendees will have a better understanding of the differences and similarities between these three language features, and will be able to make informed decisions about which one is best suited for their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kolja Maier</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pycon-de-2023/specifying-behavior-with-protocols-typeclasses-or-traits-who-wears-it-better.html</guid><category>PyCon DE 2023</category><category>Rust</category><category>Scala</category></item><item><title>Interacting with C and Rust using CFFI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2017/interacting-with-c-and-rust-using-cffi.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of Python's main advantages has always been its ability to expose external libraries to Python code very easily, however, writing wrappers around these libraries has always been a pain point that CFFI aims to address. CFFI allows you to call code written in other programming languages without having to write anything other than Python code, it is famous for being able to call C code but is also able to call code written in other languages like Rust and Go. This talk will go over the advantages of using CFFI as opposed to the other ways of calling external libraries in Python (such as writing C extensions) and showcase more advanced ways of using CFFI to improve PyPy's compatibility with Python modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Guillebert</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-21:/pycon-ireland-2017/interacting-with-c-and-rust-using-cffi.html</guid><category>PyCon Ireland 2017</category><category>rust</category></item><item><title>Rusty Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/rusty-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python è un linguaggio “colla”, esistono librerie per creare estensioni
nei linguaggi più vari, da C/C++ a Fortran con poche righe di codice
abbiamo il nostro wrapper bello funzionante.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Da qualche tempo un nuovo linguaggio di aggiunge alla lista: Rust!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ci sono due strade, la prima è quella di fare in modo che la libreria
Rust esponga una API C, e per poi usarla con &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ctypes&lt;/tt&gt; o &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;cffi&lt;/tt&gt;.
L’altra strada passa per &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;rust-cpython&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;, un wrapper Rust per le API C
di Python, con cui è possibile sia chiamare Python da Rust che estendere
Python con moduli in puro Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk vedremo come è possibile esporre delle strutture Rust in
modo da offrire una interfaccia Pythonica senza venire a compromessi con
le prestazioni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisiti:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conoscenza base di Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conoscenza minima di Rust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Si può fare!!” un modulo Python in Rust, con setup e test su Travis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matteo Bertini</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:/pycon-italia-2017/rusty-python.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2017</category><category>Python</category><category>extensions</category><category>Rust</category></item><item><title>Pumping up Python modules using Rust</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/pumping-up-python-modules-using-rust.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve spent much time writing (or debugging) Python performance problems, you’ve probably had a hard time managing memory with its limited language support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we venture deep into the belly of the Rust Language to uncover the secret incantations for building high performance and memory safe Python extensions using Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust has a lot to offer in terms of safety and performance for high-level programming languages such Python, Ruby, Js and more with its easy Foreign Function Interface capabilities which enables developers to easily develop bindings for foreign code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">vigneshwer dhinakaran</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-13:/pycon-us-2018/pumping-up-python-modules-using-rust.html</guid><category>PyCon US 2018</category><category>rust</category></item><item><title>Pragmatic ways of using Rust in your data project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/pragmatic-ways-of-using-rust-in-your-data-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing efficient data pipelines in Python can be tricky. The standard recommendation is to use vectorized functions implemented in Numpy, Pandas, or the like. However, what to do, when the processing task does not fit these libraries? Using plain Python for processing can result in lacking performance, in particular when handling large data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a modern, performance-oriented programming language that is already widely used by the Python community. Augmenting data processing steps with Rust can result in substantial speed ups. In this talk will present strategies of using Rust in a larger Python data processing pipeline with a particular focus on pragmatism and minimizing integration efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Prohm</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/pragmatic-ways-of-using-rust-in-your-data-project.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>Rust</category></item></channel></rss>