<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Running Django Apps on Google App Engine</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/running-django-apps-on-google-app-engine.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running Django Apps on Google App Engine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by wesley chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, Django users couldn't run apps unmodified on Google App
Engine. Some tools helped with integration but required you to change
your data models. Django-nonrel removes this requirement letting you run
native Django apps on App Engine with only config changes if you bear in
mind its restrictions like no JOINs. In this talk, we'll discuss
Django-nonrel &amp;amp; porting App Engine apps to Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, Django users could not get their apps to run unmodified on
Google App Engine, the cloud application-hosting platform. Older tools
like &amp;quot;the Helper&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;the Patch&amp;quot; required a change to the data models
as well as perhaps integrating additional tools into the application
source tree. The creators of the Patch realized how cumbersome this is
and created a replacement for all of these older tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django-nonrel allows users to run pure Django apps on App Engine with
only minor configuration changes. It basically enables Django's ORM to
operate on top of non-relational databases (in addition to preserving
its ability to support standard relational DBs), one of which is Google
App Engine's Datastore. (MongoDB is another.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means that current Django users can now use their existing
knowledge to write apps for App Engine as long as they keep App Engine
restrictions in mind, e.g., no JOINs. Projects written in this manner
will work without any modifications other than changing the
configuration settings. On the other side, App Engine developers now
have an alternative to the '&amp;quot;webapp&amp;quot; framework that comes with its SDK.
You can now leverage the power of a full web framework like Django and
still enjoy the flexibility and scalability of App Engine. In this talk,
we'll discuss Django-nonrel, and how to port App Engine apps from webapp
to pure Django to run on App Engine using Django-nonrel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/running-django-apps-on-google-app-engine.html</guid><category>django-nonrel</category><category>gae</category><category>googleappengine</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item></channel></rss>