<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - Internet of Things (IoT)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building Industry 4.0 logistics applications with MicroPython and ESP32 MCUs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/building-industry-40-logistics-applications-with-micropython-and-esp32-mcus.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this session, we will report about a forklift hailing application
we built using MicroPython and the ESP32-based prototyping hardware
M5Stack.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In a production facility, machine operators can hail a forklift using
an ESP32 device running MicroPython. The device sends a request to a
forklift dispatcher software, written in Python. The request is queued
and subsequently, the next available forklift is notified and sent to
the machine. Each forklift is also fitted with an ESP32 device. In
this project, the prototyping hardware M5Stack was used. It features
an ESP32 micro controller with Bluetooth, WIFI, GPIO, three buttons,
and a display.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will learn how MicroPython and prototyping hardware can be
used to scale from an idea on the developers desk to a working system in
a rough Industry 4.0 production environment. The talk will recap our
journey with MicroPython, the lessons learned, and the pitfalls to
avoid. Furthermore, the tooling setup will be introduced, including our
M5Stack GUI-simulator to mock the M5Stack display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central dispatch server is built using Python and deployed in a
Docker container. Messages are exchanged using MQTT, a popular IoT
message protocol. The talk will conclude with a live demonstration of
the forklift hailing system. Attendees should be comfortable with the
Python syntax but are not expected to have any MicroPython, MQTT, Docker
or domain knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials can be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitlab.com/fwahl/europython2019"&gt;https://gitlab.com/fwahl/europython2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Florian Wahl</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/building-industry-40-logistics-applications-with-micropython-and-esp32-mcus.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Cross-Platform-Development</category><category>DIY</category><category>Hardware/IoT</category><category>Internet of Things (IoT)</category><category>MicroPython</category></item><item><title>How software can feed the world 🌱</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-software-can-feed-the-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infarm is a FaaS, Farming as a Service, and whether you believe it or
not, our business is in-house farming at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We design and build our farms, grow vegetables and sell them, and the
backbone of our infrastructure is based on Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check this video to see what we do -&amp;gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/christianbarra/status/1096399602159439874"&gt;https://twitter.com/christianbarra/status/1096399602159439874&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 10 million observations are recorded from our farms, feeding
our farm management system that allows operators, plant scientists, and
supervisors to monitor each farm in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk I will briefly introduce the world's problems we are
trying to resolve at Infarm and then talk about our IoT farms,
infrastructure, how we use Python and how we plan to improve the
capabilities of our farms by adding edge machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- What are the problems we are trying to solve at Infarm&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Our 4 tech pillars&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How we started with Python&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Issues we are facing while scaling our Python infrastructure to
support &amp;gt; 400 farms&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How we plan to evolve our software and infrastructure on 4 different
levels: consolidate, architecture, cloud native and observability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How Python is going to support our automated farms and its role in
making the farms smarter (edge computing with AI)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Barra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/how-software-can-feed-the-world.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Hardware/IoT</category><category>Internet of Things (IoT)</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Python general</category></item><item><title>Ensuring data integrity with asynchronous programming in a cloud IoT core</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/ensuring-data-integrity-with-asynchronous-programming-in-a-cloud-iot-core.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python3.6, AsyncIO, Flask, RabbitMQ. A simple and powerful combination for IoT data integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly this will be the decade of low-cost and high-performance cloud IoT core development.
All cloud IoT solutions will have to meet the same two fundamental requirements: Performance and Data Integrity. Having said that,  AsyncIO comes to mind.
While researching similar topics on cloud IoT solutions, we noticed that the vast majority of such solutions primarily includes performance. In this discussion we would like to demonstrate how you can ensure that a low-cost, fast developed cloud IoT core can ensure that its data is not corrupted and is accurate  for the user.
Technically speaking, it is very interesting to analyze how a bucket of async/await tasks can handle (consume or even produce) messages from or to message queues, interact with other (even non pythonic) modules inside the core, manage socket connections and many other functionalities that make Python3.6+ the heart of any IoT core. Note that it is equally important to check imported data with periodic tasks, acquire statistics from devices and sanitize database data in order to ensure data integrity.
Our goal: Firstly, to encourage new developers to get involved with cloud IoT cores and use Python and AsyncIO as the heart of their core. Secondly, as new developers we would like to show our logic and our prefered python libraries and techniques in order to receive feedback from more experienced developers.
We are a team of software engineers located in Athens, Greece working for a fast growing startup in San Francisco (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.veturilo.io"&gt;https://www.veturilo.io&lt;/a&gt;). We have developed our own cloud IoT core for a vehicle fleet management SaaS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Theofanis Petkos</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/ensuring-data-integrity-with-asynchronous-programming-in-a-cloud-iot-core.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>ASYNC / Concurreny</category><category>Internet of Things (IoT)</category><category>Python 3</category><category>Software Design</category><category>Use Case</category></item><item><title>IoTPy: Python + Streams + Agents for Streaming Applications</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/iotpy-python-streams-agents-for-streaming-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ingest and analyze streams of data generated by sensors, social media an other sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensors, social media, news feeds, webcams and other sources generate streams of data which are analyzed to control actuators, generate alerts, and feed displays. These applications process streams on onboard computers, such as the Raspberry Pi, connected directly to sensors, and send summarized information to the cloud for further processing. These applications have two characteristics: (1) Concurrency: The applications are concurrent using multiple threads to connect to sensors and actuators, shared memory across multiple processes on multicore machines and message passing for distributed systems spanning multiple computers. (2) Data Analysis: The applications use programs from a variety of libraries including those for signal processing, machine learning and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers of streaming applications can use open-source software to deal with both characteristics. Concurrency: multiprocessing.Array can be used to construct shared-memory multiprocessing Python programs in multicore computers, and frameworks such as APMQ and Kafka can be used to build distributed applications. Data Analysis: A vast collection of open-source Python libraries can be used to analyze data in streams. Developers of streaming applications encounter an impedance mismatch between the software libraries that address these two characteristics. The next paragraph describes the mismatch and how IoTPy addresses it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programs in most software libraries apply a function to data, get results, and terminate execution. By contrast, streaming applications are perpetual processes that analyze endless streams of data. IoTPy helps developers: (1) build non-terminating streaming applications by harnessing conventional terminating programs from Python’s huge base of libraries and (2) create multithreaded, multicore and distributed Python applications by simply connecting streams to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.AssembleSoftware.com"&gt;https://www.AssembleSoftware.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kanianthra Chandy</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/iotpy-python-streams-agents-for-streaming-applications.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Distributed Systems</category><category>Internet of Things (IoT)</category><category>Messaging and Job Queues (RabbitMQ/Redis/...)</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category><category>Sensors</category></item></channel></rss>