<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_image-analysis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>SimpletITK: Advanced Image Analysis for Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/simpletitk-advanced-image-analysis-for-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bradley Lowekamp</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-14:scipy-2014/simpletitk-advanced-image-analysis-for-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SimpleITK brings advanced image analysis capabilities to Python. In
particular, it provides support for 2D/3D and multi-components images
with physical. SimpleITK exposes a large collection of image processing
filters from ITK, including image segmentation and registration.
SimpleITK is freely available as an open source package under the Apache
2.0 License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SimpleITK provides scientific image analysis, processing, segmentation
and registration for biomedical, microscopy and other scientific fields
by supporting multi-dimensional images with physical locations [1]. It's
is a layer build upon the Insight Segmentation and Registration Toolkit
(ITK) [2].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are many Python packages to process 2D photographic images,
scientific image analysis adds additional requirements. Images
encountered in these domains often have anisotropic pixel spacing, or
spatial orientations, and calculations are best performed in physical
space as opposed to pixel space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SimpleITK brings to Python a plethora of capabilities for performing
image analysis. Although SimpleITK was developed by the biomedical
imaging community, it is also used for generic image processing. It
differentiates from OpenCV in offering 3D images and multi-component
images, and it differentiates from scipy by offering the abstraction of
image classes and their associated data structures. This applies to
images modalities such as CT scans, MRI, fMRI, ultrasound, and in
microscopy modalities such as confocal, SEM, TEM, and traditional bright
and dark field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the key functionalities supported by SimpleITK are over 260
advanced image filtering and segmentation algorithms as well as access
to scientific image file formats, including specialized formats such as
DICOM, Nifti, NRRD, VTK and other formats that preserve 3D metadata.
Example algorithms include Level Sets Segmentation including
multi-phase, Label Maps, Region Growing, Statistical Classification,
Advanced Thresholding, Geometrical Transformations, Deconvolution,
Anti-Aliasing, Edge Detection, Mathematical Morphology on both labels
and grayscale images and Fourier Analysis [4,5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SimpleITK is an open source project with an active community, that
builds upon the large amount of image analysis experience of the ITK
community [3] working in biomedical images analysis since 1999, and that
continues to grow year by year, aggregating state of the art algorithms
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SimpleITK development is sponsored by the US National Library of
Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="image analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>Lidless: A Video Analyzer and IRC Bot</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/chipy/lidless-video-analyzer-and-irc-bot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eric Stein</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-11-10:chipy/lidless-video-analyzer-and-irc-bot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A great Eye, lidless, wreathed in webcams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Pumping Station: One (Chicago's Hackerspace) people often send
messages to the mailing list or ask on IRC if anyone is at the space or
plans to be later. There's an opportunity there to solve problems
automatically rather than through human input. Member Eric Stein
designed a Python / OpenCV based application (lidless) to monitor four
video cameras in the space and offer a REST API, a web front end with
historical graphs, and an IRC bot in the IRC channel to relay
information about how busy the space is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a short demo of the application accompanied by motivations
and high level archtechture breakdown. Following the demo/archtechture
I'll dive into the parts of the code that people are most interested in
hearing about with Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="image analysis"></category></entry></feed>