<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vim your Python, Python your Vim</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/vim-your-python-python-your-vim.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you use to write source code, docs, books or e-mails? Single
brain, single pair of hands, single keyboard, but a different keyboard
layout for each language and a different text editor for each purpose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you use an IDE to work on Python code, then switch to an e-mail
client to write a message, then open a different editor to work on the
documentation and finally ssh to a remote server to edit a configuration
file? Do you switch languages frequently or are your colleagues named
Müller, François, Muñoz or even Šedivý?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you how I am happily typing in several languages on a single
standard US keyboard layout and why my CapsLock became so useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you how I use a single editor on all my machines to produce
all sorts of text, especially Python code with a few useful plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you my own plugin written in Python to hack my e-mails far
beyond imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 20 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miroslav Šedivý</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/vim-your-python-python-your-vim.html</guid><category>neovim</category><category>vim</category><category>editor</category><category>keyboard</category><category>internationalization</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>Vim your Python, Python your Vim</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/vim-your-python-python-your-vim.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miroslav Šedivý&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;eumiro)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to write source code, docs, books or e-mails? Single brain, single pair of hands, single keyboard, but a different keyboard layout for each language and a different text editor for each purpose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you use an IDE to work on Python code, then switch to an e-mail client to write a message, then open a different editor to work on the documentation and finally ssh to a remote server to edit a configuration file? Do you switch languages frequently or are your colleagues named Müller, François, Muñoz or even Šedivý?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll show you how I am happily typing in several languages on a single standard US keyboard layout and why my CapsLock became so useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll show you how I use a single editor on all my machines to produce all sorts of text, especially Python code with a few useful plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll show you my own plugin written in Python to hack my e-mails far beyond imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miroslav Šedivý</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/vim-your-python-python-your-vim.html</guid><category>ide</category><category>neovim</category><category>vim</category><category>editor</category><category>python</category></item></channel></rss>