<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - System Architecture</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Better WebSockets - Server-Sent Events, a carefree alternative</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/better-websockets-server-sent-events-a-carefree-alternative.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Have you ever found yourself in a situation where you:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- had to use WbSockets?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- had to to create a separate project and had the issue of interfacing
both?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- had to handle disconnections?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- had to handle reconnections?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- had to handle all the above and scale WebSockets?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your experience was horrible (like mine was), we shall take a look at
Server-Sent Events, an alternative to WebSockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The following arguments will be discussed:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- intro to the subject&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- inner workings&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- differences from WebSockets&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- implementation explanation for a generic HTTP server in Python&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- use cases&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrei Neagu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:/europython-2019/better-websockets-server-sent-events-a-carefree-alternative.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Mobile</category><category>System Architecture</category><category>Web</category><category>Web Protocols</category><category>Web Servers and MicroFWs</category></item><item><title>Pluggable Architecture</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/pluggable-architecture.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extend functionality without touching existing code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications and libraries with a pluggable architecture allow developers to add custom functionality. Plugins can customize user interfaces, create new workflows, and interface with legacy systems. Designing a plugin is often difficult - documentation is sparse, outdated, or non-existent. You end up diving into a unfamiliar codebase to figure out what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk examines Pluggable Architecture by creating a custom plugin system: we will design an interface, think about where to hook in custom behavior, and discuss testing techniques. Understanding these principles will enable us to write custom plugins for third-party libraries. Extend the functionality of your favourite library without touching existing code!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aly Sivji</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/pluggable-architecture.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Abstractions</category><category>Architecture</category><category>Development</category><category>Software Design</category><category>System Architecture</category></item><item><title>Social distancing from your system’s dependencies: An API’s Story</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/social-distancing-from-your-systems-dependencies-an-apis-story.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How isolating your dependencies can affect your architecture choices and lead to nicer tests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever imagined life without your tests breaking due to an external dependency having changed? My team chased the dream. We used mocks, stubs, other dependency isolation techniques, and the result was … a lot of ugly tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We soon realized our tests required more care and they invoked some difficult questions. Is it possible that the limitations of the testing framework add or give away flaws on your design? Should your architecture be affected by your efforts to test the system? What did we learn in the process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will introduce some testing isolation concepts and discuss how the choice of each can affect your architecture design. We will go through the basics of the unittest.mock library and the pytest framework and explore their potential. By diving into scenarios, attendees will learn where these features can be applied more effectively, and more importantly, how an API design can and should be driven by the value of testability, allowing the tests to be structured around clarity, readability and a happy Continuous Integration platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target audience includes beginner Pythonistas, who are looking for ways to structure and test their code cleanly, while intermediate developers will enjoy a fun refreshment on dependency isolation and leave the session with practical examples on how to use it more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Olga Matoula</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/social-distancing-from-your-systems-dependencies-an-apis-story.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>System Architecture</category><category>TDD</category><category>Test Libraries (pytest/nose/...)</category><category>Testing</category></item></channel></rss>