<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - DawnWages</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>At The Root : Wagtail + Gatsby + GitPod</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/at-the-root-wagtail-gatsby-gitpod.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dawn Wages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/KBXD9E"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/KBXD9E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring if a GatsbyJS progressive web app generator frontend with a headless Wagtail backend could be a solution for small-sized clients and personal projects when I want to &amp;quot;whip something up&amp;quot; quickly without sacrificing design, performance/hosting costs, user or site editor experience (Can I have it all)? Gatsby (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/"&gt;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&lt;/a&gt;) is a open source framework based on React. Wagtail (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wagtail.io/"&gt;https://wagtail.io/&lt;/a&gt;) is a Django CMS with LOTS of cool features for content creators, and &amp;quot;plays nicely with everything else in your tech stack&amp;quot; (source: Wagtail) because its built on and easily integrates with all uses of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Not only do I enjoy the new and shiny things as a consultant, both Wagtail and GatsbyJS are established frameworks and active communities that put considerable effort in providing a great product with a smooth developer experience. We enjoy the benefits of Django / Wagtail CMS, with a incredibly fast pre-fetched progressive web app with GatsbyJS. The goal is nice, fast and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am approaching this talk by walking through how I started out with minimal experience with GatsbyJS or GraphQL, and moderate experience with React and headless Wagtail to creating and deploying (Netlify) this app. I am not an expert in either technology, but was able to quickly navigate getting started as well as identify lots of resources in both communities to build out in a more complex experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Sep  5 10:25:00 2020 at Floperator&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dawn Wages</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/at-the-root-wagtail-gatsby-gitpod.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2020</category><category>DawnWages</category><category>PyCon</category><category>PyConAU</category><category>PyConline</category><category>Python</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2020</category></item></channel></rss>