<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_scalable.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building a hosting platform with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/building-a-hosting-platform-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Godwin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-20:europython-2011/building-a-hosting-platform-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Andrew Godwin - 20 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At ep.io we built a Python hosting platform from the ground up, designed
to run large numbers of web applications on a small number of physical
machines both securely and in a reasonably scalable way. This talk will
show you how we built our infrastructure - using Redis, eventlet,
PostgreSQL and more - and what lessons we learnt from our first few
thousand deploys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how we split services into multiple processes and greenthreads; the
pains of building a cooperatively-multitasking PTY module; how Redis
isn't the answer to everything, but is still very useful; how to
persuade third-party software to work securely in a shared environment;
and how important it is to have good logging, especially when you have
more than five servers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ep.io"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="redis"></category><category term="scalable"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Leveraging an instant messaging protocol to build a scalable cloud architecture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/leveraging-an-instant-messaging-protocol-to-build.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Achiel van der Mandele</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/leveraging-an-instant-messaging-protocol-to-build.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Achiel van der Mandele - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;XMPP is an open technology for real-time communication. Although
primarily known for its application in the IM service &amp;quot;Jabber&amp;quot; (and,
subsequently, gchat/gtalk), it has numerous applications and creates new
opportunities for inter-system communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While researching for an alternative to webservices at Mendix, we came
across XMPP and realized it solved many of the shortcomings of
webservices. It is currently being used to handle all inter-system and
inter-process communication in the Mendix cloud hosting environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will give a general overview of what XMPP is, an introduction
to the sleekxmpp python library and how the core features of xmpp can
help an architecture scale well horizontally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required knowledge: basic understanding of hosting environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="real-time"></category><category term="scalable"></category><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Scalable Web Apps</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/building-scalable-web-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Cramer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-07:europython-2011/building-scalable-web-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] David Cramer - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building scalable web applications may seem like a distant problem, but
the problem is not thinking about it before it's too late. This talk
will focus on designing a scalable web application before it needs to be
(and avoiding the premature optimization dilemma). It will cover topics
such as efficient usage of your database, appropriate caching (and
invalidation!), and what the speaker considers as best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="optimization"></category><category term="scalable"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>MongoDB + Pylons at Catch.com: Scalable Web Apps with Python and NoSQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--mongodb---pylons-at-catch-com--scalab.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Niall O'Higgins</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--mongodb---pylons-at-catch-com--scalab.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MongoDB + Pylons at Catch.com: Scalable Web Apps with Python and NoSQL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Niall O'Higgins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Catch.com backend provides an API for publishing and querying your
personal data - used by many hugely popular Android, iOS and Web
clients. We ported this system to Python and MongoDB, using the Pylons
Web framework. This talk details our reasoning for choosing - and
experiences with - these cutting-edge Web and NoSQL database
technologies in a high-traffic, real-world production system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with the limits of our initial Catch.com Java/BDB backend
implemention, we evaluated various alternative technologies including
Amazon SimpleDB, MySQL, Cassandra and MongoDB. Eventually we settled on
Python, Pylons and MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found Python and MongoDB gave us unique flexibility with our data
model, allowed us to scale for increased reliability and performance and
decreased feature development time - and in this talk we'll describe
exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are many advantages, Python/Pylons and MongoDB (as a
relative newcomer on the database scene) certainly have issues and
limitations which must be taken into careful consideration for any
real-world production deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We compare MongoDB with other database technologies such as more
traditional RDBMS like MySQL and competing NoSQL options such as
Cassandra, CouchDB and BDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give a detailed introducton to data modeling in MongoDB - with
special attention paid to how this differs from a traditional relational
system - the operators provided by its rich query language and utilizing
advanced features such as GeoSpatial indexing, Replica Sets, Sharding -
and how to deal with some of the more publicized limitations of the
system (such as single-server durability).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While much of this talk will be about using MongoDB with Python, we will
also touch on issues surrounding production deployment of the Pylons Web
framework, including how we work around the GIL to take advantage of
multi-core machines.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="casestudy"></category><category term="mongodb"></category><category term="nosql"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="pylons"></category><category term="scalable"></category></entry></feed>