<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Panel: Dashboards for PyData</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/panel-dashboards-for-pydata.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will see how to use Panel (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://panel.pyviz.org"&gt;https://panel.pyviz.org&lt;/a&gt;) to add widgets and layouts to the output from just about any plotting program, and then how to share the result as a fully standalone application. You should walk away knowing you can very easily make any of your analyses interactive and shareable, in just a few lines of code!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James A Bednar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/panel-dashboards-for-pydata.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>dashboards</category></item><item><title>Python3 Panel Talk</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/hsvpy-huntsvilles-python-meetup/python3-panel-talk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A moderated panel discussing what the Python 2 EOL means, the future of Python3, and how the community responds&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pat Viafore</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-26:hsvpy-huntsvilles-python-meetup/python3-panel-talk.html</guid><category>Python 3</category><category>panel</category></item><item><title>Python Steering Council - Keynote - PyCon 2019</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2019/python-steering-council-keynote-pycon-2019.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python Steering Council Keynote panel&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Barry Warsaw</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-us-2019/python-steering-council-keynote-pycon-2019.html</guid><category>keynote</category><category>steering council</category><category>panel</category></item><item><title>import género, diversidad (panel)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2018/import-genero-diversidad-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debate sobre género y diversidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hablemos del avance del movimiento de mujeres e identidades disidentes, de violencias, diversidad e inclusión en el mundo informático.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelistas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucía García Itzigsohn (licenciada en comunicación social, periodista, directora de la Comisión de DD. HH. en la Legislatura de la Ciudad de Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berenice Larsen Pereyra (analista programadora en formación, trabaja haciendo satélites, formó parte de distintos espacios feministas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adriana Aiassa (mujer trans, analista funcional y técnica en operaciones, co-administradora de los grupos de Facebook Transgente y TRANSLABURO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrés Snitcofsky (diseñador gráfico en deconstrucción, apasionado de la visualización de datos, integrante de Economía Femini(s)ta)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modera: Mariela Osete (licenciada en trabajo social, militante feminista, trabajadora del Programa Nacional de Prevención del Cáncer Cervicouterino).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lucía García Itzigsohn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-24:pycon-ar-2018/import-genero-diversidad-panel.html</guid><category>panel</category></item><item><title>Webフレームワークパネル</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2012/webhuremuwakupaneru.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;去年好評だったパネルディスカッションを今年も行います。
今年はFlaskの作者であり基調講演を行うArmin Ronacherを初めとした各フレームワークの第一人者を迎え、 Flask, Django, Pyramid, Google App Engine の利点と欠点を赤裸々に討論して頂きます。
この討論を聴いて頂ければ、状況に応じたwebフレームワークの選択が出来るようになるはずです。&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yoshifumi Yamaguchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-16:pycon-japan-2012/webhuremuwakupaneru.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>framework</category><category>flask</category><category>django</category><category>pyramid</category><category>googleappengine</category></item><item><title>パネルディスカッション:Google App Engine を選ぶ理由</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2012/panerudeisukatsushiyongoogle-app-engine-woxuan-buli-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;本パネルディスカッションでは、実際にGoogle App Engineを使ったアプリケーション開発に携わっていらっしゃる方々に登壇いただき、「なぜGoogle App Engineのプラットフォームを選択したのか？」、「Google App Engineによって開発がどう変わったか(PaaSとは何か)」と「Google App Engineに向いてるアプリケーションと向いてないアプリケーション」について、これまでの経験談を中心に語って頂きます。 このパネルディスカッションを通じて、参加者の皆様にGoogle App Engineのリアル(いいところ、悪いところ)を知ってもらえればと思います。&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">楠元 朗</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-15:pycon-japan-2012/panerudeisukatsushiyongoogle-app-engine-woxuan-buli-you.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>googleappengine</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion: What is Static Typing in Python?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pybay-2017/panel-discussion-what-is-static-typing-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This panel discussion was MC by Daniel Pyrathon and held as part of the opening night at PyBay, SF Bay Area's regional Python Conference, on Friday, August 11, 2017.  For more information on PyBay, visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pybay.com"&gt;https://pybay.com&lt;/a&gt;, subscribe to be notified of upcoming conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is static typing in Python?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python added support for annotation as part of function definitions with PEP 3107. PEP 484 later provided a standard syntax for type annotations, bringing static analysis, runtime type checking, and faster refactoring to Python. Since Python is a dynamic programming language, type hints don’t have any influence at runtime, but they allow certain tools to save time with fewer bugs. For example, IDEs such as PyCharm are able to perform safer refactoring, and static analysis tools such as Mypy can perform further type checks during build phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, static typing has been adopted by some renowned open source projects such as Zulip and is used at companies such as Google, Instagram, Lyft, and Quora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will we be speaking about during this panel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be making this panel discussion accessible to everyone, so expect the panel to start with an introduction to static typing and then go deeper into best practices, support, and experience from open source project maintainers and companies. Since this feature has been a topic of substantial debate in the community, we’ll be discussing not only the pros but also the cons of this feature. Indeed, there are situations where type hinting may do more harm than good, and our panelists will be sharing with us their words of advice on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why might this panel discussion be interesting to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type hints are one of the new additions to the Python syntax may drastically increase the speed at which you program. Beginners will learn more about where the language development is heading.
Open source project maintainers and contributors will learn the tooling, support, and best “getting started” advice from our expert panelists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project managers, CTOs, and engineers will learn how type hints can make their team more productive. We know companies spend a huge amount of money recruiting and sourcing engineers, and I’m sure they would do everything possible to make their onboarding experience more enjoyable, easier and faster since employees can expect to be more productive with an annotated codebase.
This panel will not only help developers learn more about static typing, but also help identify areas where static type checking isn’t doing a good job, and learn how we can all improve it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our panelists
And now for the part that I’m most proud of, our list of panelists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Łukasz Langa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Łukasz is one of the PEP484 authors, a Python core developer, and currently a Production Engineer at Facebook. Łukasz has also been using mypy at work and I imagine has also been part of the latest push to port Instagram’s code base to Python 3! Łukasz is a long-time Python contributor, was a mentor for the Python Software Foundation for Google Summer of Code, and has spoken about Python around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Jelle Zijlstra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jelle is a Staff Engineer at Quora, where he works on infrastructure, internationalization, development tools, and ML infrastructure. He’s a contributor to mypy and has also used mypy at Quora. Jelle will offer his perspective on advocating for static type checking at a great engineering organization like Quora and will also be talking about typeshed, a project that hosts type stubs for the standard library and major third-party libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Ethan Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethan has been involved with mypy for a while and has been working on typical, a project that uses the frame evaluation API (PEP 523) to dynamically generate stubs. While Ethan is still in college, he has been doing some amazing work to improve the support of type hints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Andrey Vlasovskikh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrey is the PyCharm community lead and maintainer of IdeaVim. PyCharm is used by many Python developers and its support for type checking “out of the box” makes it easy for developers to adopt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Matthias Kramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthias is the author of pytype, one of the maintainers of typeshed, and has been working on Python static analysis tools for Google. Pytype is used in a few hundred projects at Google, including YouTube! Matthias will give us great insight into adopting type checking “at scale”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Łukasz Langa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-11:pybay-2017/panel-discussion-what-is-static-typing-in-python.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>static-typing</category></item><item><title>Panel Discussion Developer - Career Progression</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/panel-discussion-developer-career-progression.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a panel of four experts answering pre-submitted questions from the assembled audience under the guidance of a chairperson. Audience participation will be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to break into programming? Are you a junior developer wondering about the next steps in your career? Perhaps you're at a crossroads in your career and wonder what to do next? Is there a problematic issue about the workplace that you think should be discussed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit your questions via this form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think &amp;quot;Question Time&amp;quot; on BBC1 at 10:30pm on a Thursday and you have a pretty good idea of what it will be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samathy Barratt&lt;/strong&gt; (Chair)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samathy is a magical code fairy passionate about diverse people and well documented code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently finishing her BSC in Computer Science at Coventry University, she's always interested in learning new technologies and ideas. Despite being a student herself, she loves teaching what she's excited about to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can usually find her getting involved with LGBT+ activism, going to conferences or drinking a good coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jessica Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Rose is a self taught technologist and technical manager with FutureLearn. She's founded the Open Code meetup series, co-founded Trans*Code and hosts the Pursuit Podcast. She's a mentor and advisor for those looking to enter the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kristian Glass&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kristian is the CTO at LaterPay, leading a team distributed across over a dozen countries. Prior to that he ran Moorhen Solutions where he helped growing tech companies scale their systems and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was the treasurer for PyCon UK 2016, and co-founder of the PyCon UK Society Ltd and the UK Python Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meri Williams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meri is a geek, a manager, and a manager of geeks. She's a CTO, delighted to be leading the tech team at MOO, and also runs ChromeRose, a micro-consultancy which helps digital &amp;amp; technical teams be brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has had a career spanning development, programme &amp;amp; product management and more recently engineering &amp;amp; operations leadership. She’s led teams ranging in size from 30 to 300, mostly with people spread across the world, in a range of organisations from Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, to startups, to the Government Digital Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A published author and international speaker, she sponsors scholarships to help more girls start STEM careers in her hometown of Stellenbosch, South Africa. She's proud to be the host and co-curator of The Lead Dev conference for technical leads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michelle Coventry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelle is a talent advisor at Kindred Capital and Five AI. She has 16 years of experience sourcing and nurturing talent in high growth, investor backed tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously she was a founding partner at Maven Ventures - a leading headhunting firm recruiting for private equity and venture capital backed Tech and Digital companies across EMEA and the US. She also works with large organisations undergoing digital transformation (for example, Marks and Spencer) to help them recuit and nurture technical colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samathy Barratt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-29:pycon-uk-2017/panel-discussion-developer-career-progression.html</guid><category>panel</category></item><item><title>Diversity Panel: experience and discussion from all over the world</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion table about Diversity in all its hues with organizers and
experts from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Carr</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/diversity-panel-experience-and-discussion-from-all-over-the-world.html</guid><category>diversity</category><category>panel</category></item><item><title>Ethics in Machine Learning Panel</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advances in AI are happening at a tremendous pace, and especially Machine Learning systems are hastily deployed in settings that span as wide as social media, search engines, advertising, military use, and legal systems. At first sight results are often promising, but more and more &amp;quot;outliers&amp;quot; are becoming visible as well. Systemic bias in culture, language, or business practices often become intensified: From the Tay-chatbot turning racist, to both Google and Flickr classifying images of African-Americans as &amp;quot;monkeys&amp;quot;, to discrimination and sexism encoded in language models used for everything from translation, to court sentencing decision. Luckily, initiatives that address some of these concerns is happening through more interpretable models, new privacy regulations, novel privacy-preserving learning algorithms, and researchers and engineers standing up for more just and transparent machine learning models and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel aims to debate these themes with speakers, and the audience, and go beyond the usual &amp;quot;AI hype&amp;quot; and discuss both the amazing progress, as well as the setbacks, in making societies better, more humane, and ready for the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the panel will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roelof Pieters, Panel Host, Co-founder at creative.ai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marek Rosa, CEO/CTO at GoodAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Françoise Provencher, Data Team Lead at Shopify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hendrik Heuer, Researcher at Institute for Information Management (ifib) at the University of Bremen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andreas Dewes, Founder at 7scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katharine Jarmul, Founder at kjamistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to Q&amp;amp;A: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw"&gt;https://youtu.be/uOKhB1_vyAw&lt;/a&gt; (Second pyvideo tab)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roelof Pieters</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/ethics-in-machine-learning-panel.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>ethics</category><category>machine learning</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Django in Journalism</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-in-journalism.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator:
Adrian Holovaty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists:
Matt Waite, Maura Chace, Matt Croydon, Ben Welsh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrian Holovaty</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-in-journalism.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Django Success Stories</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-success-stories.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator:
Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists:
Matt Croydon, Michael Greer, Joshua Jag Ginsberg, Leah Culver, Andy McCurdy, Jason Yan&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Kaplan-Moss</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-success-stories.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Django Technical Design</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-technical-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderated by Michael Trier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists: Jacob Kaplan-Moss, Adrian Holovaty, Simon Willison, James Bennett, Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Trier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-technical-design.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Schema Evolution</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-schema-evolution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator:
Michael Trier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists:
Simon Willison, Russ Keith-Magee, Andrew Godwin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Trier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-schema-evolution.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>Panel: Python in the webs</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2011/panel-python-in-the-webs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will be a panel discussion wherein we wax philosophical about the
state of web frameworks in Python - talking about invention,
reinvention, multitudes of choice, how all of them suck, etc. Panelists
will include Dylan Jay, Malcolm Tredinnick, Russell Keith-Magee and
Richard Jones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dylan Jay</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-08-22:pycon-au-2011/panel-python-in-the-webs.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Panel: Form Generator Generators (#28)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--panel--form-generator-generators---28.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panel: Form Generator Generators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Perkins; Brandon Craig Rhodes (Rhodes Mill Studios, Inc.);
Chris P McDonough (Agendaless Consulting); Jacob Kaplan-Moss
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:jacob&amp;#64;jacobian.org"&gt;jacob&amp;#64;jacobian.org&lt;/a&gt;); Jonathan Ellis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that almost every python web framework in existence has solved
the problem of automatically generating forms. Some have straight
forward techniques, some are unique or even an unusual approach to the
problem. The question is: &amp;quot;what can we learn from each other?&amp;quot;. This
panel will examine the different ways developers generate forms by
offering examples, and summarizing the functionality, differences, and
similarities between these valuable web development tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Feedback galore when moving between mics, cover your
ears]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--panel--form-generator-generators---28.html</guid><category>forms</category><category>panel</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>restish</category><category>turbogears</category><category>web</category><category>web2py</category><category>zope</category></item><item><title>How to sell Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--how-to-sell-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to sell Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Daniel Greenfeld , C. Titus Brown , Dan Mesh , Chris
Shenton , Rich Leland , Frank Wiles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people want to use Python, but their customer, management,
school, government, or organization won't let them. Python is a great
tool, but it can be challenging to get in the door. This panel will
explore how companies and individuals have successfully introduced
Python, what tools are available to sell Python, and what pitfalls there
are to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people want to use Python, but their customer, management,
school, government, or organization won't let them. Python is a great
tool, but it can be challenging to get in the door. This panel will
explore how companies and individuals have successfully introduced
Python, what tools are available to sell Python, and what pitfalls there
are to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible questions will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a good example success story you can share?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What pitfalls should you avoid?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you deal with organizations that have already spent
bucketloads of money on a piss-poor technology stack, are hurting for
it, but can't seem to let go?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you fight Fear-Uncertainty-Doubt (FUD) spread by people who
stand to lose from introducing Python?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tools are available to help sell Python?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five panelists will be chosen from a broad spectrum of individuals
including academic, government, for-profit organizations, and non-profit
organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academia: C. Titus Brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goverment: Chris Shenton of Koansys/NASA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large Commercial Organization: Dan Mesh of Evite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small Commercial Organization: Frank Wiles of RevSys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Profit Organization: Rich Leland of National Geographic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Shenton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--how-to-sell-python.html</guid><category>panel</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>sellingpython</category></item></channel></rss>