<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_altair.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Exploratory Data Visualization with Vega, Vega-Lite, and Altair</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/exploratory-data-visualization-with-vega-vega-lite-and-altair.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jake VanderPlas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/exploratory-data-visualization-with-vega-vega-lite-and-altair.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploring a new dataset visually can provide quick intuition into the
relationships within the data. There are a few well-developed
visualization packages in Python, but they often have very imperative
APIs that force the user to focus on the mechanics of the visualization
– tick locations, axis limits, legends, etc. – rather than the salient
relationships within the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will introduce data visualization with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://altair-viz.github.io"&gt;Altair&lt;/a&gt;, a
package designed for exploratory visualization in Python that features a
declarative API, allowing data scientists to focus more on the data than
the incidental details. Altair is based on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vega.github.io/"&gt;Vega&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/"&gt;Vega-Lite&lt;/a&gt;
visualization grammars, and thus automatically incorporates best
practices drawn from recent research in effective data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will provide an introduction to the Altair package and its
API, but more importantly will dive into the core concepts of effective
data visualization that can be applied using any visualization package
or tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="vega"></category><category term="vega-lite"></category><category term="altair"></category></entry><entry><title>Telling stories with data: from analysis to web visualisations</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/telling-stories-with-data-from-analysis-to-web-visualisations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Éléonore Mayola</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/telling-stories-with-data-from-analysis-to-web-visualisations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When analysing datasets one usually creates static visualisations. But wouldn't it be nice to use the same project to share interactive web visualisations without learning new tools. Altair is a Python API using JSON to build visualisations in a Jupyter notebook or in the browser. My talk will take the audience through using Altair to analyse a dataset and generate web based visualisations with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="altair"></category></entry><entry><title>Keynote: Project Jupyter</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/keynote-project-jupyter-scipy-2016-brian-granger.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Granger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/keynote-project-jupyter-scipy-2016-brian-granger.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brian Granger is an Associate Professor of Physics at Cal Poly State University in San Luis Obispo, CA. He has a background in theoretical physics, with a Ph.D from the University of Colorado. His current research interests include quantum computing, parallel and distributed computing and interactive computing environments for scientific computing and data science. He is a leader of the IPython project, co-founder of Project Jupyter and is an active contributor to a number of other open source projects focused on data science in Python. He is a board member of the NumFocus Foundation and a fellow at Cal Poly’s Center for Innovation and Entrepreneurship. He is &amp;#64;ellisonbg on Twitter and GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announcement of Altair, Altair is a declarative statistical visualization library for Python. Altair is developed by Brian Granger and Jake Vanderplas in close collaboration with the UW Interactive Data Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Altair, you can spend more time understanding your data and its meaning. Altair's API is simple, friendly and consistent and built on top of the powerful Vega-Lite JSON specification. This elegant simplicity produces beautiful and effective visualizations with a minimal amount of code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="SciPy 2016"></category><category term="altair"></category><category term="jupyter"></category><category term="jupyter notebook"></category></entry></feed>