<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tox</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/chipy/tox.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a great new open source tool that helps you support all versions of
python with your existing automated tests. It's not a test runner, it's
a super test runner runner! Or something. There is no easy way to
describe it which is why the front page of the website is sort of
confusing, IMO. We use tox on the Nose project to make sure each code
change doesn't break the tests in Python 2.4, 2.5, 2.6, 2.7, 3.0 or
Jython. Not everybody targets so many environments but if you want to
maintain a widely used module then you probably will want to use tox
someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's our Hudson matrix setup w/ tox:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hudson.testrun.org/job/nose-unstable/"&gt;http://hudson.testrun.org/job/nose-
unstable/&lt;/a&gt; (we just set
this up recently which is why most builds were broken in one or two
envs) I can also spend some time going over how we are currently
maintaining a test suite that runs in both 2.x and 3.x simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be our Best Meeting Ever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://codespeak.net/tox/"&gt;http://codespeak.net/tox/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chipy.org/"&gt;http://chipy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kumar McMillan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-11-11:chipy/tox.html</guid><category>chipy</category><category>testing</category><category>tox</category></item><item><title>Supporting All Versions of Python All The Time With Tox</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--supporting-all-versions-of-python-all.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supporting All Versions of Python All The Time With Tox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Kumar McMillan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk explains the modern techniques that every module maintainer
needs to know in order to support all major versions of Python. You
probably already have a massive test suite using a tool like nosetests,
py.test, unittest, or a custom runner. Using the tox command line tool,
you'll see how to run your tests in Python 2.x, 3.x, Jython, and
whatever else in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tox is a new tool that lets you set up isolated virtual environments to
test your module's deployment and compatibility with all major versions
of Python. It's easy to install and is flexible enough that it probably
already supports your existing test suite. With one simple command you
can execute your test suite in each version of Python, you can build its
documentation with Sphinx, and get a nice printout of the results. It
has also been designed from the ground up to integrate into continuous
integration (CI) tools like Hudson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using practical examples, this talk will show you how to toxify your
existing test suite and trick it out with the tox.ini config file.
You'll also see how to leverage Hudson's matrix build so that each code
checkin will run tests in all versions of Python and report detailed
failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your app supports Python 3, right? No? Tox is the best way to develop in
parallel with 2.x and 3.x. We'll go over how to set up tox for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kumar McMillan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--supporting-all-versions-of-python-all.html</guid><category>ci</category><category>hudson</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>testing</category><category>tox</category></item></channel></rss>