<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From days to minutes, from minutes to milliseconds with SQLAlchemy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/from-days-to-minutes-from-minutes-to-milliseconds-with-sqlalchemy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Object Relational Mappers (ORMs) are awesome enhancers of developer
productivity. The freedom of having the library write that SQL and give
you back a useful, rich model instance (or a bunch of them) instead of
just a tuple or a list of records is simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you forget you have an actual database behind all that
convenience, then it'll bite you back, usually when you've been in
production for a while, after you've accumulated enough data that your
once speedy application starts slowing down do a crawl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Databases work best when you ask them once for (or to do) a bunch of
stuff, instead of asking them lots of times for small stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll discuss how innocent looking attribute accesses on your model
instances translate to sequential queries (the infamous N+1 problem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we'll go through some practical solutions, taken from real cases,
that resulted in massive speed ups. We'll cover how changes in Python
code resulted in changes to the resulting SQL Queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see solutions not only for queries, but also for inserts and
updates, which tend to be less well documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though this talk focuses on SQLAlchemy, the lessons should be applicable
to most ORMs in most programing languages. The ideas discussed, and
solutions proposed are also valid for any storage back-end, not only SQL
databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is geared towards Python developers with systems that talk to
databases. It should be accessible to anyone who already programs in
Python (early intermediary level), but will be most useful for
developers with projects talking to SQL databases, specially using an
ORM like SQLAlchemy. Attendees will learn to detect how N+1 query
situations arise and how to work around them effectively. They will also
learn how to do mass inserts and mass updates with SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Leonardo Rochael Almeida</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/from-days-to-minutes-from-minutes-to-milliseconds-with-sqlalchemy.html</guid><category>Debugging</category><category>Performance</category><category>SQL Alchemy</category><category>python</category></item></channel></rss>