<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Solving the web most popular code shortening competition with Python 3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/solving-the-web-most-popular-code-shortening-competition-with-python-3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Code shortening” is the “sport” where participants strive to achieve
the shortest possible source code that solves a programming problem by
exploiting all the tricks and quirks of the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoj.com/problems/SIZECON"&gt;SIZECON problem&lt;/a&gt; on SPOJ
is one of the oldest and most popular code shortening problems on the
web with a bizarre twist, only character above ASCII value 32 are
counted for the penalty. During the talk we will take a journey into
some frightening depths of the Python language in order to write shorter
and shorter solutions to SIZECON until, exploiting a number of
mind-blowing tricks, we will reach the current record solution for
Python 3 of 31 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise I’ll show you the most obfuscated, contrived and sick python
code you have ever seen and (hopefully!) will ever see. I invite
participants to give &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoj.com/problems/SIZECON"&gt;SIZECON&lt;/a&gt;
a try and check their score against the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spoj.com/ranks/SIZECON/lang=PYTH%203.2.3"&gt;Python3
rankings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an updated version of a talk I presented during Europython 2015
and that had an unexpected success both on-site and on social media. The
talk is now centred on Python 3 shorting tricks and is has been reworked
to be much more easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Amici</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/solving-the-web-most-popular-code-shortening-competition-with-python-3.html</guid><category>coding-competitions</category><category>fun-and-humor</category><category>python3</category></item></channel></rss>