<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Vault to better protect your secrets.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/using-vault-to-better-protect-your-secrets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All developers have seen it and few will admit to doing it. Putting
unprotected authentication credentials like usernames and passwords or
cloud service authentication keys into application code, scripts or
Ansible playbooks. We do this because it saves us time and effort. Add
in external source control tools, like Github, and the risks of these
credentials being publicly exposed increases. While most developers
agree on the importance of automated testing and syntax checking, its
time to add protecting application secrets, to the list of best
practices. In this talk, we will explore how to use Hashicorp Vault, a
secure storage and encryption tool, to help manage authentication in a
way that is safe and secure. Time will be spent on learning how to setup
a Vault server, migrate secrets into the service, and modify python
scripts and Ansible playbooks to take advantage of Vault. This talk is
for developers of all levels who are interested in a better way to
manage their secrets and become the next hero with their security
department. (Your results may vary.) Presenter has no affiliation with
Hashicorp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1657"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1657&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 09:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bryce Verdier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/using-vault-to-better-protect-your-secrets.html</guid><category>identity-management</category><category>configuration-management</category><category>Hashicorp-Vault</category></item></channel></rss>