<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_python-3.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python3 Panel Talk</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/hsvpy-huntsvilles-python-meetup/python3-panel-talk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pat Viafore</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-26:hsvpy-huntsvilles-python-meetup/python3-panel-talk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A moderated panel discussing what the Python 2 EOL means, the future of Python3, and how the community responds&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="panel"></category></entry><entry><title>AsyncIO in production - War Stories</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/asyncio-in-production-war-stories.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michal Wysokinski</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/asyncio-in-production-war-stories.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My team has been running AsyncIO in production for over 2 years now and
the only thing I can say about my experience with it is: &amp;quot;Oh boy, what a
rollercoaster of feelings&amp;quot;. I've experienced laughs and tears, sweat and
blood but also sang songs of glory. AsyncIO is currently the biggest
buzzword in the Python world advertised as a silver bullet capable of
solving all Python's shortcomings in the field of performance. However,
it also brings a burden of being a completely new approach with a fresh
implementation which is not often mentioned and taken into
consideration. In some of my team's projects we've achieved a great
success thanks to AsyncIO, but there's been a few where we decided to
get rid of it and replace it with a more traditional fork-join
architecture. I'd like to share my experience with AsyncIO, tell some
War Stories and discuss which projects it suits perfectly and which ones
should avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Debugging"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Use Case"></category></entry><entry><title>Code quality in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/code-quality-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Radosław Ganczarek</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/code-quality-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Four years ago I talked about code quality during EuroPython in
Bilbao. A lot of things changed from that time. Firstly, most tools I
presented were still developed and gained new features, but also new
ones appeared I wanted to discuss with you. Secondly, Python changed,
Python 3 has type hints on board and there is a new tool dedicated to
checking the types. Thirdly - I changed. I'm more distanced form my
zealous approach from four years ago. I got real and reasonable.
That's why I wanted to talk about code quality tools in Python again.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I'll talk about all the software that can make code review a bit
simpler by pointing out possible errors, duplicates or unused code.
I'll talk again about formatters and how can they be used in
modern-time projects. And I'll talk about hobgoblins, if you know what
I mean :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Code Analysis"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Tooling"></category><category term="Type-Hinting"></category></entry><entry><title>Moving big projects to Python 3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/moving-big-projects-to-python-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lennart Regebro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/moving-big-projects-to-python-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next year Python 2 is no longer maintained. But you have a monster code
base with clever tricks and libraries that don't support Python 2, and
your data may be stored in a format that is hard to move Python 3. And
that's the easy bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk focuses on the process of moving, not the code changes.
Because it's the process that is the hard part. How do you get your code
in a state where it's ready to move? How do you get the whole team on
the boat to Python 3?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Python 3 talks I have seen, including those I have given, and all
the texts on how to port, including the book I wrote, focus on the code
changes. With increasing backwards compatibility in Python 3 and
forward-compatibility in Python 2, this actually became a lesser problem
for big code bases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The extra issues of large, old code bases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you stop adding features? (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate team vs getting everyone on it (2 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2 compatibility: You need it (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix your development process (2 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace old libraries, or take over maintenance and port them (2 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your tests are solid (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 2to3 but only backwards compatible fixers (2 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run tests on Python 3 to stop backsliding (4 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run all tests: Expansive or slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store passed tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detect tests that change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turning it off adds a lot of extra work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port all your little utilities and tool scripts (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix fix fix fix (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add tests with Python 2 data, to test migration (2 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might need migration scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra careful staging tests (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Production: Try, fail, repeat (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean the code up (3 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="Deployment/Continuous Integration and Delivery"></category><category term="Management"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Testing"></category></entry><entry><title>The Story of Features Coming in Python 3.8 and Beyond</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-story-of-features-coming-in-python-38-and-beyond.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrey Vlasovskikh</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/the-story-of-features-coming-in-python-38-and-beyond.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's coming in Python 3.8? You can learn it by yourself by reading an
excellent document [What's New in Python 3.8][1]. I'm not going to
retell this document. Instead I'll focus on things barely described
there or not mentioned at all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why will the new features appear in Python 3.8 and what's the story
behind them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is being discussed and developed now, but won't appear in Python
3.8?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll share the news I learned at PyCon 2019 from the talks and
discussions with Python core developers. I'll mention the following
topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New syntax: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;x := expr&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;f(...,&lt;/span&gt; /, &lt;span class="pre"&gt;...)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;f'{expr=}'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New types: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;Literal&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;Final&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;TypedDict&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future features of typing and async/await&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New approaches to optimizing Python: sub-interpreters, mypyc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Compiler and Interpreters"></category><category term="New Features"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Type-Hinting"></category></entry><entry><title>Exceptional Exceptions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/exceptional-exceptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mario Corchero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/exceptional-exceptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Did you know there are multiple ways to raise and capture exceptions?
Have you ever wondered if you should raise a built-in exception or
create your own hierarchy? Did you ever find it hard to understand
what an exception meant?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk will go through the decisions needed to raise and capture
exceptions when creating a library. We will look at how to translate
and handle errors, create your own exceptions, and make exceptions
clear and easy to troubleshoot, while also understanding how they
actually work, common pitfalls.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will enable intermediate developers to leave the room with a
solid understanding of how to work effectively with exceptions. As the
exception flow usually goes untested, this will help prevent frustrating
situations when errors occur that are not easy to understand or when an
unexpected result is produced. The talk will delve into the different
ways of working with exceptions. We will illustrate this with a
real-world example to which many developers will be able to relate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the talk, intermediate developers will leave the room more
informed and better prepared to create and handle exceptions, having
learned about many utilities that were already available to them, but
were never used or were used improperly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The not-so-advanced Pythonistas will get an in-depth dive into
exceptions. Even if they might not be able to grasp all of the content,
they will get a sense of the features that most programmers are unaware
of and learn to use them when the proper situation arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced programmers will find this to be a humorous talk that will
certainly teach them at least one new thing, as I will dive into parts
of the grammar of Python that even many advanced programmers are not
used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk is also full of niche information like why the variable that
catches exceptions doesn’t like outside of the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;except&lt;/tt&gt; scope.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk is comprised of four main sections preceded by an
introduction to the problem and a conclusion with time for questions
at the end. We will look at how to raise, capture, create and design
exceptions, offering tips and pitfalls in each section.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="General"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category></entry><entry><title>Refactoring in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/refactoring-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tin Marković</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/refactoring-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[Replacement talk]&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk was a replacement for Stanislav Geidl's talk: From legacy
code to modern code&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honest apologies to anyone whose expectations were subverted, but
Stanislav fell sick and could not attend. Find the updated abstract
below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe experiences and lessons learned from tackling
extremely demanding code. How to bring order to mismanaged code and
elevate the code base to a standard that's acceptable in today's tech
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python makes wonderful code accessible at our fingertips, but it also
allows us to take a lot of liberty. When you start, code is beautiful
and makes sense. With each step you walk on, you find more and more
hacks showing up. Eventually, the brilliant codebase you've started with
can not be seen under the mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every code-base can be rewritten, not everything can be redone from
scratch. Cool libraries often take a lot of liberty with code structure
and make cross-integration difficult, if not impossible. Tests sound
ideal, but in practice, they're just so hard to make right. Why is this,
and how to change it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk will tackle the problems in three parts:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- The Easy Wins: What to do to instantly increase the code quality in
your organisation. How? Why isn't it enough?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Patterns and Antipatterns: How to identify code that &amp;quot;smells&amp;quot;, how
to replace it? How to integrate into old code, better?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- The Philosophy: What approach to set down for the future? Why to
care? How to write replace-able code. How to prevent history from
repeating.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will close with audience discussion and experiences, questions
and proposals - building a collection of some on-premise tips and
tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Clean Code"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="legacy-code"></category></entry><entry><title>Publish a (Perfect) Python Package on PyPI</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/publish-a-perfect-python-package-on-pypi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Smith</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/publish-a-perfect-python-package-on-pypi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always wanted to publish a package on PyPI, but didn't know where to
start? This talk is for you! Starting with nothing, we'll build a
package and publish it on PyPI using current best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to structure your project and your code. Discover what goes in
your &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/tt&gt; and your &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;setup.py&lt;/tt&gt;. Ensure your code will
work in different on different platforms! Document your code so people
won't ask you loads of questions! Finally, learn how avoid doing any of
this yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should you package your code for PyPI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to structure your project and your code, including why you need a
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;src&lt;/tt&gt; folder!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover what goes in your &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt; and your &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;setup.py&lt;/tt&gt;, and
why. Learn the difference between installing your library to use it,
and installing it to develop on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write tests for your project, and run them using Tox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure your code will work in different on different platforms with
Continuous Integration!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document your code so people won't ask you loads of questions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to actually get your code on PyPI using Twine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, learn how avoid doing any of this yourself (or avoid doing
it twice) using CookieCutter templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Packaging"></category><category term="Python 3"></category></entry><entry><title>Teaching Programming to the Next Generation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/teaching-programming-to-the-next-generation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lilian Nandi anonymous</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/teaching-programming-to-the-next-generation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our generation of young people in school (aged 5-18) have noticed the
connection between Computer pRogramming, Technology &amp;amp; Success and
Billionaires.On mass they are clamoring to master the skill of Computer
pRogramming. We describe a successful working model for the teaching of
Computer pRogamming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Science is now regarded as one of the leading disciplines in
the 21st century. Computers are ubiquitous and prevalent in most, if not
all, sectors of our modern society – applications include using them in
weather forecasting, robotic surgery, space exploration, e-commerce,
smart cities, driverless cars, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, coding or computer programming is now regarded by many as an
essential skill for the young person, and it has been dubbed the ‘4th’
R’ (computer pRogramming) along with Reading, wRiting and aRithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recognition of the new status of computer programming, governments
worldwide have launched initiatives to have it taught in schools from
Kindergarten through to junior school and all the way through secondary
school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the question emerges is how do we best teach and motivate the next
generation in acquiring this skill? Given the fact that this field is
very much in its infancy, there are insufficient number of skilled
Computer Science teachers and very little pedagogy to guide the
educator. Therefore, the whole world is learning how best to teach this
subject by trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will describe a case study whereby coding/computer programming,
in the form of Python programming, was introduced to a group of 110
young people from the ages of 11 to 18 (Years 7-13 in a U.K secondary
school). The talk will include descriptions of the various teaching
methodologies introduced to the young people for this purpose and the
outcomes; the talk will also address various challenges and questions
about how to teach coding to young people. The talk will conclude with
helpful suggestions, based on the findings of the case study, on how to
proceed with the teaching of computer programming to these people.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="All Other Programming Languages"></category><category term="Education"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Teaching"></category></entry><entry><title>What about recommendation engines?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/what-about-recommendation-engines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adriana Dorneles</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/what-about-recommendation-engines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;How recommendation engines are taking part in our daily routine and
how companies as Netflix and Amazon implement it?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk aims to show the elements that compound a recommendation
engine to people who have never been in touch with the matter or want
to know a bit more. At the end of this session, you might be able to
reproduce your own recommendation system and also know where to find
more about it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Talk structure:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. What is and why use a recommendation engine?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. Recommendation engine importance&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3. Steps of a recommendation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4. Recommendation algorithms&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;5. Basic Statistics for distance and correlation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;6. Example&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Business"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Python 3"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing a Python autoreloader</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/writing-a-python-autoreloader.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Forbes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/writing-a-python-autoreloader.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reloading your code changes quickly is an integral part of the
development experience in frameworks like Django and Flask that
developers have come to rely on. But how do they work under the hood and
what challenges do you face while writing one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will explore how I refactored the autoreload
implementation in Django 2.2 and the lessons I learned along the way
(hint: it's surprisingly complex!). I will also be introducing a library
I've developed to simplify this if you ever find yourself writing your
own.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Software Design"></category></entry></feed>