<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_the-answer-to-life-the-universe-and-everything-else.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>How to Avoid Becoming a 10x Engineer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/how-to-avoid-becoming-a-10x-engineer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivana Kellyerova</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/how-to-avoid-becoming-a-10x-engineer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why you should ignore advice by random internet people, by a random internet person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has never failed at being, among other things, a giant treasure of unsolicited advice by random people on all sorts of things, programming being no exception. Wanna become a better coder? Learn to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why you should ignore advice by random internet people, by a random internet person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has never failed at being, among other things, a giant treasure of unsolicited advice by random people on all sorts of things, programming being no exception. Wanna become a better coder? Learn to maximize your WPM (c). Never look at documentation because that's just embarrassing. And for crying out loud, change your screen background to black!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you are, a fairly okay programmer, looking for ways to become better at coding. How do you achieve that? Well I'm no 10x engineer myself (thank goodness), but I do believe that there's a handful of things we can safely rule out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category></entry><entry><title>Running EuroPython 2020 as an online conference</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/running-europython-2020-as-an-online-conference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Andre Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/running-europython-2020-as-an-online-conference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Challenges we faced switching to an online event due to COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had been planning the EuroPython 2020 conference in Dublin, Ireland ever since late in 2019, when we ran the CFP. In March, it became apparent that the COVID-19 crisis would not be over by July 2020 and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Challenges we faced switching to an online event due to COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had been planning the EuroPython 2020 conference in Dublin, Ireland ever since late in 2019, when we ran the CFP. In March, it became apparent that the COVID-19 crisis would not be over by July 2020 and so we had to make a hard decision to either drop the event for 2020 or go online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we wanted to support the community even in difficult times, we decided to go for the online version -- even though this would be much less engaging than the in-person event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past months, we have been creating a concept for the conference from scratch. The talk will present our approach, how it came to be and which challenges we faced. The concept should be usable by other conference as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="EuroPython"></category><category term="EuroPython Society (EPS)"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category></entry><entry><title>The Hitchhiker's Guide to CLIs in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-clis-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinayak Mehta</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-clis-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn all about CLIs and how to create one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command-line applications and interfaces are used by both newcomers and experienced Python developers everyday. But do you know how they came to be? Hop on to this ship as we go through the CLI galaxy and look at its history …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn all about CLIs and how to create one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command-line applications and interfaces are used by both newcomers and experienced Python developers everyday. But do you know how they came to be? Hop on to this ship as we go through the CLI galaxy and look at its history, explore the CLI anatomy and discover some Python packages that can help us create them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll then look at some widely used CLIs of our time. And emulate one of them by creating our own CLI using Click. Finally, we’ll package it and publish it on PyPI. Are you ready to travel faster-than-light using this ship’s Infinite Improbability Drive? Carry your towel!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Command-Line"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Python general"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry><entry><title>There’s a Snake in the Birdhouse!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/theres-a-snake-in-the-birdhouse.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mason Egger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/theres-a-snake-in-the-birdhouse.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building a Python Culture at Vrbo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise why many of us are so enamored with Python. Its simplicity, accessibility, and community make it a prime choice for many projects. However, not all software engineering shops use Python, maybe even some of the jobs you work at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building a Python Culture at Vrbo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise why many of us are so enamored with Python. Its simplicity, accessibility, and community make it a prime choice for many projects. However, not all software engineering shops use Python, maybe even some of the jobs you work at. Introducing Python to your company and building a Pythonic culture from the ground up is no small task, but it can be done. Join me as I take you through the journey of getting Python from zero to hero within my previous company. I’ll share the experience from start to finish, including what worked, what didn’t, what I would have done differently, and how I evangelized Python to bring it to be a supported language within my company’s ecosystem. Viewers will leave having learned from my experiences—both successes and mistakes—and with a solid plan for implementing Python at their job.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Business"></category><category term="Business Cases"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category><category term="Use Case"></category><category term="failures/mistakes"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing Zenlike Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/writing-zenlike-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jason McDonald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/writing-zenlike-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write beautiful, Pythonic code with insights from the legendary Zen of Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a profound gap between working code and Pythonic code. To the developer whose first language is NOT Python, the distinction can appear blurry, even arbitrary. What is this &amp;quot;one obvious way&amp;quot; all those Python nerds are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write beautiful, Pythonic code with insights from the legendary Zen of Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a profound gap between working code and Pythonic code. To the developer whose first language is NOT Python, the distinction can appear blurry, even arbitrary. What is this &amp;quot;one obvious way&amp;quot; all those Python nerds are going on about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us are familiar with the &amp;quot;Zen of Python&amp;quot;, Tim Peters's legendary, if tongue-in-cheek, set of guiding principles for the Python language. But can they actually inform Pythonic code?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Jason C. McDonald will unpack how the twenty principles (including the unwritten rule) of the Zen can guide you to write beautiful, maintainable code, by treating Python AS Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is intended primarily for developers who have come to Python from another language, no matter their experience level. McDonald will shed light on how to work WITH Python's type system, statements, and iterative tools, rather than against them. You'll walk away with a new appreciation of the language, and an understanding of what Pythonic really means; an understanding which will empower you to find the One Obvious Way to solve any problem in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Beginners"></category><category term="Clean Code"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Python general"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category></entry><entry><title>Your Name Is Invalid!</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/your-name-is-invalid.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miroslav Šedivý</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/your-name-is-invalid.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Names of people cannot be invalid. Your app shouldn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have names. Most people do. People have first names and last names. Many people do. People have any sorts of names that often don't fit fixed fields in the forms. These names may contain letters, accented letters, and other …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Names of people cannot be invalid. Your app shouldn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have names. Most people do. People have first names and last names. Many people do. People have any sorts of names that often don't fit fixed fields in the forms. These names may contain letters, accented letters, and other characters, that may cause problems to your code depending on the encoding you use. They may look differently in uppercase and lowercase, or may not be case foldable at all. Searching and sorting these names may be tricky too. And if you design an application, web form, and/or database dealing with personal names, you'll have to take that into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is not about GDPR, but will help you to use the best tools to handle encoding and locales in Python and prevent your application from appearing in my talk and in uxfails memes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Diversity"></category><category term="Internationalization"></category><category term="Natural Language Processing"></category><category term="The Answer to Life the Universe and Everything Else"></category><category term="failures/mistakes"></category></entry></feed>