<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_computervision.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Deep Learning for brain MRI segmentation: Big Data, AI and HPC meet together</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-for-brain-mri-segmentation-big-data-ai-and-hpc-meet-together.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Giuseppe Di Bernardo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-for-brain-mri-segmentation-big-data-ai-and-hpc-meet-together.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With ever-increasing advancements in technology, neuroscientists are
able to collect data in greater volumes and with finer resolution. There
has been a growing interest in leveraging this vast volume of data
across levels of analysis, measurement techniques, and experimental
paradigms to gain more insight into brain function. At multiple stages
and levels of neuroscience investigation, ML holds great promise as an
addition to the arsenal of analysis tools for discovering how the brain
works. As quantitative analysis of brain MRI is routine for many
neurological diseases and conditions, deep learning-based segmentation
approaches for brain Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) are gaining
interest due to their self-learning and generalisation ability over
large amounts of data. On the other hand, High Performance Computing
(HPC) and AI will increasingly intertwine as we transition to an
exascale future using new computing, storage, and communications
technologies. In this talk I will walk you through fundamentals of
generating high- performance deep-learning models in TensorFlow platform
using Python on large computing system (e.g NVIDIA® Tesla® GPUs powered
by Tensor Cores), in order to infer and segment thousands of cell
centroids out of the brain objects of interest. From a more
technological perspective, although astonishing results have been
achieved concerning the distribution of training large convolutional
neural networks on big data, to date the Python scientific ecosystem is
still missing tools for an optimised and, above all, distributed
inference of deep learning models. In this talk I will show you how a
tiling-based inferencing approach could be a good solution to remedy the
problem. The talk is intended for intermediate PyData researchers and
practitioners. Basic to intermediate level experience in image
recognition/object detection deep learning applications is assumed.
Overall, a good proficiency with the Python language and with scientific
python libraries (e.g. numpy, TensorFlow, Keras) are required for the
entire talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1794"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1794&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="GPUComputing"></category><category term="parallelization"></category><category term="bio-informatics"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="ComputerVision"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="Artificial Intelligence"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine learning approaches for road scene video analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-approaches-for-road-scene-video-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Benericetti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-approaches-for-road-scene-video-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dashboard cameras (dashcams), inward or front-facing cameras installed
in personal or commercial vehicles, are becoming increasingly popular
due to the pervasiveness of their applications: driver safety,
autonomous driving, fleet management systems, insurance, theft detection
are some examples. Focusing on safety, one of the main problems is to
analyze videos and automatically detect dangerous situations occurring
in them, such as the risk of a near crash with another vehicle or
pedestrian. In this talk, we show how we tackle this real- world problem
at Verizon Connect, using a mix of state-of-the-art deep learning
methods and traditional computer vision / machine learning techniques,
leveraging libraries such as scikit-learn, scipy/numpy, pandas, openCV,
and keras/tensorflow. We also describe how we use AWS and docker to
deploy, serve and scale the application to customers all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1603"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1603&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ComputerVision"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="opencv"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="optical-flow"></category><category term="pandas"></category></entry><entry><title>Deep Learning in Computer Vision: state of the art techniques and applications in industry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/deep-learning-in-computer-vision-state-of-the-art-techniques-and-applications-in-industry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rocco Michele Lancellotti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/deep-learning-in-computer-vision-state-of-the-art-techniques-and-applications-in-industry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Audience Level Data Scientists and Data Science Practitioners with basic
to intermediate level experience in image recognition/object detection
deep learning applications, basic Python programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brief Description Deep Learning is revolutionizing both Data Science and
Artificial Intelligence real-world applications. Yet, being the
discipline so young, it’s not straightforward to understand both the
reasoning at its core and its countless use cases. In this talk we will
review the basics of Neural Networks, from the classical CNNs to the
current state of the art, comparing them through real industry
applications and highlighting pros and cons in a business setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract / Summary Deep Learning has been on a hype roll for a few
years. Being such a young discipline makes deep learning interesting,
but also subject to misunderstandings. Every year, brand new
architectures rise, taking over old ones and outperforming state of the
art benchmarks for accuracy. Further, the applications of deep learning
are at the core of some of the most advanced technologies like
autonomous driving, personal assistants, and customer profiling. In such
a context it is not straightforward to grasp what is at the core of deep
learning itself, and what is common to all the architectures, neither to
realize how concrete use cases can be tackled. Using Python, we’ll take
the audience from the simplest neuron, the atom of the deep learning
world, to the most recent architectures. We’ll achieve this using a
simple Convolutional Neural Network as a building block and comparing
that to the latest breakthroughs in image recognition. In doing this
we’ll try to give an answer to the following questions: • Is deep
learning actually useful in a business setting? • What about state of
the art techniques in the Computer Vision field: are we just stacking
more and more convolutional and pooling layers? We will then address
real industry applications (e.g. the insurance sector) using analyzed
techniques. This will include opening some of these so- called black box
models and retraining them, at least partially, on our datasets, or
building a complete brand new network from scratch, tailoring it
according to the application needs and datasets characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="image-recognition"></category><category term="transfer-learning"></category><category term="industry applications"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="ComputerVision"></category><category term="computer vision"></category><category term="image recognition"></category><category term="transfer learning"></category><category term="industry-applications"></category></entry><entry><title>Image Generation with Tensorflow (GANs)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/image-generation-with-tensorflow-gans.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cenk Bircanoğlu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/image-generation-with-tensorflow-gans.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is an opensource language that has a wide community, and nowadays
the biggest companies also create frameworks, libraries with Python and
open- sourced them. Tensorflow is the most used library in Deep Learning
by researchers and there are many examples of various fields like
Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Signal Processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, Generative Adversarial Networks a.k.a. GAN collect nearly all
interests on it by the Computer Vision experts. There are diverse
applications like image colorization, image generation from random
numbers, computer game character creation, face frontalization, face
alignment, 2D to 3D image transfer, style transfer and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we are going to talk about GANs and the implementation
details on Tensorflow which is backed by Google and has the power of
either work on CPU and GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation of GANs can be divided into 2 parts. One is called
generator and other is called discriminator. In this talk, the
differences between the discriminator and generator also are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, some various architecture of GANs like PGGAN, DCGAN, STARGAN,
architectures showed in Tensorflow code, which of these are not already
implemented in Tensorflow by the date now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session will be finished with showing some examples of outputs in
face generation, room generation, and also live demo of the style
transfer implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Deep-Learning"></category><category term="image-processing"></category><category term="computer-science"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category><category term="ComputerVision"></category></entry></feed>