<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_webframeworks.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>An (biased) survey of the python web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--an--biased--survey-of-the-python-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mark Ramm</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--an--biased--survey-of-the-python-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An (biased) survey of the python web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Mark Ramm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may be BDFL of one framework, but that's also why I pay attention to
the whole ecosystem. From the release of Plone 4, TurboGears 2, Django
1.2 and Pylons 1 ,it's been an interesting year. And things like
html5lib, an updated WSGI spec, and a contender for the next generation
WSGI have all made things interesting. Come explore the wild and dynamic
jungle that I call &amp;quot;the python web toolkit.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will not teach people to use python to make websites. It's to
teach people who already use python, that there are lots of different
tools out there, and to help us all get some perspective on the python
web toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005 Pycon had the great PyWebOff, and while this talk won't be about
throwing Twisted into a cage match with Zope3, or setting Flask up in a
fight to the death against web.py, it will one again provide an attempt
to survey the full landscape of the python web world, and to see how far
we've come in the last 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've definitely come a long way. Django has brought over many converts
to Python, google released app engine with python as the first supported
language, and there are quite a few sites in the top 100 using python to
serve up dynamic content to hundreds of millions of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it hasn't all been good either, there's more fragmentation than
ever. We've also got more half finished libraries, and broken framework
extensions, and abandoned projects littering up the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="webframeworks"></category></entry></feed>