<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Advanced Django Form Usage</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--advanced-django-form-usage.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced Django Form Usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Daniel Greenfeld, Miguel Araujo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django forms are really powerful but there are edge cases that can cause
a bit of anguish. This talk will go over how to handle many common
solutions not currently described in the core documentation. It will
also cover some useful third-party libraries and will end with
clarifications about what the state of form features will be in Django
1.4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Greenfeld</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-05:djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--advanced-django-form-usage.html</guid><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2011</category><category>forms</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Sqlkit: empowering database access</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlkit-empowering-database-access.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Alessandro Dentella - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's very easy to access databases with Python, and there are many ORMs
allowing a high level of abstraction. Still, it's a long road from there
to interactive handling of data, even for very simple tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sqlkit tries to act as a bridge, offering some mega-widgets that allow
you to build GUI applications or directly access data using the
'sqledit' application, shipped with sqlkit; sqlkit is built with PyGTK
and SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation covers some of the most powerful features of sqlkit,
and shows how easy it is to build small programs for personal use, as
well as rich and complex applications. It primarily focuses on two
points: how easy it is to create data forms (eventually with one2many or
many2many, thanks to a original definition of layouts), and the template
system based on OpenOffice which allows easy report creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation shows how sqlkit can be used both as application
development framework and as a tool to help us while developing other
applications (e.g.: Django, OpenERP,… ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deliver a gradual presentation, we'll use the configuration system of
sqledit, starting from a minimal configuration (a single URL) we'll add
elements to that until we'll have a full application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Dentella</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/sqlkit-empowering-database-access.html</guid><category>database</category><category>forms</category><category>framework</category><category>gui</category><category>openoffice</category><category>python,</category></item><item><title>MiG - A Complete Grid Middleware (mostly) in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/mig-a-complete-grid-middleware-mostly-in-pyth.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Jonas Bardino - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grid computing was all the buzz in the beginning of the millennium and
still has serious attention in different forms although many of the
original grand promises were never delivered. The general level of
ambitions have instead slowly but steadily degraded to those of the
latest buzz word, Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as a project have proven that most of the original promises &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;
actually be delivered and we have done so using Python almost solely as
the implementation language. The choice of Python provided us with a
stable and versatile base for quickly getting this far and it
significantly eases extending and maintaining our middleware in the
future. MiG is currently about 50000 lines of source code but it still
offers more features than competing grid systems with millions of lines
of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from introducing the open source MiG middleware and summarizing
how we got here, this talk will outline some of the core technologies
used to reach that goal and underline why it can make a lot of sense to
choose Python for complex HPC projects like MiG, too. Talk keywords
include Network Programming, Open Source Python projects, Science and
Math and Web-based Systems. There's no special intended audience, but a
certain level of Python knowledge and experience may be an advantage.
Please refer to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/migrid/"&gt;http://code.google.com/p/migrid/&lt;/a&gt; for further MiG
information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jonas Bardino</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/mig-a-complete-grid-middleware-mostly-in-pyth.html</guid><category>forms</category><category>hpc</category><category>network</category><category>science</category></item><item><title>Spatial data and GeoDjango</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/spatial-data-and-geodjango.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Bruno Renie - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GeoDjango is the &amp;quot;world-class geographic web framework&amp;quot; everyone has
probably heard of. The purpose of this talk, targeted at people familiar
with Django itself, is to introduce in more details the capabilities of
this framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning the basics of Geographic Information Systems, we will
see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to get started with a GeoDjango installation,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to import, store and query spatial data,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to geo-enable your forms to allow user-generated spatial data,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to serialize and display your data using the different formats
and mapping frameworks such as OpenLayers and Polymaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this talk we will be building a simple GeoDjango application to
illustrate the different concepts introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bruno Renié</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/spatial-data-and-geodjango.html</guid><category>django</category><category>forms</category><category>geodjango</category><category>learning</category><category>mapping</category><category>spatial</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Panel: Form Generator Generators (#28)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--panel--form-generator-generators---28.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Panel: Form Generator Generators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Perkins; Brandon Craig Rhodes (Rhodes Mill Studios, Inc.);
Chris P McDonough (Agendaless Consulting); Jacob Kaplan-Moss
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:jacob&amp;#64;jacobian.org"&gt;jacob&amp;#64;jacobian.org&lt;/a&gt;); Jonathan Ellis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that almost every python web framework in existence has solved
the problem of automatically generating forms. Some have straight
forward techniques, some are unique or even an unusual approach to the
problem. The question is: &amp;quot;what can we learn from each other?&amp;quot;. This
panel will examine the different ways developers generate forms by
offering examples, and summarizing the functionality, differences, and
similarities between these valuable web development tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Feedback galore when moving between mics, cover your
ears]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--panel--form-generator-generators---28.html</guid><category>forms</category><category>panel</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>restish</category><category>turbogears</category><category>web</category><category>web2py</category><category>zope</category></item></channel></rss>