<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AI and algorithmic art</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/ai-and-algorithmic-art.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people think of neural networks as magic boxes, using them as such
is similar to allowing the computer or the machine to have a mind of
their own. Classification and prediction are the best-known applications
of these algorithms. But it has been demonstrated that they can also be
used in multiple creative or artistic ways such as generating pictures,
musical pieces, humour based dialogues or jokes and plays or literary
pieces. Leading to the following question: can these black boxes express
true creativity? A trait commonly associated with humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic Art (or computer generated art) refers to the use of
computer algorithms to create artistic pieces. Algorithmic art has been
around from the early 1960s, when artists used a plotter controlled by a
computer to create some visual artwork pieces. In the 80s when computer
graphics became more accessible, digital fractal artworks dominated to
become the mainstream of algorithmic art. By the end of the 80s, genetic
algorithms had matured enough to have a major influence in the
algorithmic composition of music. At the same time, the artificial
neural networks were used to explore the creation of musical
compositions. Most recently, thanks to the blooming of neural network
frameworks (e.g. tensorflow), availability of GPUs and development in
sophisticated neural network architecture, they play an important part
in academic research and data science business applications. Besides
that, these enhanced resources and frameworks have enabled the neural
networks to make significant contributions in the area of Algorithmic
Arts. Examples of this are the Deep Dream and artistic style transfer
and GANs (generative adversarial network) which can generate highly
deceptive pictures. A specially trained neural network is also capable
of composing music mimicking the style of Beethoven or generating a
modern music piece. In the same way, a neural network can be used to
generate poems or literary pieces in the true style of Shakespeare or
Hamilton. In this talk, we will go through a gallery of art and music
created by algorithms, showcasing what roles computers took in different
algorithmic art forms. From the earliest fractal art to the music and
pictures generated by the state of the art neural networks and GANs.
This talk is suitable for everyone, from the curious general public to
experts in the field of neural networks, both will find this talk
inspiring and amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide for this talk:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slides.com/cheukting_ho/ai-and-algorithmic-art/live#/"&gt;https://slides.com/cheukting_ho/ai-and-algorithmic-art/live#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1778"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1778&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cheuk Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/ai-and-algorithmic-art.html</guid><category>art</category><category>pydata</category><category>AI</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>algorithmicart</category><category>neural network</category></item></channel></rss>