<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_mock.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Intermediate testing with Django: Outside-in TDD and Mocking effectively</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/intermediate-testing-with-django-outside-in-tdd-and-mocking-effectively.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Harry  Percival</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/intermediate-testing-with-django-outside-in-tdd-and-mocking-effectively.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once developers have got the hang of the basics of testing, problems of applying it in the real world soon start to manifest themselves, and common questions come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What order should I write my tests and code in to avoid wasting time on blind alleys?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I'm using Mocks in my tests to avoid external dependencies, how do I avoid getting stuck with unwieldy, unreadable tests that don't actually tell me when things have gone wrong?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit tests vs integration tests vs functional tests, which should I use when, and what are the trade-offs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we'll work through an example of using an existing Django codebase, adding a new feature, and experimenting with different testing techniques along the way to illustrate the pros and cons of each&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bottom-up vs outside-in development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double-loop TDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using Mocks to isolate application layers from each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;listen to your tests&amp;quot;, and learning to use ugly or convoluted tests as a signal for improving design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some familiarity with Django is desirable, although skills learned in other web frameworks are transferrable.  By the end, you'll be able to go back to your own projects with practical experience, and a new way of thinking about how to optimise your tests for your own circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="tdd"></category><category term="mock"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing with mock</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--testing-with-mock.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Foord</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--testing-with-mock.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing with mock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Michael Foord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mock is a Python testing library. It has the goal of making mocking in
tests brain dead simple! mock provides the Mock class and the patch
decorator for safely patching out the objects you are mocking in your
tests. This talk will cover standard mocking patterns. We'll also look
at some of the newer features in the latest release, including support
for mocking magic methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mock provides a core Mock class that removes the need to create a host
of trivial stubs throughout your test suite. After performing an action,
you can make assertions about which methods / attributes were used and
arguments they were called with. You can also specify return values and
set specific attributes in the normal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.voidspace.org.uk/python/mock/"&gt;http://www.voidspace.org.uk/python/mock/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/mock/"&gt;http://pypi.python.org/pypi/mock/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mock module also provides a patch() decorator that handles safely
patching out the things you are mocking during your test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll cover standard mocking patterns, and how mock makes them easy.
We'll also be looking at some of the newer features in the latest
release, including the magic method support that can be used (for
example) for mocking out objects used as context managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mock is designed for &amp;quot;unit test style&amp;quot; testing, but is used with Python
testing libraries like nose and py.test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be some emphasis on how &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to use mocking in testing, and
why 'over mocking' is bad (and makes for brittle tests).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mock"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="testing"></category></entry></feed>