<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - StephenTierney</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>At the Turn of the Tide – Teaching Python in Real-Time at Scale</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/at-the-turn-of-the-tide-teaching-python-in-real-time-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Stephen Tierney, Alison Wong) Teaching a programming language can be challenging, even more so when your classroom is suddenly virtual and you have to teach 1200 students. With some clever thinking our multidisciplinary teaching team turned this crisis to our advantage and achieved an all time high level of student satisfaction. We are now able to reach any student, no matter their location, timezone or computing device with a real-time collaborative coding environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover what we consider “must-haves” for teaching in these extreme circumstances and how we have been able to maintain student engagement. We will demonstrate our solution to hosting tutorials online and share the lessons we learnt along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/RWKZXE/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/RWKZXE/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 13:30:00 2021 at Education&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stephen Tierney</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/at-the-turn-of-the-tide-teaching-python-in-real-time-at-scale.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2021</category><category>AlisonWong</category><category>StephenTierney</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2021</category></item></channel></rss>