<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scaling AI @ H&amp;M</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2019/scaling-ai-hm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk is about sharing the journey &amp;amp; learnings from building a world class AI function that builds scalable software for the entire H&amp;amp;M group. In the talk we will go through the tech stack behind it and some of the key enablers for us to scale and drive value from AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Errol Koolmeister</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-31:pycon-se-2019/scaling-ai-hm.html</guid><category>artificial intelligence</category><category>ai</category></item><item><title>Aprendizaje por refuerzo con OpenAI Gym</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-cordoba-2019/aprendizaje-por-refuerzo-con-openai-gym.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Esta charla ofrece una introducción a aprendizaje por refuerzo y cómo podemos experimentar con estos algoritmos usando la librería OpenAI Gym.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ana Laura Diedrichs</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-27:pydata-cordoba-2019/aprendizaje-por-refuerzo-con-openai-gym.html</guid><category>artificial intelligence</category><category>openai gym</category><category>reinforcement learning</category></item><item><title>AI pipelines powered by Jupyter notebooks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/ai-pipelines-powered-by-jupyter-notebooks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Jupyter Notebook has become the de-facto platform used by data scientists to develop their AI/ML models. In this scenario, it’s very common to decompose various phases of the development into multiple notebooks to simplify the development and management of the model lifecycle. This session will detail different approaches to compose notebook based AI pipelines and running in different runtimes&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luciano Resende</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/ai-pipelines-powered-by-jupyter-notebooks.html</guid><category>data pipelines</category><category>ai</category><category>artificial intelligence</category><category>jupyter notebooks</category></item><item><title>The Cortex in the Code: How Neuroscience Makes AI Intelligent</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/the-cortex-in-the-code-how-neuroscience-makes-ai-intelligent.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI algorithms, which are capable of intelligent data processing and decision making, mirror the function of the human brain. How does neuroscience inform the design of modern AI algorithms? How does looking at the structure of the brain play a role in designing intelligent machines? In addition to examining these questions, we'll discuss how this will help innovate future AI design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dalton A. R. Sakthivadivel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/the-cortex-in-the-code-how-neuroscience-makes-ai-intelligent.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>AI</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning for brain MRI segmentation: Big Data, AI and HPC meet together</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-for-brain-mri-segmentation-big-data-ai-and-hpc-meet-together.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With ever-increasing advancements in technology, neuroscientists are
able to collect data in greater volumes and with finer resolution. There
has been a growing interest in leveraging this vast volume of data
across levels of analysis, measurement techniques, and experimental
paradigms to gain more insight into brain function. At multiple stages
and levels of neuroscience investigation, ML holds great promise as an
addition to the arsenal of analysis tools for discovering how the brain
works. As quantitative analysis of brain MRI is routine for many
neurological diseases and conditions, deep learning-based segmentation
approaches for brain Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) are gaining
interest due to their self-learning and generalisation ability over
large amounts of data. On the other hand, High Performance Computing
(HPC) and AI will increasingly intertwine as we transition to an
exascale future using new computing, storage, and communications
technologies. In this talk I will walk you through fundamentals of
generating high- performance deep-learning models in TensorFlow platform
using Python on large computing system (e.g NVIDIA® Tesla® GPUs powered
by Tensor Cores), in order to infer and segment thousands of cell
centroids out of the brain objects of interest. From a more
technological perspective, although astonishing results have been
achieved concerning the distribution of training large convolutional
neural networks on big data, to date the Python scientific ecosystem is
still missing tools for an optimised and, above all, distributed
inference of deep learning models. In this talk I will show you how a
tiling-based inferencing approach could be a good solution to remedy the
problem. The talk is intended for intermediate PyData researchers and
practitioners. Basic to intermediate level experience in image
recognition/object detection deep learning applications is assumed.
Overall, a good proficiency with the Python language and with scientific
python libraries (e.g. numpy, TensorFlow, Keras) are required for the
entire talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1794"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1794&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giuseppe Di Bernardo</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-for-brain-mri-segmentation-big-data-ai-and-hpc-meet-together.html</guid><category>GPUComputing</category><category>parallelization</category><category>bio-informatics</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>ComputerVision</category><category>optimization</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category></item><item><title>Defence Against the Dark Arts: Adversarial ML</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/defence-against-the-dark-arts-adversarial-ml.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security and Privacy issues need no introduction. But how exactly is
this affecting the field of Machine Learning? This is what this talk
will cover. We first expose the attack surface of systems deploying
machine learning. We then describe how an attacker may force models to
make wrong predictions with very little information about the victim.
One such attack can be biometric recognition where fake biometric traits
may be exploited to impersonate a legitimate user. We demonstrate that
these attacks are practical against existing machine learning as a
service platform. Towards the end, we will discuss current research to
defend models from such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1700"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1700&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amit Kushwaha</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/defence-against-the-dark-arts-adversarial-ml.html</guid><category>security</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>privacy</category></item><item><title>Machine Learning for Inventory Management</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-for-inventory-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Material forecast is the process of deciding which items to stock in the
inventory, how much, and when. Aim of the forecast is to increase parts
availability with the less possible impact on inventory, having enough
stock in the warehouse to ensure the business keeps moving but not
enough stock to drain its limited cash reserves. This decision process
is being profoundly revised in its foundational concepts, thanks to new
classification methodologies enabled by Machine Learning. We integrated
domain knowledge and ML to create a new classification and level setting
process, leveraging on 6 years of data and new statistical indicators
for demand patter. These new features are used to run the machine
learning algorithm that classify Make To Stock / Make To Order items in
a single flow approach. The validation phase is reduced at each
iteration as ML model can be re-trained to incorporate past validations,
increasing efficiency and performances. Level setting problem is
addressed benchmarking ML methods (Reinforcement Learning), Montecarlo
simulations and traditional statistical methodologies. Regarding RL and
Montecarlo we established punishments for letting an particular
inventory item run out of stock and we also punish the model for stock
too higher value for too long. For rewards, we primarily focus on
ordering items within a safe window before the demand. First application
of this new methodology brings a 20% reduction of inventory, without
impact on sales, and a workload reduction of about 70%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1554"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1554&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laura De Stefanis</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/machine-learning-for-inventory-management.html</guid><category>logistics</category><category>clustering</category><category>statistics</category><category>Python</category><category>Big-Data</category><category>gestionali</category><category>django</category><category>supplychain</category><category>sql</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning with PyTorch for Fun and Profit (Part III / Italian Edition: Divina Commedia)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-with-pytorch-for-fun-and-profit-part-iii-italian-edition-divina-commedia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are all these great articles and blog posts about Deep Learning
describing all that awesome stuff. - Is it all that easy? Let’s check!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll look into: style transfer (making a picture look like painting),
speech generation (like Siri or Alexa) and text generation (writing a
story). In this talk I’ll describe the whole journey: A fun ride from
the idea to the very end including all the struggles, failures and
successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ongoing talk on how far we can get creating a full &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_drama"&gt;radio
drama (Hörspiel)&lt;/a&gt; with
deep learning and the resources required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps, we’ll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data challenge: get the data ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a character-level language models with an Recurrent Neural
Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a text generator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating artwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthesising speech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making it sound like a real person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this special PyCon X edition we will also try to recreate text in the
style of Dante’ Divina Commedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1687"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1687&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Hendorf</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/deep-learning-with-pytorch-for-fun-and-profit-part-iii-italian-edition-divina-commedia.html</guid><category>deep learning</category><category>Pytorch</category><category>art</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>nlp</category></item><item><title>Hearing Colours and Seeing Sounds using Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/hearing-colours-and-seeing-sounds-using-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We humans are the masterpieces. We are born with awesome capabilities
and applaudable talents making us different from one another. As an
individual , nobody thinks the way others do , they have their own
intriguing ways to look at this world. Few of us have this exceptional
quality to be able to visualise sounds and map colours with the words.
It is termed as Synesthesia. It is fascinating to know how human brain
can see sounds and hear colours, how it thinks of a word, and sees
blocks of colours, and then these blocks get translated into letters.
There are few who see the letters with a halo-effect. The letters
give- off almost a glow of a certain colour.It is a striking fact that
the synesthetic brains are wired a little differently from the ones of
non-synesthetes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk will cover the interesting applications of python
programming by harnessing simple mathematical techniques to simulate
the synesthetic ( bridging modalities) behaviour of brain. It is
really appealing to be able to look at the world wearing colourful
shades and building an AI that does bridge these modalities (vision ,
hearing ,etc ) is truly astounding. The talk covers an interesting
viewpoint on how python can be used widely to analyse some of the
really complex human brain behaviours ,in addition to solving
comparatively trivial real world problems.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the slides :
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/aakanksha07/hearing-colours-and"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/aakanksha07/hearing-colours-and&lt;/a&gt;-
seeing-sounds-using-python?slide=28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1776"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1776&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aakanksha Chouhan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/hearing-colours-and-seeing-sounds-using-python.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Build text classification models ( CBOW and Skip-gram) with FastText in python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/build-text-classification-models-cbow-and-skip-gram-with-fasttext-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;FastText has been open-sourced by Facebook in 2016 and with its release,
it became the fastest and most accurate library in Python for text
classification and word representation. It is to be seen as a substitute
for gensim package's word2vec. It includes the implementation of two
extremely important methodologies in NLP i.e Continuous Bag of Words and
Skip-gram model. Fasttext performs exceptionally well with supervised as
well as unsupervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will be divided in following four segments :&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kajal Puri</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/build-text-classification-models-cbow-and-skip-gram-with-fasttext-in-python.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>NLP</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Building your own conversational AI with open source tools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/building-your-own-conversational-ai-with-open-source-tools.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conversational AI is far from being a solved problem, but you don’t need
to rely on third-party APIs to build great chat and voice apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will live-code a useful, engaging conversational AI bot
based entirely on machine learning. We’ll be using Rasa NLU &amp;amp; Rasa Core,
which are open source libraries for building machine learning-based
chatbots and voice assistants. We will teach our system how to hold
multi-turn conversations by creating some initial training data, and
then refine its behaviour by interacting with the system and providing
feedback. We will cover the fundamentals of conversational AI, including
the most important algorithms for intent classification, entity
extraction, and dialogue management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will attendees learn:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Justina Petraitytė</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/building-your-own-conversational-ai-with-open-source-tools.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>NLP</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>From exploration to deployment - combining PyTorch and TensorFlow for Deep Learning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/from-exploration-to-deployment-combining-pytorch-and-tensorflow-for-deep-learning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the many deep learning frameworks out in the wild few have
achieved widespread adoption. Two of them are TensorFlow and PyTorch.
Where PyTorch relies on a dynamic computation graph TensorFlow goes for
a static graph. Where TensorFlow shows greater adoption and additional
useful extensions with TensorFlow Serving and TensorBoard, Pytorch
proves useful trough its easy and more pythonic API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data scientists are confronted with explorative challenges, but also
need to be aware of model deployment and production. Do we need to
single out frameworks until we end up with the only one or is there a
case for joint usage of two deep learning frameworks? Can we leverage
the strengths of the frameworks for different tasks along the path from
exploration to production?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I want to present a case combining the benefits of PyTorch
and TensorFlow using the first for explorative and latter for deployment
tasks. Therefore, I will choose a common deep learning challenge and
discuss the strengths and weaknesses of both frameworks along a demo
that brings a model from development into production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marcel Kurovski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/from-exploration-to-deployment-combining-pytorch-and-tensorflow-for-deep-learning.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Satellite data is for everyone: insights into modern remote sensing research with open data and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/satellite-data-is-for-everyone-insights-into-modern-remote-sensing-research-with-open-data-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The largest earth observation programme Copernicus
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://copernicus.eu"&gt;http://copernicus.eu&lt;/a&gt;) makes it possible to perform terrestrial
observations providing data for all kinds of purposes. One important
objective is to monitor the land-use and land-cover changes with the
Sentinel-2 satellite mission. These satellites measure the sun
reflectance on the earth surface with multispectral cameras (13 channels
between 440 nm to 2190 nm). Machine learning techniques like
convolutional neural networks (CNN) are able to learn the link between
the satellite image (spectrum) and the ground truth (land use class). In
this talk, we give an overview about the state-of-the-art land-use
classification with CNNs based on an open dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EuroSAT benchmark dataset (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://madm.dfki.de/downloads"&gt;http://madm.dfki.de/downloads&lt;/a&gt;) is freely
provided by German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI).
It consists of 27.000 image patches for ten different land use/cover
classes, e.g. industrial and residential areas, different crop and
vegetation types and forests. All samples have 64 by 64 pixel dimension
and include either only the RGB images or all 13 bands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use different out-of-box CNNs for the Keras deep learning
library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://keras.io/"&gt;https://keras.io/&lt;/a&gt;). All networks are either included in Keras
itself or are available from Github repositories. We will show the
process of transfer learning for the RGB datasets. Furthermore, the
minimal changes required to apply commonly used CNNs to multispectral
data are demonstrated. Thus, the interested audience will be able to
perform their own classification of remote sensing data within a very
short time. Results of different network structures are visually
compared. Especially the differences of transfer learning and learning
from scratch are demonstrated. This also includes the amount of
necessary training epochs, progress of training and validation error and
visual comparison of the results of the trained networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we give a quick overview about the current research topics
including recurrent neural networks for spatio-temporal land-use
classification and further applications of multi- and hyperspectral
data, e.g. for the estimation of water parameters and soil
characteristics. Additionally, we provide links to the code and dataset
used in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felix M. Riese</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-26:pycon-de-2018/satellite-data-is-for-everyone-insights-into-modern-remote-sensing-research-with-open-data-and-python.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Computer Vision</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Science</category></item><item><title>Beyond Jupyter Notebooks - Building your own Data Science platform with Python &amp; Docker</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/beyond-jupyter-notebooks-building-your-own-data-science-platform-with-python-docker.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interactive notebooks like Jupyter have become more and more popular in
the recent past and build the core of many data scientist's workplace.
Being accessed via web browser they allow scientists to easily structure
their work by combining code and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet notebooks often lead to isolated and disposable analysis artefacts.
Keeping the computation inside those notebooks does not allow for
convenient concurrent model training, model exposure or scheduled model
retraining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those issues can be addressed by taking advantage of recent developments
in the discipline of software engineering. Over the past years
containerization became the technology of choice for crafting and
deploying applications. Building a data science platform that allows for
easy access (via notebooks), flexibility and reproducibility (via
containerization) combines the best of both worlds and addresses Data
Scientist's hidden needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joshua Görner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/beyond-jupyter-notebooks-building-your-own-data-science-platform-with-python-docker.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Data Science</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Infrastructure</category><category>Jupyter</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Programming</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Data Science meets Data Protection: Keeping your data secure while learning from it.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/data-science-meets-data-protection-keeping-your-data-secure-while-learning-from-it.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will discuss anonymization and pseudonymization techniques that you
can apply to your data to keep it secure and comply with the law(s)
while still being able to gain useful insights from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will show concrete Python implementations of various techniques and
use example data sets to show how applying pseudonymization and
anonymization will affect our ability to do machine learning / data
science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Dewes</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/data-science-meets-data-protection-keeping-your-data-secure-while-learning-from-it.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Data Science</category></item><item><title>Satellite Image Segmentation Photovoltaic Potential Estimation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/satellite-image-segmentation-photovoltaic-potential-estimation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The used technologies are python based and include: MongoDB tensorflow
Flask google.cloud python API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dataset of labelled satellite images is created. Several networks are
trained and tested on this dataset. The network is deployed on a
production server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the classification/segmentaion are used to feed python
based photovotlaic simulation libaries. The output is displayed and the
results (the potential) evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Johannes Oos</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/satellite-image-segmentation-photovoltaic-potential-estimation.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Computer Vision</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Science</category></item><item><title>Active Learning - Building Semi-supervised Classifiers when Labeled Data is not Available</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/active-learning-building-semi-supervised-classifiers-when-labeled-data-is-not-available.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many situations large datasets are available but unfortunately
labeling is expensive and time consuming. Active Learning is a concept
for building classifiers by letting the algorithm choose the training
data it uses. This achieves greater accuracy than just labeling a random
subset of the available dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The active learning algorithm selects some unlabeled data instances
which are then labeled by a human annotator. Given this information a
classifier is trained and new instances for the human annotator to label
are selected. This iterative process tries to label as few instances as
possible while achieving high classification accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will give a general overview of the core concepts and
techniques of active learning like algorithms for selecting the queries
and convergence criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Hendrik Niemeyer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/active-learning-building-semi-supervised-classifiers-when-labeled-data-is-not-available.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Experiences from applying Convolutional Neural Networks for classifying 2D sensor data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/experiences-from-applying-convolutional-neural-networks-for-classifying-2d-sensor-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When being the first in your company to apply a deep learning algorithm
on your data you often have to overcome several obstacles. One challenge
is to understand your data and to form a training and test dataset.
Another one is to get your algorithms and its performance accepted and
integrated in your existing processing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convolutional Neural Networks have become a standard tool in processing
image data. They have shown to reach human-level classification
performance on some object recognition tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will present my experiences in getting started using a
convolutional neural network for classification of 2D sensor data. I
will point out the importance of understanding your data and give hints
of how to select your train and test datasets according to the
requirements. Furthermore, I will show how to get a feature extractor
out of the classifier and how to visualize it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matthias Peussner</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/experiences-from-applying-convolutional-neural-networks-for-classifying-2d-sensor-data.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Computer Vision</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Germany's next topic model</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/germanys-next-topic-model.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identifying topic models for user generated content like hotel reviews
turns out to be difficult with the standard approach of LDA (Latent
Dirichlet Allocation; Blei et al., 2003). Hotel review texts usually
don't differ as much in the topics that are covered as is typical with
other genres such as Wikipedia or newsgroup articles where there is
commonly only a very small set of topics present in each document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, we developed our own approach to topic modeling that is
especially tailored to non-edited texts like hotel reviews. The approach
can be divided into three major steps. First, using the concept of
second-order cooccurrences we define a contextual similarity score that
enables us to identify words that are similar with respect to certain
topics. This score allows us to build up a topic network where nodes are
words and edges the contextual similarity between the words. With the
help of algorithms from graph theory, like the Infomap algorithm
(Rosvall and Bergstrom, 2008), we are able to detect clusters of highly
connected words that can be identified as topics in our review texts. In
a further step, we use these clusters and the respective words to get a
topic similarity score for each word in the network. In other words, we
transform a hard clustering of words into topics into a probability
score of how likely a certain word belongs to a given topic/cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is structured as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References: David M. Blei, Andrew Y. Ng, Michael I. Jordan: Latent
dirichlet allocation. In: Journal of Machine Learning Research, Jg. 3
(2003), S. 993–1022, ISSN 1532-4435 M. Rosvall and C. T. Bergstrom, Maps
of information flow reveal community structure in complex networks, PNAS
105, 1118 (2008) &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0706851105"&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0706851105&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.0609"&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.0609&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Mayer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/germanys-next-topic-model.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Networks</category><category>NLP</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Visualisation</category></item><item><title>Productionizing your ML code seamlessly</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/productionizing-your-ml-code-seamlessly.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science and Machine Learning are hot topics right now for Software
Engineers and beyond. There are a lot of python tools that allow you to
hack together a notebook to quickly get insight on your data, or train a
model to predict or classify. Or you might have inherited some data
wrangling and modeling {Jupyter/Zeppelin} notebook code from someone
else, like the resident data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code works on test data, when you run the cells in the right order
(skipping cell 22), and you believe that the insight gained from this
work would be a valuable game changer. But now how do you take this
experimental code into production, and keep it up-to-date with a regular
retraining schedule? And what do you need to do after that, to ensure
that it remains reliable and brings value in the long term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be the questions this talk will answer, focusing on 2 main
themes: What does running an ML model in production involve? How to
improve your development workflow to make the path to production easier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will draw examples from real projects at Yelp, like migrating
a pandas/sklearn classification project into production with pyspark,
while aiming to give advice that is not dependent on specific
frameworks, or tools, and is useful for listeners from all backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lauris Jullien</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/productionizing-your-ml-code-seamlessly.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Pyccel, a Fortran static compiler for scientific High-Performance Computing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/pyccel-a-fortran-static-compiler-for-scientific-high-performance-computing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pyccel&lt;/em&gt; is a new &lt;strong&gt;static compiler&lt;/strong&gt; for Python that uses &lt;strong&gt;Fortran&lt;/strong&gt;
as backend language while enabling High-Performance Computing &lt;strong&gt;HPC&lt;/strong&gt;
capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran is a computer language for scientific programming that is
tailored for efficient run-time execution on a wide variety of
processors. Even if the &lt;em&gt;2003&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;2008&lt;/em&gt; standards added major
improvements like &lt;em&gt;OOP, Coarrays, Submodules, do concurrent&lt;/em&gt; , etc ...
they are not covered by all available compilers. Moreover, the Fortran
developer still suffers from the lack of &lt;strong&gt;meta-programming&lt;/strong&gt; compared
to &lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt; ones. Therefore, it is more and more difficult for applied
mathematicians and computational physicists to write applications at the
&lt;em&gt;state of art&lt;/em&gt; (targeting CPUs, GPUs, MICs) while implementing
complicated algorithms or numerical schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyccel can be used in two cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to achieve the second point, we developed an internal DSL for
&lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;macros&lt;/em&gt;. The later is used to map sentences based on
&lt;em&gt;mpi4py&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;scipy.linalg.blas or lapack&lt;/em&gt; onto the appropriate calls in
Fortran. Moreover, two parsers, for &lt;em&gt;OpenMP&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;OpenACC&lt;/em&gt; , were added
too, allowing for explicit parallelism through the use of pragmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, Pyccel is an extension of &lt;strong&gt;Sympy&lt;/strong&gt;. Actually, it
converts a Python code to symbolic expressions/trees, from a Full Syntax
Tree ( &lt;em&gt;RedBaron&lt;/em&gt; ), then annotates the new AST using types or different
settings provided by the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, after a brief description of Pyccel, I will show different
applications including Finite Elements (1d, 2d, 3d), Semi-Lagrangian
schemes (4d), Kronecker linear solvers, diagnostics for 5D kinetic
simulations and Machine Learning for Partial Differential Equations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Ing. Ratnani Ahmed</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/pyccel-a-fortran-static-compiler-for-scientific-high-performance-computing.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Astronomy</category><category>Parallel Programming</category><category>Programming</category><category>Python</category><category>Science</category></item><item><title>reticulate: R interface to Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/reticulate-r-interface-to-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and R are the preferred languages for data science. In 2018,
RStudio introduced its package reticulate and clearly demonstrates that
it favours to join forces. Both languages have strengths and weaknesses.
Tools to combine the strengths will enable easier collaboration in
projects and more possibilities to succeed. Using Python from R gives R
users wider access to functions and makes it easier for Python beginners
to just run scripts and being able to collaborate in Python projects.
The talk will show the possibilities of reticulate: The main part starts
with demonstrating the Python interpreter within R. It will show how to
source Python scripts as well as install and import modules. Then it
will deal with the most important types of Python objects, how they are
represented in R and how to further manipulate them. Thereby, a special
focus is on using Python for data science. In addition, it will be
presented how Conda environments can be created and used from R. A
further application will be the creation of reports with Markdown and
LaTeX where R and Python can be used within one document and share
objects. A last topic is about showing the possibilities for easier
development in RStudio (help regarding Python functions, auto
completion).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jens Bruno Wittek</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/reticulate-r-interface-to-python.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Algorithms</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Deep Learning &amp; Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Data Science</category><category>NLP</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Visualisation</category></item><item><title>Explore the brain with Nilearn</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/explore-the-brain-with-nilearn.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past recent years, the Python programming language became popular
and widely used in many science areas, that you can notes from huge
amount of high quality &lt;strong&gt;scientific&lt;/strong&gt; libraries available in GitHub.
Python has already won the confidence in neuro-imaging community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis of different &lt;strong&gt;neuroimaging&lt;/strong&gt; modalities consists of
identifying such a complex pipeline that include supporting specific
&lt;strong&gt;MRI&lt;/strong&gt; data acquisition, image processing, statistics and predictive
modeling, and visualization of the results. &lt;strong&gt;Nilearn&lt;/strong&gt; is a Python
package designed to face these challenges. It provides state-of-the-art
&lt;strong&gt;machine-learning&lt;/strong&gt; methods for analysis task fMRI, resting-state, or
anathomical data. In my talk, I would like to present general purpose of
Nilearn, focusing on &lt;strong&gt;functional connectivity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;connectome&lt;/strong&gt;
analysis in resting-state fMRI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Darya Chyzhyk</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/explore-the-brain-with-nilearn.html</guid><category>computer-science</category><category>cognitive-science</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>Facial Analysis Techniques for Pythonista (and beyond!)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/facial-analysis-techniques-for-pythonista-and-beyond.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to detect, track, and analyze faces opens up a wide range of
interesting use cases, ranging from interactive smart applications and
real- time video processing, all the way to biometric security and
augmented reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will showcase the available &lt;strong&gt;tools built by the Python
community&lt;/strong&gt; and their corresponding pros &amp;amp; cons, limitations, and
complexity. While discussing the possible scenarios and what is actually
required to &lt;strong&gt;DIY with Python&lt;/strong&gt;, I will compare such handmade solutions
with &lt;strong&gt;Cloud-based products and APIs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: basic understanding of Python’s data science stack
(especially numpy).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Casalboni</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/facial-analysis-techniques-for-pythonista-and-beyond.html</guid><category>CloudComputing</category><category>aws</category><category>scikit-learn</category><category>scikit-image</category><category>google-cloud</category><category>Deep-Learning</category><category>opencv</category><category>scikits</category><category>cv</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>Facial-Analysis</category><category>dlib</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category></item><item><title>AI, Machine Learning e Deep Learning: cosa cambia?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/ai-machine-learning-e-deep-learning-cosa-cambia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt; e &lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;:
cosa sono e qual’è la loro storia? Ma soprattutto quali sono le
differenze tra questi tre?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questo talk è orientato a coloro che non hanno alcuna base su nessuno di
questi argomenti&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonio Spadaro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/ai-machine-learning-e-deep-learning-cosa-cambia.html</guid><category>Deep-Learning</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item><item><title>How to turn Wikipedia into a Quiz Game</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/how-to-turn-wikipedia-into-a-quiz-game.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiz games let people test their knowledge through multi-choice
questions. Unfortunately, generating such questions can be very
time-consuming and it is typically done manually. In this talk we
will present a pipeline to automatically generate quiz games starting
from generic knowledge (e.g. Wikipedia). The pipeline consists of the
following components: (i) a parser to retrieve text from Wikipedia
pages, (ii) a Natural Language Processing module (based on the Google
Natural Language API) to extract information about syntax, entities
and relations, (iii) a Natural Language Generation module to generate
test questions and correct answers, and finally (iv) a domain-aware
module that uses domain-specific knowledge to generate wrong answers
(i.e. distractors). Every module is written in Python and it is based
on either available libraries or Cloud services (e.g., Google Natural
Language).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: basic knowledge of python, minimal understanding
of text syntactic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrea Cappelli</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/how-to-turn-wikipedia-into-a-quiz-game.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>AI</category><category>games</category><category>computational-linguistics</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>text-analysis</category><category>google-cloud</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>linked-data</category></item><item><title>A Gentle Introduction to Neural Networks (with Python)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/a-gentle-introduction-to-neural-networks-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A gentle introduction to neural networks, and making your own with
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session is especially designed to be accessible to everyone,
including anyone with no expertise in mathematics, computer science or
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this session you will have an intuitive understanding of what
neural networks are and how they work. If you are more technically
capable, you will see how you could make your own with Python and numpy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 1 - Ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the search for AI, hard problems for computers easy for humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning from examples (simple classifier)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;biologically inspired neurons and networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;training a neural network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the back propagation breakthrough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matrix ways of working (good for computers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 - Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python is easy, and everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python notebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MNIST data set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a very simple neural network class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus on concise and efficient matrix calculations with numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;97.5% accuracy recognising handwritten numbers - with just a few lines of code!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 3 - Live Demo! … and Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tariq Rashid</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/a-gentle-introduction-to-neural-networks-with-python.html</guid><category>image-processing</category><category>numpy</category><category>neural network</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Machine Learning</category></item></channel></rss>