<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Evolving a helper script into a 180,000-lines-of-Python-code project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/evolving-a-helper-script-into-a-180000-lines-of-python-code-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GRR Rapid Response (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/google/grr"&gt;https://github.com/google/grr&lt;/a&gt;) is an incident
response framework focused on remote live forensics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It consists of a Python client (agent) that is installed on target
systems, and Python server infrastructure that can manage and talk to
clients. The goal of GRR is to support forensics and investigations in a
fast, scalable manner to allow analysts to quickly triage attacks and
perform analysis remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRR was started at Google in 2009 as a simple Python helper script used
by Incident Response engineers. Eventually a little Python script got a
little server component, was adapted to run on multiple systems (Mac,
Linux, Windows), then a little UI was added and a few nice features were
introduced (large-scale hunts, collection of predefined artifacts,
memory analysis). A helper script has eventually evolved into a
sophisticated framework with 180,000 lines of Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In the presentation we’ll talk about the process of evolving a small
prototype-like Python project into a production-ready system, using
GRR as an example. The topics that we’ll cover are:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Taking shortcuts - both in terms of design and implementation.
Reasons for taking them and their eventual costs.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Relying on Python’s power features (i.e. meta-classes, mixins)?
Long-term consequences on maintainability and readability.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Organising the project into separate PyPI packages - benefits of
doing that.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Continuous integration, testing and automated builds for various
platforms - implementation costs and maintainability effects.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mikhail Bushkov</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/evolving-a-helper-script-into-a-180000-lines-of-python-code-project.html</guid><category>Databases</category><category>Deployment/Continuous Integration and Delivery</category><category>Development</category><category>Open-Source</category><category>Security</category></item><item><title>Darkweb + Python: discover, analyze and extract information from hidden services</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/darkweb-python-discover-analyze-and-extract-information-from-hidden-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will start explaining how Tor project can help us to the
research and development of tools for online anonymity and privacy of
its users while surfing the Internet, by establishing virtual circuits
between the different nodes that make up the Tor network. In addition,
we will review how Tor works from anonymity point of view, preventing
websites from tracking you. Python help us to automate the process to
search an discover hidden services thanks to packages like
requests,requesocks and sockspy. At this point we will review the
crawling process and show tools in python ecosystem available for this
task such as Deep Explorer(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/blueudp/deep-explorer"&gt;https://github.com/blueudp/deep-explorer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These could be the talking points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Tor project and hidden services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovering hidden services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modules and packages we can use in python for connecting with Tor
network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools that allow search hidden services and atomate the crawling
process in Tor network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1563"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1563&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jose Manuel Ortega</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/darkweb-python-discover-analyze-and-extract-information-from-hidden-services.html</guid><category>tor</category><category>security</category><category>privacy</category><category>hacking</category><category>crawler</category></item><item><title>Defence Against the Dark Arts: Adversarial ML</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/defence-against-the-dark-arts-adversarial-ml.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security and Privacy issues need no introduction. But how exactly is
this affecting the field of Machine Learning? This is what this talk
will cover. We first expose the attack surface of systems deploying
machine learning. We then describe how an attacker may force models to
make wrong predictions with very little information about the victim.
One such attack can be biometric recognition where fake biometric traits
may be exploited to impersonate a legitimate user. We demonstrate that
these attacks are practical against existing machine learning as a
service platform. Towards the end, we will discuss current research to
defend models from such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1700"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1700&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amit Kushwaha</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/defence-against-the-dark-arts-adversarial-ml.html</guid><category>security</category><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>privacy</category></item><item><title>Open Sourcing at Work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2018/open-sourcing-at-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We just open sourced 2 projects (datacompy, and locopy) with roots in Data Science and Engineering which we will showcase. While is it exciting and rewarding to share your ideas with the world it isn't always easy. Thinking about licenses, copyrights, and protecting confidential information is a must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in a large organization which is embracing the mantra 'open source first' is really exciting. Part of this journey is to make sure we give back to the open source community when we can. Two of our projects had gained traction internally: datacompy, and locopy. As part of our commitment we wanted to make sure we could open source these projects for others to use and contribute back to. DataComPy is a package to compare two Pandas DataFrames. Originally started to be something of a replacement for SAS's PROC COMPARE for Pandas DataFrames with some more functionality than just Pandas.DataFrame.equals(Pandas.DataFrame) (in that it prints out some stats, and lets you tweak how accurate matches have to be). Then extended to carry that functionality over to Spark Dataframes. Locopy helps load flat files to S3 and then to Amazon Redshift, and assist with ETL processing. It is DB Driver (Adapter) agnostic, provides basic functionality to move data to S3 buckets, execute COPY commands to load data to S3, and into Redshift, and UNLOAD commands to unload data from Redshift into S3. While building these products was exciting and fun, some of the legal considerations were as interesting, complex, and required collaboration between many teams, from security, licensing, brand, and IP/copyright. We'll explore the projects, and some of these other considerations which can make or break if you decide to release a project into the wild, along with the road blocks we faced with in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Faisal Dosani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-11:pycon-ca-2018/open-sourcing-at-work.html</guid><category>open source</category><category>licensing</category><category>copyright</category><category>data</category><category>security</category><category>testing</category><category>best practices</category><category>data science</category></item><item><title>Testing python security</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/testing-python-security.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is a language that in a easy way allows to scale up from starter projects to complex applications for data processing and serving dynamic web pages. But as you increase complexity in your applications, it can be easy to introduce potential problems and vulnerabilities. In this talk, I will highlight the biggest problems we can find in python functions, how to use then in a secure way and tools and services that help you identify vulnerabilities in the python source code. These could be the main talking points: -Introduction to secure programming in python. -Introduce dangerous functions for code inyection and how we can solve this issues from a security point of view. -Common attack vectors on Python applications like Remote Command Execution and SQL injection -Best practices for avoid execution of malicious commands -Tools that help us to protect and obfuscate our source code&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jose Manuel Ortega</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/testing-python-security.html</guid><category>security</category></item><item><title>Python for hackers and Penetration testing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-for-hackers-and-penetration-testing.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Oltjano Terpollari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/python-for-hackers-and-penetration-testing.html</guid><category>sqlmap</category><category>subnet</category><category>set</category><category>networking</category><category>zip</category><category>whitehat</category><category>web</category><category>windows</category><category>sysadmin</category><category>ssh</category><category>linux</category><category>hacking</category><category>pythonscripts</category><category>security</category><category>socket</category></item><item><title>Passwords - the server side</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/passwords-the-server-side.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Waldmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/passwords-the-server-side.html</guid><category>sysadmin</category><category>best-practices</category><category>security</category><category>servers</category></item><item><title>Celery and Social Networks. 5 Things I Have Learned During Earthquake Hackathon.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/celery-and-social-networks-5-things-i-have-learned-during-earthquake-hackathon.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Mleczko</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/celery-and-social-networks-5-things-i-have-learned-during-earthquake-hackathon.html</guid><category>celery</category><category>security</category><category>open-source</category><category>case-study</category><category>social</category></item><item><title>Everyday security issues and how to avoid them</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/everyday-security-issues-and-how-to-avoid-them.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security is hard, yet vital for any software these days. After all you
don’t want to become the laughing stock on hacker news or cause your
company to loose billions in shareholder value. This talk won’t turn you
into a security specialist over night, but you will learn how to avoid
common mistakes in your daily work as developer or administrator. I’m
going to take you on a brief tour in secure software design, illustrate
various attack vectors, and point you to helpful tools and resources.
Topics include threat analysis, deployment, parsing, authentication,
TLS/SSL, crypto, and user interaction, with some real life examples from
my daily work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="note"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Note&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The talk will be an extended version of my PyCon UK 2017 and DevConf.CZ
2018 info sec talk. Slides are recordings of my PyCon UK talk are
available at
https://speakerdeck.com/tiran/pycon-uk-2017-everyday-security-issues-and-how-
to-avoid-them .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 20 April&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Heimes</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/everyday-security-issues-and-how-to-avoid-them.html</guid><category>security</category><category>infosec</category><category>Cryptography</category></item><item><title>La sicurezza dei database MySQL in ottica GDPR</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/la-sicurezza-dei-database-mysql-in-ottica-gdpr.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Il 25 maggio 2018 la GDPR diventerà legge per tutte le aziende che
trattano dati sensibili di cittadini europei, a prescindere dalla
nazionalità o dalle leggi locali: in pratica tutte le aziende private
italiane, nessuna esclusa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa presentazione è quindi dedicata a chi si occupa di sicurezza e
che dovrà fare i conti con questa normativa, ma non da un punto di vista
legale, bensì tecnico: come posso aderire alle richieste se uso il
database MySQL?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quindi dopo un breve introduzione alla GDPR, ci concentreremo su come
MySQL possa soddisfarne le richieste (con riferimento ai vari articoli)
così da fornire la conoscenza che permetta di scegliere le strategie
migliori per il proprio business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa sessione è indicata per chiunque lavori con MySQL. Saranno date
per scontate solo le conoscenze di base dei database, ma chi ha già
conoscenza di MySQL potrà apprezzarne a pieno le opzioni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Carlessi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/la-sicurezza-dei-database-mysql-in-ottica-gdpr.html</guid><category>Cryptography</category><category>sql</category><category>architecture</category><category>mysql</category><category>best-practices</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>Protecting Privacy and Security — For Yourself and Your Community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/protecting-privacy-and-security-for-yourself-and-your-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet service providers, ad networks, governments… Many organizations
have increasing access to our personal information. Protecting privacy
in this environment is a non-trivial effort, and the threats posed by
malicious attackers further exacerbates this problem. We, as developers,
owe it to ourselves and to our communities to do the best we can to
improve our collective security and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees of this talk will walk away with a thorough understanding of
the following topics and the problems they solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multi-factor authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encrypted DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH/VPN tunnels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full disk encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compartment isolation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“onion-skin” routing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, digital interactions with other people increasingly occur
via hosted services, which while convenient can compromise the privacy,
integrity, and control of our data. With some open-source software and
inexpensive virtual servers, we can take back control and empower us all
to securely share our lives with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Justin Mayer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/protecting-privacy-and-security-for-yourself-and-your-community.html</guid><category>Privacy</category><category>PyCon SK</category><category>Python</category><category>Security</category></item><item><title>Pyramidセキュリティ</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2012/pyramidsekiyuritei.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pyramidセキュリティ&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">村岡 友介</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-15:pycon-japan-2012/pyramidsekiyuritei.html</guid><category>pyramid</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>Value Driven Threat Modeling - Security by Design</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2018/value-driven-threat-modeling-security-by-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Threat Modeling is a great method to identify potential security weaknesses, and is an important part of any secure design. A threat model can help analyze how to best protect your assets, prevent attacks, harden your systems, and efficiently prioritize security investment. Regardless of programming language, threat modeling provides a far greater return than most any other security technique in the development process. Therefore, threat modeling should be an early priority in application design process. Unfortunately, it is common knowledge that building a full threat model is always heavily resource intensive, requires a full team of expensive security professionals, takes up far too much developer time, and does not scale at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the common knowledge is wrong! In fact, this is not at all necessary, and should not be an excuse to avoid building a robust system. Using a value-driven approach, skilled development teams can very efficiently ensure that the features they build can protect themselves, the application, and the business value that the features were created for. Value Driven Threat Modeling offers an alternative to top-heavy, big-model-up-front threat modeling that security pros love, in favor of agility, speed, and developer independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe Value Driven Threat Modeling, and show how to incorporate it into your existing agile development. We will discuss how developers can efficiently produce and leverage a threat model to improve application development, and walkthrough some example scenarios. If you want to be a good developer in 2018, you need to prepare for the threats of 2020!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Avi Douglen</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-06-04:pycon-israel-2018/value-driven-threat-modeling-security-by-design.html</guid><category>security</category></item><item><title>All in the timing: How side channel attacks work</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/all-in-the-timing-how-side-channel-attacks-work.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, you’ll learn about a category of security issue known as side channel attacks. You’ll be amused to see how features like automatic data compression, short-circuit execution, and deterministic hashing can be abused to bypass security systems. No security background knowledge is required. The talk assumes at least intermediate Python experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll take a tour of real side channel vulnerabilities in open source Python codebases, including the patches that fixed them. It also offers practical advice for avoiding these issues. My goal is to demystify this topic, even if you aren’t writing security-critical software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip James</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/all-in-the-timing-how-side-channel-attacks-work.html</guid><category>security</category><category>vulnerability</category></item><item><title>Scientific Hooliganism: lessons from the first hack in history</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/scientific-hooliganism-lessons-from-the-first-hack-in-history.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1903, Guglielmo Marconi prepared to unveil his world-first,
long-distance wireless communication technology to the Royal Institution
in London. He was looking forward to roaring success, scientific
acclaim, and a string of wealthy new customers - but he didn’t count
upon falling victim to the first hack in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a tale of business secrets, flame wars, stage magic, and
magnificent sideburns, direct from the records of Edwardian England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk highlights several of the lessons that the FLOSS and
information security communities can still learn from the fateful events
of 1903. Marconi’s tale is a master class in the necessity of open
source technology, as well as being a delightful introduction to the art
of vulnerability reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilly Ryan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/scientific-hooliganism-lessons-from-the-first-hack-in-history.html</guid><category>infosec</category><category>FLOSS</category><category>radio</category><category>security</category><category>hacking</category><category>history</category></item><item><title>Oh, I found a Security Issue</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/oh-i-found-a-security-issue.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A talk together with Florian Apolloner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever thought about what happens when somebody finds a security issue in Django? How does one responsibly disclose the issue? What happens after that? How does the Django team work on it? What happens until a Django security release is published? What comes afterwards?
Also, Django is “reassuringly secure”. Let’s look at the history ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll give an insight on how the Django team handles security issues,
which can serve as a guideline and followed in own projects. We'll
will also review the history of Django's security issues to identify
hotspots and areas to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Holtermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-28:pyconweb-2017/oh-i-found-a-security-issue.html</guid><category>django</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>Frog and Toad Learn Django Security</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/frog-and-toad-learn-django-security.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Philip James&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join us by the fire as we have Security Story Time with our friends, Frog and Toad. With them, you'll learn about all the things Django does to protect users and developers out of the box. We'll look at simplified code samples from the Django codebase to see what's happening under the hood, and cover how to make the Django security model even stronger in your application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip James</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/frog-and-toad-learn-django-security.html</guid><category>security</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Eat Your Vegetables Data Security for Data Scientists</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/eat-your-vegetables-data-security-for-data-scientists.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/WilliamVoorhees1/eat-your-vegetables-data-security-for-data-scientists"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/WilliamVoorhees1/eat-your-vegetables-data-security-for-data-scientists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've got data: lots of it. People want to get their hands on that data. You don't want that, so let's go over a few things you can do to dissuade attackers from getting their grubby mitts on your hard processed datastore. We'll cover the obvious things (spoiler alert: encryption) and then some advanced techniques for keeping data secure while still keeping it usable (that is to say, analyzable).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Will Voorhees</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/eat-your-vegetables-data-security-for-data-scientists.html</guid><category>Data</category><category>Security</category></item><item><title>The Internet of (Better) Things</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/the-internet-of-better-things.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things! Existential menace or meaningless buzzword? Automating away drudgery or just eroding privacy? Cornucopia or Panopticon? We'll look at the poor state of the current IoT in terms of security, privacy and interoperation. We'll consider a set of requirements for a better IoT. And we'll look at what we as Pythonistas can do to improve on this, as a community and an industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nick Moore</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:pycon-au-2016/the-internet-of-better-things.html</guid><category>Internet-of-Things</category><category>Security</category><category>Privacy</category><category>Interoperation</category></item><item><title>Pony Pwning</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--pony-pwning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django's awesomeness unfortunately doesn't make it impenetrable. This
talk will cover common pitfalls of the Django developer as seen through
the eyes of a hacker or malicious user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django is arguably the most secure web framework. The Django team have
done an excellent job making secure-by-default decisions for our web
applications in many situations. Still, the last mile in development is
where the bulk of security vulnerabilities can be introduced and
Django's powerful flexibility allows for plenty of rope for developers
to hang themselves. Understanding the vulnerabilities that can be
created by common mistakes or misconceptions and overlooked details in
development will be useful for any Django user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Baldwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-08:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--pony-pwning.html</guid><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2010</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>Advanced security topics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--advanced-security-topics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced security topics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Paul McMillan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An in-depth look (with demonstrations) at the how and why of several
advanced security topics. Discussion of ways to improve security of the
framework moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul McMillan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-05:djangocon-us-2011/djangocon-2011--advanced-security-topics.html</guid><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2011</category><category>security</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>How we found our security best practices (and what they are)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2012/how-we-found-our-security-best-practices-and-wha.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mozilla takes data security very seriously. We have AppSec, OpSec, and
InfraSec teams, and our web developers have baked our security best
practices into documentation and a Django app called Funfactory. Hear
how we came to those best practices, what they are, and how to follow
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Privacy and security are key parts of Mozilla's mission, and we build
some of the largest Django applications on the web, so being at the
absolutely forefront of security is crucial to us. And having a great
user experience is, too. So over the past few years, we've developed a
number of proposals, tools --like Bleach and django-ratelimit--and best
practices, and we've wrapped these up into our application template
Playdoh and an app called Funfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll share those best practices and their motivations. We'll also go
over a number of tools, settings, and even some fairly new web standard
proposals (with tools, of course) to help you build the most secure
Django applications you can, at whatever scale you're building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Socol</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-04:djangocon-us-2012/how-we-found-our-security-best-practices-and-wha.html</guid><category>django</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>sqlmap - security development in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlmap-security-development-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Miroslav Stampar - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;sqlmap&amp;quot; is one of the largest, widely used and most active Python
projects in the IT security community (more than 2000 commits in one
year period with community of over 100 active testers). It combines it's
developers' strong security knowledge together with analytical,
mathematical and Python development skills to provide IT professionals
with vibrant features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk would be consisted of several parts: short introduction to project
and developers, developing and testing environment, programming cycle,
program's workflow, technologies used, common pitfalls and how we've
circumvent them, usage of mathematical models, optimizations, project's
future goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The significant part of this talk would be the immediate insight into
the developing process of probably the world's most advanced open-source
Python IT security project today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miroslav Stampar</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/sqlmap-security-development-in-python.html</guid><category>community</category><category>security</category><category>testing</category></item><item><title>What is Google App Engine?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google App Engine is a unique hosting platform that lets you build
applications and run them in Google's data centers using the massive
global infrastructure built to run the Internet's most powerful company.
App Engine offers a development environment that uses familiar
technologies (Java and Python) and provides a powerful and robust set of
APIs to users while maintaining security and independence from other
apps running in the cloud. It is always free to get started so you can
try it out with no risk, and if you need additional computing resources,
you can purchase additional computing resources beyond the free quota
limits. (If you enable billing and trust us with your credit card, we
will extend your free quotas even further; you won't get charged until
you exceed those &lt;em&gt;extended&lt;/em&gt; quotas.) Scale your application to millions
of users and pay only for what you use at competitive market pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we provide an update of the newest features found in
the most recent releases of the App Engine platform. We also share some
suggestions for best practices to existing App Engine developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners to the App Engine platform will be interested in the
introductory workshop which may be offered (see description below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google App Engine workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we'll give you a comprehensive introduction to the
platform in two/three components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-hour Introduction to Cloud computing and Google App Engine seminar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-hour App Engine hands-on workshop/codelab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first hour, we review Cloud Computing as an industry and where
Google App Engine fits into the picture. Specifically, we discuss App
Engine as a PaaS solution because of the inherent challenges of building
web and other applications. We'll outline the architecture of App
Engine, what it's major components are, introduce its features and APIs,
discuss the service and how it works (including information on the free
quotas), present some information about current users and usage,
including integration with Google Apps, and finally, give an overview of
its enterprise edition called Google App Engine for Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the approximately one-hour lecture, we'll show you how to create
applications that run on App Engine by building a simple but real web
application from the ground up via a hands-on coding laboratory.
Although based on the online tutorial, this codelab goes up and beyond
what's in the documentation: you will get a more detailed step-by-step
instructions to replicate that example as well as have the opportunity
to extend your application with some of the newer APIs that come with
App Engine. The codelab will cover the Users service, non-relational
Datastore, and Memcache APIs. Time-permitting, we'll also discuss some
of the newest features found in recent App Engine releases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html</guid><category>architecture</category><category>cloud</category><category>google</category><category>hosting</category><category>infrastructure</category><category>memcache</category><category>security</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Seattle: A Python-based Platform for Easy Development and Deployment of Networked Systems and Applications (#162)</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--seattle--a-python-based-platform-for-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Python-based Platform for Easy Development and Deployment of Networked
Systems and Applications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Ivan Beschastnikh, Justin Samuel, and Justin Cappos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle is an open-source platform for developing and deploying
networked applications. Core feature of Seattle is that it allows safe
execution of untrusted code on end-user systems. In our talk we look at
how we used Python to build a safe, restricted code execution
environment for Seattle that not only provides execution safety but also
enforces strict resource consumption limits. In addition, Seattle
includes a high-level API to hide inconsistent OS-specific behaviors
from developers. What results is a platform that welcomes the
participation of end-user machines for general-purpose distributed
programming and creates new possibilities for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://seattle.cs.washington.edu/"&gt;http://seattle.cs.washington.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Beginning of talk missing, due to technical
problems.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan Beschastnikh</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--seattle--a-python-based-platform-for-.html</guid><category>api</category><category>language</category><category>mobile</category><category>network</category><category>p2p</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>seattle</category><category>security</category><category>university</category></item><item><title>Through the Side Channel: Timing and Implementation Attacks in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--through-the-side-channel--timing-and-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the Side Channel: Timing and Implementation Attacks in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Geremy Condra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python's dynamic nature, large standard library, and concern for beauty
over performance make it an elegant and uniquely easy to use language,
but they also cause some unique problems. In this talk we'll explore how
features ranging from dictionaries to duck typing can become security
risks, demonstrate those attacks on real Python projects, and examine
how you can protect yourself and your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, an increasing body of evidence has accumulated
indicating that even when a system is hardened enough to provide strong
guarantees about its high-level behavior, implementation details and
especially performance properties can still provide attackers with an
easy way in. For Python, this is especially problematic: its generally
high-level view and the emphasis placed on flexibility often mean that
it can be difficult to stop attackers from gaining a foothold, while its
comparatively low execution speed increases the efficacy of wide variety
of implementation and timing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help Pythonistas understand and cope with these problems, we've
divided this talk into two parts: in the first, we demonstrate the
attacks against a series of widely-deployed Python projects with the
goal of both improving awareness about the issue and demonstrating
common weaknesses to be avoided. The second demonstrates effective
countermeasures and alternative constructions with the goal of improving
defenders' odds of spotting and correcting these flaws in their own
code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Geremy Condra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--through-the-side-channel--timing-and-.html</guid><category>hacking</category><category>hardening</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>TUF: Secure Software Updates in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--tuf--secure-software-updates-in-pytho.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TUF: Secure Software Updates in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Geremy Condra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an attacker's point of view there are few entry points with as much
to offer as a vulnerable software updater, yet history tells us that
such vulnerabilities are common. In this talk we'll demonstrate a number
of attacks, explain how common approaches fail to defend against them,
and demonstrate a pure Python library (TUF) that provides both robust
protection and extreme ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities in software update systems expose users to huge range of
potential security risks, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freeze attacks,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix-and-match attacks,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rollback attacks, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endless data attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this talk, we'll demonstrate each of these against
real- world software updaters and explain how commonly used
countermeasures fail in application. We'll then move on to the second
part of the talk, demonstrating TUF, its internals, and the mechanisms
it uses to additionally defend against key compromise. Finally, we'll
demonstrate how easy it is to integrate TUF into your application and
its lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Geremy Condra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--tuf--secure-software-updates-in-pytho.html</guid><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>security</category><category>tuf</category><category>updates</category></item></channel></rss>