<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_sentiment-analysis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>An Introduction to Sentiment Analysis of Textual Data</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/an-introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-of-textual-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Fatma Tarlaci</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/an-introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-of-textual-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you’ll be introduced to Sentiment Analysis (SA), the extraction of subjective, affective information from text through Natural Language Processing (NLP) to enable data-driven decisions. Participants will work through a step-by-step application of SA to build a sound knowledge of its different components and an understanding of this powerful technique in various business settings&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="sentiment analysis"></category><category term="natural language processing"></category><category term="nlp"></category></entry><entry><title>Multi-lingual Text Data for Sentiment Classification</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-philippines-2019/multi-lingual-text-data-for-sentiment-classification.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gyenn Neil Ibo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-02-23:pycon-philippines-2019/multi-lingual-text-data-for-sentiment-classification.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labeled Training Datasets or off-the-shelf tools for labeling training datasets for Sentiment Classification are readily available for English and other major languages. For Tagalog and other Filipino languages, however, this is rarely the case. I developed a novel technique that essentially transfers the knowledge of the labeled training dataset on one language (English) into Tagalog and other Filipino languages. This thus enables one to develop Neural Network Sentiment Classification models on several Filipino languages, leveraging on the availability of large amounts of training data on the English language. This is a better approach than manually labeling data on Filipino languages, as it would take too many resources, and Neural Networks need huge amounts of training data in order to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="sentiment analysis"></category><category term="multilingual"></category></entry><entry><title>Increasing the trading prediction by mining aggregated human texting messages</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-barcelona-2017/increasing-the-trading-prediction-by-mining-aggregated-human-texting-messages.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-21T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-21T12:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Yang Liu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-21:pydata-barcelona-2017/increasing-the-trading-prediction-by-mining-aggregated-human-texting-messages.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A novel approach is proposed to predict intraday directional-movements of the stock in the trading market based on the text of breaking financial news or social media by event data. This work is an effort to put more emphasis on the text-mining methods and tackle some specific aspects thereof that are weak in previous works. The research is a specific market, namely, the trading and stock market,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentiment analysis This step is observed the time series of the company‘s event based on the financial news or the social media, which analyses problem of coreference in text mining that is sentiment classification. Fasttext is inspired method that focuses on the meaning of words, which solves to obscure by ambiguity and play on words. This way can classify polarity, subjectivity and intensity in the corpus. According to the results of the classification, then it changes to the word representation. Thus, prediction accuracy increases significantly at this layer that is attributed to appropriate noise-reduction from the feature-space. Model creation and prediction The first layer is termed Sentiment Integration Layer by the deep neural network, which integrates sentiment analysis capability into the algorithm by proposing a sentiment weight that reflects their sentiment. Additionally, this layer reduces the dimensions by eliminating value in terms of sentiment and thereby improves prediction accuracy. The second layer encompasses a deep neural network model creation algorithm. It updates the models with the most recent information available, the deep learning algorithm is extensively evaluated using real market data and news content across multiple years, which is a good fitting capability to evaluate and select the financial news. The third layer is that it uses the recursive neural network explore patterns and of financial news through the recursive and pooling operation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="sentiment analysis"></category></entry></feed>