<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_sandianationallaboratories.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Supercomputer and Cluster Application Performance Analysis using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--supercomputer-and-cluster-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel W. Barnette</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--supercomputer-and-cluster-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyCon 2011: Supercomputer and Cluster Application Performance Analysis
using Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Daniel W. Barnette, PhD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandia National Labs analyzes high-performance computing environments to
optimize application performance, analyze system architectures, and
provide design guidance for future systems. We discuss 1) generating
performance data across multiple systems using mini-applications, and 2)
using our open source Python tools Pylot/Co-Pylot to store and analyze
data using a MySQL database server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandia National Laboratories analyzes large-scale, state-of-the-art high
performance computing environments for the Department of Energy (DOE),
Department of Defense (DoD), and other government agencies. Execution
efficiency is vital when dealing with datasets that require billions of
elements or when running simulations that take millions of core-hours to
complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One approach to investigating execution efficiency is to instrument our
large- scale applications and platforms to generate timings and other
performance data. Although effective in mature computing environments,
working directly with large-scale applications is cumbersome, time
consuming, and even impossible in the early stages of computer system
analysis and design. Furthermore, the software and data sets of these
applications may be restricted, limiting our abilities to collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to enhance our analysis capabilities far upstream from when
large- scale applications can be used and when working with external
collaborators, we have developed a collection of mini-applications that
capture the essence of our much larger scientific codes, are readily
applicable to both large and small systems, and whose run-time
information can accurately reveal problems associated with execution
efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating the data is only half the problem, though. We need the
ability to capture platform-relevant mini-app performance data at the
convenience of the testers when and where they generate the data. We
also need the ability to search through, filter, and visualize the
resulting performance measurement datasets in detail to identify and
understand trends and patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandia National Laboratories has developed a performance analysis suite
primarily consisting of two tools written in Python, Pylot and Co-Pylot.
Co- Pylot is a relatively simple interface that enables easy batch
transfer of performance data to a remote MySQL database server for
persistent storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once stored, the performance data is extracted, organized, filtered, and
analyzed using Pylot, a more functionally complex interface. Pylot is
used to present user-selected MySQL database fields in a variety of
views including statistical data, bar and pie charts, Cartesian or
log-log or semi-log plots, reference curves for comparisons, and Kiviat
diagrams (also called radar charts) for multivariate datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A built-in storage buffer provides the ability to store, compare, and
analyze data from multiple databases. This capability is critical for
studying performance variations of a code running on a particular
architecture, comparing application performance across architectures, or
comparing multiple applications on one or more architectures. Values in
up to four database fields at a time can be mathematically combined to
generate a new temporary field to provide complete generality while
accessing a database. Further, Pylot provides the ability to easily move
MySQL databases and tables between computers, including the analyst’s
laptop. This coherency of databases across multiple analysis platforms
can be used, for example, to avoid network latency issues associated
with accessing remote servers. It also serves as a distributed backup
system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outline of this presentation follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications at Sandia National Laboratories (6 mins)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulation size and runtime of typical large Sandia applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulties of using large-scale applications in early computer
system design and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mantevo mini-apps – small, self-contained programs that embody
essential performance characteristics of key applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gathering data (4 mins)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What information Mantevo mini-apps provide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-Pylot – getting your data into a remote database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supercomputer and Cluster application analysis (10 mins)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pylot – demo of accessing and graphing MySQL data as a method for
analyzing performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diagnosing performance issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing different systems and different runs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future Extensions of Pylot (5 mins)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capturing compile-time and execution info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efforts to move parts of Pylot to the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="pylot"></category><category term="sandianationallaboratories"></category><category term="supercomputer"></category></entry></feed>