<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bokeh: Using python for interactive data visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/bokeh-using-python-for-interactive-data-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is an interactive visualization library that targets modern web
browsers for presentation. Its goal is to provide elegant, concise
construction of novel graphics in the style of D3.js, and to extend this
capability with high- performance interactivity over very large or
streaming datasets. In this talk, you will learn to use Bokeh to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create simple interactive plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;annotate and styling the plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using bokeh plots in web pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;link interactive visualizations to a running python instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stream data to plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using Datashader to view and interact with large datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization is key to understanding the information contained in
data. The interactivity provide a valuable means for engineers, data
journalist, and scientist to explore their data. This talk will
introduce ( &lt;em&gt;using also some code example&lt;/em&gt; ) the audience to the basics
of using Bokeh, demonstrate different aspects of the library, and teach
how to deal with data formats ( &lt;em&gt;pandas&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;numpy&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;bokeh Column Data
Source&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge required: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;python3&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas basics&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;numpy bascis&lt;/tt&gt;,
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;data mining&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;jupyter notebook&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some visualization examples refers
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/docs/gallery.html#gallery"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ernesto Arbitrio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/bokeh-using-python-for-interactive-data-visualization.html</guid><category>plot</category><category>Jupyter</category><category>pydata</category><category>bokeh</category><category>DataVisualization</category><category>dataminig</category></item><item><title>Data Visualization in Mixed Reality with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/data-visualization-in-mixed-reality-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Visualization charts are supposed to be our map to information.
However, when making charts, customarily we are just re-sizing lines and
circles based on metrics instead of creating data-driven version of
reality. The contemporary charting techniques have a few shortcomings
(especially when dealing with high-dimensional dataset):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context Reduction: in order to fit a high-dimensional dataset into a
chart one needs to filter/ aggregate/ flatten data which results in
reduction of full context of information. Without context most of the
charts show only a part of the story, that can potentially lead to
data misinterpretation/misunderstanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numeric Thinking: naturally humans have hard time perceiving big
numbers. While data visualization is suppose to help us to
conceptualize large volumes, unless the dataset is carefully
prepared, 2D charts rarely give us the intuitive grasp of magnitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceptual de-humanization: when examining charts it is easy to
forget that we are dealing with activity in real world instead of
lines/bars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augmented/Mixed Reality can potentially solve all of the issues listed
above by presenting an intuitive and interactive environment for data
exploration. Three dimensional space provides conditions to create
complex data stories with more “realistic assets” (beyond lines and
bars). The talk would present the architecture required to create MR
data visualization story with Python (70% of architecture), starting
with drawing 3D assets in a data-driven way and finishing with
deployment on MR devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Nicanorova</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/data-visualization-in-mixed-reality-with-python.html</guid><category>DataExploration</category><category>DataAnalysis</category><category>DataVisualization</category></item><item><title>Dai dati alla visualizzazione: la mia prima data pipeline</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/dai-dati-alla-visualizzazione-la-mia-prima-data-pipeline.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Costruire una data pipeline non deve essere per forza complicato. Nel
talk vedremo come si può realizzare una semplice data pipeline usando
Luigi per consumare dati da una API e prepararli per fare esplorazione e
visualizzazione con Superset (AKA Caravel).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Riccardo Magliocchetti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/dai-dati-alla-visualizzazione-la-mia-prima-data-pipeline.html</guid><category>DataExploration</category><category>superset</category><category>DataVisualization</category><category>etl</category><category>luigi</category></item><item><title>Basic principles of scientific data visualization</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/basic-principles-of-scientific-data-visualization.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific data visualization has its rules, and they are essential to
warrant effectiveness of the desired message one wants to convey. In
this talk, following the guidelines of Edward Tufte, a master of data
visualization, we show why these rules are important, and what happens
if some of them are not properly followed and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giuseppe Jurman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/basic-principles-of-scientific-data-visualization.html</guid><category>DataVisualization</category></item><item><title>Data Science &amp; Data Visualization in Python. How to harness power of Python for social good?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python as an Open Data Science tool offers many libraries for data visualization and I will show you how to use and combine the best. I strongly believe that power of data is not only in the information &amp;amp; insight that data can provide us, Data is and can be really beautiful and can not only transform our perception but also the world that we all live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I will primarily focus on answering/offer the answer to these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why we need data science and why more and more people should be really interested in analyzing data and data visualization? (motivation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is data science and how to start doing it in Python? (introduction of procedures, tools, most popular IDE-s for Python, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tools for data analysis and data visualization Python offers? (in each stage of analysis the best libraries will be shown for the specific purpose; as for data visualization we will focus particularly on Bokeh, Seaborn, Plotly and use of Jupyter Notebook and Plotly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to 'unlock' the insight hidden in data through Python and how to use it to transform not only public administration or business, but ultimately the transformation of the whole society and economy towards the insight &amp;amp; knowledge based? (potential of data science)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Data, Open Government Partnership, Open Public Administration &amp;amp; all the advantages of Open Data Science &amp;amp; Python. Data-Driven Approach. Everywhere. Now. (the end of talk +vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radovan Kavicky</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html</guid><category>python</category><category>data-science</category><category>data-visualization</category><category>analytics</category><category>PyData</category><category>PyDataBLN</category><category>PyDataBerlin</category><category>PyDataBA</category><category>PyDataBratislava</category><category>talk</category><category>Data</category><category>Bokeh</category><category>Social Good</category><category>datascience</category><category>jupyter</category><category>open science</category><category>open data science</category><category>DataVisualization</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>analysis</category><category>matplotlib</category><category>numpy</category><category>data wrangling</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>pandas</category><category>machine learning</category><category>deep learning</category><category>Open Data</category><category>Citizen Data Science</category></item></channel></rss>