<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mezzanine, the best CMS on Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2016/mezzanine-the-best-cms-on-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mezzanine &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mezzanine.jupo.org/"&gt;http://mezzanine.jupo.org/&lt;/a&gt; is one of CMSs on Python. I've used Mezzanine to host djangoproject.jp. On this session, you can learn the best way to host web sites on Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want you create nice, rich Web site by Python? Try Mezzanine.Mezzanine is one of CMSs on Python. I've used Mezzanine to host djangoproject.jp. On this session, you can learn the best way to host web sites on Python.
Mezzanine features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want you create nice, rich Web site by Python? Try Mezzanine. You can create pages, posting news and uploading images though nice Web interfaces. But also it can manage users flexibly, adding redirects and customize easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll tell you why I choiced Mezzanine. There's a lot of alternative CMSs in the world. Wordpress, django-cms, Plone and so on. Benefits and disadvantages of each CMSs is thene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ofcause I'll tell you way to start the project and deplay Mezzanine server to the Web. and way to customize Mezzanine. There's some nice themes. and you can change the page and design very easily. And it created by Python and Django, so If you can use them, you can add your own features very, very easily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hiroki KIYOHARA</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-20:pycon-japan-2016/mezzanine-the-best-cms-on-python.html</guid><category>mezzanine</category></item><item><title>Comparing Wagtail, Django CMS and Mezzanine</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/comparing-wagtail-django-cms-and-mezzanine.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adam Brenecki
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/102/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/102/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Django CMS, Mezzanine and Wagtail are the three most popular Django-based content management systems; all three have kept (or, in Wagtail's case, gained) their popularity because they are so different to each other. In many ways, from their fundamental data models right through to how they approach their content editing UIs, each one has a very different take on how a CMS should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore the different approaches, strengths and weaknesses of each CMS, and what they mean for you as a developer and for your content editors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Brenecki</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/comparing-wagtail-django-cms-and-mezzanine.html</guid><category>django</category><category>django cms</category><category>mezzanine</category><category>wagtail</category></item></channel></rss>