<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyOhio 2010: Project Management 101</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--project-management-101.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Project Management 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by James Bonanno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is employed for a general purpose project management tool.
Contrasted to tools like Sphinx which focus on documenting a software
project, this framework is intended for general purpose project
management, with a specific application into engineering projects.
Intermediate uses of Python are employed, as well as the Web.py
framework, Sphinx documentation tool and the Mako template system. The
author has used this tool to create internal commercial applications of
the project management software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Technical issues at beginning (first talk of
conference, gear wasn't quite setup); missing initial section of talk,
then missing 20 seconds about 3 minutes in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bonanno</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-07-31:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--project-management-101.html</guid><category>projectmanagement</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2010</category></item><item><title>Breaking down the process of building a custom CMS</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--breaking-down-the-process-of-buil.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to share some of the important insights
gained over a couple years of working on custom CMS-type projects
serving large organizations. Acknowledging that approx. 30 minutes is a
short time to cover a broad subject, the focus of the talk would be on
outlining a basic strategy for managing large projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, Brian and Yann's team have built and
worked on several large Django projects for large organizations. They
will discuss how to start and manage large CMS projects, with an
emphasis on pointing people to the best reference information and
breaking down the common operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary discussion topics would cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking Down the Job: Over the course of the project you'll end up
accounting for thousands of details; here's how to figure out the
first few Centering Around a Prototype: Hedging your bets for the
inevitable &amp;quot;give me a ballpark figure&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing With Legacy Data Stores: Migrate legacy information early and
often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selecting 3rd Party Components: Reuse exiting app, fork it early or
Trailblaze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad News: Django Ain't Perfect - where it has weaknesses and how to
compensate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk the audience will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
* Break down this type of project into meaningful phases
* Migrate large dataset to populate the django models that are still under development.
* Have a rational and objective approach to select django reusable component and understand how to refine them during the different stages of the project lifecycle.
* Find and evaluate quality information about the tradeoffs Django presents in these types of projects
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Luft</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-07:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--breaking-down-the-process-of-buil.html</guid><category>development</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2010</category><category>projectmanagement</category></item></channel></rss>