<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - errbufferoverfl</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_errbufferoverfl.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Collapsology: Why your biggest threat isn’t exposed RDP</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/collapsology-why-your-biggest-threat-isnt-exposed-rdp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>errbufferoverfl</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/collapsology-why-your-biggest-threat-isnt-exposed-rdp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(errbufferoverfl) What can we learn from decades of research on collapsology, the study of industrial civilizations collapsing? What do ancient civilizations have in common with security culture? The answer is a lot more than you think, and it doesn't even involve patching! So come along to discover what we …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(errbufferoverfl) What can we learn from decades of research on collapsology, the study of industrial civilizations collapsing? What do ancient civilizations have in common with security culture? The answer is a lot more than you think, and it doesn't even involve patching! So come along to discover what we can learn about identifying risks and threats in our security culture. Because if you aren't hacking it, who is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/JEQDAS/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/JEQDAS/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 09:30:00 2021 at Snakeoil Academy (Security &amp;amp; Privacy)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="errbufferoverfl"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry></feed>