<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_parsing.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Making use of OpenStreetMap data with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/making-use-of-openstreetmap-data-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrii Mishkovskyi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/making-use-of-openstreetmap-data-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Andrii Mishkovskyi - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how web maps are created? Ever wondered if you could build
something like Google Maps over a weekend? You probably can't, but this
talk will show you the basics of what you need to know, such as
importing data, rendering maps and even building simple routes. And all
of this in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract: * Learning how OSM data looks * Parsing and importing the
data * Rendering maps with Mapnik * Bits of code required to build
geocoder * Building simple router with Python and PostGIS * And anything
else I forgot to mention in this abstract but will talk about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitions: OpenStreetMap - the so-called &amp;quot;Wikipedia of maps&amp;quot; project,
with thousands of contributors who edit the map data of the whole world.
Unlike similar projects, the map data is completely free (both as in
beer and as in speech) and thus anyone can make use of it. Mapnik -
rendering framework, created specifically for OpenStreetMap, written in
C++ and Python. PostGIS - an extension of PostgreSQL database, with
support for many useful GIS features.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="gis"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="importing"></category><category term="learning"></category><category term="maps"></category><category term="parsing"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConAU 2010: Using Python for Natural Language Generation and Analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--using-python-for-natural-language-g.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tennessee J Leeuwenburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--using-python-for-natural-language-g.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Python for Natural Language Generation and Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Tennessee J Leeuwenburg (Australian Government Bureau of
Meteorology)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is used within the Bureau of Meteorology to automatically
generate weather forecast text based on numerical data. In addition, the
development team has also used Python to introspect the forecast
language and statistics used in the past. NTLK is an open-source
language processing toolkit which can be used for visualising language
patterns. This presentation will talk about some of the techniques used
for automatically describing datasets and also how NTLK can be used to
discover information about language uses and requirements in an
organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="language"></category><category term="nltk"></category><category term="parsing"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau2010"></category></entry><entry><title>Python-Aware Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--python-aware-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ned Batchelder</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--python-aware-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python-Aware Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Ned Batchelder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python provides many features for introspecting, analyzing, parsing,
compiling, and otherwise grokking Python code. This talk will cover a
number of the techniques for writing Python-Aware Python, and will
hopefully inspire you to build the next great Python tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python provides many features for introspecting, analyzing, parsing,
compiling, and otherwise grokking Python code. These modules and
techniques provide the foundation for developer's tools such as
autocompletion IDE's, code analysis tools, test runners, profilers, and
so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll delve into a number of the common techniques used to write
Python-Aware Python. Each has its area of applicability and its
strengths and weaknesses. I'll demonstrate small samples that show how
those techniques underlie the tools we all know and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of Python tools is ready for new exploration. This talk will
give you the foundation you need to write the next great Python-aware
application.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="analysis"></category><category term="compiling"></category><category term="introspection"></category><category term="parsing"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>