<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Exploratory Data Visualization with Vega, Vega-Lite, and Altair</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/exploratory-data-visualization-with-vega-vega-lite-and-altair.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploring a new dataset visually can provide quick intuition into the
relationships within the data. There are a few well-developed
visualization packages in Python, but they often have very imperative
APIs that force the user to focus on the mechanics of the visualization
– tick locations, axis limits, legends, etc. – rather than the salient
relationships within the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will introduce data visualization with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://altair-viz.github.io"&gt;Altair&lt;/a&gt;, a
package designed for exploratory visualization in Python that features a
declarative API, allowing data scientists to focus more on the data than
the incidental details. Altair is based on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vega.github.io/"&gt;Vega&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/"&gt;Vega-Lite&lt;/a&gt;
visualization grammars, and thus automatically incorporates best
practices drawn from recent research in effective data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial will provide an introduction to the Altair package and its
API, but more importantly will dive into the core concepts of effective
data visualization that can be applied using any visualization package
or tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jake VanderPlas</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/exploratory-data-visualization-with-vega-vega-lite-and-altair.html</guid><category>vega</category><category>vega-lite</category><category>altair</category></item></channel></rss>