<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_mind-bending.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>And now for something completely different.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/and-now-for-something-completely-different.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Danny Engelbarts</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/and-now-for-something-completely-different.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to show the audience a different way of
thinking about and developing regex statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working with UNIX for decades now and, although i always
managed to avoid Perl, i have been intrigued with Regex constructs ever
since my first encounter. These weird unreadable things that can
transform text like nothing else or can find what i’m looking for in
massive files, in no time at all. I’ve created regexes that only appeal
to the most nerdiest of nerds and i’ve stunned colleagues by fixing
their futile regex attempts in just a few keystrokes. But when Damian
Conway showed me how regexes really work i was awestruck. And now i want
to share this knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at pythonistas that have some experience with the re
module. I will take some easy examples and explain in plain english how
a regex engine searches for a match. This will show that a regex is not
some mysterious incomprehensible pattern description or declarative
blueprint. Instead it is a small program that is very good at comparing
single characters. Like any programming language it turns out that once
you understand the rules and structure it suddenly becomes so much
easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new found knowledge we will up the ante and try some more
difficult stuff, adding other semantics and some tips and tricks. We’ll
look at some pitfalls, maybe compare regex to python solutions and have
a look at some regexes found in the wild (either on my drive or on
github).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Compiler and Interpreters"></category><category term="Mind Bending"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry></feed>