<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Writing effective bayesian programs using TensorFlow and TFP</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-cordoba-2019/writing-effective-bayesian-programs-using-tensorflow-and-tfp.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial aims to provide some examples of how to write effective Bayesian programs using TensorFlow and Tensorflow Probability. In TFP land, effectiveness usually comes from writing model that could generate batch-able functions, and utilizing modern hardware (GPU, TPU) with compiler accelerator (i.e., XLA). I will give a walkthrough on how to do so and highlight some gotchas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Junpeng Lao</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-09-27:pydata-cordoba-2019/writing-effective-bayesian-programs-using-tensorflow-and-tfp.html</guid><category>bayesian</category><category>tensorflow</category><category>probability</category></item><item><title>Statistics and probability: your first steps on the road to data science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/statistics-and-probability-your-first-steps-on-the-road-to-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An introduction to statistics and probability geared toward enabling attendees to understand the capabilities and limitations of statistics and probability and to help them implement calculations in their projects. Where possible/feasible, attendees will build their own tools to help them grasp the underlying concepts. In addition, attendees will be introduced to the pre-built tools in world-class Python and data science libraries to help them capitalize on the efficiencies and utility that those libraries offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chalmer Lowe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/statistics-and-probability-your-first-steps-on-the-road-to-data-science.html</guid><category>statistics</category><category>probability</category></item></channel></rss>