<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Becoming Free</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2019/becoming-free.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has become the most widely used programming language. From time to time, employed professionals consider going on their own and become a freelancer. This talk will cover the most demanded Python based services for outsourcing. Anna will also talk about the freelancer mindset together with the legal and economical aspect of being self-employed in Sweden. After the talk, you will be able to see the full picture of freelancing and decide for yourself, if it is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Kazakova</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-31:pycon-se-2019/becoming-free.html</guid><category>freelancing</category></item><item><title>The Dangers of Outsourcing Software Development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-dangers-of-outsourcing-software-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customer lock-in. Dubious “Land and Expand” strategies. We have all
heard about outsourced software projects that run far past schedule and
obliterates the budget, yet somehow fail to meet even basic
requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can this happen. How can your company reduce the risks of delegating
software development to an external party?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal–Agent Problem is a well researched dilemma in economic
literature. It occurs when a person or entity (“agent”), is tasked to
work on behalf of another person or entity (&amp;quot;principal&amp;quot;). When the two
parties have divergent interests, the agent might act contrary to the
best interests of the principal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Examples of principal-agent relationships are:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Employer vs Employee&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Shareholder vs Management&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Voter vs Political party&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Contractor vs Software Consultant&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a firm decides to outsource software development to a third party,
there is an economic divergence of interest at play, as both parties
seek to maximize profit. The contractor wants its requirements met at
low cost and on a predictable schedule. The third party, when acting
nefariously, can maximize its own gains by extending the project,
utilizing junior or low-cost labor, and creating a relationship of
dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session we will look into some nefarious techniques and
practices used in the IT consulting industry and how best to avoid them.
We will also learn why it is particularly hard to mitigate the risks of
outsourced software development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Roll</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/the-dangers-of-outsourcing-software-development.html</guid><category>Business</category><category>Clients</category><category>Ethics</category><category>Management</category><category>freelancing</category></item></channel></rss>