<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_graphql.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Take Back the Web with GraphQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2019/take-back-the-web-with-graphql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Robert Myers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-13:pytexas-2019/take-back-the-web-with-graphql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GraphQL is an exciting technology that can help simplify web logic. Most of the attention has been focused on client-side improvements. This talk will show how GraphQL can structure your backend logic to reduce the client-side dependencies or remove them entirely!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>Real world Graphene - lessons learned from building a GraphQL API on top of a large Django project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-on-top-of-a-large-django-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marcin Gębala</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/real-world-graphene-lessons-learned-from-building-a-graphql-api-on-top-of-a-large-django-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphene is currently the most popular framework for building a GraphQL
in Python and it’s also an obvious choice for adding a GraphQL layer to
Django applications. Over the course of a year, we successfully built an
API with about 50 queries and over 100 mutations on top of existing
Django project (Saleor), but we also learned some hard lessons and had
to overcome several shortcomings of the framework along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I’d like to share some practical tips to overcome the most
common problems that a Django developer might face when building an
optimized and maintainable API with Graphene, such as: - using useful
abstractions to build queries and mutations faster - optimizing database
queries in a graph - structuring a large Graphene project - unified
error handling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to bring up a few limitations of the framework that we
discovered as we were working on the project and then end the talk with
the most important benefits that adoption of GraphQL brings to modern
web applications development - both for the backend and frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: - Intermediate knowledge of Django - Familiarity with API
design and concepts in terms of web development - Basic knowledge of
GraphQL or interest in it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the talk would be of great value to anyone working with a
Graphene framework and those who want to know more about building
GraphQL in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All code examples in the presentation would be based on Saleor
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mirumee/saleor"&gt;https://github.com/mirumee/saleor&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1644"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1644&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="API Design"></category><category term="e-commerce"></category><category term="graphql"></category><category term="open-source"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>How I migrate from REST API to GraphQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/odessapy-2018/how-i-migrate-from-rest-api-to-graphql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Igor Davydenko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-30:odessapy-2018/how-i-migrate-from-rest-api-to-graphql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hype around GraphQL now bigger than ever and I want to talk about it. How's easy to migrate from REST API to GraphQL, especially if you are Django developer? What you need to know to succeed? GraphQL in production is not a myth, and there are libraries to make it easy in Python world. Let's talk about them and path to migrate from Django REST Framework to Django + Graphene. Also I will talk why the migration will benefit frontend developers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>Choose Your Own Adventure for Client Web Services with GraphQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/choose-your-own-adventure-for-client-web-services-with-graphql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Anderson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/choose-your-own-adventure-for-client-web-services-with-graphql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we discuss Facebook’s graphql standard, an a la carte way
for front end clients to consume data from the backend, the python
implementation of that standard (graphine), basic queries and mutations,
and some advanced techniques. We’ll work up from shared principals with
traditional REST web services to the new paradigm of data specific to
each client request and how this makes backend and frontend developers
happier and more productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="audience-experience"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Audience Experience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermediate (requires some knowledge of Python, Django, REST web
services, etc. But will try to build a shared understanding of the core
concepts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="duration"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Duration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;45 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About me, Prologue to the Adventure (5m)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 - Architecture and Design (15m)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2 - Advanced Considerations (Authentication, Scaling,
Performance, Rate Limiting, etc.) (10m)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 - Authentication and Building a Rich Client Web Application
(10m)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epilogue + Questions (5m)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;domenica 22 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Relay"></category><category term="reactjs"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="graphql"></category><category term="Graphine"></category><category term="Apollo"></category></entry><entry><title>GraphQL in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/graphql-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Patrick Guido Arminio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/graphql-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In questo talk si parlerà di GraphQL, un “data query language” creato da
Facebook come alternativa al famoso REST. Verrano elencate la varie
differenze e i vantaggi/svantaggi rispetto ad una tradizionale API REST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrà inoltre mostrato come utilizzare GraphQL con Python con un piccolo
approfondimento su come utilizzarlo con Django. In caso ci sia
abbastanza tempo, verrano elencate anche alcune informazioni avanzate,
come Authentication, Caching, Security e Realtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeaway: l’obiettivo del talk è di dare una prima occhiata a GraphQL,
dando alcuni input su perché usarlo e sopratutto come iniziare ad usarlo
in Python con e senza Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: il talk è rivolto a sviluppatori web con un po’ di esperienza
di API web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="flask"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="graphql"></category><category term="REST"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Building personalized APIs with GraphQL and python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-nigeria-2018/building-personalized-apis-with-graphql-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Samuel Omole</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-09-13:pycon-nigeria-2018/building-personalized-apis-with-graphql-and-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>Django and GraphQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2017/django-and-graphql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Patrick Arminio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-21:pycon-ireland-2017/django-and-graphql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a new alternative to REST API. GraphQL. GraphQL has been created by Facebook in 2012 and since then is being used by big companies like Facebook itself, Github, Shopify and so on. In this talk I'd like to explain why we need an alternative to REST APIs and why GraphQL is that alternative. Also we will see how to use GraphQL with Django and how to use it for non trivial applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>GraphQL, Dizendo Adeus ao REST</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/caipyra-2016/graphql-dizendo-adeus-ao-rest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Cassio Antonio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:caipyra-2016/graphql-dizendo-adeus-ao-rest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra do Cassio Antonio no Caipyra 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dizendo Adeus ao REST&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>Graphql in the Python World</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/graphql-in-the-python-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nafiul Islam</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/graphql-in-the-python-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nafiul Islam&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;gamesbrainiac)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm Nafiul. I am a Bangladeshi who got lucky and is now working in Amsterdam. I have a deep passion for teaching and learning; I spend a lot of time on StackOverflow, answering questions, and I also spend a lot of time mentoring people on hackhands. I've even written a book in PyCharm, to share all of my IDE secrets. I don't I have a right to have people listening to me, but I feel that what I have to say is worth a try listening to, and I'm also (I believe) a good guy to have a discussion with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a fan of One Direction, primarily because they seem like a bunch of overgrown teenage boys unable to come to terms with their own maturity. In case you want to hear some real music you might want to try out &amp;quot;Fortunate Son&amp;quot; by Creedence Clearwater Revival. I have more :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you've heard about this new thing called Graphql. What is it all about? What problems does it solve, and most importantly, how can you leverage it the python ecosystem? This talk is a tell all on what what Graphql is and how you can start using it with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphql is a new way of communicating with your data sources. It will very likely replace RESTful APIs because it provides a better framework for dealing with your data. This talk is about what Graphql is, what problems it actually solves in comparison to RESTful APIs, and if you like it, how you can get started using the python graphene library, and how to use it with different ORMs like Django and SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>Introducción a GraphQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/introduccion-a-graphql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-23T16:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T16:30:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Adrián Matellanes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-23:pycon-es-2017/introduccion-a-graphql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En la actualidad, la mayoría de las APIs que usamos a diario son REST o SOAP. La necesidad de ofrecer productos más complejos que simples aplicaciones CRUD donde creamos, borramos, listamos y modificamos recursos ha empujado a cambiar la forma en la que interactuamos con las APIs. En 2012, Facebook desarrolló GraphQL y lo lanzó al público en 2015 como proyecto open source. GraphQL nace para solucionar la mayoría de los problemas que nos encontramos cuando interactuamos con una API REST.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphql"></category></entry><entry><title>Why and how to GraphQL</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/why-and-how-to-graphql.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Victor Menezes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/why-and-how-to-graphql.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, GraphQL was introduced to the developer's world as the vaccine to our REST APIs addiction but looks like not many of us are looking for a cure. Why would we? What are the main differences in the development and how to get started with GraphQL on Python/Django are questions that are going to be answered during this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="GraphQL"></category></entry></feed>