<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_pyconsk.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Skynet your Infrastructure with QUADS</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/skynet-your-infrastructure-with-quads.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Will Foster</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-10:pycon-sk-2018/skynet-your-infrastructure-with-quads.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The very small 2-person DevOps team within Red Hat Performance/Scale
Engineering has developed a set of Open Source Python-based systems and
network automation provisioning tools designed to end-to-end automate
the provisioning of large-scale systems and network switches using tools
like Foreman, Ansible, and other Open Source bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QUADS – or “quick and dirty scheduler” allows a normally overburdened
DevOps warrior to fully automate large swaths of systems and network
devices based on a schedule, even set systems provisioning to fire off
in the future so they can focus on important things like Netflix and
popcorn or not reading your emails while your datacenter burns in an
inferno of rapid, automated skynet provisioning. QUADS will also
auto-generate up-to-date infrastructure documentation, track scheduling,
systems assignments and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll show you how we’re using QUADS (backed by Foreman) to
empower rapid, meaningful performance and scale testing of Red Hat
products and technologies. While QUADS is a new project and under
constant development, the design approach to handling large-scale
systems provisioning as well as the current codebase is consumable for
others interested in improving the efficiency and level of automation
within their infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll also dive into purposeful development design choices, how some of
these choices might not scale for the future (but work well at present)
and provide a future roadmap of a new redesign based on Flask, Celery,
Sqlite and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="DevOps"></category><category term="PyConSK"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Quads"></category></entry><entry><title>Interviews (CC) - Pycon SK 2018</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-sk-2018/interviews-cc-pycon-sk-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Kellner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-03-09:pycon-sk-2018/interviews-cc-pycon-sk-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interviews with PyCon SK 2018 conference participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Kellner - Conference Chair:
00:00 - What was the biggest challenge you had to face, while preparing the PyCon conference?
00:22 - Do you remember your first rendezvous with Python?
00:40 - What do you like the most about working with Python?
01:00 - Will you find motivation also to prepare the next year?
01:05 - What's your favourite programming language?
01:40 - What's your favourite animal?
02:04 - Would you like to say something to the organizers?
02:54 - Is this your first time on PyCon Slovakia?
03:11 - Can you see the improvement in comparison to previous years?
03:42 - Would you like to come also next year?
03:58 - Which presentation did you like the most?
04:35 - How did you like this conference?
EXTRA
04:52 - Which library do you use the most?
05:18 - How was the party yesterday?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Conference"></category><category term="PyConSK"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry></feed>