<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Using Python to create political acts</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/using-python-to-create-political-acts.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Pycon Italia I showed how my team has using Python and Data Science
to fight corruption - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiJ5a4CXRF8&amp;amp;t=8s"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiJ5a4CXRF8&amp;amp;t=8s&lt;/a&gt;
This time I want to show something that can be replicated in Italy right
after we finish the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &amp;#64;participatory (World Bank Internet impact researcher) says, every
country has a good response for public pressure across the internet, and
this response is even better within autocratic governments because they
want to keep healthy international relations. But how we can keep a
record of all the drafts of legislation that are happening right now?
How we can use this information and create an action for the public to
show their agreement or not for every change that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Scrapy, Python, Django, and Open source! Let me show you how has
been done in Brazil and the Pipeline that makes possible to replicated
here in Italy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1702"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1702&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe Cabral</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/using-python-to-create-political-acts.html</guid><category>web-scraping</category><category>Python</category><category>programming</category><category>scrapy</category><category>api</category><category>open-data</category><category>opendata</category><category>hacking</category></item><item><title>What's going on there? Understanding cities with location data.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/whats-going-on-there-understanding-cities-with-location-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, the audience will learn how to build from scratch with
Python machine learning models for predicting spatiotemporal activities
in cities using location data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing availability of data from cities (e.g., traffic flow, human
mobility and geographical data) opens new opportunities for predicting
and thus optimizing human activities. These may include human mobility,
land use classification, event detection and location recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we characterize the main activity of an area (e.g. Business,
Commercial, Nightlife)?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to detect and forecast unusual spatiotemporal events (e.g.
protest, sport game, concert)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to understand why people are moving between places?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will try to answers these questions explaining how, making use
of Python, it is possible to (i) collect and aggregate geo-located data;
and (ii) build machine learning models to predict spatiotemporal
activities. For example, an unusual activity in a local area at a
specific time can be predicted by analyzing the text from geo-located
tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we will present an organized picture of geo-located data such
as mobile phone data, geo-located texts from social networks (e.g.
Foursquare and Twitter), census and Open Street Map. Then, we will
briefly discuss how to collect and aggregate such data using Python
packages such as GeoPandas and OSMnx. Finally, we will cover topics
related to cities activities including event detection and forecasting,
human mobility, and location recommendation and prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As location data, we will mostly use samples from Open Street Map and
Foursquare. The example code will make use of (basics) Pandas and
GeoPandas. However, this is a beginner talk and it will be
self-contained as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;domenica 22 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gianni Barlacchi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-22:pycon-italia-2018/whats-going-on-there-understanding-cities-with-location-data.html</guid><category>geo-data-science</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>open-data</category><category>location-data</category></item><item><title>Data Science &amp; Data Visualization in Python. How to harness power of Python for social good?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python as an Open Data Science tool offers many libraries for data visualization and I will show you how to use and combine the best. I strongly believe that power of data is not only in the information &amp;amp; insight that data can provide us, Data is and can be really beautiful and can not only transform our perception but also the world that we all live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I will primarily focus on answering/offer the answer to these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why we need data science and why more and more people should be really interested in analyzing data and data visualization? (motivation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is data science and how to start doing it in Python? (introduction of procedures, tools, most popular IDE-s for Python, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tools for data analysis and data visualization Python offers? (in each stage of analysis the best libraries will be shown for the specific purpose; as for data visualization we will focus particularly on Bokeh, Seaborn, Plotly and use of Jupyter Notebook and Plotly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to 'unlock' the insight hidden in data through Python and how to use it to transform not only public administration or business, but ultimately the transformation of the whole society and economy towards the insight &amp;amp; knowledge based? (potential of data science)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Data, Open Government Partnership, Open Public Administration &amp;amp; all the advantages of Open Data Science &amp;amp; Python. Data-Driven Approach. Everywhere. Now. (the end of talk +vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radovan Kavicky</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html</guid><category>python</category><category>data-science</category><category>data-visualization</category><category>analytics</category><category>PyData</category><category>PyDataBLN</category><category>PyDataBerlin</category><category>PyDataBA</category><category>PyDataBratislava</category><category>talk</category><category>Data</category><category>Bokeh</category><category>Social Good</category><category>datascience</category><category>jupyter</category><category>open science</category><category>open data science</category><category>DataVisualization</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>analysis</category><category>matplotlib</category><category>numpy</category><category>data wrangling</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>pandas</category><category>machine learning</category><category>deep learning</category><category>Open Data</category><category>Citizen Data Science</category></item></channel></rss>