<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_neutrinos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Catching Neutrinos with Python and KM3NeT</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/catching-neutrinos-with-python-and-km3net.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Moritz Lotze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/catching-neutrinos-with-python-and-km3net.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;KM3NeT is the next generation underwater neutrino telescope located in
the deepest seas of the Mediterranean. Once completed, it will have an
instrumented volume of several cubic kilometres. One of the technical
challenges in such a huge project is providing software tools, which can
be rapidly developed and maintained while keeping a focus on
portability, compatibility and usability. The area of application ranges
from live monitoring over offline processing and analysis to data
visualisation and 3D event displays. Python with it’s wonderful standard
library combined with extraordinary open source frameworks proves to be
able to handle all these different tasks with ease. This talk covers
some of the projects used in our collaboration to make our lives easier,
featuring technologies such as Cython, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
Jupyter, Tornado, PyOpenGL, urwid and more, and focusses on one of our
key ingredients: a framework called KM3Pipe, which provides a
pipeline-based workflow to allow us building complex analysis chains by
stitching together modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="physics"></category><category term="pipeline"></category><category term="neutrinos"></category><category term="hephysiscs"></category></entry></feed>