<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Developing ecommerce platform with Django Oscar</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/developing-ecommerce-platform-with-django-oscar.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern technologies has changed the way how we buy and sell in the
Internet nowadays. Thus, we also constantly evolve the way how we build
projects to sell and buy goods using our technologies of choice - Python
and Django. Ease of customization and flexibility made Oscar application
of my choice for building custom ecommerce platforms on top of Django,
allowing to satisfy client requirements without necessity of
implementing solution from scratch, since Oscar have ready-made
applications for basket, checkout, shipping etc, available for the
further tweak and refinement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using and contributing to Django Oscar since 2015, designed
and supported various ecommerce projects in different fields (food,
accessories, shoes) and sizes during this time. In this talk I’m going
to share some of the experience and conclusions about building complex
ecommerce platform using Django, and eventually, Django Oscar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will go through the next topics:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Gaevsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/developing-ecommerce-platform-with-django-oscar.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Code-Review</category><category>Django</category></item><item><title>Code Reviews Using Art Critique Principles</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/code-reviews-using-art-critique-principles.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code reviews don't have to be a time consuming, morale zapping, arduous tasks. Not only can they catch bugs and errors but they can contribute in positive ways to the individual developer, the team, management and company as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art critiques have existed in academia for hundreds of years. The methodology of the critique has evolved to be time sensitive and productive, while keeping the enthusiasm of the student artist intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the art critique is to get peers and mentors to look at the work and raise any problems they may see. It's also time where people with more experience could contribute their knowledge in a helpful way. This process is about producing the best work, quickly and in a productive and constructive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods can be applied to code review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stacy Morse</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/code-reviews-using-art-critique-principles.html</guid><category>code review</category></item><item><title>Revisión de código en Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/revision-de-codigo-en-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de esta charla es dar a conocer los beneficios de la revisión de código, detallando los aspectos prácticos para llevar a cabo esta técnica de manera exitosa en proyectos colaborativos de desarrollo de software escritos en Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cesar Cardenas Desales</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/revision-de-codigo-en-python.html</guid><category>Track Básico</category><category>code review</category></item></channel></rss>