<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - Other Hardware</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_other-hardware.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Building quantum applications with D-Wave's Leap</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/building-quantum-applications-with-d-waves-leap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Condello</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/building-quantum-applications-with-d-waves-leap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get started coding on a quantum computer using D-Wave's Python-based Leap cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, quantum computing was largely reserved for researchers, physicists, and scientists with direct access to physical quantum computing systems. But the game has changed, thanks to the cloud. Barriers to quantum computing are coming …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get started coding on a quantum computer using D-Wave's Python-based Leap cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, quantum computing was largely reserved for researchers, physicists, and scientists with direct access to physical quantum computing systems. But the game has changed, thanks to the cloud. Barriers to quantum computing are coming down quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, cloud access (like D-Wave’s Leap 2 quantum application environment) and improvements in quantum computing hardware, software, and developer tools are allowing programmers around the world to code on live quantum computers in real-time. Developers, students, and researchers around the world can now tap into the power of a quantum via their browser — quantum mechanical knowledge not required. Users and private companies have already built over 200 early applications on D-Wave’s computers in industries ranging from automotive to machine learning, aerospace, finance, and beyond. The quantum application era is here, and the growing quantum developer community is making it a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, Alex Condello, Manager of Applications Development Technology and Tools at D-Wave Systems, will talk about the burgeoning quantum application development ecosystem, and how developers can start learning to code on a quantum computer today. This includes a walkthrough of Leap 2, D-Wave's new quantum cloud service equipped with hybrid solvers, and D-Wave's Ocean SDK. Alex will also explore some of the early applications that developers and companies have built to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Jupyter"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category><category term="Other Hardware"></category><category term="Python general"></category></entry><entry><title>Speak Python with Devices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/speak-python-with-devices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Petertc Chu</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/speak-python-with-devices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How Python can be used in IoT/infrastructure automation tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be a getting start guide on controlling hardware devices with Python. We know Python users are very keen on multitasking and always wish to know more about how it can be used in different tasks. This …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How Python can be used in IoT/infrastructure automation tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be a getting start guide on controlling hardware devices with Python. We know Python users are very keen on multitasking and always wish to know more about how it can be used in different tasks. This talk will help audiences exploring new Python skillset. Audiences may be inspired by this talk and apply it to many scenarios, e.g., IoT and infrastructure automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intended audiences include:
1. wish to know how Python can be used beyond data analysis and web dev
2. a Pythonista who interested in craft some touchable things
3. want to acquire something new into your Python skillset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audiences are expected to have basic knowledge about:
1. Python syntax and control flow
2. Computer and operating system (especially UNIX)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, audiences will have:
1. The basic idea of controlling devices with Python
2. Expanding their Python skillset. Know how to use Python in another interesting and useful task besides ML, web scrapping, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="EuroPython 2020"></category><category term="europython"></category><category term="europython-2020"></category><category term="europython-online"></category><category term="CPython"></category><category term="Hardware/IoT"></category><category term="Other Hardware"></category><category term="Unix"></category><category term="python"></category></entry></feed>