<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>An Introduction to Sentiment Analysis of Textual Data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/an-introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-of-textual-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you’ll be introduced to Sentiment Analysis (SA), the extraction of subjective, affective information from text through Natural Language Processing (NLP) to enable data-driven decisions. Participants will work through a step-by-step application of SA to build a sound knowledge of its different components and an understanding of this powerful technique in various business settings&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fatma Tarlaci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/an-introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-of-textual-data.html</guid><category>sentiment analysis</category><category>natural language processing</category><category>nlp</category></item><item><title>Enhancing Common Natural Language Processing with Cognitive Linguistics</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/enhancing-common-natural-language-processing-with-cognitive-linguistics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will present an overview of what we have learned in my company from combining our own proprietary cognitive linguistics technology with simple NLP methods such as sentiment analysis and named entity recognition. We will explore several use cases and discuss the impact of using both approaches together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Leonard</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/enhancing-common-natural-language-processing-with-cognitive-linguistics.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>natural language processing</category><category>cognitive linguistics</category></item><item><title>Multilingual embeddings to scale NLP models to multiple languages</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-austin-2019/multilingual-embeddings-to-scale-nlp-models-to-multiple-languages.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In NLP, we often come across situations where the text documents are not limited to one language. In this talk, we'll explore multilingual embeddings as an alternative to traditional word embeddings for creating NLP models that can scale effectively to data in multiple languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Deeksha Yennam</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-12-07:pydata-austin-2019/multilingual-embeddings-to-scale-nlp-models-to-multiple-languages.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>natural language processing</category></item><item><title>Natural language processing with neural networks.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/natural-language-processing-with-neural-networks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Getting started with a natural language processing and neural networks
is easier nowadays thanks to the numerous talks and tutorials. The
goal is to dive deeper for those who already know the basics, or want
to expand their knowledge in a machine learning field.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk will start with the common use cases that can be generalized
to the specific problems in a NLP world. Then I will present an
overview of possible features that we can use as input to our network,
and show that even simple feature engineering can change our results.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Furthermore, I will compare different network architectures - starting
with the fully connected networks, through convolution neural networks
to recursive neural networks. I will not only considering the good
parts, but also - what is usually overlooked - pitfalls of every
solution.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;All of these will be done considering number of parameters, which
transfers into training and prediction costs and time. I will also
share a number of “tricks” that enables getting the best results even
out of the simple architectures, as these are usually the fastest and
quite often hard to beat, at the same time being the easiest to
interpret.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hubert Bryłkowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/natural-language-processing-with-neural-networks.html</guid><category>Data Science</category><category>Deep Learning</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Natural Language Processing</category></item><item><title>Let the AI Do the Talk: Adventures with Natural Language Generation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/let-the-ai-do-the-talk-adventures-with-natural-language-generation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in Artificial Intelligence have shown how computers can
compete with humans in a variety of mundane tasks, but what happens when
creativity is required?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the concept of Natural Language Generation, the
task of automatically generating text, for examples articles on a
particular topic, poems that follow a particular style, or speech
transcripts that express some attitude. Specifically, we’ll discuss the
case for Recurrent Neural Networks, a family of algorithms that can be
trained on sequential data, and how they improve on traditional language
models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is for beginners, we’ll focus more on the intuitions behind the
algorithms and their practical implications, and less on the
mathematical details. Practical examples with Python will showcase
Keras, a library to quickly prototype deep learning architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brief outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Natural Language Generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Modelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recurrent Neural Networks and Long Short Term Memory for NLG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RNN examples with Keras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1574"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1574&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Bonzanini</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/let-the-ai-do-the-talk-adventures-with-natural-language-generation.html</guid><category>nlp</category><category>Keras</category><category>natural-language-processing</category><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>Procesamiento del lenguaje natural en python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2014/procesamiento-del-lenguaje-natural-en-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cubre algunos aspectos del procesamiento de lenguaje natural con NLTK (Natural Language ToolKit), explicando por encima en qué consiste, pasos para poder procesar un lenguaje, identificar patrones en un lenguaje y casos de uso útiles para aplicar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Iván Compañy</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-06:pycon-es-2014/procesamiento-del-lenguaje-natural-en-python.html</guid><category>nltk</category><category>natural language processing</category></item></channel></rss>