<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyOhio 2010: Processing Large Datasets with Hadoop and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--processing-large-datasets-with-hadoo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processing Large Datasets with Hadoop and Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by William McVey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how Hadoop along with Python can be used to
process large datasets. An overview of the Apache Hadoop project will be
given. The map/reduce concept will be introduced and some methods of
coding the data processing routines in python will be explored. The talk
will use real world examples to illustrate how this approach can be used
to parallelize computationally expensive operations across multiple
cluster nodes effectively using python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course will assume familiarity with the Python language during the
demos, but will not actually require a deep knowledge of python to
understand the concepts introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">William McVey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-07-31:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--processing-large-datasets-with-hadoo.html</guid><category>datasets</category><category>hadoop</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2010</category></item><item><title>Visualization and Analysis of Large Scale Datasets with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/visualization-and-analysis-of-large-scale-dataset.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Christine Moran - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Margherita &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce ParaView, an open source application
developed by researchers around the world for parallel visualization and
analysis of large scale datasets, which in can be used to visualize and
analyze terabytes of data in real time. ParaView’s core algorithms are
implemented in C/C++ but all its major functionality can be scripted
from python with ease. I’ll give a short introduction to AstroViz, a
parallel visualization tool for astrophysical simulations implemented as
an opensource plugin to ParaView, which I have been lead developer on
since 2009. The focus of the talk will be on driving ParaView from
within python however, both general out of the box use and customized
extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have access to several parallel supercomputers so if there’s a
huge dataset we as a crowd would like to tackle visualizing during the
course of the week that would be fun project. The end of the talk will
be a short brainstorm of cool applications of analysis and visualization
of large scale datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.paraview.org/"&gt;http://www.paraview.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christine Moran</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/visualization-and-analysis-of-large-scale-dataset.html</guid><category>analysis</category><category>datasets</category><category>opensource</category><category>parallel</category><category>simulations</category><category>visualization</category></item><item><title>Python(x,y): diving into scientific Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/pythonxy-diving-into-scientific-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Vincent Noel - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Margherita &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This training session will introduce the Python scientific stack to
beginner or intermediate-level Python programmers. The basics of
scientific programming with Python will be presented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creation of arrays and structured arrays using numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fast, loopless manipulation of numpy arrays through fancy indexing
and vectorized functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;convenient saving/loading of array variables using numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved interactive use through ipython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data analysis using various scipy modules (signal analysis, image
classification, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plotting large time series, histograms, scatterplots, images etc.
using matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saving/loading large datasets in structured scientific formats such
as netCDF, HDF (depending on interest)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts will be used in coding exercises, in the programming
environnement provided by the Python(x,y) distribution, which is freely
downloadable and includes recent versions of Python, numpy and
matplotlib. The Python(x,y) distribution runs on Windows, which will be
the OS of choice for this session. You should still be able to follow
the examples in other Python distributions, e.g. EPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire talk (PDF), code samples and data files can be downloaded
from the following
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lmd.polytechnique.fr/~noel/EP2011/DivingIntoSci%20entificPython.zip"&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vincent Noel</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/pythonxy-diving-into-scientific-python.html</guid><category>analysis</category><category>datasets</category><category>image</category><category>numpy</category><category>python,</category><category>scientific</category><category>scipy</category></item><item><title>PyConAU 2010: Displaying Australian datasets with Django</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--displaying-australian-datasets-with.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Displaying Australian datasets with Django&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last 18 months or so in Australia have seen an increased number of
government and public sector organisations releasing datasets to the
public under reasonable reuse terms (often Creative Commons license).
This talk will take a couple of those local real-world datasets and
create a minimal website for remixing them, using Django as the
underlying framework. The goals are to provide a short walk through the
process of importing and extracting such data in practice, show how to
incorporate Django's GIS features into an application, as well as
highlighting that real world is messy and so is the data it produces.
Working with datasets for journalism or research purposes, or simply
fun, requires a certain attention to detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic knowledge of Django is assumed, although the GIS components will
be introduced carefully as they are less familiar to many developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Malcolm Tredinnick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--displaying-australian-datasets-with.html</guid><category>datasets</category><category>gis</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau2010</category></item></channel></rss>