<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bonobo, Airflow and Grafana to visualize your business</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/bonobo-airflow-and-grafana-to-visualize-your-business.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zero-to-one hands-on introduction to building a business dashboard using
Bonobo ETL, Airflow, and a bit of Grafana (because graphs are cool).
Although the opposite is better, there is no need of prior knowledge
about any of those tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short introduction about the tools, we'll go through the
following topics, using the real data of a small SaaS software:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can expect to be able to build a similar system at the end of the
talk in a few days (of course, the implementation is only a small part
of this process, data is what really matters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;«Metrics you watch tend to improve over time»&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Dorgueil</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/bonobo-airflow-and-grafana-to-visualize-your-business.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Visualisation</category><category>Web</category></item><item><title>Creating an inclusive corporate culture</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/creating-an-inclusive-corporate-culture.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having a tech career as a minority is challenging. It could mean being
the only one to speak against the popular opinion, or becoming more
visible to get the same level of recognition. What can we do on the
corporate level to make sure everyone feels welcome and retain these
talents? Creating an inclusive corporate culture helps us achieve just
that. This talk shares concrete steps that employees and employers can
take to improve minorities in tech’s sense of belonging and engagement:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yenny Cheung</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/creating-an-inclusive-corporate-culture.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Community</category></item><item><title>Data Science meets Data Protection: Keeping your data secure while learning from it.</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/data-science-meets-data-protection-keeping-your-data-secure-while-learning-from-it.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will discuss anonymization and pseudonymization techniques that you
can apply to your data to keep it secure and comply with the law(s)
while still being able to gain useful insights from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will show concrete Python implementations of various techniques and
use example data sets to show how applying pseudonymization and
anonymization will affect our ability to do machine learning / data
science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Dewes</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/data-science-meets-data-protection-keeping-your-data-secure-while-learning-from-it.html</guid><category>Artificial Intelligence</category><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Data Science</category></item><item><title>How to make your (digital) Communication strong &amp; future ready</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/how-to-make-your-digital-communication-strong-future-ready.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your business is all set up and ready. You want to enter the market with
a new product or service. As digital communication evolves, brands and
companies are constantly facing new challenges. The ways of providing
information and interacting become more and more multi-layered and
complex. A well-defined communicative base can serve as a corrective
that prevents technology from becoming self-serving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simon Daubermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/how-to-make-your-digital-communication-strong-future-ready.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Community</category></item><item><title>Python on the blockchain: Triumphs and tribulations in a crypto startup</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/python-on-the-blockchain-triumphs-and-tribulations-in-a-crypto-startup.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many cryptographic components of blockchain protocols can be
extremely complex, blockchain systems themselves are relatively easy to
understand when viewed from a distance. To take the example of Bitcoin,
users store digital currency in hardware or software wallets, and use
private keys to sign and broadcast transactions. Broadcasted
transactions are grouped together into a block through a cryptographic
process known as mining, with miners rewarded through the collection of
transaction fees and the issuance of new coins. The mined block of
transactions is appended to the existing chain, and verified by a global
network of nodes. This process repeats in perpetuity, with each newly
added block adding to the trustedness and security of data stored on the
chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased interest in and demand for cryptocurrencies has brought about
a need for places where digital assets can easily be bought, sold or
traded. Our platform, Bitpanda, accomplishes this with a backend written
in Python, and relying heavily on Django and MySQL databases. In our
presentation, we begin by providing a brief overview of how blockchains
work. Following this, we describe the Python architecture that (e.g.)
generates cryptocurrency wallets, builds, signs and sends transactions,
and monitors blockchains for new, relevant data. Key challenges,
solutions and failures encountered during the development of the system,
and growth of our team, are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout our talk, we also highlight a number of broader social
implications of blockchains, and our work with them. More specifically,
we describe the need for open-innovation based approaches to blockchain
development, the value of open-source within the blockchain community,
and the current lack of critical discourse surrounding the potential
uses of blockchains as mechanisms of surveillance and control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Danny McDonald</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-25:pycon-de-2018/python-on-the-blockchain-triumphs-and-tribulations-in-a-crypto-startup.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Community</category><category>Django</category><category>Infrastructure</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>About going Open-Source</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/about-going-open-source.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will start of talking about why &amp;quot;working for free&amp;quot; became an important
part of the developer culture all around the world and talk about why
companies should try to share as many tools as possible. I'll give some
examples of tools that were open sourced and got immense traction
leading to the projects growing with an intense speed. I'll try to take
away the &amp;quot;fear&amp;quot; of open sourcing tools that cost ten of thousands of
dollars to create. Then I'll describe how my journey with open source
looks like and start talking about how you can get your feet into
contributing to known projects. After that I will close off with some
hints on doing and contributing to open source projects that worked out
great for me. They will also get an impression on what opportunities
will show up if they put some of their time into doing OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience can be mixed, but it's way more interesting for people that
are either new to programming or have never worked with open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, some of the listeners would leave the presentation
with the motivation and hard goal to start with OS as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tim Großmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/about-going-open-source.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category></item><item><title>Developing ecommerce platform with Django Oscar</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2018/developing-ecommerce-platform-with-django-oscar.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern technologies has changed the way how we buy and sell in the
Internet nowadays. Thus, we also constantly evolve the way how we build
projects to sell and buy goods using our technologies of choice - Python
and Django. Ease of customization and flexibility made Oscar application
of my choice for building custom ecommerce platforms on top of Django,
allowing to satisfy client requirements without necessity of
implementing solution from scratch, since Oscar have ready-made
applications for basket, checkout, shipping etc, available for the
further tweak and refinement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using and contributing to Django Oscar since 2015, designed
and supported various ecommerce projects in different fields (food,
accessories, shoes) and sizes during this time. In this talk I’m going
to share some of the experience and conclusions about building complex
ecommerce platform using Django, and eventually, Django Oscar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will go through the next topics:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Gaevsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-10-24:pycon-de-2018/developing-ecommerce-platform-with-django-oscar.html</guid><category>Business &amp; Start-Ups</category><category>Code-Review</category><category>Django</category></item></channel></rss>