<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Parallel computing in Python: Current state and recent advances</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/parallel-computing-in-python-current-state-and-recent-advances.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Parallel computing in Python: Current state and recent advances&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Modern hardware is multi-core. It is crucial for Python to provide&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;high-performance parallelism. This talk will expose to both
data-scientists and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;library developers the current state of affairs and the recent
advances for&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;parallel computing with Python. The goal is to help practitioners and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;developers to make better decisions on this matter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I will first cover how Python can interface with parallelism, from
leveraging&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;external parallelism of C-extensions –especially the BLAS family– to
Python's&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;multiprocessing and multithreading API. I will touch upon use cases,
e.g single&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;vs multi machine, as well as and pros and cons of the various
solutions for&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;each use case. Most of these considerations will be backed by
benchmarks from&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the scikit-learn machine&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;learning library.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;From these low-level interfaces emerged higher-level parallel
processing&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;libraries, such as concurrent.futures, joblib and loky (used by dask
and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;scikit-learn) These libraries make it easy for Python programmers to
use safe&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;and reliable parallelism in their code. They can even work in more
exotic&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;situations, such as interactive sessions, in which Python’s native&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;multiprocessing support tends to fail. I will describe their purpose
as well as&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the canonical use-cases they address.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The last part of this talk will focus on the most recent advances in
the Python&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;standard library, addressing one of the principal performance
bottlenecks of&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;multi-core/multi-machine processing, which is data communication. We
will&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;present a new API for shared-memory management between different
Python&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;processes, and performance improvements for the serialization of large
Python&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;objects ( PEP 574, pickle extensions). These performance improvements
will be&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;leveraged by distributed data science frameworks such as dask, ray and
pyspark.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pierre Glaser</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/parallel-computing-in-python-current-state-and-recent-advances.html</guid><category>Distributed Systems</category><category>Multi-Processing</category><category>Multi-Threading</category><category>Performance</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>Building Data-Driven Client Relationship Management in Banking with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/building-data-driven-client-relationship-management-in-banking-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a case study that documents how a small data science team in a
big bank took on the challenge to transform a fragmented sales process
into a data-driven one using Python and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk outlines the various ways Python has been instrumental in
delivering a production solution that serves advisers and relationship
manager on a continuous basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The Challenge&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- A bank has many clients with diverse needs and cost pressures mean
fewer advisers resulting in reduced client coverage.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Multiple sales channels and mixed service levels meant sales
processes were uncoordinated and driven by heuristics and often very
subjective.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- And... Excel sheets everywhere!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Solution&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Go data-driven!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Learn from clients and understand product usage&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Empower and inform advisers and call centre agents&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Build a front-to-back sales process (no more Excels!)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How? With Python!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The Python Bits&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Scikit learn machine learning pipelines that implement two distinct
approaches to product affinity in banking and wealth management&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- SQL Alchemy based API for data engineering and rapid prototyping of
analytics&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Pandas and Jupyter for development and collaboration&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Luigi pipeline for daily processing of millions of transactions and
engineering features&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Extracting features from text with NLP (Spacy)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Delivering machine learning interpretability in production, e.g.
with Random Forests and treeinterpreter&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- A Python module that we built with all the reusable bits: building
training and prediction datasets, developing pipelines, generating
monitoring data and enabling explainability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Hughes</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/building-data-driven-client-relationship-management-in-banking-with-python.html</guid><category>Business Cases</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category><category>Windows</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning with TensorFlow 2.0</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/deep-learning-with-tensorflow-20.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn about the updates being made to TensorFlow in its 2.0 version.
We’ll give an overview of what’s available in the new version as well as
do a deep dive into an example using its central high-level API, Keras.
You’ll walk away with a better understanding of how you can get started
building machine learning models in Python with TensorFlow 2.0 as well
as the other exciting available features!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brad Miro</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/deep-learning-with-tensorflow-20.html</guid><category>Data Science</category><category>Deep Learning</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>Machine learning on non curated data</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/machine-learning-on-non-curated-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to industry surveys [1], the number one hassle of data
scientists is cleaning the data to analyze it. Textbook statistical
modeling is sufficient for noisy signals, but errors of a discrete
nature break standard tools of machine learning. I will discuss how to
easily run machine learning on data tables with two common dirty-data
problems: missing values and non-normalized entries. On both problems, I
will show how to run standard machine-learning tools such as
scikit-learn in the presence of such errors. The talk will be didactic
and will discuss simple software solutions. It will build on the latest
improvements to scikit-learn for missing values and the DirtyCat package
[2] for non normalized entries. I will also summarize theoretical
analyses in recent machine learning publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk targets data practitioners. Its goal are to help data
scientists to be more efficient analysing data with such errors and
understanding their impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With missing values, I will use simple arguments and examples to outline
how to obtain asymptotically good predictions [3]. Two components are
key: imputation and adding an indicator of missingness. I will explain
theoretical guidelines for these, and I will show how to implement these
ideas in practice, with scikit-learn as a learner, or as a preprocesser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-normalized categories, I will show that using their string
representations to “vectorize” them, creating vectorial representations
gives a simple but powerful solution that can be plugged in standard
statistical analysis tools [4].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[1] Kaggle, the state of ML and data science 2017
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kaggle.com/surveys/2017"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/surveys/2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[2] &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dirty-cat.github.io/stable/"&gt;https://dirty-cat.github.io/stable/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[3] Josse Julie, Prost Nicolas, Scornet Erwan, and Varoquaux Gaël
(2019). “On the consistency of supervised learning with missing
values”. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1902.06931"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1902.06931&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[4] Cerda Patricio, Varoquaux Gaël, and Kégl Balázs. &amp;quot;Similarity
encoding for learning with dirty categorical variables.&amp;quot; Machine
Learning 107.8-10 (2018): 1477 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.00979"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.00979&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gael Varoquaux</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/machine-learning-on-non-curated-data.html</guid><category>Big Data</category><category>Data</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>Understanding Numba - the Python and Numpy compiler</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/understanding-numba-the-python-and-numpy-compiler.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you have numerical code written in Python and Numpy? Do you wish it
ran faster, using the full potential of your CPU?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you should try Numba, a JIT compiler that translates a subset of
Python and Numpy code into fast machine code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain how Numba works, and when and how to use it for
numerical algorithms, focusing on how to get very good performance on
the CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand this talk, only a basic knowledge of Python and Numpy is
needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will learn how Python compiles functions to bytecode and how Numba
compiles bytecode to machine code. Why algorithms implemented using
Numpy sometimes don't yield great performance, and how to do better
using Numba. You will learn about the &amp;#64;numba.jit and &amp;#64;numba.vectorize
decorators and how to create functions that use the CPU well by using
e.g. multi-threading (several CPU cores), vector instructions (single
instruction multiple data) and fast math (trade float accuracy for
speed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also learn when it does and doesn't make sense to use Numba, by
contrasting it briefly with some other options for high-performance
computing from Python: PyPy, C, C++, Cython, Numexpr, Dask, PyTorch,
Tensorflow and Google JAX&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christoph Deil</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/understanding-numba-the-python-and-numpy-compiler.html</guid><category>CPython</category><category>Compiler and Interpreters</category><category>Multi-Threading</category><category>Performance</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>“When a biologist met Python”</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/when-a-biologist-met-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Biology and computing are closer than we usually think, for example
many algorithms are inspired in biology patterns, and complementary to
that, researchers needs special algorithms to have a better
understanding of our environment. Thus, there is a strong relation an
dependency.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In the past years, Biology has been transformed into computational
biology. Therefore&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;technological advances helps us to predict physical interactions
between atoms and DNA, because we are being able to integrate
information from biology into algorithms.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become a popular programming language in biosciences because
it has a clean syntax that makes it easy to read language. In addition
to this, there are many modules (toolkits) extending to different
biological domains, like metabolomics, structure analysis,
phylogenomics, molecular biology and others. Python is currently
improving researcher’s workflow, helping us to focus on the theory or
experimental part, instead of fighting with old buggy applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to be oriented to all audiences (with/without biological
background) since we will go together through an amazing adventure into
the natural sciences using tools like Biopython, Bokeh, Networkx, Ecopy
and much more! Are you brave enough to follow me on this journey?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maria Molina-Contreras</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/when-a-biologist-met-python.html</guid><category>Algorithms</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Natural Science</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category><category>python</category></item><item><title>How to train an image classifier using PyTorch</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-train-an-image-classifier-using-pytorch.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neural networks are everywhere nowadays. But while it seems everyone is
using them, training your first neural network can be quite a hurdle to
overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will take you by the hand, and following an example image
classifier I trained, I will take you through the steps of making an
image classifier in PyTorch. I will show you code snippets and explain
the more intricate parts. Also, I will tell you about my experience, and
about what mistakes to prevent. After this all you need to start
training your first classifier is a data set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I will provide a link to the full codebase at the end. The
talk will focus on the practical aspect of training a neural network,
and will only touch the theoretical side very briefly. Some basic prior
knowledge of neural networks is beneficial, but not required, to follow
this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rogier van der Geer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/how-to-train-an-image-classifier-using-pytorch.html</guid><category>Deep Learning</category><category>Fun and Humor</category><category>Image Processing</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item><item><title>Image processing with scikit-image and Dash</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/image-processing-with-scikit-image-and-dash.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Images are an ubiquitous form of data in various fields of science and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;industry. Images often need to be transformed and processed, for
example for helping medical diagnosis by extracting regions of
interest or measures, or for building training sets for machine
learning.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this talk, I will present and discuss several tools for automatic
and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;interactive image processing with Python. I will start by a short&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;introduction to scikit-image (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scikit-image.org/"&gt;https://scikit-image.org/&lt;/a&gt;), the
open-source&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;image processing toolkit of the Pydata ecosystem, which aims at&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;processing images from a large class of modalities (2-D, 3-D, etc.)
and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;strives to have a gentle learning curve with pedagogical example-based&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;documentation. scikit-image provides users with a simple API based on
a large number of functions, which can be used to build pipelines of
image processing workflows.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In a second part, I will explain how to use Dash for building
interactive&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;image processing operations. Dash (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dash.plot.ly/"&gt;https://dash.plot.ly/&lt;/a&gt;) is an&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;open-source Python web application framework developed by Plotly.
Written on top of Flask, Plotly.js, and React.js, Dash is meant for
building data visualization apps with highly custom user interfaces in
pure Python. The dash-canvas component library of Dash
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dash.plot.ly/canvas"&gt;https://dash.plot.ly/canvas&lt;/a&gt;) is an interactive component for
annotating images with several tools (freehand brush, lines, bounding
boxes, ...). It also provides utility functions for using
user-provided annotations for several image processing tasks such as
segmentation, transformation, measures, etc. The latter functions are
based on libraries such scikit-image and openCV. A gallery of examples
showcases some typical uses of Dash for image processing on&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dash-canvas.plotly.host/"&gt;https://dash-canvas.plotly.host/&lt;/a&gt;. Also, other components of Dash can
be leveraged easily to build powerful image processing applications,
such as widgets to tune parameters or data tables for inspecting
object&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;properties.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Emmanuelle Gouillart</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/image-processing-with-scikit-image-and-dash.html</guid><category>Computer Vision</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Image Processing</category><category>JavaScript Web Frameworks (AngularJS/ReactJS/...)</category><category>Scientific Libraries (Numpy/Pandas/SciKit/...)</category></item></channel></rss>