<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Developing multi-platform apps with Python in 2013</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/developing-multi-platform-apps-with-python-in-2013.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guillaume Aubert</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/developing-multi-platform-apps-with-python-in-2013.html</guid><category>gui</category><category>application-development</category><category>deployment</category></item><item><title>The next iteration of your GUI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/the-next-iteration-of-your-gui.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will show how GUI applications written as a series of
generators are fun to write, responsive, user friendly and easy to unit
test. We dive into the details of language functions of PEP 342
(Coroutines via Enhanced Generators) and PEP 380 (Syntax for Delegating
to a Subgenerator). With this knowledge refreshed, we discuss why and
how these functions can be integrated in an event loop. Then we
demonstrate how we used these functions to rewrite all the asynchronous
operations of the Camelot framework and avoided series of callbacks
transforming the code from complicated to beatiful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erik Janssens</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/the-next-iteration-of-your-gui.html</guid><category>camelot</category><category>gui</category><category>coroutine</category></item><item><title>Building a cross-platform native app with BeeWare</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/building-a-cross-platform-native-app-with-beeware.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to write a GUI application you can run on your laptop? What about an app that you can run on your phone? Historically, these have been difficult to achieve with Python, and impossible to achieve without learning a different API for each platform. But no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeeWare is a collection of tools and libraries that allows you to build cross-platform native GUI applications in pure Python, targeting desktop, mobile and web platforms. In this talk, you'll be introduced to the BeeWare suite of tools and libraries, and see how you can use them to develop, from scratch, a GUI ChatBot application that can be deployed as a standalone desktop application, a mobile phone application, and a single page webapp - without making any changes to the application's codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Russell Keith-Magee</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/building-a-cross-platform-native-app-with-beeware.html</guid><category>beeware</category><category>cross-platform</category><category>gui</category></item><item><title>Genropy: 10 anni di sviluppo di un framework italiano</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
consente allo sviluppatore di scrivere applicazioni complesse in tempi
brevissimi. Lo scopo del framework è di mettere a disposizione un
potente costruttore di GUI web, un ORM molto facile, veloce ed intivo ed
una serie di component che rendono possibile costruire la propria
applicazione in poche righe di codice. A questo si aggiungono tools di
amministrazione per la gestione di permessi, grafici, gestione del
workflow, gestore di stampe e molti altri che fanno di Genropy
un’ambiente usabile immediatamente in produzione anche in situazioni
complesse e critiche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abbiamo cominciato a scrivere Genropy nel 2005 e durante il primo Pycon
qui a Firenze nel 2007, abbiamo ne abbiamo mostrato la primissima
versione. Da allora, ogni edizione di Pycon è stata l’occasione per
presentare le nuove features e cercare di diffondere la copnoscenza di
questo framework . A distanza di 10 anni possiamo dire che esiste una
minuscola ma molto attiva community che utilizza Genropy come strumento
quotidiano per scrivere le proprie applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk vorremmo raccontarvi questa avventura, e darvi modo di
conoscere meglio Genropy e di capire se può essere anche per voi il
vostro nuovo modo di scriverre applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giovanni Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html</guid><category>community</category><category>genropy</category><category>gui</category><category>web-development</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>La GUI di Genropy</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/la-gui-di-genropy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lo scopo di quersto talk è di offrire una panoramica della GUI di
Genropy e del suo meccanismo di funzionamento. In particolare verra
mostrato come sia possibile, scrivendo solo codice python, usare genropy
come interfaccia grafica al di fuori del classico uso del gestionale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proveremo a vedere come dare un’ interfaccia grafica ad alcuni comandi
di shell e a mostrare come tramite i widget di genropy sia possibile
gestire con poche righe di codice python widget complessi come griglie,
griglie editabili e alberi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi mostreremo l’utilizzo sia in versione classica nel browser, che con
electron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostreremo anche l’uso di RPC classiche e di websocket.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giovanni Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/la-gui-di-genropy.html</guid><category>genropy</category><category>gui</category><category>websockets</category></item><item><title>tqdm - A Fast, Extensible Progress Bar for Python and CLI</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-meetups/tqdm-a-fast-extensible-progress-bar-for-python-and-cli.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A demonstration of the world's most-used progress bar by its primary developer&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Casper da Costa-Luis</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-07:pydata-meetups/tqdm-a-fast-extensible-progress-bar-for-python-and-cli.html</guid><category>lightning-talks</category><category>tutorial</category><category>performance</category><category>jupyter</category><category>notebook</category><category>tqdm</category><category>progressbar</category><category>progressmeter</category><category>progress-bar</category><category>meter</category><category>rate</category><category>eta</category><category>console</category><category>terminal</category><category>time</category><category>progress</category><category>bar</category><category>gui</category><category>python</category><category>parallel</category><category>cli</category><category>utilities</category></item><item><title>PyOhio 2010: GUI Tools</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--gui-tools.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GUI Tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by James Bonanno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several Graphical User Interface frameworks available for
Python. In this talk, perpahs the two most popular, wxPython and PyQt,
are examined. The talk will focus on major differences, tools, and a
specific example done both in wxPython and PyQt, that is a non-trivial
production grade example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: sound is inaudible for the first minute]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bonanno</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-07-31:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--gui-tools.html</guid><category>gui</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2010</category><category>pyqt</category><category>wxpython</category></item><item><title>PyOhio 2011: Commercial GUI Development with Python &amp; PySide</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--commercial-gui-development-with-pyth.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commercial GUI Development with Python and PySide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by James Bonanno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commercial Desktop GUIs need to be secure, flexible, reliable, and easy
to maintain. A rapid application development framework, called PyRad, is
introduced, that uses PySide and Cython. Together with Python, this
development framework has allowed the authors to create numerous GUIs in
a short time period, with a consistent look and feel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bonanno</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-30:pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--commercial-gui-development-with-pyth.html</guid><category>cython</category><category>gui</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2011</category><category>pyrad</category><category>pyside</category></item><item><title>Developing Desktop and mobile apps with PySide and QML</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/developing-desktop-and-mobile-apps-with-pyside-an.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Thomas Perl - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Margherita &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PySide offers Python bindings to the Qt libraries. This allows rapid
development of great UI-based Python applications. With the addition of
QML in Qt 4.7, this now gives developers a chance to develop
touch-based, rich applications directly with Python. This talk
introduces PySide development, combined with QML, and shows some
real-world examples of mobile PySide applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is based on my PySide/QML on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thp.io/2010%20/meego-python/"&gt;MeeGo
tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, and shows some of
the possibilities. It is aimed at Python developers looking for a GUI
toolkit to create fluent, hardware-accelerated cross-platform UIs using
QML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials available at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thp.io/2011/europython/"&gt;http://thp.io/2011/europython/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thomas Perl</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/developing-desktop-and-mobile-apps-with-pyside-an.html</guid><category>gui</category><category>mobile</category><category>pyside</category><category>qt</category></item><item><title>Sqlkit: empowering database access</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlkit-empowering-database-access.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Alessandro Dentella - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's very easy to access databases with Python, and there are many ORMs
allowing a high level of abstraction. Still, it's a long road from there
to interactive handling of data, even for very simple tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sqlkit tries to act as a bridge, offering some mega-widgets that allow
you to build GUI applications or directly access data using the
'sqledit' application, shipped with sqlkit; sqlkit is built with PyGTK
and SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation covers some of the most powerful features of sqlkit,
and shows how easy it is to build small programs for personal use, as
well as rich and complex applications. It primarily focuses on two
points: how easy it is to create data forms (eventually with one2many or
many2many, thanks to a original definition of layouts), and the template
system based on OpenOffice which allows easy report creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation shows how sqlkit can be used both as application
development framework and as a tool to help us while developing other
applications (e.g.: Django, OpenERP,… ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deliver a gradual presentation, we'll use the configuration system of
sqledit, starting from a minimal configuration (a single URL) we'll add
elements to that until we'll have a full application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Dentella</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/sqlkit-empowering-database-access.html</guid><category>database</category><category>forms</category><category>framework</category><category>gui</category><category>openoffice</category><category>python,</category></item><item><title>Sqlkit: database ad accesso immediato</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/sqlkit-database-ad-accesso-immediato.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Alessandro Dentella - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Italiana
Big Mac&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;È molto facile accedere ad un database con Python e ci sono molti ORM
che permettono un alto livello di astrazione. Da qui c'é ancora una
lunga strada per arrivare a manipolare interattivamente i dati anche per
semplici compiti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sqlkit cerca di coprire questa distanza fornendo alcuni mega-widgets che
permettono di costruire ogni applicazione GUI o accedere direttamente ai
dati con l'applicazione 'sqledit', che viene distribuita con sqlkit.
Sqlkit è costruita con PyGTK e SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa presentazione esplora alcune fra le più potenti caratteristiche
di sqlkit e mostra quanto sia semplice costruire piccoli programmini ad
uso personale o applicazioni ricche ed articolate. Si focalizza
principalmente su due punti: quanto sia facile creare maschere per
editare dati (anche relazioni on2many o many2many, grazie al modo
originale di definire i layout) e al sistema di template basato su
OpenOffice che rende incredibilmente semplice creare report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa presentazione vuole mostrare come sqlkit può essere usato sia
come framework di sviluppo di applicazioni, sia come strumento che ci
aiuta mentre sviluppiamo altre applicazioni (es.: Django, OpenERP,… ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per rendere la presentazione più graduale, sfrutteremo il sistema di
configurazione di sqledit Partendo da una configurazione minima -un URL-
aggiungeremo elementi fino ad ottenere una vera applicazione.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Dentella</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/sqlkit-database-ad-accesso-immediato.html</guid><category>ci</category><category>database</category><category>framework</category><category>gui</category><category>openoffice</category><category>orm</category></item><item><title>Volker Kuhlmann - Rapid GUI application development with python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/volker-kuhlmann---rapid-gui-application-developme.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rapid GUI application development with Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Volker Kuhlmann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options and tools for rapid desktop GUI application development using
python are examined, and how they compare to competing languages and
platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examine GUI options for python including Qt, and their performance with
respect to ease of use, runtime, and platform portability. Examine
options for the tool chain (IDE, editor, debugger, programming aids) and
characterise their ease of use and level of sophistication, and compare
with commonly used equivalents, both open source and not open source.
Demonstrate a sample program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Volker Kuhlmann</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/volker-kuhlmann---rapid-gui-application-developme.html</guid><category>gui</category><category>kiwipycon</category><category>kiwipycon2009</category><category>qt</category></item><item><title>PyConAU 2010: An Introduction to Processing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--an-introduction-to-processing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Introduction to Processing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Clinton J Roy (University of Queensland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processing is an Open Source language designed to make interactive
graphics and animation programming easier than traditional GUI toolkits.
Processing is used to prototype systems and create interactive data
visualisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[NOTES: Missing first 2 minutes of audio, then camera microphone for
first section.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Clinton J Roy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--an-introduction-to-processing.html</guid><category>gui</category><category>multimedia</category><category>processing</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau2010</category></item><item><title>PyConAU 2010: Genropy - a framework for creating complex applications deployed on the web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--genropy---a-framework-for-creating-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy - A framework for creating complex applications deployed on the
web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jeff B Edwards (Goodsoftware)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.genropy.org/"&gt;Genropy&lt;/a&gt; is the python implementation of
Genro, and is an application framework quite different from the standard
(django, cherrypy, turbogears), for building powerful database
applications deployed from the browser. Many differences and advantages
between this framework and traditional python application frameworks are
explained. Genropy is a suitable for creating complex 'applications' as
opposed to 'sites'. The differentiation is that an application is
something an operator uses all day, has trained users, that have to
'squeeze' all the power from it available. Conversely, a 'site' is
basically public and not necessarily powerful as a user spends a
relatively small amount of time on it. Genropy is the framework for
creation applications. It is used for attendee registration and sales in
pycon italy, the larger national conference in Europe (Florence, Italy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will demonstrate how to create a simple application (3
tables) and demonstrate the ease and power of using python for the model
view and controller on the client. It demonstrates how one api- being
the genro Bag - is used to create the model, to map the sql to objects,
to create the GUI and communicate all data. So all of it can be done in
python instead of having to use many different technologies and
languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Edwards from Goodsoftware is strategic partner of Sofwell who is
the author of Genropy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jeff B Edwards</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--genropy---a-framework-for-creating-.html</guid><category>databases</category><category>gui</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau2010</category><category>web</category></item></channel></rss>