<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PyPy hands-on</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/pypy-hands-on.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Antonio Cuni,Armin Rigo - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training
Pizza Margherita&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The session is divided into two parts, of roughly 2 hours each. People
who are interested only in the first part, can leave the session after
it. However, the first part is a prerequisite for the second one, thus
people are not advised to join in the middle of the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session is meant to be highly interactive. People are invited to
bring their own laptop and try things by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-1-run-your-application-under-pypy"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Part 1: Run your application under PyPy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is targeted to Python users who want to run their favorite
Python application under PyPy, and exploit the most of it. The following
topics will be covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
- how to fix/avoid CPython implementation details (e.g., refcounting)

- general overview of how the PyPy JIT works

- how to optimize your program for the PyPy JIT

- how to view and interpret the traces produced by the JIT

- how to tweak the parameters of the JIT and the GC

- how to use existing CPython C extensions on PyPy, and fix them if necessary
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-2-write-your-own-interpreter-with-pypy"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Part 2: Write your own interpreter with PyPy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyPy is not only a Python interpreter, but also a toolchain to implement
dynamic languages. This tutorial is targeted to people who want to
implement their own programming languages, or who simply want to know
more about how the PyPy JIT works internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students will be given the source code for a toy language
implemented in RPython. They will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
- how to translate it to C using the PyPy translation toolchain

- what are the &amp;quot;hints&amp;quot; needed by the JIT generator, and how to place them
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, they will be challenged to add the proper hints to the toy
interpreter, to get the best result with the JIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THINGS TO DO BEFORE THE TRAINING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are encouraged to bring your laptop to the training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that the following prerequisites are met:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install PyPy 1.5:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypy.org/download.html"&gt;http://pypy.org/download.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://doc.pypy.org/en/latest/getting-started.html#installing-pypy"&gt;http://doc.pypy.org/en/latest/getting-started.html#installing-pypy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;setuptools&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;distribute&lt;/tt&gt; are installed (look
at the URL above for instructions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the pypy repository, and update to the 1.5 version:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ hg clone &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bitbucket.org/pypy/pypy"&gt;http://bitbucket.org/pypy/pypy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ cd pypy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ hg up -r release-1.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the jitviewer repository and install it on pypy:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ hg clone &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bitbucket.org/pypy/jitviewer"&gt;http://bitbucket.org/pypy/jitviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ cd jitviewer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ /path/to/pypy-1.5/bin/pypy setup.py develop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you intend to follow also the second part (&amp;quot;Write your own
interpreter with PyPy&amp;quot;), you need to make sure you have a working
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://doc.pypy.org/en/latest/getting-started-python.html%20#translating-the-pypy-python-interpreter"&gt;developing
environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Antonio Cuni</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/pypy-hands-on.html</guid><category>cd</category><category>cpython</category><category>extensions</category><category>hg</category><category>jit</category><category>optimize</category><category>pypy</category><category>setup.py</category><category>tutorial</category></item><item><title>Writing Books using Python &amp; Open Source Software</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/writing-books-using-python-open-source-software.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 20 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of us are familiar with using open source tools to develop software
applications with, but instead of writing code, it is also possible to
create the manuscript of a book in very much the same way. These days,
authors have many choices in terms of the tools which are available to
aid them in writing a book. Gone are the times when the only option is
using a proprietary word processor, so why not try it using open source
tools? It's especially attractive to those who develop software using
open source tools as well those who are writing books about open source
tools. Both code and the written word are created in plain text files.
These files are easily archived using some version control system. They
can be shared easily via e-mail and can also be backed up in the same
manner. In the end, the final product is shipped to the customer: in the
case of software, it's distribution via CD or DVD, or perhaps a release
for installation on a server, and for a book, it's delivering a
manuscript to the publisher, perhaps in a format such as HTML or PDF®.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon some reflection, writing a book is, in many ways, similar to
writing an application: you create text or code which is saved to a file
(or files- typically one but could be more) file in some format,
proprietary or otherwise. Additions, changes, or deletions are made to
the file(s), which is then updated when the file is (re)saved. Backups
need to be made, some versioning may be required to keep track of
multiple files during the course of development, and finally, the
resulting file(s) have to be delivered, as described above. Because of
all the similarities described, we assert that it is possible to use a
development environment utilizing Python and other open source tools to
not only write application with, but also be able to create the entire
manuscript for a book as well! While this entire concept should not
really be mind-blowing, it does represent a trend seemingly growing in
popularity in the open source world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, we highlight the following requirements that are
necessary when creating a manuscript, especially with co-authors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versioning and Backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated Testing of Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML/PDF® Generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we highlight one particular case study, the development of
Addison Wesley's 2009 publication, &amp;quot;Python Web Development with Django&amp;quot;,
as well as provide some insight into other projects created using
similar tools. Open source software has radically affected how
applications are built today, and this phenomenon has the ability to
affect the book publishing world in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/writing-books-using-python-open-source-software.html</guid><category>cd</category><category>html</category><category>testing</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Continuous deployment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--continuous-deployment.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Laurens Van Houtven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is about continuous deployment practices and tools, lessons
learned from implementing it, and putting them into perspective. The
goal is to give other people tips and pointers for applying these ideas
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous deployment is the practice of putting the latest revision of
software into production use all the time, as opposed to working towards
larger releases. The important difference is iteration time: whereas
large software packages produce new software in timeframes of years or
months, continuous deployment teams typically put new code into
production in timeframes of hours or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice is slowly attracting a small but growing group of loyal
followers, just like continuous integration over the past few years and
test- driven development did before that. They can be explained in terms
of being natural extensions of each other. Like TDD and CI, CD gets eyed
somewhat suspiciously (and rightfully so: skeptical analysis is great),
but the undersigned believes there's a legitimate advantage for many
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, TTD and testing tools in general were mostly ad-hockery.
Now, with many different production-quality testing tools, this has
become unthinkable. Similarly, continuous integration was something
other people did for a long time, but now we have tools such as Buildbot
and Hudson. Continuous deployment is still somewhat in the early stage
in terms of ready-to-use tools, but it's likely that we'll see a similar
evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a rough outline of what I plan to cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a short history of people developed software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from the recent models to CD (sort of a working definition of CD
here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when is it a good idea? pros/cons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requirements &amp;amp; battle plan for applying CD in an existing development
environment (and possibly code base)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an overview of existing tools and how they work together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caveat emptors, known pitfalls (deployment and recovery strategies go
here, since most implementations figure out they need them after
stuff blows up)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;questions! (hopefully lots of people who've tried or are thinking
about implementing something similar -- like I said, there are a lot
of people implementing it but not too many ideas being bounced
around)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Laurens Van Houtven</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--continuous-deployment.html</guid><category>cd</category><category>ci</category><category>continuousdeployment</category><category>deployment</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>softwaredevelopment</category><category>tdd</category><category>workflow</category></item></channel></rss>