<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_managementshell.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2010-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data Herding: How to Shepherd Your Flock Through Valleys of Darkness</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--data-herding--how-to-shepherd-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Luft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-07:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--data-herding--how-to-shepherd-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use common tools like the management shell,
django-extensions, and iPython to craft an effective workflow whether
you're building a new schema or migrating from old systems. We'll also
look at how to take advantage of the latest ORM features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation would consist of walking through a few example
scenarios where one would deal with processing or converting data in
some manner. For example, migrating from a large legacy database often
brings a number of tedious problems. I would demonstrate how to work in
an iterative, repeatable style using the Django sql management commands,
a few iPython tricks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another demonstration would be showing a team workflow for South
migrations, illustrating how to deal with some common problems that crop
up in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will leave with some solid techniques for dealing with a
few specific data management challenges. The unifying philosophy
throughout is to break large, difficult problems into small, repeatable
steps and audience members should also come away knowing how to select
tools that help them work in this style.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2010"></category><category term="django-extensions"></category><category term="ipython"></category><category term="managementshell"></category><category term="orm"></category></entry></feed>