<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - PyScript</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Let’s PyScript: Flask frontends in Python!</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/flaskcon-2025/lets-pyscript-flask-frontends-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicholas Tollervey live codes a chat system with a Flask API and PyScript UI. He and Paul Everitt talk about how PyScript works, and then take Q&amp;amp;A from the audience through the newly created app. Presented at FlaskCon 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicholas Tollervey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2025-05-16:/flaskcon-2025/lets-pyscript-flask-frontends-in-python.html</guid><category>FlaskCon 2025</category><category>FlaskCon</category><category>Flask</category><category>API</category><category>PyScript</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>Running (snippets of) Python in the browser</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/running-snippets-of-python-in-the-browser.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll start with an overview of solutions to run Python in the browser. Then we’ll explain how our solution (PyScript) works and what its advantages/disadvantages are. Next, we’ll demonstrate its use in a few real-world projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that “the web” is becoming an increasingly important place to publish research findings. Apart from the obvious advantage of being able to reach a wide audience at negligible cost, browser technology allows for increasingly sophisticated means to present your data and findings in various interactive ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the language of the web (JavaScript) is a language that is notorious for its many flaws. It seems that Pythonistas are especially repelled by the language, since the number of projects that try to “run Python in the browser” is steadily growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our approach (PyScript), we do not aim to run the full Python language in the browser. It’s rather a way to write JavaScript using a Python syntax, making it as Pythonic as we can. There are a few pitfalls, but these have been reduced over time, which makes writing PyScript feel almost like writing Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One advantage of our approach is that one can generate snippets of JavaScript code that can interact as-is with other JavaScript libraries. Combined with the fact that PyScript is valid Python, it allows for a natural way to define client-side reactivity inside common Python modules. Also, it makes PyScript faster than most other Python-in-the-browser solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of its use-cases is Bokeh’s new capability to define client-side callbacks in Python. There are plans to use a similar approach to allow users to define custom Bokeh models. The Flexx project is a pure Python widget toolkit, that renders in the browser. All widgets are implemented with PyScript (wrapping PhosphorJS for some layouts). In a project with Clinical Graphics, PyScript is used in a system that allows visualization and user-annotations of medical images, with plans for 3D visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1X069udByOTw3d4-NVU14XwhTANCdECvjY0R7fDuXTpA/pub?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000"&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1X069udByOTw3d4-NVU14XwhTANCdECvjY0R7fDuXTpA/pub?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Almar Klein</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:/pydata-amsterdam-2016/running-snippets-of-python-in-the-browser.html</guid><category>PyData Amsterdam 2016</category><category>pyscript</category></item><item><title>Actionable Machine Learning in the Browser with PyScript</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2023/actionable-machine-learning-in-the-browser-with-pyscript.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyScript brings the full PyData stack in the browser, opening up to unprecedented use cases for interactive data-intensive applications. In this scenario, the web browser becomes a ubiquitous computing platform, operating within a (nearly) zero-installation &amp;amp; server-less environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will explore how to create full-fledged interactive front-end machine learning applications using PyScript. We will dive into the the main features of the PyScript platform (e.g. built-in Javascript integration and local modules ), discussing new data &amp;amp; design patterns (e.g. loading heterogeneous data in the browser), required to adapt and to overcome the limitations imposed by the new operating environment (i.e. the browser).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Valerio Maggio</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2023-04-17:/pydata-berlin-2023/actionable-machine-learning-in-the-browser-with-pyscript.html</guid><category>PyData Berlin 2023</category><category>PyScript</category></item></channel></rss>