<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_sklearn.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>A Worked Intro to Scikit-learn</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/a-worked-intro-to-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anders Bogsnes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/a-worked-intro-to-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A talk introducing the audience to Scikit-learn as a library aimed at
people who know Python at a beginner/intermediate level but are new to
machine learning concepts. The goal of the talk is for the audience to
leave with an understanding of the foundations of machine learning while
respecting how easy it is to make a wrong choice that invalidates your
model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be a short background on scikit-learn followed by a livecoding
demo where I demonstrate how scikit-learn works and detail common
pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will demonstrate ways of coping with problems such as data leakage,
the importance of train-test splits, choosing metrics wisely, and
explain how cross-validation works and why we use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1596"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1596&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pydata"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="scikit-learn"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to machine learning using Python tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/introduction-to-machine-learning-using-python-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Satish Shankar</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/introduction-to-machine-learning-using-python-tools.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="statistics"></category><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="datamining"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="scientific-computing"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Sports performance evaluation: from cognitive mechanisms to data-driven algorithms</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/sports-performance-evaluation-from-cognitive-mechanisms-to-data-driven-algorithms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Luca Pappalardo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/sports-performance-evaluation-from-cognitive-mechanisms-to-data-driven-algorithms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Not everything that counts can be counted, and not everything that
can be counted counts. A. Einstein&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are routinely asked to evaluate the performance of other
individuals, separating success from failure and affecting outcomes from
science to education and sports. Yet, little is known about the aspects
that determine the human perception of performance. How do expert
reviewers, as well as ordinary people, arrive to their evaluations? To
what extent these evaluations are based on objective performance
features? How are they affected by subjective biases or contextual
influences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will answer these fascinating questions focusing on &lt;em&gt;soccer&lt;/em&gt; ,
the most popular sport in the world. Firstly, we will show how machine
learning can accurately reproduce the mechanisms human judges use to
evaluate the performance of soccer players, uncovering limits and
characteristics of the human evaluation process. Second, we design a
Python package that allows, in a completely unsupervised and data-driven
way, to (i) evaluate the quality of a player’s performance and (ii) rank
soccer players based on their performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the talk will show how soccer ratings assigned to
every player of a game by sport-specialized newspapers are associated
with a high- dimensional vector of features extracted by massive data
which describe any quantifiable aspects of soccer games. The talk will
show how, by using Scikit- learn, we can train an &lt;em&gt;artificial judge&lt;/em&gt;
which learns the relation between technical performance and soccer
ratings, hence &lt;em&gt;accurately reproducing&lt;/em&gt; the human evaluation process. By
inspecting the structure of the artificial judge, the talk will show
that the human evaluation criteria follow a simplistic cognitive process
based on a simple heuristic: judges first select a limited number of
features which attract their attention and then rate a performance based
on the presence of noticeable values, i.e., features values far from the
norm that can be easily brought to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the talk will show how to overcome the simplicity of
the human evaluation process presenting &lt;strong&gt;PlayeRank&lt;/strong&gt; , a Python package
which implements an unsupervised data-driven framework to evaluate the
performance of soccer players in the main European leagues. The talk
will show how to use PlayeRank to construct a data-driven ranking of
players and highlight the factors which determine why celebrated
players, like Messi and Cristiano Ronaldo, actually result to be the top
players in the world. The modules composing PlayeRank will be presented,
showing how they allow the user to define the features characterizing a
performance, to detect in an automatic way the relevance of each
player’s action to a game outcome, to detect the role of a player given
his game data, to rate every performance as well as to obtain a final
ranking of all players in Europe. A short demo will be provided during
the talk through a Jupyter notebook, exploiting interactive data
visualization with the Bokeh package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will learn how to use Python to construct evaluation
algorithms entirely based on machine learning and big data, a step
forward to a thorough and objective evaluation of performance which
overcomes the biases and the limitations of human perception of
performance. Just a basic knowledge of Python and of data mining
principles is required for a full understanding of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 15:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mathematical-modelling"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="sports-analytics"></category><category term="Machine Learning"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploying Machine Learning using sklearn pipelines</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/deploying-machine-learning-using-sklearn-pipelines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Goetsch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-27:pydata-chicago-2016/deploying-machine-learning-using-sklearn-pipelines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sklearn pipeline objects provide an framework that simplifies the lifecycle of data science models. This talk will cover the how and why of encoding feature engineering, estimators, and model ensembles in a single deployable object.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deploying"></category><category term="learning"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Data driven literary analysis</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/data-driven-literary-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Serena Peruzzo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/data-driven-literary-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can unsupervised learning mimic a literary critic? This talk will give an overview of unsupervised document classification techniques and apply them to the analysis and classification of Shakespeare’s plays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsupervised document classification addresses the problem of assigning categories to documents without the use of a training set or predefined categories. This is useful to enhance information retrieval, the basic assumption being that similar contents are also relevant to the same query. A similar assumption is made in literature to define literary genres and sub-genres, where works which share specific conventions in terms of form and content are described by the same genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk gives an overview of document clustering and its challenges, with a focus on dimensionality reduction and how to address it with topic modelling techniques like LDA (Latent Dirichlet Allocation). Using Shakespeare’s body of work as a case study, the talk describes how to use nltk, sklearn and gensim to process and analyse theatrical works with the final goal of testing whether document clustering yields to the same classification given by literature experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/sereprz/data-driven-literary-analysis-an-unsupervised-approach-to-text-analysis-and-classification"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/sereprz/data-driven-literary-analysis-an-unsupervised-approach-to-text-analysis-and-classification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="nltk"></category><category term="sklearn"></category><category term="gensim"></category></entry><entry><title>¡Eureka! (Python y ciencia)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyday-galicia-2016/eureka-python-y-ciencia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Sánchez de León Peque</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pyday-galicia-2016/eureka-python-y-ciencia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En esta charla se plantea una pregunta de física básica que se resolverá científicamente con ingenio, mátemáticas y python, aprovechando para (de una manera amena) ver librerías habituales en el entorno científico como sympy, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, bokeh, numba, pandas y sklearn.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyday"></category><category term="sympy"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="scipy"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="numba"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry></feed>