<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Explaining AI to Managers 👨‍💼🤖👩‍💼</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/explaining-ai-to-managers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Artificial intelligence promises great value. The technology is mostly
understood only by few, yet still unexplainable even for experts.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In this talk I'll present how to narrow the hype down to real value
explainable to everyone in your organisation - without the math.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can you downloaded at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/ai-executives-data-litteracy"&gt;http://bit.ly/ai-executives-data-litteracy&lt;/a&gt;-
europython&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander CS Hendorf</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/explaining-ai-to-managers.html</guid><category>Analytics</category><category>Business</category><category>Deep Learning</category><category>Management</category></item><item><title>The Dangers of Outsourcing Software Development</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-dangers-of-outsourcing-software-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customer lock-in. Dubious “Land and Expand” strategies. We have all
heard about outsourced software projects that run far past schedule and
obliterates the budget, yet somehow fail to meet even basic
requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can this happen. How can your company reduce the risks of delegating
software development to an external party?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal–Agent Problem is a well researched dilemma in economic
literature. It occurs when a person or entity (“agent”), is tasked to
work on behalf of another person or entity (&amp;quot;principal&amp;quot;). When the two
parties have divergent interests, the agent might act contrary to the
best interests of the principal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Examples of principal-agent relationships are:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Employer vs Employee&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Shareholder vs Management&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Voter vs Political party&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Contractor vs Software Consultant&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a firm decides to outsource software development to a third party,
there is an economic divergence of interest at play, as both parties
seek to maximize profit. The contractor wants its requirements met at
low cost and on a predictable schedule. The third party, when acting
nefariously, can maximize its own gains by extending the project,
utilizing junior or low-cost labor, and creating a relationship of
dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session we will look into some nefarious techniques and
practices used in the IT consulting industry and how best to avoid them.
We will also learn why it is particularly hard to mitigate the risks of
outsourced software development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sebastian Roll</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/the-dangers-of-outsourcing-software-development.html</guid><category>Business</category><category>Clients</category><category>Ethics</category><category>Management</category><category>freelancing</category></item><item><title>Using Python to Teach Computational Finance</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/using-python-to-teach-computational-finance.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this demo-driven session, we will introduce the Probo package for
teaching Python programming and concepts from computational finance to
beginning programmers in the domain of finance. We'll show how Python is
the perfect tool for teaching computational thinking to develop deeper
quantitative reasoning. Jupyter notebooks, together with Python packages
such as NumPy and Pandas, provide the ideal learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start by introducing the Probo package for derivative pricing
and hedging. We will demo the pricing of European and American options
via the famous Black-Scholes option pricing model. Other examples
include Monte Carlo simulation and binomial trees. Using Probo, the
answers to derivative pricing problems are right at the students'
fingertips. Students can operationalize their understanding by going
directly from the mathematics of derivative pricing theories to their
implementation in clean and simple code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will end with a demonstration using Probo to teach the concept of
dynamic hedging. Dynamic hedging is perhaps &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; crucial concept in
modern financial derivatives theory. It is also one of the most
difficult concepts to grasp. We'll show how developing deeper intuition
is possible with computational thinking via Monte Carlo simulation of
delta-hedging. By leveraging the power and simplicity of Python and
Jupyter notebooks, the Probo package provides the ideal learning
platform for students of computational finance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tyler Brough</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/using-python-to-teach-computational-finance.html</guid><category>Beginners</category><category>Business</category><category>Business Cases</category><category>Education</category><category>Jupyter</category></item><item><title>What about recommendation engines?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/what-about-recommendation-engines.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;How recommendation engines are taking part in our daily routine and
how companies as Netflix and Amazon implement it?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk aims to show the elements that compound a recommendation
engine to people who have never been in touch with the matter or want
to know a bit more. At the end of this session, you might be able to
reproduce your own recommendation system and also know where to find
more about it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Talk structure:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. What is and why use a recommendation engine?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. Recommendation engine importance&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3. Steps of a recommendation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4. Recommendation algorithms&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;5. Basic Statistics for distance and correlation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;6. Example&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adriana Dorneles</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/what-about-recommendation-engines.html</guid><category>Algorithms</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Business</category><category>Data Science</category><category>Python 3</category></item><item><title>Efficient Python development with small teams</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/efficient-python-development-with-small-teams.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marc-André Lemburg</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/efficient-python-development-with-small-teams.html</guid><category>quality-assurance</category><category>project-management</category><category>business</category><category>communication</category><category>testing</category><category>principles</category><category>application-design</category><category>design</category><category>software-engineering</category><category>strategies</category><category>best-practices</category><category>architecture</category></item><item><title>Introducing Python as a main programming language in a company</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/introducing-python-as-a-main-programming-language-in-a-company.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Büchler</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/introducing-python-as-a-main-programming-language-in-a-company.html</guid><category>best-practices</category><category>teamwork</category><category>software-engineering</category><category>business</category><category>ecommerce</category></item><item><title>Designing Large-Scale Applications in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/designing-large-scale-applications-in-python.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marc-André Lemburg</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/designing-large-scale-applications-in-python.html</guid><category>business</category><category>database</category><category>integration</category><category>scalability</category><category>servers</category><category>refactoring</category><category>application-design</category><category>design</category><category>software-engineering</category><category>framework</category><category>sql</category><category>best-practices</category><category>architecture</category></item><item><title>Come vanno gli affari? Visualizziamolo con Superset</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/come-vanno-gli-affari-visualizziamolo-con-superset.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Superset è una piattaforma Open Source di Business Intelligence incubata
nel progetto Apache. Superset permette, senza scrivere una riga di
codice, di creare, esplorare, visualizzare e condividere piccole o
grandi quantità di dati. Nel talk verrà fatta una introduzione a
Superset, mostrandone le funzionalità. Quindi vedremo come usare questo
strumento per analizzare un database di una azienda di vendita online.
Partendo da un database creeremo delle visualizzazioni e quindi delle
dashboard. Senza scrivere una riga di Python :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Riccardo Magliocchetti</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/come-vanno-gli-affari-visualizziamolo-con-superset.html</guid><category>analytics</category><category>superset</category><category>#data</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Da applicativi Desktop a Web</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/da-applicativi-desktop-a-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’evoluzione nel campo dell’informatica sta rendendo obsoleti moltissimi
applicativi desktop sviluppati negli ultimi anni. Lo sviluppatore che
deve aggiornare il proprio lavoro deve quindi decidere la tecnologia
migliore, impararla e procedere alla conversione sia delle procedure
(replicando in web il funzionamento che aveva in desktop) sia dei dati.
Nel talk vi racconteremo la nostra esperienza, del perchè abbiamo scelto
Python e Genropy e dei risultati che abbiamo ottenuto in poco tempo. In
particolare vedremo a titolo di esempio un applicativo per la gestione
del personale, uno per la gestione delle assemblee ed uno per la
gestione di un economato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luigi Renna</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/da-applicativi-desktop-a-web.html</guid><category>genropy</category><category>gestionali</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>And now to something ELSE: Real Time Data Processing @ billiger.de</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/and-now-to-something-else-real-time-data-processing-billigerde.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Axel Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having started as a computational physicist, developing GPU-accelerated based molecular dynamics software for 14 years, I developed a passion for Python as scripting frontend and powerful numeric analysis tool. And NumPy makes teaching numerical math to 3rd year physics students so much easier! Eventually, I decided to make my living using Python and joined solute GmbH as Python developer. I still have a passion for high throughput systems, but now not only from developer's, but also the operations point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;billiger.de is one of the largest price comparison websites in Germany. In this talk, we want to share how we built the scalable, event-driven processing system which renders the products for our website using Python, Elasticsearch and redis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;billiger.de is one of the largest price comparison websites in Germany. Tens of millions of offers need to be clustered into products, with a considerable amount of offers changing every few hours. In this talk, we want to share our experiences and the challenges we were facing on our way to building a scalable, event-driven processing system which renders the products you will eventually find on our website. We give an overview of that system, which consists of a number of services written in Python, a Redis based queueing system and an Elasticsearch cluster for storage. We tell the story of how all of this works together and how it allows us to scale storage and processing throughput according to our needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Axel Arnold</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/and-now-to-something-else-real-time-data-processing-billigerde.html</guid><category>use-case</category><category>python</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Automated testing with 400TB memory</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/automated-testing-with-400tb-memory.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christoph Heer&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;ChristophHeer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m an Infrastructure Engineer in the team behind SAP’s huge test infrastructure for SAP HANA. In my spare time, I develop web applications with Django or playing around with new programming languages like Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAP operates a dedicated test infrastructure with more than 400TB main memory for its in-memory database SAP HANA. All custom implementations like improved scheduling, caching of artifacts and monitoring were implemented in our favorite programming language Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAP operates a large test infrastructure to test its in-memory database SAP HANA. In 2010, we started with a single Jenkins master with ten nodes. But to keep our testing time acceptable for the growing number of developers we had to scale up, which led to multiple different scaling challenges. The current test infrastructure is powered by more than thousand physical servers and provides different services like continuous integration, code coverage and code linting for a huge C++ project. These services are essential for developing and shipping new SAP HANA versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk provides insights into how we scaled and improved our test infrastructure. All custom implementations like improved scheduling, expressive test configuration and caching of artifacts were implemented in our favorite programming language Python. With the flexibility and power of Python it has been easier to extend, optimize and adapt the infrastructure for new requirements like different CPU architectures and newer operating system versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christoph Heer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/automated-testing-with-400tb-memory.html</guid><category>python</category><category>use-case</category><category>devops</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Data Science Best Practices : From Proof of Concepts to Production</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/data-science-best-practices-from-proof-of-concepts-to-production.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yasir Khan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yasir Khan is working as a Data Science Manager. He has nearly 12 years of experience in consulting and R&amp;amp;D domains. He obtained his PhD in Applied Machine Learning and has been invited as a speaker at several leading international forums and conferences. He has nearly 12 research articles and journals to his credit and book chapters published by Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his spare time he loves flying WWII aircrafts at a local aeroclub and is an avid scuba diver. He is also an investor in 2 technology startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will benefit the audience as it brings forward the practical issues in the industry today as we move towards industrializing data science algorithms. We will discuss the best practices around organization, methodology and tools to integrate a data science project into production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the industry understands the importance of Data Science for transforming businesses an interesting trend is arising. We have started seeing a widening gap &amp;amp; increasing difficulty to move teams from Proof of Concepts to Production. Apart from searching for the best data scientists, the industry is now looking for answers to organize &amp;amp; federate the data teams around practical business use cases. In this talk, Yasir Khan will provide an overview of the bottlenecks, and hurdles involved in a practical data project. While citing lessons learned from industry, this presentation will focus on important aspects such as business centric, data culture, data pipelines, organization, methodology &amp;amp; tools all of which are important but seldom ignored in large corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Yasir Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/data-science-best-practices-from-proof-of-concepts-to-production.html</guid><category>use-case</category><category>analytics</category><category>python</category><category>machine learning</category><category>ai</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Data Science Project for Beginners</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/data-science-project-for-beginners.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natalie Speiser,Jens Beyer&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;natalie_lavrio)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natalie is a psychologist focused on statistics and machine learning for predictions. Jens is a pyhsicist turned consultant for IBM and d-fine and helped big companies with statistical models since 2009. Together, we founded LAVRIO.solutions and help our clients to make the most out of their data. In our recent data science projects, we faced specific hurdles which seem to be typical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI and Machine Learning are taking over the world - but how do you actually start with understanding your data and predicting events? And what kind of &amp;quot;political&amp;quot; trouble could you run into? With examples from real projects, we try to give you a feeling for data science projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be talking about examples from projects we did as data science consultants. What should be organized before you go to a client (internal or external). How should the data look like. What are problems you have to face while working with the clients IT department. You get to see a rough draft of our code. It won't be a thorough manual, just our experiences and how we dealt with problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Natalie Speiser</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/data-science-project-for-beginners.html</guid><category>business</category><category>data-science</category><category>use-case</category><category>python</category><category>machine learning</category></item><item><title>Deep Learning for Computer Vision</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/deep-learning-for-computer-vision.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alex Conway&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;alxcnwy)
Alex is the founder &amp;amp; CTO of NumberBoost, a startup that builds deep learning applications. He previously worked as a quant for a hedge fund and as a data scientist for an e-commerce company. He has an honours degree in actuarial science and a MSc in statistics. He is one of the organizers of the Cape Town Deep Learning meet-up and has built numerous computer vision systems that run at scale in production predicting labels for millions of images per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state-of-the-art in image classification has skyrocketed thanks to the development of deep convolutional neural networks and increases in the amount of data and computing power available to train them. The top-5 error rate in the ImageNet competition to predict which of 1000 classes an image belongs to has plummeted from 28% error in 2010 to just 2.25% in 2017 (human level error is around 5%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to being able to classify objects in images (including not hotdogs), deep learning can be used to automatically generate captions for images, convert photos into paintings, detect cancer in pathology slide images, and help self-driving cars ‘see’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will give an overview of the cutting edge and some of the core mathematical concepts and will also include a short code-first tutorial to show how easy it is to get started using deep learning for computer vision in python…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a crash course on convolutional neural networks and how to use them to solve 2 real-world applications at scale. The first is an image moderation system and the second is a visual similarity system where a user uploads an image of an item and the system returns visually similar items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Conway</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/deep-learning-for-computer-vision.html</guid><category>business</category><category>data-science</category><category>use-case</category><category>deep learning</category><category>ai</category><category>machine learning</category></item><item><title>Empowered by Python - A success story</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/empowered-by-python-a-success-story.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jens Nie, Peer Wagner&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;jneines)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jens works primarily as a Technology Scout focusing on Big Data and Data Science at the ROSEN Technology &amp;amp; Research Center in Lingen, Germany. In this role he screens for latest developments in these areas and evaluates and demonstrates their possible use and benefit for the company. Looking back to more than 20 years in using Python and Linux, he considers him to be an Open Source enthusiast and committed Python advocate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing a new programming language in a company is always a daring task, usually involving a lot of effort and the will for change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to take you on a journey reflecting eight years of challenges, solutions and success ending in a best practice guide helping you to achieve the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROSEN is most recognized as a technology leader in the pipeline inspection business. To steadily achieve the best in class service for our customers, we are building and using the most sophisticated tools in the industry to perform the inspection services. This often results in very large volumes of data which have to be handled and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, we were always out to search for the latest technology and state of the art tools to aid us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a point where the most traditionally used tools for data analysis no longer scaled a handful of pioneers were brave enough to introduce a massive change in the scientific tool chain. This involved to address driving laboratory equipment, data processing, analysis and display, handling large volumes of data efficiently, building attractive graphical user interfaces, integrate with existing software applications and prepare for modern data analysis concepts based on machine learning to ensure both increasing result quality and faster data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've found Python to be the ideal foundation to achieve all this and started off with a few initial projects in order to prove. It turned out Python would be a real game changer for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jens Nie</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/empowered-by-python-a-success-story.html</guid><category>use-case</category><category>python</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Master 2.5 GB of unstructured specification documents with ease</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/master-25-gb-of-unstructured-specification-documents-with-ease.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Andreas Schilling&lt;/strong&gt; is Senior Software Engineer at eXXcellent solutions. In his job, he helps customers to develop software solutions from the early stage of defining the particular requirements to developing information systems which meet their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before working at eXXcellent solutions Andreas Schilling studied Information Systems at the University of Bamberg focusing on distributed systems and information management. Thereafter, he pursued his PhD and studied collaboration dynamics in open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Do you kick start a project which is based on 2.5 GB files of unstructured specification documents? To answer this question, we present our lessons learned from developing a Python based knowledge management tool which provides a lightweight and intuitive browser frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we present lessons learned from and practical advice on how to deal with a large body of specification documents in your next project. We introduce our approach as well as code excerpts from our powerful toolset to transform a large set of unstructured and partially corrupt specification documents into structured JSON Files. Finally, we showcase a simple, yet powerful Javascript frontend which requires no additional infrastructure to present the compiled artefacts in an intuitive and responsive user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular this talk covers the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make use of pywin32 to access layout and content information from partially corrupt .doc and .docx files and create simple JSON files with UTF-8 encoding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and categorize signal words in your specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use pandas to compile content based recommender functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use networkx and py2cytoscape to visualize call sequences and semantic relationships in your specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the compiled artefacts and identified relationships in an easy-to-use and lightweight Javascript browser interface without any additional infrastructure (i.e. no webserver and no database server).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andreas Schilling</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/master-25-gb-of-unstructured-specification-documents-with-ease.html</guid><category>networkx</category><category>pandas</category><category>visualization</category><category>knowledge-management</category><category>analytics</category><category>use-case</category><category>python</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>No Compromise: Use Ansible properly or stick to your scripts</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/no-compromise-use-ansible-properly-or-stick-to-your-scripts.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bjoern Meier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bjoern is a software engineer at Blue Yonder GmbH since 2016 after graduating in Computer Science. More correctly you could say he is a DevOps engineer at Blue Yonder where he is developing and operating - among other things - the services for the external data interfaces, preprocessing and data storage to enable the data scientists to run their prediction models. He loves the versatility and ecosystem of python to write e.g. production web apps, data analysis tools or operational scripts. If there was more free time he would like to spent it to dive deeper into functional programming languages like elixir to have a different view on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you do in Ansible should be clean an simple. What we did was not. So I will show what we did wrong but also what we have changed or still have to, to make our life easier again. But I will also show how we progressively utilize Ansible to deploy our Data Science infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible should help you to orchestrate your systems, automate the deployments and set up well defined infrastructures. But if you want to make something work quickly in Ansible the chances are high that you fall back to shell/command tasks, the mother of all evil. Those tasks usually prevent you from running dry runs where you would see the upcoming changes and you prevent Ansible to shine. So, we went blindly into every deployment and hoped the best. But we wanted to see what would change, we wanted to make ansible --check work again and therefore in this talk I will show you what we did wrong and what we changed to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More precisely, I will show what you can do to replace the nasty shell tasks with proper modules, plugins and filters, how they are developed, tested and included in your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Björn Meier</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/no-compromise-use-ansible-properly-or-stick-to-your-scripts.html</guid><category>infrasturcture</category><category>business</category><category>devops</category><category>ansible</category></item><item><title>Python with Apache OpenWhisk</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/python-with-apache-openwhisk.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ansgar Schmidt&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;ansi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a full time nerd. Really thrilled by technology and love to make and hack. From PCB design, soldering, embedded development to server- backend hacking. Beside way to many small projects I work on a mobile robot based on ROS and try to add human interaction to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenWhisk is an opensource implementation of a so called serverless computing platform. At a live presentation I will show how to write an serverless application and how to deal with libraries and events. OpenWhisk is an open source alternative to AWS lambda or MS functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am a developer advocate working for IBM. Meaning I am a technician and geek not a salesman. In my talk I will give a live demo on how to use the open source implementation of a serverless compute platform called OpenWhisk and help python developers on how to use it and write serverless applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ansgar Schmidt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/python-with-apache-openwhisk.html</guid><category>devops</category><category>use-case</category><category>python</category><category>web</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Rasa: open source conversational AI to build next generation chatbots</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/rasa-open-source-conversational-ai-to-build-next-generation-chatbots.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joey Faulkner&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;JoeyMFaulkner)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD student in machine learning/astronomy, and an AI researcher at Rasa. We make open source libraries for conversational AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon you will primarily communicate with your computer through conversation. At Rasa, we believe that this revolution in user experience should be available to everyone. In this spirit we have developed open source tools that use machine learning to make chatbots in a developer-friendly interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revolution-in-waiting for user experience is conversational AI, and this revolution should be available to everyone. The ability to communicate with your computer via a fulfilling and useful conversation will change the way we approach user interaction. Recent advances in machine learning have made this goal not only possible to reach, but possible to bring to the developer community at large. At Rasa we have developed a set of open-source Python libraries which can comprehend natural language and handle complex, interesting conversations. We utilise deep learning to bypass existing rigid conversational norms (state machines, if/else statements, etc.) and allow developers to make awesome bots simply by talking to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Joey Faulkner</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/rasa-open-source-conversational-ai-to-build-next-generation-chatbots.html</guid><category>python</category><category>machine learning</category><category>deep learning</category><category>open source</category><category>chatbot</category><category>natural language</category><category>ai</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Simple Data Engineering in python 3.5+ with Bonobo</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/simple-data-engineering-in-python-35-with-bonobo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Romain Dorgueil&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;rdorgueil)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer, sysadmin, technical team builder, founder of two companies), advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently helping start-ups to achieve more with less in our acceleration programs in Paris, and in charge of our product development activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I play go and make music, but not at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple is better than complex, and that's True for data pipelines, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonobo is a python 3.5+ tool used to write and monitor data pipelines. It’s plain, simple, modern, and atomic python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a practical encounter, from zero to a complete data pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler : no «big data» here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple is better than complex, right? That’s true for data pipelines too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 5 years, I hacked together extract-transform-load (ETL) processes in various different positions (ETL is just a fancy term for «bunch of things that take data somewhere and put it elsewhere, eventually transformed»).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did it as a founder, as a consultant, as a technical co-founder, for some side projects, big corporates and small side projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each case, I felt frustrated with the tools available, and in some serious cases, I had to hack things myself to get the job done. Bonobo is the repackaging of my past experiences for python 3.5+, and grasping the basics should not take more than the length of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline (subject to small changes, for the greater good) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;INTRO : The ETL market, why a new tool, what it is, what it is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basics and concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete data pipeline example, using SQL, RDF and a small Django frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OUTRO : A glimpse at the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonobo is the glue you need to tie together regular functions in a transformation graph (think unix pipes). Execution strategies are abstracted so you can focus on the real operations. As a result, you can engineer simple and testable systems, using the same good computer development practices as you use in .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Dorgueil</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/simple-data-engineering-in-python-35-with-bonobo.html</guid><category>python</category><category>business</category><category>data-engineering</category><category>etl</category><category>simple</category><category>bonobo</category></item><item><title>The Python Ecosystem for Data Science: A Guided Tour</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/the-python-ecosystem-for-data-science-a-guided-tour.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Staudt&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;C_L_Staudt)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an independent data scientist with a background in computer science, in-depth in algorithms, data analysis, high-performance computing and software engineering. My current interests include machine learning and data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pythonistas have access to an extensive collection of tools for data analysis. The space of tools is best understood as an ecosystem: Libraries build upon each other, and a good library fills an ecological niche by doing certain jobs well. This is a guided tour of the Python data science ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python Ecosystem for Data Science: A Guided Tour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is on its way to becoming the lingua franca of data science, and Pythonistas have access to an impressive and extensive collection of tools for data analysis. Here, a data scientist needs to see the forest for the trees: The space of tools is best understood as an ecosystem, where libraries build upon each other, and where a good library fills an ecological niche by doing certain jobs well. This talk is a guided tour of the Python data science ecosystem. More than a list of libraries, it aims to provide some structure, classing tools by type of data, size of data, and type of analysis. In our tour, we visit a number of areas, including working with tabular data (numpy, pandas, dask, ...) and graph data (e.g. networkx), statistics (e.g. statsmodels), machine learning (scikit-learn, ...), data visualization (matplotlib, seaborn, bokeh, ...). Aspiring data scientists, and everyone else working with data, should find this useful for selecting the right tools for their next data-driven project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Staudt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/the-python-ecosystem-for-data-science-a-guided-tour.html</guid><category>use-case</category><category>business</category><category>ai</category><category>analytics</category><category>data-science</category><category>python</category><category>machine learning</category></item><item><title>Growing a Python community</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about people, not tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share one recipe of building a community from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reveals hands-on experience about the organisational journey,
including insider details and financial questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is packed into the story, how one year ago a tempting
idea of making a little Python conference in Munich was born. Six month
later, with poor German skills, no business network and mostly foreign
crew a little idea was converted into PyCon.DE. This conference had a
noticeable Italian flavour, and it’s time to tell why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anton Caceres</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html</guid><category>humor</category><category>conferences</category><category>business</category><category>community</category><category>beer</category><category>teamwork</category><category>social</category><category>education</category></item><item><title>Genropy: 10 anni di sviluppo di un framework italiano</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
consente allo sviluppatore di scrivere applicazioni complesse in tempi
brevissimi. Lo scopo del framework è di mettere a disposizione un
potente costruttore di GUI web, un ORM molto facile, veloce ed intivo ed
una serie di component che rendono possibile costruire la propria
applicazione in poche righe di codice. A questo si aggiungono tools di
amministrazione per la gestione di permessi, grafici, gestione del
workflow, gestore di stampe e molti altri che fanno di Genropy
un’ambiente usabile immediatamente in produzione anche in situazioni
complesse e critiche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abbiamo cominciato a scrivere Genropy nel 2005 e durante il primo Pycon
qui a Firenze nel 2007, abbiamo ne abbiamo mostrato la primissima
versione. Da allora, ogni edizione di Pycon è stata l’occasione per
presentare le nuove features e cercare di diffondere la copnoscenza di
questo framework . A distanza di 10 anni possiamo dire che esiste una
minuscola ma molto attiva community che utilizza Genropy come strumento
quotidiano per scrivere le proprie applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk vorremmo raccontarvi questa avventura, e darvi modo di
conoscere meglio Genropy e di capire se può essere anche per voi il
vostro nuovo modo di scriverre applicazioni web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Giovanni Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/genropy-10-anni-di-sviluppo-di-un-framework-italiano.html</guid><category>community</category><category>genropy</category><category>gui</category><category>web-development</category><category>business</category></item><item><title>Python in Africa</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Makarudze</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</guid><category>conferences</category><category>business</category><category>startup</category><category>beginner</category><category>community</category><category>women</category><category>teamwork</category><category>OpenSource</category><category>social</category><category>pyladies</category><category>education</category><category>Learning environment</category><category>user-groups</category></item><item><title>Realizzare stampe HTML e PDF usando solo Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/realizzare-stampe-html-e-pdf-usando-solo-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uno dei compiti più noiosi per chi fa software orientato al business ma
non solo, è quello di generare stampe con layout complessi e specifici
sulle esigenze del committente. Creare documenti come fatture, moduli
d’ordine, bolle di lavorazione e trasporto, schede prodotto o qualsiasi
cosa il cliente abbia il desiderio di vedere sulla stramaledetta carta è
una cosa che di norma comporta diverse criticità. Infatti ci troviamo a
dover ingabbiare dati, che solitamente rappresentiamo a video con layout
elastici e responsivi, in strutture grafiche rigide che devono risultare
sempre uguali, misurate in millimetri e ben leggibili una volta
stampate. Per rispondere a questa necessità &lt;strong&gt;Genropy&lt;/strong&gt; mette a
disposizione la libreria &lt;em&gt;gnrhtml&lt;/em&gt; che permette di descrivere in Python
layout complessi ed annidati, ottenendo come risultato un documento HTML
ed eventualmente PDF tramite il comando &lt;em&gt;wkhtmltopdf&lt;/em&gt;. La libreria
&lt;em&gt;gnrhtml&lt;/em&gt; è perfettamente integrata con il framework &lt;strong&gt;Genropy&lt;/strong&gt;, ma può
essere facilmente utilizzata anche al di fuori da questo ambiente.
Durante il talk spiegheremo il funzionamento della libreria e ne
mosteremo l’utilizzo con un caso d’esempio realizzato sia &lt;strong&gt;Genropy&lt;/strong&gt;
che in &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saverio Porcari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/realizzare-stampe-html-e-pdf-usando-solo-python.html</guid><category>pdf</category><category>prints</category><category>html</category><category>business</category><category>genropy</category></item><item><title>PyOhio 2010: Python and Entrepreneurship</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--python-and-entrepreneurship.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and Entrepeneurship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featuring Eric Floehr, Nick Albright, Matt Wilson, Austin Godber, James
Bonanno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the strengths of dynamic languages is rapid development and quick
results. Python has been used by a number of Ohio small businesses, from
supporting back-office operations to being the language the company's
products are built on. This panel discussion will talk about the
opportunities and challenges in using Python to build a business on, as
well as a discussion on starting, running, and growing a
technology-based business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-07-31:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--python-and-entrepreneurship.html</guid><category>business</category><category>entrepeneur</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2010</category></item><item><title>Pricing products using Python graphs and sets</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/pricing-products-using-python-graphs-and-sets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Rob Collins - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will look at the limitations of available rule engines when it comes
to complex pricing rules. Rob has been part of a Python team writing a
pricing engine based on network graphs. We will show:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why pricing is not easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rule engine anti-patterns, e.g. to change one price requires a week's
development time, and has to be fitted into a release cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make pricing rules data driven, usable by the business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the use of graphs and sets reduces the complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob is joined by David Layton of Grey Squirrel Consulting, who is a
fellow contractor working with Rob on the pricing project. He is an
American expatriate and Python developer, currently living and working
in London. His background is in scientific computing, CRMs and Business
Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Collins</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/pricing-products-using-python-graphs-and-sets.html</guid><category>business</category><category>graphs</category><category>network</category><category>scientific</category></item><item><title>Getting ready for PostgreSQL 9.1</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/getting-ready-for-postgresql-91.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Gabriele Bartolini,Harald Armin Massa,Marco Nenciarini
- 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza Napoli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL is an advanced, versatile open-source database management
system that integrates perfectly with Python. It is developed by a very
active international community and is distributed under the BSD-like
PostgreSQL License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise-class features (including SQL standard compliance, ACID
transactions, disaster recovery, high availability, replication,
partitioning and general extensibility) make PostgreSQL suitable for
business critical environments seeking to reduce the TCO of their
database solutions without altering their functional needs. PostgreSQL
9.0, released in September 2010, was the first version of PostgreSQL
with Hot Standby, a built-in master/slave replication mechanism.
Asynchronous replication through the standard and consolidated log
shipping technique (previously used with Warm Standby for high
availability) has been enhanced with streaming replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 9.1, expected to be out later in 2011, will add synchronous
replication to PostgreSQL, making it the first DBMS that allows
developers and users to control the replication strategy at
transactional granularity. Come to the talk and discover all the major
new features of PostgreSQL 9.1, including extensions management,
writable common table expressions (WCTE), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gabriele Bartolini</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/getting-ready-for-postgresql-91.html</guid><category>asynchronous</category><category>business</category><category>community</category><category>database</category><category>distributed</category><category>extensions</category><category>partitioning</category><category>postgresql</category><category>replication</category></item><item><title>OpenERP: 100% pythonic way for business management</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/openerp-100-pythonic-way-for-business-managemen.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Davide Corio - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business management isn't just accounting. Let's see how Python can help
us to build a complete ERP infrastructure. From CRM to e-commerce, from
accounting to document management…we'll see how Python is mature and
able to do great things where Java and .NET are still considered as the
only option. Case studies to be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Davide Corio</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/openerp-100-pythonic-way-for-business-managemen.html</guid><category>business</category><category>crm</category><category>java</category><category>.net</category></item><item><title>PostgreSQL - the database-sister of Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/postgresql-the-database-sister-of-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Harald Armin Massa - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is the updated and especially enhanced of the &amp;quot;Python and
PostgreSQL - a match made in heaven&amp;quot; talk of EP 2006, CERN, Switzerland.
PostgreSQL and Python share more then the first letter: their
communities have great similiarities; their development processes are
really comparable; their licenses and their openness to academics AND
business (on a technical and communitie perspective) are big pluses. We
will have a look at those similiarities and learn why PostgreSQL is
really the database sister to Python. There will be an overview of
PostgreSQL, information of how to connect PostgreSQL and Python; how
PostgreSQL streaming replication works and what it can do for you, how
PL/Python helps to have Web 2.5 JSON storage and handling right inside
PostgreSQL. We will show that YESQL is also a valid answer to many data
storage qeuestions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Harald Armin Massa</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/postgresql-the-database-sister-of-python.html</guid><category>business</category><category>database</category><category>json</category><category>postgresql</category><category>replication</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Serious Business: Python is not just for Engineering</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--serious-business--python-is-not-just-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serious Business: Python is not just for Engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Zach Steindler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a great business is quite different from building a great
product, but by measuring Key Performance Indicators (things like cash
flow, if users keep coming back, etc.) you can make sure your business
is on the right track. In this talk I'll cover common KPI in the tech
business and show you how we automate collecting and presenting KPI at
Olark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a hacker-turned-founder, you quickly realize there's more to building
a great business than just building a great product. The easiest way to
know your business is on the right track is to measure Key Performance
Indicators (KPIs): things like cash flow, what parts of the product is
used the most, if your users keep coming back, if users are experiencing
problems... and many, many others. How are you supposed to keep track of
it all without getting lost in a sea of noise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Python, of course! In this talk I'll cover the most common KPIs
technology businesses track and show you how we used Python at Olark to
automatically collect and present KPIs to the team. This has made it
much easier to quickly answer business questions and help us know we're
on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're a Python hacker who would like to learn more about how to
engineer a business, or if you're a business person who's just starting
to learn Python, come learn how Python isn't just for engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Zach Steindler</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--serious-business--python-is-not-just-.html</guid><category>business</category><category>kpi</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item></channel></rss>