<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_opensource.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Open Source and Free Software</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-pakistan-2019/open-source-and-free-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Van Lindburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-10-12:pycon-pakistan-2019/open-source-and-free-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Van Lindberg, Director of Python Software Foundation, kicked off Pycon Pakistan 2019 talking about open source and free software.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="opensource"></category><category term="psf"></category><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Python to bring democracy to the A.I. age</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/using-python-to-bring-democracy-to-the-ai-age.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Felipe Cabral</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/using-python-to-bring-democracy-to-the-ai-age.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-you-go-full-big-data-at-public-data-and-become-a-citzen"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When you go full Big Data at public data and become a citzen.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience type: developers, data scientists of any level of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a political coup Brazil drowned in scandals and political
disbelief. That was the final straw for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a bot persona who uses Machine Learning to analyze public
spending, launching our own data journalism investigations. As expected
we use the internet publicize our findings and icing on it was to use
Twitter to directly engage the public and politicians under the topic of
suspicious expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come with me and I’ll show some figures from Brazilian corruption, share
some code and cherry-pick the best of our toolbox to deal with public
data and machine learning. I’ll introduce our public dashboard that
makes visualization and browsing government data easy peasy. And surely
we can take a look in some tweets from Rosie, the robot, and how some
politicians are now vociferating with a ROBOT on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you guessed it right: everything is open-source and our mission is
to create a global community to bring democracy to the A.I. age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 18:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="machine-learning"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="agile"></category><category term="Data Mining"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="e-gov"></category><category term="data"></category></entry><entry><title>Just one Shade of OpenStack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/just-one-shade-of-openstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Roberto Polli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/just-one-shade-of-openstack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to start using openstack? Come to this talk and meet shade! Shade
is a python library that wraps the many OpenStack clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This introductory talk presents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an overview of openstack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting to openstack with shade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating and listing machines, networks &amp;amp; co&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shade usage in ansible modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contributing to shade (tox, git review, …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="OpenStack"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Africa</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Makarudze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="startup"></category><category term="beginner"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="women"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="pyladies"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="Learning environment"></category><category term="user-groups"></category></entry><entry><title>A socio-political analysis of open source community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2009/djangocon-2009--a-socio-political-analysis-of-ope.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Bicking</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-09-09:djangocon-us-2009/djangocon-2009--a-socio-political-analysis-of-ope.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon presents A socio-political analysis of open source community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Ian Bicking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covers why are we doing what we're doing and why it matters in terms of
Open Source and the movement. Focuses on the Django community, what's
being produced and finding meaning in that.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2009"></category><category term="opensource"></category></entry><entry><title>Designing Your Open Source Project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2012/designing-your-open-source-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Veloso</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-04:djangocon-us-2012/designing-your-open-source-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an ever present rift between designers and developers and it is
one that has existed since our paths started crossing. We'll talk about
how to be mindful of design in your own open source project and how to
attract designers to help your project become even more awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an ever present rift between designers and developers and it is
one that has existed since our paths started crossing. While it has
almost become a requirement for designers to be able to grok the code
they work with on a daily basis, that has unfortunately had no effect on
the willingness of designers to work on open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, if your project is in need of a designer, there are ways
that you can make your project more appealing to our “special breed” of
personality. In this quick talk, we’ll jump into the mind of your
typical designer, show you just how many similarities we share and then
apply that knowledge to make your project easy and appealing for
designers to jump into.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="opensource"></category></entry><entry><title>Visualization and Analysis of Large Scale Datasets with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/visualization-and-analysis-of-large-scale-dataset.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christine Moran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/visualization-and-analysis-of-large-scale-dataset.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Christine Moran - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Margherita &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will introduce ParaView, an open source application
developed by researchers around the world for parallel visualization and
analysis of large scale datasets, which in can be used to visualize and
analyze terabytes of data in real time. ParaView’s core algorithms are
implemented in C/C++ but all its major functionality can be scripted
from python with ease. I’ll give a short introduction to AstroViz, a
parallel visualization tool for astrophysical simulations implemented as
an opensource plugin to ParaView, which I have been lead developer on
since 2009. The focus of the talk will be on driving ParaView from
within python however, both general out of the box use and customized
extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have access to several parallel supercomputers so if there’s a
huge dataset we as a crowd would like to tackle visualizing during the
course of the week that would be fun project. The end of the talk will
be a short brainstorm of cool applications of analysis and visualization
of large scale datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.paraview.org/"&gt;http://www.paraview.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="analysis"></category><category term="datasets"></category><category term="opensource"></category><category term="parallel"></category><category term="simulations"></category><category term="visualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Grant Paton-Simpson - SOFA Statistics - Developing, packaging, and promoting a Python open source project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/grant-paton-simpson---sofa-statistics---developin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Grant Paton-Simpson</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/grant-paton-simpson---sofa-statistics---developin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SOFA Statistics - Developing, packaging and promoting a Python open
source project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Grant Paton-Simpson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of an open source Python project. Will cover wxPython (GUI
toolkit) plus graphics generally; quirks of different databases; making
python installer packages; using Sourceforge, Freshmeat, and Launchpad
(and Bazaar); and promoting the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOFA Statistics (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sofastatistics.com/"&gt;http://www.sofastatistics.com/&lt;/a&gt;) is an open source
desktop Python application with an emphasis on ease of use, learn as you
go, and beautiful output. The talk will cover technical aspects of the
project as well as project management issues. Specific areas covered
will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the cross-platform GUI toolkit wxPython (including wxWebKit and
the grid widgets) plus initial exploration of Matplotlib and Raphael
(Javascript and SVG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience using different database engines including SQLite, MySQL,
MS Access, and MS SQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issues with standard statistics modules e.g. in SciPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making python installer packages – currently only deb packages and
Windows installers (using NSIS). Plus managing releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Sourceforge, Freshmeat, and Launchpad (including Bazaar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting the project through blogging, answering posts e.g. Ubuntu,
wikipedia, special aggregator lists and reviews, presentations,
articles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions are very welcome as this is a very broad topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Sound and video are poor. Slides are hard to read.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="kiwipycon"></category><category term="kiwipycon2009"></category><category term="launchpad"></category><category term="opensource"></category><category term="sofa"></category><category term="sourceforge"></category></entry></feed>