<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>STEAM Workshops using Jupyter Notebooks, JupyterHub, and Binder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/steam-workshops-using-jupyter-notebooks-jupyterhub-and-binder.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Middle School and High School students can learn by doing. Jupyter Notebooks and the rich Python ecosystem with libraries on a variety of topics can engage many learners of the sciences and humanities. Interactive content, using Jupyter Widgets and visualization libraries, put the student in charge of manipulating content and extending their learning. Giving students engaging content in familiar subjects encourages them to develop and use computational skills to build upon their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difficulty of teaching workshops is access to computers and the ability to install software on those systems. This talk will demonstrate how a workshop organizer or teacher can deploy JupyterHub easily for a class using the Zero to JupyterHub Guide, Kubernetes, and Cloud Services. Even if students only have access to smartphones, tablets, or shared computers, a workshop can be held using Binder which allows a notebook environment to be served at the click of a button to any modern web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carol Willing</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/steam-workshops-using-jupyter-notebooks-jupyterhub-and-binder.html</guid><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>jupyterhub</category><category>binder</category></item><item><title>Sharing Reproducible Environments with Binder</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/sharing-reproducible-environments-with-binder-scipy-2016-andrew-osheroff.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Binder (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mybinder.org"&gt;http://mybinder.org&lt;/a&gt;) is a service that bundles GitHub repositories with code, Jupyter notebooks, and data into reproducible, executable environments that can be launched instantaneously in the browser with the click of a button. Under the hood, Binder uses simple and flexible dependency specifications to build Docker images on demand, and then launches and schedules them across a public Kubernetes cluster. In this talk, I’ll describe in detail how Binder works, and highlight some exciting use cases. I’ll then describe several future directions for the project, including handling larger datasets, lowering barriers for environment specification, and supporting custom deployments with user-provided computing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Osheroff</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/sharing-reproducible-environments-with-binder-scipy-2016-andrew-osheroff.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>binder</category><category>jupyter notebook</category></item></channel></rss>