<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Darkweb + Python: discover, analyze and extract information from hidden services</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/darkweb-python-discover-analyze-and-extract-information-from-hidden-services.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talk will start explaining how Tor project can help us to the
research and development of tools for online anonymity and privacy of
its users while surfing the Internet, by establishing virtual circuits
between the different nodes that make up the Tor network. In addition,
we will review how Tor works from anonymity point of view, preventing
websites from tracking you. Python help us to automate the process to
search an discover hidden services thanks to packages like
requests,requesocks and sockspy. At this point we will review the
crawling process and show tools in python ecosystem available for this
task such as Deep Explorer(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/blueudp/deep-explorer"&gt;https://github.com/blueudp/deep-explorer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These could be the talking points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Tor project and hidden services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovering hidden services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modules and packages we can use in python for connecting with Tor
network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools that allow search hidden services and atomate the crawling
process in Tor network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1563"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1563&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jose Manuel Ortega</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/darkweb-python-discover-analyze-and-extract-information-from-hidden-services.html</guid><category>tor</category><category>security</category><category>privacy</category><category>hacking</category><category>crawler</category></item><item><title>Using Python to create political acts</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/using-python-to-create-political-acts.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Pycon Italia I showed how my team has using Python and Data Science
to fight corruption - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiJ5a4CXRF8&amp;amp;t=8s"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiJ5a4CXRF8&amp;amp;t=8s&lt;/a&gt;
This time I want to show something that can be replicated in Italy right
after we finish the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &amp;#64;participatory (World Bank Internet impact researcher) says, every
country has a good response for public pressure across the internet, and
this response is even better within autocratic governments because they
want to keep healthy international relations. But how we can keep a
record of all the drafts of legislation that are happening right now?
How we can use this information and create an action for the public to
show their agreement or not for every change that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Scrapy, Python, Django, and Open source! Let me show you how has
been done in Brazil and the Pipeline that makes possible to replicated
here in Italy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1702"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1702&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 3 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 10:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe Cabral</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-03:pycon-italia-2019/using-python-to-create-political-acts.html</guid><category>web-scraping</category><category>Python</category><category>programming</category><category>scrapy</category><category>api</category><category>open-data</category><category>opendata</category><category>hacking</category></item><item><title>Magical attributes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/magical-attributes.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radomir Dopieralski</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/magical-attributes.html</guid><category>best-practices</category><category>hacking</category><category>api</category><category>design</category></item><item><title>Python for hackers and Penetration testing</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-for-hackers-and-penetration-testing.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Oltjano Terpollari</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/python-for-hackers-and-penetration-testing.html</guid><category>sqlmap</category><category>subnet</category><category>set</category><category>networking</category><category>zip</category><category>whitehat</category><category>web</category><category>windows</category><category>sysadmin</category><category>ssh</category><category>linux</category><category>hacking</category><category>pythonscripts</category><category>security</category><category>socket</category></item><item><title>ByteCode al supporto dei test per protocolli ed enforcing di best practices</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/bytecode-al-supporto-dei-test-per-protocolli-ed-enforcing-di-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python è un linguaggio interpretato con efficaci strumenti di
introspezione, fino a permetterci di accedere al suo bytecode e vedere
cosa la virtual machine sta per eseguire. Per quanto questa esigenza sia
solitamente molto limitata in ambito di produzione ed uso del software
può venirci utile all’interno delle test suite per verificare che il
codice scritto da terzi o dal noi stessi del domani rispetti ancora dei
protocolli o delle best practices che avevamo presupposto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La maggior parte di queste esigenze possono essere soddisfatte anche
tramite l’uso di metaclassi o monkeypatching, ma in alcuni casi è
possibile saltare i check preposti involontariamente (ad esempio
ereditando dalla classe sbagliata nel caso delle metaclassi), mentre la
verifica del byte code ci consente di controllare cosa effettivamente
sarà eseguito, non cosa ci aspettiamo sia eseguito.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Molina</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/bytecode-al-supporto-dei-test-per-protocolli-ed-enforcing-di-best-practices.html</guid><category>quality-assurance</category><category>CPython</category><category>testing</category><category>robustness</category><category>static-typing</category><category>bytecode</category><category>hacking</category><category>compiler</category></item><item><title>Scientific Hooliganism: lessons from the first hack in history</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/scientific-hooliganism-lessons-from-the-first-hack-in-history.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1903, Guglielmo Marconi prepared to unveil his world-first,
long-distance wireless communication technology to the Royal Institution
in London. He was looking forward to roaring success, scientific
acclaim, and a string of wealthy new customers - but he didn’t count
upon falling victim to the first hack in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a tale of business secrets, flame wars, stage magic, and
magnificent sideburns, direct from the records of Edwardian England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk highlights several of the lessons that the FLOSS and
information security communities can still learn from the fateful events
of 1903. Marconi’s tale is a master class in the necessity of open
source technology, as well as being a delightful introduction to the art
of vulnerability reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lilly Ryan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/scientific-hooliganism-lessons-from-the-first-hack-in-history.html</guid><category>infosec</category><category>FLOSS</category><category>radio</category><category>security</category><category>hacking</category><category>history</category></item><item><title>Hacking PyLongObject on Python 3.2</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/hacking-pylongobject-on-python-32.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Cesare Di Mauro - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning with Python 3 the old integer (&amp;quot;int&amp;quot;) type has gone leaving
the place to &amp;quot;long&amp;quot;, which replaced it giving a unique, uniform type to
deal with integers. However longs need a more complex structure which
effectively dropped a bit of Python 3.x performance. Looking at their
implementation, an idea grown that can help to improve the situation on
common sceneries (using &amp;quot;short&amp;quot; integers). A slightly changed structure
will be presented and compared with the old PyIntObject and the current
Python 3.2 PyLongObject, along with some optimizations, thoughts, and
issues found on the road, which will show the effort required by such
change on a Python core element.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cesare Di Mauro</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/hacking-pylongobject-on-python-32.html</guid><category>hacking</category></item><item><title>Through the Side Channel: Timing and Implementation Attacks in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--through-the-side-channel--timing-and-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the Side Channel: Timing and Implementation Attacks in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Geremy Condra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python's dynamic nature, large standard library, and concern for beauty
over performance make it an elegant and uniquely easy to use language,
but they also cause some unique problems. In this talk we'll explore how
features ranging from dictionaries to duck typing can become security
risks, demonstrate those attacks on real Python projects, and examine
how you can protect yourself and your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, an increasing body of evidence has accumulated
indicating that even when a system is hardened enough to provide strong
guarantees about its high-level behavior, implementation details and
especially performance properties can still provide attackers with an
easy way in. For Python, this is especially problematic: its generally
high-level view and the emphasis placed on flexibility often mean that
it can be difficult to stop attackers from gaining a foothold, while its
comparatively low execution speed increases the efficacy of wide variety
of implementation and timing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help Pythonistas understand and cope with these problems, we've
divided this talk into two parts: in the first, we demonstrate the
attacks against a series of widely-deployed Python projects with the
goal of both improving awareness about the issue and demonstrating
common weaknesses to be avoided. The second demonstrates effective
countermeasures and alternative constructions with the goal of improving
defenders' odds of spotting and correcting these flaws in their own
code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Geremy Condra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--through-the-side-channel--timing-and-.html</guid><category>hacking</category><category>hardening</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>security</category></item></channel></rss>