<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_communication.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>From HTTP to Kafka-based microservices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/from-http-to-kafka-based-microservices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wojciech Rząsa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/from-http-to-kafka-based-microservices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTTP or asynchronous communication in microservices? This question is
frequently repeated and discussed. Obviously, HTTP-based communication
is easier for developers and architects. Even if your developers have no
prior experience with microservices, they will probably understand how
to implement an HTTP service well. While asynchronous communication has
a lot of advantages that allow to design and implement really robust
microservices system, they also bring new challenges not so obvious for
people who didn’t have a chance to work with such an environment before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In FLYR we mostly have HTTP-based Inter Process Communication (IPC) in
our infrastructure. At some point, we realized that to provide the
functionality required by our product we needed something more flexible
and more… asynchronous. We designed and implemented a Python library to
facilitate switching to asynchronous IPC, supporting one- or two-way or
even single- request – multi-response communication. An important thing
in the design process was to provide developers having HTTP experience a
tool that would ease the process of switching to asynchronous
communication. Consequently, to switch an HTTP server-side endpoint to
asynchronous IPC is a straightforward task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We selected Kafka for our message broker, not surprisingly by comparing
its performance reports with our very rough, but no less demanding
performance requirements. But we also took care to hide the details of
the broker logic from developers. Yes, we don’t use all Kafka
capabilities, if you need e.g. Kafka Streams, you will have to use
another solution. But we can decide what capabilities are used in our
microservices and how we can make changes in the way our services
communicate in a single place. There are also hooks, Kubernetes health
checks and more with a lot of flexibility available out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to opensource our library. At the moment of writing it
‘opensourcing’ is still a work in progress and we didn’t have sufficient
time to do it due to strict time constraints we have on delivering
functionality to our customers, but we hope to be able to do it soon. In
this talk I would like to describe how we solved particularly important
problems, what solutions we developed, how we use them and what problems
still need to be addressed by developers. In other words, I would like
to describe you the journey we made from HTTP to Kafka-based
microservices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Communication"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category></entry><entry><title>Software patterns for productive teams</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/software-patterns-for-productive-teams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Radoslav Georgiev</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/software-patterns-for-productive-teams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software development is a team game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we want to deliver more work, one of the variables that we can
change is the team size. But as we all know, increasing the team size
does not automatically translate into increased productivity &amp;amp; more
features shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If things are left unmanaged, people can step on each other toes, block
each other &amp;amp; generally decrease the overall productivity of a given
software project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll identify different problems teams can face &amp;amp; see how
we can solve them using different strategies &amp;amp; patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, we want to enable the team to perform better &amp;amp; ship features
with high confidence. We want enable the team &amp;amp; put its potential into
building good software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems we are going to cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constant merge conflicts / working in the same files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocking each other on different features / Feature deadlock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantly switching between bugfixing &amp;amp; feature development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constant regressions and things breaking down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fighting with local setup &amp;amp; not being able to properly test things,
especially when working with 3rd parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge strategies &amp;amp; improving the work with git &amp;amp; GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication between team members &amp;amp; ego fights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each problem, we are going to propose different solutions with
provided real-life examples from our experience &amp;amp; projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples show are going to be in the context of large Python /
Django projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is the natural sequel of the following talks from previous
EuroPythons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EuroPython 2017 - Practical Debugging - Tips, Tricks and Ways to
think - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Ys4gCUtTh8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Ys4gCUtTh8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EuroPython 2018 - Django structure for scale and longevity -
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yG3ZdxBb1oo"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yG3ZdxBb1oo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="Abstractions"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Communication"></category><category term="Django Projects"></category><category term="Management"></category></entry><entry><title>How To Build a Python Microservice Without Losing a Job</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-build-a-python-microservice-without-losing-a-job.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/how-to-build-a-python-microservice-without-losing-a-job.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarcastic talk, sharing real-life experience on both technical and
social aspects of doing an architecture migration to microservices
without losing a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any change in software architecture is a significant time investment.
Writing microservices in Python is a joy, but when you decide on it,
there is often no way back. Therefore it is always an advantage to know
what to expect in advance, not just from inspiring blog posts but also
from the harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share typical pitfalls of choosing a framework stack,
communication protocol, conventions, and deployment process — all
covered by real projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Communication"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category><category term="Microservices"></category></entry><entry><title>Opt Out of Online Sexism – Open Source Activism</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/opt-out-of-online-sexism-open-source-activism.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Teresa Ingram</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/opt-out-of-online-sexism-open-source-activism.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Although people of all genders can experience violence and abuse
online, the abuse experienced by women is often sexist or misogynistic
in nature, and online threats of violence against women are often
sexualized and include specific references to women’s bodies. &amp;quot; -
Amnesty International. This abuse pushes women offline, affecting their
social well-being, representation and economic potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss how we plan to help resolve this with our
browser extension, Opt Out. I will discuss the online global tragedy
that is online sexual harassment, our idea and where we’re at with
current implementation. I will also talk about what it’s like to build
an open source activism project, one which aims to be lead by the
community it’s trying to protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover current research and results from our own engagement with
the community, where the idea came from and challenges we have faced and
plan to face in the future. I will also dive into the intricate world of
natural language processing (NLP) for online harassment and talk about
balancing state-of-the-art data science with web development in an open
source community, one being managed by someone relatively new to tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Communication"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Open-Source"></category><category term="TDD"></category><category term="Web"></category></entry><entry><title>Communicating Between Microservices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/communicating-between-microservices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/communicating-between-microservices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microservices are not just a bunch of little apps, it’s a connected
ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a monolith, code modules invoke each other simply by using
language- level function calls, but in a microservice architecture,
communication between components does not come for free anymore.
Choosing not just a protocol, but a paradigm for communication between
endpoints is considered the most tricky issue of microservice approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing microservices in Python is a joy, but when you decide on it,
there is often no way back. Therefore it is always an advantage to know
what to expect in advance, not just from inspiring blog posts but also
from the harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a bunch of smooth as well as tricky microservice migrations in
the past, I would like to share typical pitfalls of choosing a framework
stack, communication protocol, conventions, and deployment process — all
covered by real projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1638"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="MessageQueues"></category><category term="microservices"></category><category term="HTTP"></category><category term="communication"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="websockets"></category></entry><entry><title>Efficient Python development with small teams</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/efficient-python-development-with-small-teams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-André Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/efficient-python-development-with-small-teams.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="quality-assurance"></category><category term="project-management"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="communication"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="principles"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="strategies"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="architecture"></category></entry></feed>