<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_job.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Getting the job: the do's and don'ts of landing a Python job</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--getting-the-job--the-do--39-s-and-don.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Moloney</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--getting-the-job--the-do--39-s-and-don.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting the job: the do's and don'ts of landing a Python job&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Moloney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Python programmer is brilliant in his or her own way. That
brilliance shines in code and peer-to-peer conversation. But how do you
display your skills to a non-programmer? How do you impress management
and human resources? What do you need to do (and not do) to successfully
navigate the hiring process and land the job?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imaginary Landscape has been interviewing, hiring and not hiring Python
talent since 1999. Throughout these many years, there have been good
candidates, bad candidates and downright ugly candidates. This talk will
use actual correspondence and examples to demonstrate what can separate
you from the crowd and what can separate you from consideration.
Imaginary Landscape non- technical Managing Partner Brian Moloney will
lead the session by describing how he evaluates potential hires and what
goes through his mind while speaking with potential Python candidates.
Attendees will take away a specific set of guidelines for mastering the
non-technical aspects of the recruiting process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: There are problems with the audio for the first 5
minutes.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hiring"></category><category term="job"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>