<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Refactoring in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/refactoring-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[Replacement talk]&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk was a replacement for Stanislav Geidl's talk: From legacy
code to modern code&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honest apologies to anyone whose expectations were subverted, but
Stanislav fell sick and could not attend. Find the updated abstract
below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe experiences and lessons learned from tackling
extremely demanding code. How to bring order to mismanaged code and
elevate the code base to a standard that's acceptable in today's tech
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python makes wonderful code accessible at our fingertips, but it also
allows us to take a lot of liberty. When you start, code is beautiful
and makes sense. With each step you walk on, you find more and more
hacks showing up. Eventually, the brilliant codebase you've started with
can not be seen under the mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every code-base can be rewritten, not everything can be redone from
scratch. Cool libraries often take a lot of liberty with code structure
and make cross-integration difficult, if not impossible. Tests sound
ideal, but in practice, they're just so hard to make right. Why is this,
and how to change it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk will tackle the problems in three parts:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- The Easy Wins: What to do to instantly increase the code quality in
your organisation. How? Why isn't it enough?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Patterns and Antipatterns: How to identify code that &amp;quot;smells&amp;quot;, how
to replace it? How to integrate into old code, better?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- The Philosophy: What approach to set down for the future? Why to
care? How to write replace-able code. How to prevent history from
repeating.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will close with audience discussion and experiences, questions
and proposals - building a collection of some on-premise tips and
tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tin Marković</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/refactoring-in-python.html</guid><category>Architecture</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>Development</category><category>Python 3</category><category>legacy-code</category></item></channel></rss>