<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Grant Paton-Simpson - SOFA Statistics - Developing, packaging, and promoting a Python open source project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/grant-paton-simpson---sofa-statistics---developin.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SOFA Statistics - Developing, packaging and promoting a Python open
source project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Grant Paton-Simpson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of an open source Python project. Will cover wxPython (GUI
toolkit) plus graphics generally; quirks of different databases; making
python installer packages; using Sourceforge, Freshmeat, and Launchpad
(and Bazaar); and promoting the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOFA Statistics (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sofastatistics.com/"&gt;http://www.sofastatistics.com/&lt;/a&gt;) is an open source
desktop Python application with an emphasis on ease of use, learn as you
go, and beautiful output. The talk will cover technical aspects of the
project as well as project management issues. Specific areas covered
will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the cross-platform GUI toolkit wxPython (including wxWebKit and
the grid widgets) plus initial exploration of Matplotlib and Raphael
(Javascript and SVG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience using different database engines including SQLite, MySQL,
MS Access, and MS SQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issues with standard statistics modules e.g. in SciPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making python installer packages – currently only deb packages and
Windows installers (using NSIS). Plus managing releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Sourceforge, Freshmeat, and Launchpad (including Bazaar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting the project through blogging, answering posts e.g. Ubuntu,
wikipedia, special aggregator lists and reviews, presentations,
articles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions are very welcome as this is a very broad topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Sound and video are poor. Slides are hard to read.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Grant Paton-Simpson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/grant-paton-simpson---sofa-statistics---developin.html</guid><category>kiwipycon</category><category>kiwipycon2009</category><category>launchpad</category><category>opensource</category><category>sofa</category><category>sourceforge</category></item></channel></rss>