<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_pyusb.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PyGotham 2011: Go Go Gadget Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2011/pygotham-2011--go-go-gadget-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicholas Waite</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-09-16:pygotham-2011/pygotham-2011--go-go-gadget-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you know that embedded devices are everywhere. Perhaps you've thought
how nice it would be to make a Linux USB driver for some Windows-only
device, or you've got something proprietary you would like to
reverse-engineer and repurpose for your next big scheme. We know Python
can do pretty much anything inside the computer--but how does a software
person enter the world of circuits? And once you have some circuits, how
can you bring the data back into your box? Bridging the worlds of
hardware and software, I will show the power of PyUSB and Pyserial to
pwn some sweet hardware and charm it over the USB port. From my own
trials and tribulations building and hacking real devices, from a simple
HID-class USB missile launcher to the custom protocol used in a complex
biomedical data acquisition system, you will learn about USB packet
sniffing, rapid-prototyping device drivers in python, and deciphering
circuit boards and data sheets for fun &amp;amp; profit. I aim to leave you
armed and ready to take on hardware of your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="drivers"></category><category term="pygotham"></category><category term="pygotham2011"></category><category term="pyserial"></category><category term="pyusb"></category><category term="usb"></category></entry></feed>