<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_architecture.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Don't start with a database</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/dont-start-with-a-database.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Grzegorz Kocjan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/dont-start-with-a-database.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What you do when you start a new project? Usually, we begin with
database design, then we prepare a migration system, user registration,
and all different stuff that distracts us from doing what is most
important - business logic. With the clean architecture, we can learn
how to start a project in another way and this will be one of two main
topics of my talk. The second one will be about new features in Python.
You probably heard about typings, mypy, and dataclasses, but I will show
you how they can be used in real life project that can be developed over
many years in production lifecycle. There will be no &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; app,
no copy &amp;amp; paste of documentation, only practical knowledge learned
through many years of practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="APIs"></category><category term="Abstractions"></category><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Clean Code"></category></entry><entry><title>Running a Synchrotron on Open Source Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/running-a-synchrotron-on-open-source-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Clinton Roy</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/running-a-synchrotron-on-open-source-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A synchrotron is a large research facility that has a large software
stack to keep things running, fortunately a large chunk of the stack is
Open Source and fair chunk of it is Python to boot. By the end of the
talk attendees will understand the scale of the infrastructure (both
physical and software) that is required, and have an idea of what sort
of problems a synchrotron could help them solve.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Engineering"></category><category term="Hardware/IoT"></category></entry><entry><title>Building Data Workflows with Luigi and Kubernetes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/building-data-workflows-with-luigi-and-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nar Kumar Chhantyal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/building-data-workflows-with-luigi-and-kubernetes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on how one can build complex data pipelines in
Python. I will introduce Luigi and show how it solves problems while
running multiple chain of batch jobs like dependency resolution,
workflow management, visualisation, failure handling etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I will present how to package Luigi pipelines as Docker
image for easier testing and deployment. Finally, I will go through way
to deploy them on Kubernetes cluster, thus making it possible to scale
Big Data pipelines on- demand and reduce infrastructure costs. I will
also give tips and tricks to make Luigi Scheduler play well with
Kubernetes batch execution feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be accompanied by demo project. It will be very
beneficial for audience who have some experience in running batch jobs
(not necessarily in Python), typically people who work in Big Data
sphere like data scientists, data engineers, BI devs and software
developers. Familiarity with Python is helpful but not needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category><category term="Scaling"></category></entry><entry><title>How To Build a Python Microservice Without Losing a Job</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-build-a-python-microservice-without-losing-a-job.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/how-to-build-a-python-microservice-without-losing-a-job.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarcastic talk, sharing real-life experience on both technical and
social aspects of doing an architecture migration to microservices
without losing a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any change in software architecture is a significant time investment.
Writing microservices in Python is a joy, but when you decide on it,
there is often no way back. Therefore it is always an advantage to know
what to expect in advance, not just from inspiring blog posts but also
from the harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share typical pitfalls of choosing a framework stack,
communication protocol, conventions, and deployment process — all
covered by real projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Communication"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category><category term="Microservices"></category></entry><entry><title>How to ship a Python app to a hundred million desktops</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-to-ship-a-python-app-to-a-hundred-million-desktops.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Max Bélanger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/how-to-ship-a-python-app-to-a-hundred-million-desktops.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is widely used to write scripts and tools, but did you know that
it can also be used to build client-side end-user applications? Crossing
the gap from script to app can be challenging: Join us to learn how to
write modern, high quality desktop apps in Python!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Dropbox, we’ve been fans of Python from the very beginning: we’ll
take you on a tour of our app for Windows/macOS/Linux and share our
“lessons learned” from over 10 years of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll share best practices and techniques for shipping Python code to
hundreds of millions of devices: discover how to maximize security,
improve performance and guarantee stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore the key choices we made and why: learn how we migrated to
Python 3 by simultaneously shipping both versions, or how we use HTML to
power our GUI (a la Electron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll reveal our favorite tools and libraries: learn how we scaled from
a few engineers to over 100 and added support for other programming
languages (like Rust).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The goal of this talk is to share our learnings from using Python on
Windows, macOS and Linux to encourage the use of Python when building
Desktop apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- We also want to recognize the third-party libraries we’ve used (and
their authors) to raise their profile with the overall community.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- We hope this will inspire attendees to write more desktop Python
code, and raise awareness for this use case with the community as a
whole.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We intend to speak to any Python developer/engineer or enthusiast who
makes use of Python in a Desktop environment (or wants to), whether
it’s to make scripts, tools or apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We do not expect knowledge of any specific third-party Python
libraries; in fact, we hope to draw attention to and recognize many
libraries we’ve found useful.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Cross-Platform-Development"></category><category term="Mac OS X"></category><category term="Windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Refactoring in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/refactoring-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tin Marković</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/refactoring-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;[Replacement talk]&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk was a replacement for Stanislav Geidl's talk: From legacy
code to modern code&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honest apologies to anyone whose expectations were subverted, but
Stanislav fell sick and could not attend. Find the updated abstract
below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe experiences and lessons learned from tackling
extremely demanding code. How to bring order to mismanaged code and
elevate the code base to a standard that's acceptable in today's tech
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python makes wonderful code accessible at our fingertips, but it also
allows us to take a lot of liberty. When you start, code is beautiful
and makes sense. With each step you walk on, you find more and more
hacks showing up. Eventually, the brilliant codebase you've started with
can not be seen under the mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every code-base can be rewritten, not everything can be redone from
scratch. Cool libraries often take a lot of liberty with code structure
and make cross-integration difficult, if not impossible. Tests sound
ideal, but in practice, they're just so hard to make right. Why is this,
and how to change it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk will tackle the problems in three parts:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- The Easy Wins: What to do to instantly increase the code quality in
your organisation. How? Why isn't it enough?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Patterns and Antipatterns: How to identify code that &amp;quot;smells&amp;quot;, how
to replace it? How to integrate into old code, better?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- The Philosophy: What approach to set down for the future? Why to
care? How to write replace-able code. How to prevent history from
repeating.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will close with audience discussion and experiences, questions
and proposals - building a collection of some on-premise tips and
tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Clean Code"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="legacy-code"></category></entry><entry><title>The state of Machine Learning Operations in 2019</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-state-of-machine-learning-operations-in-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Saucedo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/the-state-of-machine-learning-operations-in-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of the key challenges and trends in
the productization of machine learning systems, including concepts such
as reproducibility, explainability and orchestration. The talk will also
provide a high level overview of several key open source tools and
frameworks available to tackle these issues, which have been identifyed
putting together the Awesome Machine Learning Operations list
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/EthicalML/awesome-machine-learning-operations"&gt;https://github.com/EthicalML/awesome-machine-learning-operations&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The key concepts that will be covered are:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Reproducibility&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Explainability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;* Orchestration of models&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reproducibility piece will cover key motivations as well as
practical requirements for model versioning, together with tools that
allow data scientists to achieve version control of model+config+data to
ensure full model lineage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explainability piece will contain a high level overview of why this
has become an important topic in machine learning, including the high
profile incidents that tech companies have experienced where undesired
biases have slipped into data. This will also include a high level
overview of some of the tools available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the orchestration piece will cover some of the fundamental
challenges with large scale serving of models, together with some of the
key tools that are available to ensure this challenge can be tackled.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Deep Learning"></category><category term="Machine-Learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Tips for the scientific programmer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/tips-for-the-scientific-programmer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michele Simionato</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/tips-for-the-scientific-programmer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a talk for people who need to perform large numeric
calculations. They could be scientists, developers working in close
contact with scientists, or even people working on finance and other
quantitative fields. Such people are routinely confronted with issues
like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1 parallelism: how to parallelize calculations efficiently&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2 data: how to store and manage large amounts of data efficiently&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3 memory: how to avoid running out of memory&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4 performance: how to be fast&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the talk is to teach some lessons learned after several
years of doing numeric simulations in a context were micro-optimizations
are the least important factor, while overall architecture, design
choices and good algorithms are of paramount importance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Algorithms"></category><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Case Study"></category><category term="Performance"></category></entry><entry><title>The dos and don'ts of task queues</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/the-dos-and-donts-of-task-queues.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Petr Stehlík</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/the-dos-and-donts-of-task-queues.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Kiwi.com we heavily rely on task queues and asynchronous execution of
code to process large amounts of requests coming to our back-ends. With
the separation of our codebase to microservices, we can quickly try new
tools and different approaches to process these large volumes of
requests. The microservice we’ll be talking about is making unreliable
slow 3rd party services reliable and asynchronous with a bit of business
logic sprinkled on top of it. We’ll tell a failure story of ours but
resulting in a valuable lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our services use Celery and it’s the go-to tool for new services
as well but we wanted to be different with this new microservice. RQ is
the next best choice for task queues and it is presented as simpler and
more straightforward than Celery. That can definitely be true but after
3 weeks of research, development and struggling we found out the
unpleasant truth about being simple and making the right choices. We
won’t talk about comparing the frameworks but rather about the approach
on how to experiment with new things in your environment. After that,
we’ll present our current setup which can take upon any number of
tasks*. How we orchestrate the app and continuously integrate and
deploy and what fun things await ahead of us in the development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Conditions may apply.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Case Study"></category><category term="failures/mistakes"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing a Python autoreloader</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/writing-a-python-autoreloader.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Forbes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/writing-a-python-autoreloader.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reloading your code changes quickly is an integral part of the
development experience in frameworks like Django and Flask that
developers have come to rely on. But how do they work under the hood and
what challenges do you face while writing one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will explore how I refactored the autoreload
implementation in Django 2.2 and the lessons I learned along the way
(hint: it's surprisingly complex!). I will also be introducing a library
I've developed to simplify this if you ever find yourself writing your
own.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Django"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Software Design"></category></entry><entry><title>Communicating Between Microservices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/communicating-between-microservices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-04:pycon-italia-2019/communicating-between-microservices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microservices are not just a bunch of little apps, it’s a connected
ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a monolith, code modules invoke each other simply by using
language- level function calls, but in a microservice architecture,
communication between components does not come for free anymore.
Choosing not just a protocol, but a paradigm for communication between
endpoints is considered the most tricky issue of microservice approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing microservices in Python is a joy, but when you decide on it,
there is often no way back. Therefore it is always an advantage to know
what to expect in advance, not just from inspiring blog posts but also
from the harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a bunch of smooth as well as tricky microservice migrations in
the past, I would like to share typical pitfalls of choosing a framework
stack, communication protocol, conventions, and deployment process — all
covered by real projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1638"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 4 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:15 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="MessageQueues"></category><category term="microservices"></category><category term="HTTP"></category><category term="communication"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="websockets"></category></entry><entry><title>Efficient Python development with small teams</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/efficient-python-development-with-small-teams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-André Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/efficient-python-development-with-small-teams.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="quality-assurance"></category><category term="project-management"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="communication"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="principles"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="strategies"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="architecture"></category></entry><entry><title>Get up to speed with OpenStack! - Part 2</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/get-up-to-speed-with-openstack-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Muharem Hrnjadovic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/get-up-to-speed-with-openstack-part-2.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="storage"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Get up to speed with OpenStack! - Part 3</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/get-up-to-speed-with-openstack-part-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Muharem Hrnjadovic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/get-up-to-speed-with-openstack-part-3.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="storage"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Python: da programmatore a domatore</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-da-programmatore-a-domatore.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessandro Pisa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/python-da-programmatore-a-domatore.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="debugging"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="integration"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="tdd"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="architecture"></category></entry><entry><title>Designing Large-Scale Applications in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/designing-large-scale-applications-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marc-André Lemburg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/designing-large-scale-applications-in-python.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="business"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="integration"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="servers"></category><category term="refactoring"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="framework"></category><category term="sql"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="architecture"></category></entry><entry><title>Meta Programming - Some Use Cases for Everyday Programming</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/meta-programming-some-use-cases-for-everyday-programming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Müller</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/meta-programming-some-use-cases-for-everyday-programming.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="debugging"></category><category term="metaprogramming"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="principles"></category><category term="refactoring"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="validation"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category></entry><entry><title>Python and PostgreSQL for Huge Data Warehouses</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-and-postgresql-for-huge-data-warehouses.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hannu Krosing</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/python-and-postgresql-for-huge-data-warehouses.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="nosql"></category><category term="parallelization"></category><category term="bigdata"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="pl/python"></category><category term="olap"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="sql"></category><category term="performance"></category></entry><entry><title>Server side story</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/server-side-story.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Simone Deponti</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-04:europython-2013/server-side-story.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="HTTP"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="deploy"></category><category term="mobile"></category><category term="javascript"></category><category term="desktop"></category><category term="sysadmin"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="gevent"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="websockets"></category><category term="architecture"></category></entry><entry><title>Coding for the Modern Warzone</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/coding-for-the-modern-warzone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gemma Hentsch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/coding-for-the-modern-warzone.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="udp"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="flask"></category><category term="tcp"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="resilience"></category></entry><entry><title>Python: from programmer to tamer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-from-programmer-to-tamer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alessandro Pisa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/python-from-programmer-to-tamer.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="debugging"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="integration"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="tdd"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="software-engineering"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="architecture"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Good Practices</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-good-practices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alan Franzoni</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-03:europython-2013/python-good-practices.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="design"></category><category term="deploy"></category><category term="patterns"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="best-practices"></category></entry><entry><title>Get up to speed with OpenStack! - Part 1</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/get-up-to-speed-with-openstack-part-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Muharem Hrnjadovic</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/get-up-to-speed-with-openstack-part-1.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="storage"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Marconi: Queuing and Notification service for OpenStack</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/marconi-queuing-and-notification-service-for-openstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Flavio Percoco</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/marconi-queuing-and-notification-service-for-openstack.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="MessageQueues"></category><category term="WSGI"></category><category term="mongodb"></category><category term="REST"></category><category term="tdd"></category><category term="application-design"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category></entry><entry><title>La sicurezza dei database MySQL in ottica GDPR</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/la-sicurezza-dei-database-mysql-in-ottica-gdpr.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Carlessi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-20:pycon-italia-2018/la-sicurezza-dei-database-mysql-in-ottica-gdpr.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Il 25 maggio 2018 la GDPR diventerà legge per tutte le aziende che
trattano dati sensibili di cittadini europei, a prescindere dalla
nazionalità o dalle leggi locali: in pratica tutte le aziende private
italiane, nessuna esclusa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa presentazione è quindi dedicata a chi si occupa di sicurezza e
che dovrà fare i conti con questa normativa, ma non da un punto di vista
legale, bensì tecnico: come posso aderire alle richieste se uso il
database MySQL?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quindi dopo un breve introduzione alla GDPR, ci concentreremo su come
MySQL possa soddisfarne le richieste (con riferimento ai vari articoli)
così da fornire la conoscenza che permetta di scegliere le strategie
migliori per il proprio business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questa sessione è indicata per chiunque lavori con MySQL. Saranno date
per scontate solo le conoscenze di base dei database, ma chi ha già
conoscenza di MySQL potrà apprezzarne a pieno le opzioni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;venerdì 20 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 14:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Cryptography"></category><category term="sql"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="mysql"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Engineering Architecture at Simple</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/data-engineering-architecture-at-simple.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Story</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-27:pydata-chicago-2016/data-engineering-architecture-at-simple.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A walk through Simple's Data Engineering stack, including lessons learned and why we chose certain tools and languages for different parts of our infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="engineering"></category></entry><entry><title>Derivatives Analytics with Python &amp; Numpy</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/derivatives-analytics-with-python-numpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/derivatives-analytics-with-python-numpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Yves Hilpisch - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In financial engineering and derivatives analytics, C/C++/Java/VBA and
other languages are still dominating. Visixion has developed with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dexision.com"&gt;DEXISION&lt;/a&gt; the first full fledged
derivatives analytics suite with Python as core language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEXISION is an On Demand application that is completely Open Source
based (LAMP). For derivatives valuation, it uses Monte Carlo simulation
- an approach known to be computationally demanding. However, Numpy
provides the performance and functionality needed to implement financial
simulation algorithms in a fast and compact manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk illustrates the architecture of our analytics suite and
demonstrates how to implement fast and compact simulation algorithms
with Python and Numpy. The talk shows that the Python/Numpy combination
reaches sufficient speed for productive financial applications -
something still widely doubted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[No prerequisites.]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="engineering"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="simulation"></category></entry><entry><title>What is Google App Engine?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wesley J. Chun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/what-is-google-app-engine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google App Engine is a unique hosting platform that lets you build
applications and run them in Google's data centers using the massive
global infrastructure built to run the Internet's most powerful company.
App Engine offers a development environment that uses familiar
technologies (Java and Python) and provides a powerful and robust set of
APIs to users while maintaining security and independence from other
apps running in the cloud. It is always free to get started so you can
try it out with no risk, and if you need additional computing resources,
you can purchase additional computing resources beyond the free quota
limits. (If you enable billing and trust us with your credit card, we
will extend your free quotas even further; you won't get charged until
you exceed those &lt;em&gt;extended&lt;/em&gt; quotas.) Scale your application to millions
of users and pay only for what you use at competitive market pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we provide an update of the newest features found in
the most recent releases of the App Engine platform. We also share some
suggestions for best practices to existing App Engine developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners to the App Engine platform will be interested in the
introductory workshop which may be offered (see description below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google App Engine workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we'll give you a comprehensive introduction to the
platform in two/three components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-hour Introduction to Cloud computing and Google App Engine seminar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-hour App Engine hands-on workshop/codelab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first hour, we review Cloud Computing as an industry and where
Google App Engine fits into the picture. Specifically, we discuss App
Engine as a PaaS solution because of the inherent challenges of building
web and other applications. We'll outline the architecture of App
Engine, what it's major components are, introduce its features and APIs,
discuss the service and how it works (including information on the free
quotas), present some information about current users and usage,
including integration with Google Apps, and finally, give an overview of
its enterprise edition called Google App Engine for Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the approximately one-hour lecture, we'll show you how to create
applications that run on App Engine by building a simple but real web
application from the ground up via a hands-on coding laboratory.
Although based on the online tutorial, this codelab goes up and beyond
what's in the documentation: you will get a more detailed step-by-step
instructions to replicate that example as well as have the opportunity
to extend your application with some of the newer APIs that come with
App Engine. The codelab will cover the Users service, non-relational
Datastore, and Memcache APIs. Time-permitting, we'll also discuss some
of the newest features found in recent App Engine releases.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="memcache"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>django-rdflib and postgresql - the best of both worlds</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/django-rdflib-and-postgresql-the-best-of-both-w.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Talpalaru</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/django-rdflib-and-postgresql-the-best-of-both-w.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Stefan Talpalaru - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;rdflib is a python library implementing a database with various triples
back- end, parser, data serializers, SPARQL is a Python interface to
extract/insert triples. We integrated it in Django reusing the database
connection and exposing an ORM interface, along with full-text search on
literals. This presentation shows a django-rdflib case study with a
PostgreSQL backend in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brancusi1.usc.edu"&gt;Brain Architecture Management
System&lt;/a&gt; - a neuroscientific project for the
University of Southern California. Benefits of the flexible RDF
structure will be shown, allowing researchers to insert free format
data, making data public with a customizable serialization and use the
powerful full-text search integrated in PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objective: show attendees an effective combination of RDF, PostgreSQL
full- text search and Django ORM via django-rdflib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Django familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="orm"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="reusing"></category><category term="search"></category><category term="serialization"></category><category term="university"></category></entry><entry><title>django-rdflib e postgresql - il meglio dei due mondi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/django-rdflib-e-postgresql-il-meglio-dei-due-mo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefan Talpalaru</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/django-rdflib-e-postgresql-il-meglio-dei-due-mo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Stefan Talpalaru - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Italiana Big
Mac &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;rdflib è una libreria python che fornisce una base di dati con vari
back-end per le triple, dei parser, serializzatori, SPARQL è
un'interfaccia in python per estrarre/inserire le triple. L'abbiamo
integrata con Django tramite il riutilizzo della connessione alla base
di dati fornendo un'interfaccia ORM e la capacità di fare ricerca
full-text sui valori letterali. La presentazione contiene un studio di
caso per django-rdflib con un back-end postgresql in Brain Architecture
Management System (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brancusi1.usc.edu"&gt;http://brancusi1.usc.edu&lt;/a&gt;) - un progetto
neuroscientifico per University of Southern California. Si vedranno i
benefici della struttura flessibile del RDF che permette ai ricercatori
di introdurre dati in formatto libero, rendere i dati pubblici con una
serializzazione personalizzata e usare la potente ricerca full-text
fornita da postgresql.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scopo: introdurre al pubblico una combinazione di RDF, la ricerca
full-text di postgresql e l'ORM di Django tramite django-rdflib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requisiti: familiarità con Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="orm"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="university"></category></entry><entry><title>Flow-based programming made easy with PyF 2.0</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/flow-based-programming-made-easy-with-pyf-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Schemoul</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/flow-based-programming-made-easy-with-pyf-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Jonathan Schemoul - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Napoli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyF is a python framework to ease flow based programming and allow
massive data crunching on multiple CPUs. We boast an optional web-based
interface to visually design processing tubes, batch scheduling, report
generation and email alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Framework is easily extensible by writing plugins, a lot of features
like data persistence, reporting and web scrapping are already part of
the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will focus on an introduction to PyF architecture and
higher-level designer ui use and how it could be useful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If available, an additional training session will focus on working with
the framework to create your own flow-based processes and plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pyfproject.org/"&gt;http://www.pyfproject.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="framework"></category><category term="processing"></category><category term="ui"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Leveraging an instant messaging protocol to build a scalable cloud architecture</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/leveraging-an-instant-messaging-protocol-to-build.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Achiel van der Mandele</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/leveraging-an-instant-messaging-protocol-to-build.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Achiel van der Mandele - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;XMPP is an open technology for real-time communication. Although
primarily known for its application in the IM service &amp;quot;Jabber&amp;quot; (and,
subsequently, gchat/gtalk), it has numerous applications and creates new
opportunities for inter-system communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While researching for an alternative to webservices at Mendix, we came
across XMPP and realized it solved many of the shortcomings of
webservices. It is currently being used to handle all inter-system and
inter-process communication in the Mendix cloud hosting environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will give a general overview of what XMPP is, an introduction
to the sleekxmpp python library and how the core features of xmpp can
help an architecture scale well horizontally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required knowledge: basic understanding of hosting environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="cloud"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="real-time"></category><category term="scalable"></category><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Design Patterns</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/python-design-patterns.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alex Martelli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/python-design-patterns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Alex Martelli - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A completely misguided meme has long been going around: that Python
doesn't have, or need, any Design Patterns. This terrible meme may
spring from not realizing what the Gang Of Four state so plainly in
their historical &amp;quot;Design Patterns&amp;quot; book: which design patterns are
useful DOES depend on the programming language one targets - design is
NOT independent of implementation, as the epic-fail &amp;quot;Waterfall&amp;quot;
Methodology Pattern would suggest. What patterns apply to a design,
depends to some extent on what implementation technologies will be used
to realize that design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you focus on some &amp;quot;classic DPs&amp;quot; that are basically workarounds for
some other language's lack of garbage collection, or for a clumsy
static-typing system, those may indeed be worthless for Python. But many
other DPs are perfectly useful and applicable, and Python's strengths as
a language afford riffing on them to develop highly Pythonic, powerful,
productive variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I analyze some of my favorite pattern families - e.g.,
Template Method and its variants, Dependency Injection and its ilk,
Callback and friends - in a highly Pythonic context. Non-pattern Idioms,
and Patterns that aren't really Design Patterns but rather Architecture
or Methodology ones, make cameo appearances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals: remove from your system any residue of the pernicious meme about
Python not having or needing design patterns. Prereqs: experience
designing and developing software; intermediate-level Python knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="architecture"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="patterns"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConAU 2010: Don't Break It: Continuous Integration &amp; Deployment</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--don--39-t-break-it--continuous-inte.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benno Rice</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--don--39-t-break-it--continuous-inte.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't Break It: Continuous Integration &amp;amp; Deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Benno Rice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you've developed your application, it appears to work and you may
even have some tests to back that up. Now what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One part of software development that tends to receive not nearly enough
attention is the process of deploying, supporting and maintaining your
code in production. This demonstration will give an overview of using
tools such as Hudson, nose, stdeb and freshen to automate the testing,
packaging, deployment and verification of production software.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="agile"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="packaging"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau2010"></category><category term="testing"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConAU 2010: GLAMkit: a harder, better, faster, stronger way to write reusable Django code</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--glamkit--a-harder--better--faster--.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Greg Turner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--glamkit--a-harder--better--faster--.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GLAMkit: a harder, better, faster, stronger way to write reusable Django
code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Dr. Greg Turner (the Interaction Consortium)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our web development work for Galleries, Libraries, Archives
and Museums (the so-called GLAM sector), we have open-sourced the common
tools and design patterns that we have developed as a web framework
called GLAMkit (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://glamkit.org/"&gt;http://glamkit.org/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLAMkit is based on Django, and is inspired by its design philosophy of
several apps which implement specific features. However, by looking at
the successes and challenges faced by other CMSes and collections of
apps such as Pinax, we have taken the philosophy a stage futher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than being a collection of Django apps, we have constructed
GLAMkit as a collection of optional and reusable Django 'toolkits' for
implementing common features. We leave the implementation details - the
things that Django already does brilliantly - to the application
developers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will present the history of GLAMkit's development, with
particular focus on how our approach to reusability came about, and some
examples of that approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="advocacy"></category><category term="architecture"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau2010"></category><category term="web"></category></entry></feed>