<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_apidesign.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>API Design: Lessons Learned</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--api-design--lessons-learned.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Raymond Hettinger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--api-design--lessons-learned.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;API lessons learned from a decade of core Python development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share the lessons learned from a decade of core Python development, what
worked and what didn't. Look at the development process and thinking
behind some of Python's successful APIs and ones that leave something to
be desired. Learn general principles for designing a good API for public
consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the story and principles behind the design of Python's &amp;quot;in&amp;quot;
operator, the development of deques, and the evolution of the set API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examine the principles and story behind the development of the named
tuple API. Learn about unforeseen use cases and a bug that made it to
production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the decimal module's API challenge -- adhering to a published
standard. Talk about the Queue module's framework style and how the API
was refactored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss what we've learned about naming functions and methods. Look at
the i-naming convention in itertools, camelcase oddities, the proposed
Italian name for enumerate, and vaguely named methods like
assertItemsEqual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about Guido's ideas on when to add flags to method signatures.
Recap his thoughts on the problems with the percent formatting operator.
Then hear Raymond's advice on packaging, hierarchies, and nested name
spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how to use documentation to mitigate API problems using examples
from regular expressions, decimal, tokenize, sorting.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="api"></category><category term="apidesign"></category><category term="cpython"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>