<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bayesian Non-parametric Models for Data Science using PyMC3</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/bayesian-non-parametric-models-for-data-science-using-pymc3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, there are many ways of building data science models using Python, including statistical and machine learning methods. I will introduce probabilistic models, which use Bayesian statistical methods to quantify all aspects of uncertainty relevant to your problem, and provide inferences in simple, interpretable terms using probabilities.  A particularly flexible form of probabilistic models uses Bayesian &lt;em&gt;non-parametric&lt;/em&gt; methods, which allow models to vary in complexity depending on how much data are available. In doing so, they avoid the over-fitting that is common in machine learning and statistical modeling. I will demonstrate the basics of Bayesian non-parametric modeling in Python, using the PyMC3 package. Specifically, I will introduce two common types, Gaussian processes and Dirichlet processes, and show how they can be applied easily to real-world problems using two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christopher Fonnesbeck</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-13:pycon-us-2018/bayesian-non-parametric-models-for-data-science-using-pymc3.html</guid><category>bayes</category><category>datascience</category><category>pymc3</category></item><item><title>Is that ham in my spam? A novice's inquiry into Naive Bayes</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-jamaica-2016/is-that-ham-in-my-spam-a-novices-inquiry-into-naive-bayes.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supervised learning, machine learning, classifiers, big data! What in the world are all of these things? As a beginning programmer the questions described as “machine learning” questions can be mystifying at best. #pyconjamaica2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will define the scope of a machine learning problem, identifying an email as ham or spam, from the perspective of a beginner (non master of all things “machine learning&amp;quot;) and show how Python can help us simply learn how to classify a piece of email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin we must ask, what is spam? How do I know it “when I see it”? From previous experience of course! We will provide human labeled examples of spam to our model for it to understand the likelihood of spam or ham. This approach, using examples and data we already know to determine the most likely label for a new example, uses the Naive Bayes classifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model will look at the words in the body of an email, finding the frequency of words in both spam and ham emails and the frequency of spam and ham. Once we know the prior likelihood of spam and what makes something spam, we can try applying a label to a new example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this exercise we will see at a basic level what types of questions machine learning asks, learn to model “learning” with Python, and understand how learning can be measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016"&gt;https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016&lt;/a&gt; the PyCon Jamaica 2016 technology conference for Python software developers was held (November 17 - 18, 2016).  The conference was immediately followed by the Great Python Scavenger Hunt &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016/scavenger-race"&gt;https://www.pythonjam.org.jm/conference-2016/scavenger-race&lt;/a&gt;. Our conferences are open to beginners, experts and non-programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lorena Mesa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-18:pycon-jamaica-2016/is-that-ham-in-my-spam-a-novices-inquiry-into-naive-bayes.html</guid><category>bayes</category></item><item><title>The Duct Tape of Heroes: Bayes Rule</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/the-duct-tape-of-heroes-bayes-rule.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will give many examples of when Bayes rule will help you in your day to day work. I'll quickly show many examples of bayesian statistical thinking in action; the pleasure of inference, probabilistic graphs, model selection, feature generation, even operations research! I'll finish with a dataset from Heroes of the Storm and I'll show why Bayesian models can outperform randomforests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is made up of the following examples;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;basic disease example: what is the value of adding an extra test to a patient
give an example of an inference task that is very hard to do properly without bayesian thinking
creating simple probibalistic models with pandas and showing how they are robust against missing data. I will also demo pomegranate, a new probabilistic programming tool for python.
show how you can use bayes rule to pick models
demo a bayesian probablistic approach to finding overpowered characters in the Heroes of the Storm video game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://koaning.io/theme/notebooks/bayes.pdf"&gt;http://koaning.io/theme/notebooks/bayes.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vincent Warmerdam</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/the-duct-tape-of-heroes-bayes-rule.html</guid><category>pomegranate</category><category>bayes</category></item></channel></rss>