<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_hardening.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Through the Side Channel: Timing and Implementation Attacks in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--through-the-side-channel--timing-and-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Geremy Condra</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--through-the-side-channel--timing-and-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the Side Channel: Timing and Implementation Attacks in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Geremy Condra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python's dynamic nature, large standard library, and concern for beauty
over performance make it an elegant and uniquely easy to use language,
but they also cause some unique problems. In this talk we'll explore how
features ranging from dictionaries to duck typing can become security
risks, demonstrate those attacks on real Python projects, and examine
how you can protect yourself and your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, an increasing body of evidence has accumulated
indicating that even when a system is hardened enough to provide strong
guarantees about its high-level behavior, implementation details and
especially performance properties can still provide attackers with an
easy way in. For Python, this is especially problematic: its generally
high-level view and the emphasis placed on flexibility often mean that
it can be difficult to stop attackers from gaining a foothold, while its
comparatively low execution speed increases the efficacy of wide variety
of implementation and timing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help Pythonistas understand and cope with these problems, we've
divided this talk into two parts: in the first, we demonstrate the
attacks against a series of widely-deployed Python projects with the
goal of both improving awareness about the issue and demonstrating
common weaknesses to be avoided. The second demonstrates effective
countermeasures and alternative constructions with the goal of improving
defenders' odds of spotting and correcting these flaws in their own
code.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hacking"></category><category term="hardening"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="security"></category></entry></feed>