<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Practical Experience in Teaching Numerical Methods with IPython Notebooks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/practical-experience-in-teaching-numerical-method.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;New tools like the IPython notebook can enhance both lectures and
textbooks, by making class time and individual study more interactive
through the inclusion of executable code and animations. I will demo
some materials and activities I've provided for students using the
IPython notebook. I will focus on practical issues I've faced that are
particular to this teaching approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional university teaching is based on the use of lectures in class
and textbooks out of class. The medium (lecture or book) discourages the
natural curiosity that can lead to deeper understanding by investigating
the result of changing a parameter, or looking at the full results of a
time-dependent simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IPython notebook provides a single medium in which mathematics,
explanations, executable code, and animated or interactive visualization
can be combined. Notebooks that combine all of these components can
enable new modes of student-led inquiry: the student can experiment with
modifications to the code and see the results, all without stepping away
from the mathematical explanations themselves. When notebooks are used
by students in the classroom, students can quickly share and discuss
results with the instructor or other class members. The instructor can
facilitate deeper learning by posing questions that students may answer
through writing appropriate code, during class time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past four years, I have taught a graduate numerical analysis
course using SAGE worksheets and IPython notebooks. I will show examples
of the notebooks I've developed and successfully used in this course. I
will describe some practical aspects of my experience, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tradeoffs between using IPython and SAGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiences with use of cloud computing platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing with students' installation issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quickly getting students up to speed with the Python language and
packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing and evaluating homework in a math course that is
programming-intensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David I. Ketcheson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/practical-experience-in-teaching-numerical-method.html</guid><category>education</category><category>ipynb</category></item></channel></rss>