<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - GajendraDeshpande</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_gajendradeshpande.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Deceptive Security using Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/deceptive-security-using-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/deceptive-security-using-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are passing through an unknown street at midnight and you find that some anti-social elements are following you. To save yourself from them you start running and look for a safe place to hide yourself. On the way …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gajendra Deshpande&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/GGGTVY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are passing through an unknown street at midnight and you find that some anti-social elements are following you. To save yourself from them you start running and look for a safe place to hide yourself. On the way, you will find a good person and request the person to help you. The person hides you in the secure place to protect you. When these anti-social elements visit a good person’s place and enquire about you, the good person misguides them and redirects them to some other place in order to protect you. This is exactly how deception works. In this analogy, YOU are the resources to be protected, anti-social elements are the hackers who want to gain access to the resources, and a good person is a deception technique that protects the resources from hackers by making them fall in the trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How we implemented deception tool in python using machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;
We designed a deception tool in python language using PyBRAIN package to model and mitigate XPath injection attacks for web services. It is known that XML can be used to store the data and this data can be queried using XPath query language. XPath as a query language, it has injection issues similar to SQL. To handle this issue, we proposed a solution, which uses count-based validation technique and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) modular neural networks to identify and classify atypical behavior in user input. Once the atypical user input is identified, the attacker is redirected to fake resources to protect the critical data. Our experiment resulted in over 90% accuracy in classification of input vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep  4 13:20:00 2020 at Python 2&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2020"></category><category term="GajendraDeshpande"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConAU"></category><category term="PyConline"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Time Series Forecasting Techniques in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/time-series-forecasting-techniques-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gajendra Deshpande</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/time-series-forecasting-techniques-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Gajendra Deshpande) Time series is one of the important as well as lesser-known fields of machine learning. In time series forecasting we analyze the time-dependent data for predicting long-term and seasonality trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Gajendra Deshpande) Time series is one of the important as well as lesser-known fields of machine learning. In time series forecasting we analyze the time-dependent data for predicting long-term and seasonality trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/QMZKMZ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 14:15:00 2021 at Science, Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="GajendraDeshpande"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry></feed>