<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - ReneeNoble</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_reneenoble.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Outbreak Outreach - How COVID broke our program for the better</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/outbreak-outreach-how-covid-broke-our-program-for-the-better.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Renee Noble</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/outbreak-outreach-how-covid-broke-our-program-for-the-better.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Renee Noble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/J9P8FY"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/J9P8FY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Girls’ Programming Network has a well tested-formula for creating communities of girls and women centred around a passion for coding. But when pandemic strikes, is maintaining communities based around connecting with hundreds of like-minded people even possible? Is it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Renee Noble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/J9P8FY"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/J9P8FY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Girls’ Programming Network has a well tested-formula for creating communities of girls and women centred around a passion for coding. But when pandemic strikes, is maintaining communities based around connecting with hundreds of like-minded people even possible? Is it even possible to run an online event that upholds our values? And will kids even want to sign up for more hours of online learning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll take you through how we devised a plan to keep the GPN spirit alive online, with a dynamic schedule of learning, socialising and fun! I’ll show you the tech that made it all possible, tell you the lessons we learnt along the way, and let you in on some of the things we’ll be keeping in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep  4 09:15:00 2020 at Floperator&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2020"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConAU"></category><category term="PyConline"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="ReneeNoble"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2020"></category></entry><entry><title>Get Kookin’ With Kookaberry</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2021/get-kookin-with-kookaberry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Renee Noble</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2021-09-11:/pycon-au-2021/get-kookin-with-kookaberry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Renee Noble) I’ve been a big fan of the BBC micro:bit for years now, but then I heard there was a &lt;em&gt;new Aussie kid&lt;/em&gt; on the &lt;em&gt;embedded systems block&lt;/em&gt;, the “Kookaberry”. I was interested to hear more but skeptical that it could lure me away from the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Renee Noble) I’ve been a big fan of the BBC micro:bit for years now, but then I heard there was a &lt;em&gt;new Aussie kid&lt;/em&gt; on the &lt;em&gt;embedded systems block&lt;/em&gt;, the “Kookaberry”. I was interested to hear more but skeptical that it could lure me away from the micro:bit lifestyle where I’d invested my time learning and developing content. But here I am, 6 months into my Kookaberry journey, and I’m a total convert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll take you through my journey of discovery and show you how Kookaberry gives you an easier entry point to MicroPython and embedded systems for beginners, more extendable, realistic, and relatable project experiences for your existing programmers (without having to get the breadboards out!), and how you can utilise Kookaberry in a huge range of cross-curricular applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/NXYTWM/"&gt;https://2021.pycon.org.au/program/NXYTWM/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python, pycon, australia, programming, conference, technical, pyconline, developers, panel, sessions, libraries, frameworks, community, sysadmins, students, education, data, science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos licensed as CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU is the national conference for the Python programming community, bringing together professional, student and enthusiast developers, sysadmins and operations folk, students, educators, scientists, statisticians, and many others besides, all with a love for working with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon AU informs the country’s Python developers with presentations, tutorials and panel sessions by experts and core developers of Python, as well as the libraries and frameworks that they rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by Next Day Video Australia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nextdayvideo.com.au"&gt;https://nextdayvideo.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep 10 09:30:00 2021 at Education&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2021"></category><category term="ReneeNoble"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2021"></category></entry></feed>