<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Brian Thorne - Computer Vision</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2009/brian-thorne---computer-vision.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Thorne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An introduction to computer vision in Python, from the general concept
to its implementation with some current open-source libraries (opencv,
scipy, pygame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of my presentation is an introduction to computer vision
(CV) and image processing in Python. I will aim to show what is possible
with current libraries, demonstrate their usability, explore their
limitations, and cover elements of best coding practice. Firstly, I will
briefly present the basics, such as video grabbing, image processing and
computer vision algorithms. I will illustrate my presentation with the
Python bindings to the opencv library and show different examples such
as displaying a video image, some filtering algorithms (dilation,
gaussian blur), and how to implement facial recognition. I will describe
after how related tasks can be achieved with other Python tools such as
scipy and pygame. I will show how these three libraries can be used in
conjunction to perform video capturing, image processing and user
interfacing. Finally, I will introduce my basic Python computer vision
framework, which is aimed at inexperienced users, and demonstrate it on
the XO laptop, the inexpensive low-powered sub-notebook distributed as
part of the One Laptop Per Child (OLPC) initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Sound and video are poor. Slides are hard to read.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Thorne</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-11-07:kiwi-pycon-2009/brian-thorne---computer-vision.html</guid><category>kiwipycon</category><category>kiwipycon2009</category><category>olpc</category><category>pygame</category><category>scipy</category><category>vision</category></item></channel></rss>