<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_social.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Celery and Social Networks. 5 Things I Have Learned During Earthquake Hackathon.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/celery-and-social-networks-5-things-i-have-learned-during-earthquake-hackathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Mleczko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-02:europython-2013/celery-and-social-networks-5-things-i-have-learned-during-earthquake-hackathon.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="celery"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="open-source"></category><category term="case-study"></category><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>Artistic Python: Mixing Python Programming with Fashion</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/artistic-python-mixing-python-programming-with-fashion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ria Baldevia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/artistic-python-mixing-python-programming-with-fashion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are numerous ways to learn and introduce the world of programming
to new coders. One way is to embrace the world of art. Python offers an
ecosystem that can take any curious programmer to merge the world of art
and technology. Artistic Python: Mixing Programming with Fashion aims to
show how Python, some hardware, and numerous libraries can inspire
anyone to incorporate coding into their artistic endeavors and vice
versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one thinks of fashion, several things come to mind: fabric, sewing,
and fashion shows. Rarely does one think about leveraging programming
and available hardware as components in creating a final product.
Artistic Python will present the ideation, design, coding, and creation
process of an outfit that incorporated Python programming, lighting, and
small programmable computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="fashion"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="multimedia"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="Math"></category></entry><entry><title>Growing a Python community</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anton Caceres</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/growing-a-python-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about people, not tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share one recipe of building a community from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reveals hands-on experience about the organisational journey,
including insider details and financial questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is packed into the story, how one year ago a tempting
idea of making a little Python conference in Munich was born. Six month
later, with poor German skills, no business network and mostly foreign
crew a little idea was converted into PyCon.DE. This conference had a
noticeable Italian flavour, and it’s time to tell why.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="humor"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="beer"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Africa</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Makarudze</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/python-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What is Python?” is a common phrase in Africa, especially when you try
to advertise Python events. This is because Python is a relatively new
programming language in most parts of Africa. In most countries where
global companies like Google, Amazon and Oracle are absent, Python is
rarely used as a programming language in businesses. Despite this, a
number of Python enthusiasts from different parts of the globe have been
working so hard to promote the use of Python in Africa by setting up a
vibrant community on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I will share on the various Python initiatives taking place
in some parts of the African continent and how they have advanced the
use of Python in Africa. I will also present the challenges faced by
developers in Africa in building their Python community. My talk will
also present the milestones that have been achieved so far in trying to
advance the use of Python in Africa. I will also share on the
opportunities that Africa presents in terms of making an impact within
the Python community. I will conclude my talk by highlighting ways in
which we can all make a difference in advancing the use and knowledge of
Python in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="startup"></category><category term="beginner"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="women"></category><category term="teamwork"></category><category term="OpenSource"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="pyladies"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="Learning environment"></category><category term="user-groups"></category></entry></feed>