<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Backup Is Hard; Let's Go Shopping</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--backup-is-hard--let--39-s-go-shopping.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Backup Is Hard; Let's Go Shopping&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Gary Bernhardt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll fly through the most clever bits of BitBacker, an online backup
app developed as a startup for three years and eventually abandoned.
Highlights: a hacked-up httplib/asyncore HTTP client; a real-life,
HATEOAS-respecting RESTful API, and an encryption scheme that can
quickly diff a file system against the server while leaking no
information – not even file timestamps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story of a solution to a huge problem: fast, secure online
backup. A single client generates a hundred gigabytes, millions of data
chunks, and thousands of file system snapshots. To appreciate the
problem's scale, consider that a Python array holding content hashes for
1,000,000 files consumes 100 MB of memory. File hashes are only a
portion of the required per- file metadata, and that's only one for
snapshot of thousands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll tour the hard parts of this system with no apology for their
difficulty. The httplib/asyncore hybrid monster that served millions of
parallel requests, transparently retrying on failures and timeouts, with
only 300 lines of python. The RESTful API – fully respecting hypertext,
with every request safely repeatable, even POSTs, and not a single
hard-coded URL in the client. The encryption scheme that leaked nothing
– not even modification times – but could quickly diff local file
systems against the server. And, that one time that a client
accidentally requested a 4.76 megabyte URL in production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gary Bernhardt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--backup-is-hard--let--39-s-go-shopping.html</guid><category>backup</category><category>bigdata</category><category>bitbacker</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item></channel></rss>