<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org - LorenzoPeña</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_lorenzopena.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Of Django, PostgreSQL schemas, and your multi-million dollar idea</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/of-django-postgresql-schemas-and-your-multi-million-dollar-idea.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lorenzo Peña</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/of-django-postgresql-schemas-and-your-multi-million-dollar-idea.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lorenzo Peña&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/CRSJXF"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/CRSJXF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although rough for the world, 2020 is proving a good year (and decade start) for Django. Boring batteries-included frameworks and established monolith makers are shining again, in a world where the hype-enchantment of JavaScript and micro-everything is starting to wear …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lorenzo Peña&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/CRSJXF"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/CRSJXF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although rough for the world, 2020 is proving a good year (and decade start) for Django. Boring batteries-included frameworks and established monolith makers are shining again, in a world where the hype-enchantment of JavaScript and micro-everything is starting to wear off and fall into a more mature position of tradeoffs. After 15 years of life, Django continues to prove solid, battle tested, and very capable of major undertakings in the web arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, the competence of the framework has extended to the SaaS world, through a number of packages that have emerged as viable options for making Django multi-tenant. PostgreSQL concept of _schemas_ has opened a new exploration space for multi-tenancy, by combining the power of RDBMS native isolation with the reduced costs of managing a single database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, nothing comes for free. The ease of using PostgreSQL schemas for multi-tenancy in Django comes at the expense of some challenges that must be overcome in the short, medium, and long term, if the project seeks to survive while gracefully escaling to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will cover the major challenges of doing multi-tenancy in Django through PostgreSQL schemas. You will learn the pros and cons of the approach as you move from tutorial-grade projects to massive multi-tenant behemoths. By the end, you will be able to answer whether or not this is going to be a feasible approach for your next multi-million dollar idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep  4 17:45:00 2020 at Python 2&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="PyCon AU 2020"></category><category term="LorenzoPeña"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="PyConAU"></category><category term="PyConline"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau_2020"></category></entry></feed>