<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_systems-programming.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python Packaging on the Enterprise</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2013/python-packaging-on-the-enterprise.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Easton</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-05:europython-2013/python-packaging-on-the-enterprise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to discuss problems and solutions when implementing an
end-to- end Python environment for a big company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term ‘Enterprise’ often has negative connotations in much of the
open- source world, usually along the lines of ‘expensive and bloated’.
In this case I’d like to use it for describing a systems environment
where the freedoms of a developer working at home with her laptop are
not always available or practical. For example, coding on the holodeck
of the Starship Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big teams and codebases need tools that make it very easy for new
developers to get up and running writing code with the minimum of fuss.
Large software platforms needs tools to manage complex package
dependency graphs and release workflows. Also, production environments
don’t always have compilers or direct internet access so many of
Python’s standard packaging tools make it a bit tricky to get things
going in these regards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to present how we managed to solve a number of these problems
for a recent client, a task which happily culminated in much of the
software being open-sourced at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/eeaston/pkglib"&gt;https://github.com/eeaston/pkglib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: The software also has numerous testing tools included which I’ll
demonstrate, including py.test fixtures for mongo, redis, pyramid and
generic servers, selenium webdriver and C/C++ code coverage and
profiling.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="packaging"></category><category term="jenkins"></category><category term="continuous-integration"></category><category term="systems-programming"></category><category term="sysadmin"></category></entry></feed>