<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ALGES: Geostatistics and Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/alges-geostatistics-and-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ALGES is a laboratory that develops tools applied to geostatistics.
We've been using python for a while and it has brought us very good
results. Its ease-of- use and portability allow us to rapidly offer
practical solutions to problems. Along with a brief introduction to the
laboratory, we cover two particular projects we are currently working
on. One project is an application for multivariate geostatistic
analysis. Most available applications provide analysis for a single
variable at a time and either obviate how variables can relate between
one another or make it really difficult to consider any relationship.
Our proposal provides both an interface that's both easy to use for
primers and fine tuning for experienced users. The other presented
project covers a problem in geological modeling and resource estimation.
Commonly, when modeling geological volumes, continuity in data is
assumed. This is not often true, as there are different kinds of faults
that break this continuity. This is very hard to incorporate when
modeling. We propose a solution to restore the original continuous
volume for better modeling as well as restitution to the real distorted
volume, all this providing a better estimation. Both projects have lots
of heavy computations and no shortage of input data. We take this as a
challenge to build fast processing solutions, so we take advantage of
both the easiness of a python interface and the speed of C/C++ code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Felipe Lema</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/alges-geostatistics-and-python.html</guid><category>Geophysics Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Building a Solver Based on PyClaw for the Solution of the Multi-Layer Shallow Water Equations</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/building-a-solver-based-on-pyclaw-for-the-solutio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The multi-layer shallow water equations are an active topic for
researchers in geophysical fluid dynamics looking for ways to increase
the validity of shallow water modeling techniques without using a fully
three dimensional model which may be too costly for the domain size
being looked at. In this talk we will step through the effort needed to
convert a Fortran based solver to one using the PyClaw framework, a
Python framework targeted at the solution of hyperbolic conservation
laws. Once the application is converted the ease of implementing
parallel and other solver strategies is greatly simplified. Discussion
of how this is accomplished and design decisions and future extensions
to PyClaw will also be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kyle Mandli</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/building-a-solver-based-on-pyclaw-for-the-solutio.html</guid><category>Geophysics Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Domain Specific Languages for Partial Differential Equations using Ignition</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/domain-specific-languages-for-partial-differentia.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As scientific computing pushes towards extreme scales, the programming
wall is becoming more apparent. For algorithms to scale on new
architectures, they often must be rewritten accounting for completely
different performance characteristics. A handful of the communities
fastest codes have already turned to automatic code generation to tackle
these issues. Code generation gives a user the ability to use the
expressiveness of a domain specific language and promises for better
portability as architectures rapidly change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, I will show Ignition, a project for creating
numerical code generators. Python and SymPy make exceptional languages
for developing these code generators in a way that domain experts can
understand and manipulate. I show examples how Ignition can generate
several different parts of geophysical simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andy Terrel</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/domain-specific-languages-for-partial-differentia.html</guid><category>Geophysics Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Parallel Computational Methods and Simulation for Coastal and Hydraulic Applications Using the Proteus Toolkit</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/parallel-computational-methods-and-simulation-for.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Kees</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/parallel-computational-methods-and-simulation-for.html</guid><category>Geophysics Mini-Symposia</category></item></channel></rss>