<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_apis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Using Python, Django, and ruthlessness to protect people from social media harassment.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2019/using-python-django-and-ruthlessness-to-protect-people-from-social-media-harassment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Eastman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-08-24:kiwi-pycon-2019/using-python-django-and-ruthlessness-to-protect-people-from-social-media-harassment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I present 'secateur', a tool for Twitter users to protect themselves from some forms of online harassment. I discuss using Python and Django to create tools that integrate with Twitter, use its APIs, and block lots of people (LOTS of people).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="twitter"></category><category term="APIs"></category><category term="secateur"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine Learning by Example</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2019/machine-learning-by-example.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriela D'Ávila Ferrara</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-04-13:pytexas-2019/machine-learning-by-example.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine you could easily use ML without having a PhD or having to mess with models or interacting with TensorFlow? Imagine ML working for your application, not you working for ML. In this session learn how to use ML APIs through demos to power your application and focus on what matters!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="APIs"></category></entry><entry><title>Don't start with a database</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/dont-start-with-a-database.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Grzegorz Kocjan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/dont-start-with-a-database.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What you do when you start a new project? Usually, we begin with
database design, then we prepare a migration system, user registration,
and all different stuff that distracts us from doing what is most
important - business logic. With the clean architecture, we can learn
how to start a project in another way and this will be one of two main
topics of my talk. The second one will be about new features in Python.
You probably heard about typings, mypy, and dataclasses, but I will show
you how they can be used in real life project that can be developed over
many years in production lifecycle. There will be no &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; app,
no copy &amp;amp; paste of documentation, only practical knowledge learned
through many years of practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="APIs"></category><category term="Abstractions"></category><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Clean Code"></category></entry><entry><title>How we run GraphQL APIs in production on our Kubernetes cluster</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/how-we-run-graphql-apis-in-production-on-our-kubernetes-cluster.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexys Jacob</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/how-we-run-graphql-apis-in-production-on-our-kubernetes-cluster.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I would like to share the workflow and tools we use to
build, deploy and operate GraphQL APIs on our on-premise Kubernetes
cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share code and command examples explaining how we are operating
our applications since our recent transition from REST APIs on Web
servers to GraphQL APIs containers on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will not be about the difference between REST and GraphQL but
focus on the workflow, tools and experience we gained in switching our
run time environments and API models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Numberly, we have built and are operating our own on-premise
Kubernetes cluster so we will also be talking about its capabilities and
share some of the experience we gained in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Proposed agenda:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Our previous workflow and its limitations&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- How we designed our Kubernetes cluster, its capabilities and the
choices we made&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Developer workflow, environments management and deployment&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- Our GraphQL stack, featuring a sample application&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- What we're still working on to improve&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="APIs"></category><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Case Study"></category><category term="Docker"></category><category term="Infrastructure"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploy Python to the cloud faster with Azure Serverless</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/deploy-python-to-the-cloud-faster-with-azure-serverless.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Hollan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/deploy-python-to-the-cloud-faster-with-azure-serverless.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bringing your Python scripts or apps and running them in the cloud is
easier than ever with serverless computing. In this talk, we’ll show how
you can use Azure Functions to easily deploy and scale your Python
workloads without having to manage any servers or pay for unused compute
resources. We’ll also show how deep integration with Visual Studio Code
offers a great local development experience with full support for
debugging and testing your app, and allows you to seamlessly deploy your
serverless code to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by giving a brief overview of the value of serverless
computing. Next, we'll create a brand new Python app in Visual Studio
Code, and start to add in business logic and ML capabilities. Once we
get the app running debugged locally, we’ll publish it to the cloud as a
serverless function, and demonstrate the serverless scalability.
Finally, we’ll walk you through the tools and capabilities you can
leverage around monitoring and management of your Python Azure
Functions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="APIs"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Microservices"></category><category term="Scaling"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry><entry><title>Django APIs, Versioning and You</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2018/django-apis-versioning-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rebecca Martin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-11-10:pycon-ireland-2018/django-apis-versioning-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will attempt to explain how to version an API within the Django framework. Say you need to change the data that your API returns to your users, but any major changes would result in breaking the API for users of any previous versions. This talk will explain how to avoid this problem, which as a developer who works on APIs with the Django framework every day is a constant problem that I would have to face. This talk will cover: 1.) Why do I even have to version my API in the first place? Surely I can just make changes? 2.) Okay, now I understand why to version my API in Django. What about the how? (this will mainly focus on the Django REST framework's library of versioning, but other methods will be considered) 3.) Live Demo of breaking changes (oh no!) and how we can apply our knowledge from the second part of the talk and avoid these.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="APIs"></category></entry><entry><title>Desenvolvendo APIs REST com Python 3 e Asyncio</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/caipyra-2016/desenvolvendo-apis-rest-com-python-3-e-asyncio.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Renato Garcia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-26:caipyra-2016/desenvolvendo-apis-rest-com-python-3-e-asyncio.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra do Renato Garcia no Caipyra 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desenvolvendo APIs REST com Python 3 e Asyncio&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="api"></category><category term="apis"></category><category term="rest"></category><category term="rest api"></category><category term="asyncio"></category><category term="async"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConAU 2010: Building the Wave Robots API: Behind the Scenes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--building-the-wave-robots-api--behin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Pamela S Fox</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-06-26:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--building-the-wave-robots-api--behin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building the Wave Robots API: Behind the Scenes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Pamela S Fox (Google)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Wave robots protocol involves JSON-RPC messages that are sent
between the Wave server and the robot, communicating events to process
and operations to perform. The Python Robots API abstracts on top of
that JSON-RPC service, allowing developers to interact with waves using
event callbacks, python classes, and chained functions. In this talk,
we'll explain the JSON- RPC protocol, talk about how we designed the API
to sit on top of that protocol, and show how developers can use the API.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="apis"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="jsonrpc"></category><category term="pyconau"></category><category term="pyconau2010"></category><category term="web"></category></entry></feed>