<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_scaling.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building Data Workflows with Luigi and Kubernetes</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/building-data-workflows-with-luigi-and-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nar Kumar Chhantyal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/building-data-workflows-with-luigi-and-kubernetes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus on how one can build complex data pipelines in
Python. I will introduce Luigi and show how it solves problems while
running multiple chain of batch jobs like dependency resolution,
workflow management, visualisation, failure handling etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I will present how to package Luigi pipelines as Docker
image for easier testing and deployment. Finally, I will go through way
to deploy them on Kubernetes cluster, thus making it possible to scale
Big Data pipelines on- demand and reduce infrastructure costs. I will
also give tips and tricks to make Luigi Scheduler play well with
Kubernetes batch execution feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will be accompanied by demo project. It will be very
beneficial for audience who have some experience in running batch jobs
(not necessarily in Python), typically people who work in Big Data
sphere like data scientists, data engineers, BI devs and software
developers. Familiarity with Python is helpful but not needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Architecture"></category><category term="Big Data"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Distributed Systems"></category><category term="Scaling"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploy Python to the cloud faster with Azure Serverless</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/deploy-python-to-the-cloud-faster-with-azure-serverless.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Hollan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/deploy-python-to-the-cloud-faster-with-azure-serverless.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bringing your Python scripts or apps and running them in the cloud is
easier than ever with serverless computing. In this talk, we’ll show how
you can use Azure Functions to easily deploy and scale your Python
workloads without having to manage any servers or pay for unused compute
resources. We’ll also show how deep integration with Visual Studio Code
offers a great local development experience with full support for
debugging and testing your app, and allows you to seamlessly deploy your
serverless code to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by giving a brief overview of the value of serverless
computing. Next, we'll create a brand new Python app in Visual Studio
Code, and start to add in business logic and ML capabilities. Once we
get the app running debugged locally, we’ll publish it to the cloud as a
serverless function, and demonstrate the serverless scalability.
Finally, we’ll walk you through the tools and capabilities you can
leverage around monitoring and management of your Python Azure
Functions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="APIs"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="Microservices"></category><category term="Scaling"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry><entry><title>Is it me, or the GIL?</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/is-it-me-or-the-gil.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christoph Heer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/is-it-me-or-the-gil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python's Global Interpreter Lock is a friend and rival at the same time.
We, as developers, can focus on the design and implementation of
applications without the hassle of memory management. On the other side,
we complain about the GIL as the limiting factor of performance
sensitive applications. Therefore, it is common to refactor parts of
systems when the system doesn't perform or scale enough anymore. The
refactoring often includes the switch of the used concurrency paradigms
like replacing multithreading with multiprocessing or asyncio. Another
option is moving logic of CPU-bound workload into C extensions or a full
rewrite in a &amp;quot;GIL-free&amp;quot; language. But how do you know that the GIL is
the actual performance bottleneck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While scaling and developing performance sensitive components in Python,
my colleagues and I often also assumed the GIL as cause of our
performance problems because it is a common and simple answer for this
usually complex and varied problems. Instead of starting a rewrite or
major refactoring, we took a step back and tried to prove our
assumption. With the result that analyzing the impact of the GIL
contention on the overall performance is a very interesting problem
without common practices or easy usable set of tools that support Python
developers. Within this talk, I will share and explain the methods and
tools, which we use to analyze the relevance of the GIL on our
application performance and how it helped us to stay focused on the
actual problematic areas of our applications that required improvements
to meet our performance goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ASYNC / Concurrency"></category><category term="Multi-Threading"></category><category term="Performance"></category><category term="Scaling"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling up to Big Data Devops for Data Science</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/scaling-up-to-big-data-devops-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marck Vaisman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/scaling-up-to-big-data-devops-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaling up R/Python from a single machine to a cluster environment can be tricky. While there are many tools available that make the launching of a cluster relatively easy, they are not focused or optimized to the specific use case of analytics but mostly on operations. Come and learn about devops tips and tricks to optimize your transition into the big data world as a data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="big data"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="data science"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="scaling"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling Django Web Applications</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2009/djangocon-2009--scaling-django-web-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Malone</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2009-09-10:djangocon-us-2009/djangocon-2009--scaling-django-web-applications.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2009"></category><category term="scaling"></category></entry><entry><title>Alice in Performanceland -- Down the Rabbit Hole with Frank Wiles</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--alice-in-performanceland----down-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Frank Wiles</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-09:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--alice-in-performanceland----down-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While pre-optimization is often the root of all evil, knowing how to
think about performance and scalability are important skills for any
geek. Learn about all the knobs you didn't know you could or should
tweak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code profiling and dealing with your database aren't the only places to
find performance gains. Performance and scalability are holistic
endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2010"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="scaling"></category></entry><entry><title>Best Practices for Python in the Cloud</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/best-practices-for-python-in-the-cloud.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gisle Aas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/best-practices-for-python-in-the-cloud.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Gisle Aas - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Whether you’re an independent developer or development manager
in a large company, “the cloud” is on everyone’s mind. But just because
it’s in the cloud, doesn’t mean development and deployment is
effortless. The cloud presents infrastructure and development challenges
in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, ActiveState's Gisle Aas will share best practices
in building and deploying a Python-centric LAMP stack(s) on the cloud
for a range of web-based applications from simple Django site to HPC GPU
Clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on ActiveState’s experiences, Gisle will discuss the challenges
faced and lessons learned in building an infrastructure to deploy web
applications to the cloud with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will learn about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which packages are critical for a secure, Python-centric LAMP stack
(and what it takes to build them)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips for developing, deploying, and scaling Python applicaitons in
the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use Python to connect and build infrastructure to support and
manage your deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="cloud"></category><category term="deploy"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="gpu"></category><category term="hpc"></category><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="lamp"></category><category term="packages"></category><category term="scaling"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Actors: What, Why, and How (#161)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--actors--what--why--and-how---161.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Donovan Preston</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--actors--what--why--and-how---161.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actors: What, Why and How&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Donovan Preston&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of concurrency research, there have been two camps:
shared everything, and shared nothing. Most modern applications use
threads for concurrency, a shared everything architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actors, however, use a shared nothing architecture where lightweight
processes communicate with each other using message passing. Actors can
change their state, create a new Actor, send a message to any Actor it
has the Address of, and wait for a specific kind of message to arrive in
it's mailbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss the benefits of using the Actor architecture and
strategies for implementing an Actor system in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bitbucket.org/fzzzy/python-%20actors/"&gt;http://bitbucket.org/fzzzy/python-actors/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="concurrency"></category><category term="eventlet"></category><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="rest"></category><category term="scaling"></category><category term="wsgi"></category></entry><entry><title>Designing to Scale: The Story of ShootQ (#5)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--designing-to-scale--the-story-of-shoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--designing-to-scale--the-story-of-shoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing to Scale: The story of ShootQ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan LaCour (ShootQ)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ShootQ is a web-based studio management solution for professional
photography studios, designed to automate and simplify the task of
running a small business. In this talk, Jonathan LaCour, the CTO of
ShootQ, hopes to share his experience designing a web application that
can scale up to meet the demands of a rapidly growing customer base. The
talk will cover a variety of topics including TurboGears 2.0, WSGI,
horizontal and vertical scaling, database replication, load balancing,
deployment, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deployment"></category><category term="loadbalancing"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="replication"></category><category term="scaling"></category><category term="turbogears"></category><category term="wsgi"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling your Python application on EC2 (#191)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--scaling-your-python-application-on-ec.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeremy Edberg</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--scaling-your-python-application-on-ec.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scaling Your Python Application on EC2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jeremy Edberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come hear about the trials and tribulations of moving reddit's Python
application from physical hardware to EC2's cloud infrastructure, and
how they have scaled since moving. Will include general discussion of
their learnings about scaling as well cloud specific issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: Missing audio first few seconds]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="reddit"></category><category term="scaling"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>What every developer should know about database scalability (#21)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--what-every-developer-should-know-abou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jonathan Ellis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--what-every-developer-should-know-abou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What every developer should know about database scalability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jonathan Ellis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caching, replication, partitioning, and distributed databases: how these
can (and can't!) help you scale your data.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="caching"></category><category term="distributeddatabases"></category><category term="partitioning"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="replication"></category><category term="scaling"></category></entry></feed>