<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Serious Business: Python is not just for Engineering</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--serious-business--python-is-not-just-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serious Business: Python is not just for Engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Zach Steindler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a great business is quite different from building a great
product, but by measuring Key Performance Indicators (things like cash
flow, if users keep coming back, etc.) you can make sure your business
is on the right track. In this talk I'll cover common KPI in the tech
business and show you how we automate collecting and presenting KPI at
Olark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a hacker-turned-founder, you quickly realize there's more to building
a great business than just building a great product. The easiest way to
know your business is on the right track is to measure Key Performance
Indicators (KPIs): things like cash flow, what parts of the product is
used the most, if your users keep coming back, if users are experiencing
problems... and many, many others. How are you supposed to keep track of
it all without getting lost in a sea of noise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Python, of course! In this talk I'll cover the most common KPIs
technology businesses track and show you how we used Python at Olark to
automatically collect and present KPIs to the team. This has made it
much easier to quickly answer business questions and help us know we're
on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're a Python hacker who would like to learn more about how to
engineer a business, or if you're a business person who's just starting
to learn Python, come learn how Python isn't just for engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Zach Steindler</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--serious-business--python-is-not-just-.html</guid><category>business</category><category>kpi</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item></channel></rss>