<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - LizzieSilver</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Panel Discussion: Ethical AI - From talk to practice</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2020/panel-discussion-ethical-ai-from-talk-to-practice.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nigel Dalton, Fiona Milne, Arna Karick, Lizzie Silver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/FNTEDL"&gt;https://2020.pycon.org.au/program/FNTEDL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the fabric of civic infrastructure becomes increasingly digitised and data-driven, and our lives are nudged in the direction of what is presented as optimal many times a day, there is an increasing awareness of the importance of ethical AI. Issues that have been called out in particular are: data privacy, the harm that algorithmic bias can have, and the negative repercussions of unchecked recommendation systems blindly maximising engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That ethical AI has become part of the discourse of data and AI is a positive sign, but how do we move from just talk? Who is responsible? What can you do about these issues?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this moderated panel, we'll hear from three experienced data science practitioners on how these issues play out in their professional lives, as well as their perspectives on how we can actively work towards more ethical AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this discussion will provide a valuable backdrop upon which to reflect throughout the rest of the day as we cover a range of exciting topics in science, data, and analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by NDV: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1"&gt;https://youtube.com/channel/UCQ7dFBzZGlBvtU2hCecsBBg?sub_confirmation=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python, PyCon, PyConAU, PyConline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fri Sep  4 09:15:00 2020 at Curlyboi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">From talk to practice</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-09-05:/pycon-au-2020/panel-discussion-ethical-ai-from-talk-to-practice.html</guid><category>PyCon AU 2020</category><category>ArnaKarick</category><category>FionaMilne</category><category>LizzieSilver</category><category>NigelDalton</category><category>PyCon</category><category>PyConAU</category><category>PyConline</category><category>Python</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau_2020</category></item></channel></rss>