<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_domainspecificframeworks.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2010-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Domain Specific Frameworks - Why they rock and what can we do to get more of them</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--domain-specific-frameworks---why-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sean O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-08:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--domain-specific-frameworks---why-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of some of the existing domain
specific frameworks (DSFs) in the Python/Django world, review some of
the common patterns used within them, and then explore some things which
can be done to make it easier for people to create and maintain DSFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a growing collection of tools such as Celery, ImageKit, and
Piston which fall into a weird but wonderful space between utility
libraries and full fledged applications. Much like Django, DSFs (domain
specific frameworks) provide more structure and have more opinion than
utility libraries, but remain focused on providing developer instead of
end-user level functionality. Unlike Django, DSFs focus on solving a
very specific set of specific problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of some of the existing DSFs in the
Python/Django world, review some of the common patterns used within
them, and then explore some things which can be done to make it easier
for people to create and maintain DSFs. Two of the DSFs to be discussed
include Celery and ImageKit. Some of the patterns to be reviewed include
registration, backends, and framework integration/independence. Finally,
the future facing discussion will explore possible tools to make DSF
building easier and steps general purpose frameworks (Django) can take
to ease integration.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2010"></category><category term="domainspecificframeworks"></category><category term="dsf"></category></entry></feed>