<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Practical decorators</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/practical-decorators.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decorators are one of Python's most powerful features. But even if you
understand what they do, it's not always obvious what you can do with
them. Sure, from a practical perspective, they let you remove repeated
code from your callables. And semantically, they let you think at a
higher level of abstraction, applying the same treatment to functions
and classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can you actually do with them? For many Python developers I've
encountered, decorators sometimes appear to be a solution looking for a
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show you some practical uses for decorators, and how
you can use them to make your code more readable and maintainable, while
also providing more semantic power. Moreover, you'll see examples of
things would be hard to do without decorators. I hope that after this
talk, you'll have a good sense of how to use decorators in your own
Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Reuven Lerner</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/practical-decorators.html</guid><category>Compiler and Interpreters</category><category>Data Structures</category><category>Programming</category><category>Python Skills</category><category>Python general</category></item><item><title>Dissecting tf.function to discover AutoGraph strengths and subtleties</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/dissecting-tffunction-to-discover-autograph-strengths-and-subtleties.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AutoGraph is one of the most exciting new features of Tensorflow 2.0: it
allows transforming a subset of Python syntax into its portable, high-
performance and language agnostic graph representation bridging the gap
between Tensorflow 1.x and the 2.0 release based on eager execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using AutoGraph with the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;#64;tf.fuction&lt;/tt&gt; decorator seems easy, but in
practice, writing efficient and correctly graph-convertible code
requires to know in detail how AutoGraph and tf.function work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, knowing how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- A graph is created and when it is re-used;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- To deal with functions that create a state;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;- To correctly use the Tensorflow &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;tf.Tensor&lt;/tt&gt; object instead of
using the Python native types to speed-up the computation;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;defines the minimum skill-set required to write correct
graph-accelerable code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will guide you trough AutoGraph and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;tf.function&lt;/tt&gt;
highlighting all the peculiarities that are worth knowing to build the
right skill-set.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paolo Galeone</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/dissecting-tffunction-to-discover-autograph-strengths-and-subtleties.html</guid><category>Data-Structures</category><category>Machine-Learning</category><category>New Features</category><category>Software Design</category></item><item><title>Uno sguardo alle Dataclasses: quando una namedtuple non basta</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/uno-sguardo-alle-dataclasses-quando-una-namedtuple-non-basta.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hanno fatto la loro prima apparizione in Python 3.7, sono la moda del
momento. Sto parlando delle DataClasses, definite nella PEP557 come
“mutable namedtuples with defaults”. Inizieremo facendo un ripasso
veloce sulla bellezza, ma anche sui limiti, delle namedtuple,
continuando poi con un tour alla scoperta di questo nuovo strumento
regalatoci da Eric V. Smith (Python Core Developer) e di come può
esserci d’aiuto nello scrivere nuove classi con minimo sforzo. Oltre
alla definizione come Standard Library suggerisce, verranno proposti
degli esempi di codice per far capire in maniera semplice ai
programmatori che si avvicinano per la prima volta a questo modulo le
caratteristiche, le differenze rispetto ad altri strumenti, e i vantaggi
nell’usare le dataclasses nei loro programmi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1534"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1534&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 12:30 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Cucci</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/uno-sguardo-alle-dataclasses-quando-una-namedtuple-non-basta.html</guid><category>data-structures</category><category>object-oriented-programming</category><category>Python</category><category>python3</category></item><item><title>You don't need n dimensions when you have pandas</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2019/you-dont-need-n-dimensions-when-you-have-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pietrobattiston.it/wiki/python:pycon#talk_you_don_t_need_n_dimensions_when_you_have_pandas"&gt;Click here for slides and material
used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a (very) quick general introduction to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt;, and in
particular to pandas &lt;strong&gt;indexes&lt;/strong&gt; , this talk will focus on particular
types of indexes, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;MultiIndex&lt;/tt&gt;es, and on the many &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt;
features allowing us to use them to store and analyze multidimensional
data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discover together &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pandas&lt;/tt&gt; does not have (any more) data
structures with more than 2 dimensions, and why we should not regret
them. We will then look at further ways to “restructure” data, including
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;groupby&lt;/tt&gt; e &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;window&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback form:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python.it/feedback-1771"&gt;https://python.it/feedback-1771&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 5 May&lt;/strong&gt; at 11:45 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/en/sprints/schedule/pycon10/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pietro Battiston</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-05-05:pycon-italia-2019/you-dont-need-n-dimensions-when-you-have-pandas.html</guid><category>data-structures</category><category>numpy</category><category>pandas</category><category>data-analysis</category><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>Databases for Data Science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2018/databases-for-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’ll present the usefulness of databases for data science
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Databases have been around for decades and were highly optimised for
data aggregations during that time. Not only &lt;em&gt;Big data&lt;/em&gt; has changed the
landscape of databases massively in the past years - we nowadays can
find many &lt;em&gt;Open Source&lt;/em&gt; projects among the most popular dbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk you will be enabled to decide if a database can make
your work more efficient and which direction to look to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A quick recap on database history, &lt;em&gt;it all starts in Florence - where
else…&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a database? What’s a data store? data lake?…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relational SQL systems and their benefits for DS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NoSQL systems and their benefits for DS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to chose the db fitting your needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in __on &lt;strong&gt;sabato 21 aprile&lt;/strong&gt; at 17:00 &lt;a class="reference external" href="/p3/schedule/pycon9/"&gt;**See
schedule**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Hendorf</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-04-21:pycon-italia-2018/databases-for-data-science.html</guid><category>data-structures</category><category>Deep-Learning</category><category>data-science</category><category>database</category></item><item><title>Learning Algorithms and Data Structures in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-japan-2012/learning-algorithms-and-data-structures-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programming languages, data structures and algorithms are the fundamentals of computer science. There are a lot of materials that cover these subjects but often do not link well with each other. This talk will explain how to use Python to learn these topics in a fast and efficient manner&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">TienVu Ho</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-16:pycon-japan-2012/learning-algorithms-and-data-structures-in-python.html</guid><category>algorithms</category><category>data structures</category></item><item><title>Python in Space - The N Body Problem</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/python-in-space-the-n-body-problem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Jilg&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;breakthesystem)
I've been an app developer, a CTO, and a Python developer, mostly at the same time. I've carried through it all a desire to learn, a love for data visualisation, and a knack to pass on what I learned. I want to learn, I want to mentor, and I want to create inclusive spaces for people to learn and mentor themselves. In my free time, I open tins for my cats (who have their own instagram account), visit various spaceports around the world, and occasionally dabble in some motor sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The N Body Problem is a computationally complex problem that we use to predict how planets and galaxies – and everything in between – move through space. I'll show you some interesting ways to calculate it, and we'll have a look at what to do, should you find yourself in a space ship's pilot seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The N Body Problem is one of those famously hard to solve problems in computer science. It describes the movement and interactions of n bodies in space (where n is usually greater 3). You need a lot of computational power to passably approximate the gravitational influences a group of celestial bodies exert on each other. Can Python do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll give a super brief overview of the history of trying to predict the motion of moon, sun and the visible stars, and then we'll dive deep into the original N Body Problem, followed by creative ways to reduce the amount of calculation needed and still get a reasonable approximation. Doing this, we can see how to tackle some complex mathematic and algorithmic problems easily using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a Python beginner or even very early in your career as a developer, you are going to get a first impression of efficient algorithms and complex data structures, and how to measure complexity using Big O notation. If you're more advanced, you'll be treated to a hopefully interesting way of implementing the Barnes-Hutt-algorithm, and some space nerdery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we have all the pieces in place, let's play with some orbits. We'll see how orbits actually behave, as opposed to what the untrained mind would expect. We can use our new algorithms to try out some manoeuvres often used by real space craft and help you be prepared for when that call from ESA or NASA finally comes, and you'll be invited to work on Python In Space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Jilg</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/python-in-space-the-n-body-problem.html</guid><category>complexity</category><category>data structures</category><category>algorithms</category><category>space</category><category>python</category></item></channel></rss>