<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org - code analysis</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Code quality in Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/code-quality-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Four years ago I talked about code quality during EuroPython in
Bilbao. A lot of things changed from that time. Firstly, most tools I
presented were still developed and gained new features, but also new
ones appeared I wanted to discuss with you. Secondly, Python changed,
Python 3 has type hints on board and there is a new tool dedicated to
checking the types. Thirdly - I changed. I'm more distanced form my
zealous approach from four years ago. I got real and reasonable.
That's why I wanted to talk about code quality tools in Python again.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I'll talk about all the software that can make code review a bit
simpler by pointing out possible errors, duplicates or unused code.
I'll talk again about formatters and how can they be used in
modern-time projects. And I'll talk about hobgoblins, if you know what
I mean :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radosław Ganczarek</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:/europython-2019/code-quality-in-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Python 3</category><category>Tooling</category><category>Type-Hinting</category></item><item><title>Code review for Beginners and Experts: Tips &amp; Tricks</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/code-review-for-beginners-and-experts-tips-tricks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Code review is not just boring duty. It's mutual responsibility for
the software we're releasing. It's one of the most critical aspects of
code quality, and therefore it's the first step of quality assurance.
This is also the key to easier programming and better maintainability.
Clean code is much easier to debug, and it's much harder to introduce
a bug in such code.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;When you think about code review, you probably think about verifying
and examining the code. Reviewing the expert's code may look like a
waste of time because he knows what he's doing. Reviewing the code by
a beginner may look like a waste of time because he's not able to find
as many defects as an experienced developer. Code review is a code
quality tool in the first place, but it's also much beyond that. You
can teach or help someone, learn from somebody and much more both from
the position of reviewer and reviewee.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;There is much more about the real power of code review which I want to
share with you.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk is also about how to do it the right way and how to not do
it based on lessons learned and my experience within the diverse teams
of people with a variety of knowledge and experience. I was reviewing
the code but, on the other hand, I was also being reviewed. I'd like
to pass my observations to people who are reviewing the code both in
commercial and open source projects for a while. This talk is also for
those who want to start to review the code, but they do not know how
to do it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Łukasz Kąkol</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:/europython-2019/code-review-for-beginners-and-experts-tips-tricks.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Development</category><category>Programming</category></item><item><title>From Python script to Open Source Project</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/from-python-script-to-open-source-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you write a cool and useful Python script? Would you like to share
it with the community, but you're not sure how to go about that? If so,
then this talks is for you. We'll go over a list of simple steps which
can turn your script into a fully fledged open-source project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python community has a rich set of tools which can help verify the
quality of your code through automated code-review and linting. You can
benefit by taking advantage of this ecosystem. Complete the steps in
this checklist, and your project will be easier to maintain, you'll be
ready to take contributions from the community and those contributions
will be up to high standards. Your project will also keep up with other
projects on PyPI and you will be alerted if any new release causes an
incompatibility with your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same checklist can be used for non open-source projects as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project maturity checklist includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly structure your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a setup.py file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add entry_points for your script command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a requirements.txt file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Black to format your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a tox.ini config and include code linters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a Git repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactor your code to be unit-testable and add tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add missing docstrings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add type annotations and a MyPy verification step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload to GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a continuous integration service (e.g. Travis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a requirements updater (e.g. pyup.bot)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add test coverage checker (e.g. coveralls)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a Readme file and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish your project on PyPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertise your project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michał Karzyński</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:/europython-2019/from-python-script-to-open-source-project.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Static Analysis</category><category>Tooling</category></item><item><title>Python vs Rust for Simulation</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/python-vs-rust-for-simulation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Both Python and Rust are getting more and more popularity. Although it
is unfair to compare them directly, this talk aims to provide a clear
comparison with a pre-defined criteria applied to a specific use-case.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Writing a simulation engine is very similar to writing a game engine
and requires certain features from a language or framework.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Possible comparison criteria:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;1. Performance&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;2. Simplicity&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;3. Amount of code necessary for a MVP&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;4. Utilities: docs, tests, profile&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;5. Compatibility&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Tl;dr&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Do I want to go back to Python after Rust? Maybe+)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alisa Dammer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:/europython-2019/python-vs-rust-for-simulation.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2019</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Development</category><category>Rust</category><category>python</category></item><item><title>Effective Code Reviews</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/effective-code-reviews.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The edge between hard skills and soft skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does your company uses code review? In this talk I will demonstrate why it should start using them immediately, share the many benefits and situations we've gone through, besides good practices that should be used for effective code reviews, that add quality to the product/service that is being delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Vinicius Gubiani Ferreira</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/effective-code-reviews.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Agile</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Communication</category></item><item><title>The joy of deleting code</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/the-joy-of-deleting-code.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to apply YAGNI to practice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say measuring code quality by its LOC is like measuring aircraft quality by its weight. There's a lot of sense in the metaphor, as we often call inefficient code with words like &amp;quot;heavy&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;bloated&amp;quot;.
In my talk I'll tell you about my approach to deleting unneeded code, tools that could help you and how did it turned out in the end in real world projects.
As you probably know, detecting unused code automatically is a hard task and doing it in Python is exceptionally hard because we sometimes call methods with getattr or write classes which are only used in non-python configuration files. Tools give us only a partial success. What you could do beyond them? What approach to take? I'd like to discuss it in detail in my talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radosław Ganczarek</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/the-joy-of-deleting-code.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Architecture</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Clean Code</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Programming</category></item><item><title>Writing Good Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/europython-2020/writing-good-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like other programming languages, it is easy to write cryptic, unmaintainable, and rigid Python code. Moreover, in teams, this problem escalates due to varied coding styles of developers. How to ensure code quality and consistency? My goal with this talk is to educate my audience about some tools and libraries that can help us in making our code more consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prashant Chaubey</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2020-07-23:/europython-2020/writing-good-python.html</guid><category>EuroPython 2020</category><category>europython</category><category>europython-2020</category><category>europython-online</category><category>Best Practice</category><category>Code Analysis</category><category>Documentation</category><category>Static Analysis</category><category>Type-Hinting</category></item><item><title>Fuzzing Python code with Atheris</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/fuzzing-python-code-with-atheris.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuzzing Python code with Atheris - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuzz testing is a well-known technique for uncovering programming
errors. Atheris is an open-source fuzzing engine for finding bugs in
Python code and native extensions, released by the Google Information
Security team. With this talk we’ll learn how Atheris works and how it
can be used in practice. Fuzz testing is a well-known technique for
uncovering programming errors. Many of these detectable errors have
serious security implications. Atheris ( is an open-source fuzzing
engine for automatically finding bugs in Python code and native
extensions. Atheris is a “coverage-guided” fuzzer, which means that
Atheris will repeatedly try various inputs to your program while
watching how it executes, and try to find interesting execution paths.
In the past, Atheris was used to find bugs in Pillow’s native code
(CVE-2020-35653) or to find differences in JSON parsing between Python’s
standard library and Ultrajson, or between Python’s idna package and the
native libidn2 library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you can learn the basics of fuzzing, how Atheris works
internally, and how it can be used for bug hunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Federico Scrinzi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Federico Scrinzi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/fuzzing-python-code-with-atheris.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>code analysis</category><category>open source</category><category>security</category><category>testing</category></item><item><title>Linting Python The Elegant Way</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/linting-python-the-elegant-way.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linting Python The Elegant Way - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for those people who know basic python but are looking
forward to writing better and cleaner python code. Python has always
been known for its easy-to-understand syntax. This talk will empower all
developers and give perspective on how can you write code in a much more
elegant way. Linting is the automated checking of your source code for
programmatic and stylistic errors. Linters analyze source code to flag
programming errors, bugs, stylistic errors, and suspicious constructs.
This is done by using a lint tool. Python being one of the most elegant
language has got a wide variety of listing tools available that can help
programmers in Code formatting and styling their code in the best
suitable form. Python has got some advance listing tools like pylint and
flake8. In this talk we will have a great deal of discussion around how
these linters can be used and how these tools can help you find more
bugs and improve your code quality. These linting tools finds problems
that are typically caught by a compiler for less dynamic languages. We
will also discuss about how can we manage import orders, code
formatting, checking security vulnerabilities, managing dependencies etc
using these tools. There are also code analysis tools that provide other
insights into your code. While maybe not linters by definition, these
tools are usually used side-by-side with linters. They too hope to
improve the quality of the code. It’s useful to have linters run against
your code frequently. If automation and consistency aren’t there, it’s
easy for a large team or project to lose sight of the goal and start
creating lower-quality code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will be able to learn 1. What is a linter? 2. Famous linting
solutions like pylint and flake 8 3. Use cases like ordering imports,
finding error bugs 4. Managing dependency in python with these linter
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Riya Bansal&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Riya Bansal</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/linting-python-the-elegant-way.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>best practice</category><category>clean code</category><category>code analysis</category><category>community</category><category>development</category></item><item><title>Vulture eats some Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2022/vulture-eats-some-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vulture eats some Python - PyCon Italia 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a high level of code quality is important for any serious
project. One aspect of this is ensuring that all code is actually used.
Finding and removing dead code allows to keep the code base clean and
reduces bugs. This is a practical guide on using and configuring Vulture
to do so. This talk is focused on how we can use Vulture to find dead
code. There are many reasons for dead code ending up in a project. The
most common is refactoring, but another is misspellings, which are only
detected at runtime for dynamic languages. Vulture helps you find unused
code in Python programs, and it is useful for cleaning up and finding
errors in large codebases. If you run Vulture on both your library and
test suite, you can find untested code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to Python’s dynamic nature, static code analyzers like Vulture are
likely to miss some dead code. Also, code that is only called implicitly
(e.g., using getattr) may be reported as unused. Nonetheless, Vulture
can be a very helpful tool for higher code quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of this talk investigates ways to improve Vulture’s
reporting such that the results are actionable and optimized for a low
number of false positives. It also discusses how to automate testing for
dead code with Vulture – there are quite a few options available: 1. Add
a step in your continuous integration testing. 2. As a pre-commit hook.
3. Run a script using Vulture API for more fine-grained control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and last part of this talk discusses a brief overview of the
internal workings of the tool, along with the scope of future
improvements. After all, the motive of this talk is not only to
encourage developers to prioritize code hygiene but also to inspire them
to come up with ideas to &lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Rahul Jha&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rahul Jha</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2022-06-03:/pycon-italia-2022/vulture-eats-some-python.html</guid><category>PyCon Italia 2022</category><category>best practice</category><category>clean code</category><category>code analysis</category><category>static analysis</category><category>tooling</category></item></channel></rss>