<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_data-engineering.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Simple Data Engineering in python 3.5+ with Bonobo</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/simple-data-engineering-in-python-35-with-bonobo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Romain Dorgueil</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/simple-data-engineering-in-python-35-with-bonobo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Romain Dorgueil&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;rdorgueil)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer, sysadmin, technical team builder, founder of two companies), advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently helping start-ups to achieve more with less in our acceleration programs in Paris, and in charge of our product development activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I play go and make music, but not at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple is better than complex, and that's True for data pipelines, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonobo is a python 3.5+ tool used to write and monitor data pipelines. It’s plain, simple, modern, and atomic python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is a practical encounter, from zero to a complete data pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler : no «big data» here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple is better than complex, right? That’s true for data pipelines too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 5 years, I hacked together extract-transform-load (ETL) processes in various different positions (ETL is just a fancy term for «bunch of things that take data somewhere and put it elsewhere, eventually transformed»).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did it as a founder, as a consultant, as a technical co-founder, for some side projects, big corporates and small side projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each case, I felt frustrated with the tools available, and in some serious cases, I had to hack things myself to get the job done. Bonobo is the repackaging of my past experiences for python 3.5+, and grasping the basics should not take more than the length of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline (subject to small changes, for the greater good) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;INTRO : The ETL market, why a new tool, what it is, what it is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basics and concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete data pipeline example, using SQL, RDF and a small Django frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OUTRO : A glimpse at the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonobo is the glue you need to tie together regular functions in a transformation graph (think unix pipes). Execution strategies are abstracted so you can focus on the real operations. As a result, you can engineer simple and testable systems, using the same good computer development practices as you use in .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="data-engineering"></category><category term="etl"></category><category term="simple"></category><category term="bonobo"></category></entry></feed>