<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Can Python's web and science communities run concurrently?</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/can-pythons-web-and-science-communities-run-conc.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python has been adopted by many disciplinary communities, showing its
adaptability to many problems. Scientific computing and web development
are two examples of such communities. These might, at first glance, seem
to share few common interests, especially at the level of algorithms and
libraries. However, at the level of integrated practice in
time-constrained academic environments, where framework development is
less valued than research and teaching productivity, ease of adoption of
tools from each of these communities can be tremendously valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using examples from the recently-deployed West Texas Lightning Mapping
Array, which is processed and visualized in real-time, this paper will
argue that a shared sense, among disciplinary communities, of the
essence of how one deploys Python for specific problems is beneficial
for continuation and growth of Python's status as a go-to language for
practitioners in academic settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Bruning</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/can-pythons-web-and-science-communities-run-conc.html</guid><category>Meteorology Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Py-ART: Python for remote sensing science</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/py-art-python-for-remote-sensing-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive to publish often leaves scientists working with old,
inflexible, poorly documented dead end software. Even operational
systems can end up being a mash of legacy systems cobbled together. As
the Atmospheric Radiation Measurement (ARM) Climate Facility brings its
30+ cloud and precipitation sensitive radars into operation a concerted
effort to modernize, modularize and adapt existing code and write new
code to retrieve geophysical parameters from the remotely sensed
signals. Due to the open nature, active development community and lack
of licensing issues Python is a natural development environment choice.
This presentation will outline the challenges involved in retrieving
model comparable geophysical parameters from scanning weather radars,
introduce the framework behind the Python ARM Radar Toolkit (Py-ART) and
discuss the challenges involved in building high performance code while
maintaining portability, readability and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scott Collis</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/py-art-python-for-remote-sensing-science.html</guid><category>Meteorology Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Running a Coupled General Circulation Model with Python</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/running-a-coupled-general-circulation-model-with.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luiz Irber</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/running-a-coupled-general-circulation-model-with.html</guid><category>Meteorology Mini-Symposia</category></item><item><title>Utilizing Python in a Real-Time, Quasi-Operational Meteorological Environment</title><link>https://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/utilizing-python-in-a-real-time-quasi-operationa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's (NOAA) Hazardous
Weather Testbed (HWT) is a facility jointly managed by NOAA's National
Severe Storms Laboratory (NSSL), NOAA National Weather Service's (NWS)
the Storm Prediction Center (SPC), and the NOAA NWS Oklahoma City/Norman
Weather Forecast Office (OUN) within the National Weather Center
building on the University of Oklahoma South Research Campus. The HWT is
designed to accelerate the transition of promising new meteorological
insights and technologies into advances in forecasting and warning for
hazardous weather events throughout the United States. The HWT
facilities include a combined forecast and research area situated
between the operations rooms of the SPC and OUN, and a nearby
development laboratory. The facilities support enhanced collaboration
between research scientists and operational weather forecasters on
specific topics that are of mutual interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cornerstone of the HWT is the yearly Experimental Forecast Program
(EFP) and Experimental Warning Program (EWP) which take place every
spring. In each of those programs, forecasters, researchers, and
developers come together to participate in a real-time operational
forecasting or warning environment with the purpose of testing and
evaluating cutting-edge tools and methods for forecasting and warning.
In the EFP program, between 5 and 10 TB of meteorological data are
processed for evaluation over the course of a 5 week period. These data
come in a variety of sources, a variety of formats, each requiring a
different set of processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss how the data flow and data creation processes of
the EFP are accomplished in a real-time setting through the use of
Python. The utilization of Python ranges from simple shell scripting, to
speeding up algorithm development (and runtimes) with Numpy and Cython,
to creating new, open source data-visualization platforms, such as the
Skew-T and Hodograph Analysis and Research Program in Python, or
SHARPpy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Marsh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-19:scipy-2012/utilizing-python-in-a-real-time-quasi-operationa.html</guid><category>Meteorology Mini-Symposia</category></item></channel></rss>