<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_wxpython.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PyOhio 2010: GUI Tools</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--gui-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>James Bonanno</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-07-31:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--gui-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GUI Tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by James Bonanno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several Graphical User Interface frameworks available for
Python. In this talk, perpahs the two most popular, wxPython and PyQt,
are examined. The talk will focus on major differences, tools, and a
specific example done both in wxPython and PyQt, that is a non-trivial
production grade example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: sound is inaudible for the first minute]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="gui"></category><category term="pyohio"></category><category term="pyohio2010"></category><category term="pyqt"></category><category term="wxpython"></category></entry><entry><title>Experiences making CPU-bound tasks run much faster</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/experiences-making-cpu-bound-tasks-run-much-faste.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Ozsvald</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/experiences-making-cpu-bound-tasks-run-much-faste.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Ian Ozsvald - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza
Margherita &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;UPDATE - post-event I've created a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ianozsvald.com/2011/06/29/high-performance-python-tutorial-v0-1%20-from-my-4-hour-tutorial-at-europython-2011/"&gt;49 page PDF write-
up&lt;/a&gt;
which summarises the 4 hour tutorial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-time R&amp;amp;D consultant I'm often working to make slow,
experimental code run faster for tasks like physics simulation, flood
modeling and natural language processing. Python allows a smooth
progression from rough-and-ready (but slow) algorithms through to finely
tuned tasks that efficiently use as much CPU power as you can bring to
bear. Speed-ups of 10-500* can be expected for the Mandelbrot code
we'll use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I'll cover a set of libraries that make CPU-bound tasks run
much faster. We'll begin with a look at profiling using RunSnakeRun and
line_profiler to identify our bottleneck. We'll take a look at slow
algorithms in Python and how they can run faster using numpy and
numexpr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we'll cover the use of multiprocessing to utilise multiple CPU
cores along with Cython or ShedSkin to easily use C code in a friendly
Python wrapper. Multiprocessing on a quad-core system can often provide
a 4* speed-up for the right tasks. Next parallelpython will let us run
our code on a network of machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we'll look at pyCUDA to utilise an NVIDIA GPU. CUDA can give the
best improvements for mathematical problems (over 100* on the right
tasks) but works on a narrower set of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it'll work: The tutorial will be hands on, you'll be converting
example files from normal Python to faster variants using the tools
below. All of it is optional, you'll get the most benefit by having
everything installed. We'll work in groups and open discussion is
encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE - you are expected to have all these tools installed &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the
tutorial (if you don't, you might find it hard to follow what's going
on!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be using Python 2.7.1 on a Macbook (Snow Leopard). All of these
tools run on Windows and Linux, as long as your versions are fairly
recent everything should run just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My versions (roughly ordered by importance):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2.7.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RunSnakeRun 2.0.1b6 (with wxPython 2.8.12.0 Unicode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;line_profiler (1.0b2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cython 0.14.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ShedSkin 0.7.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numpy 1.5.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numexpr 1.4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ParallelPython 1.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pyCUDA HEAD from git as of 14th June 2011 (with CUDA 4.0 drivers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyPy 1.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some background reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ianozsvald.com/2010/07/14/22937-faster-python-math-using-pycuda/"&gt;http://ianozsvald.com/2010/07/14/22937-faster-python-math-using-pycuda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ianozsvald.com/2008/11/17/making-python-math-196-faster-with-shedskin/"&gt;http://ianozsvald.com/2008/11/17/making-python-math-196-faster-with-shedskin/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="cython"></category><category term="git"></category><category term="multiprocessing"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="nvidia"></category><category term="profiling"></category><category term="pycuda"></category><category term="runsnakerun"></category><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="windows"></category><category term="wxpython"></category></entry><entry><title>Entwicklung wissenschaftlicher Applikationen mit Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2013/entwicklung-wissenschaftlicher-applikationen-mit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Florian Rhiem</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-10-15:pycon-de-2013/entwicklung-wissenschaftlicher-applikationen-mit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Durch Experimente und Simulationen werden im wissenschaftlichen Bereich
große Mengen an Daten erzeugt. Diese müssen geeignet aufbereitet werden,
um sie in eine für die Wissenschaftler verständliche Form zu überführen.
Ein Beispiel dafür ist die Untersuchung von Phasenwechselmaterialien,
welche in wiederbeschreibbaren optischen Medien eingesetzt werden. Der
beim Löschen und Beschreiben eintretende Wechsel zwischen kristallinem
und amorphen Zustand wird auf Großrechnern simuliert und die
resultierende molekulare Struktur auf Hohlstellen hin untersucht, da
diese Rückschlüsse auf das Verhalten des Materials zulassen. Den Kern
der Präsentation nimmt die Entwicklung der Anwendung &lt;em&gt;pyMolDyn&lt;/em&gt; ein,
welche die Analyse und Visualisierung der Moleküle und Hohlstellen
übernimmt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Vortrag gibt einen Einblick in die Erfahrungen, die während der
mehrjährigen Entwicklung dieser Software gesammelt wurden. Zum einen
wird dabei die rechenintensive Analyse der Daten betrachtet und wie
diese durch Verwendung von NumPy und (py)OpenCL vereinfacht und
beschleunigt werden kann. Zum anderen werden die grafischen
Anwendungskomponenten beschrieben, welche mithilfe von wxPython,
(py)OpenGL und einem gezielten Zusammenspiel dieser beiden Pakete
umgesetzt werden konnten. Neben Performance und Einfachheit der
Programmierung werden auch die gewonnenen Eindrücke zu
Plattformunabhängigkeit und Interversionskompatibilität vorgestellt.
Weiterhin werden Eigenheiten der Anwendungsentwicklung im Bereich der
Forschung erläutert und es wird darauf eingegangen, welche Stärken und
Schwächen Python in diesem Zusammenhang bietet. Abschließend folgt ein
Überblick darüber, wie sich die weitere Entwicklung von &lt;em&gt;pyMolDyn&lt;/em&gt;
gestalten wird und welche Konsequenzen die gesammelten Erfahrungen in
Zukunft für das Projekt haben werden.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="anwendungsentwicklung"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="opencl"></category><category term="opengl"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="visualisierung"></category><category term="wxpython"></category></entry><entry><title>Cross platform application development and distribution (#116)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--cross-platform-application-developmen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nadia Alramli</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--cross-platform-application-developmen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cross platform application development and distribution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Stani Michiels and Nadia Alramli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You think Python gives you native cross platform applications for free?
Think twice. Are you interested in distributing your application to
other platforms but not sure how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will give tips and examples on how to enhance the native feel of your
application: notifications, registration of file types and more. The
talk will also help you to avoid common pitfalls and provides solutions
for designing cross platform user interfaces. (Although we use wxPython
as an example, the principles are valid for other toolkits as well.)
We'll show you where to start if you want to distribute your application
to different platforms, briefly discussing tools like py2exe, py2app and
Debian/Ubuntu packaging ecosystem. This talk is based on our experience
from developing Phatch (Photo Batch Processor) and SPE (Python Editor).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="crossplatform"></category><category term="packaging"></category><category term="py2app"></category><category term="py2exe"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="wxpython"></category></entry><entry><title>wxPython II: Introduction to GUI Programming and MVC</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--wxpython-ii--introduction-to-gui-prog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Goodger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/pycon-2010--wxpython-ii--introduction-to-gui-prog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;wxPython II: Introduction to GUI Programming and MVC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by David Goodger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wxPython is an open-source graphical user interface (GUI) toolkit that
runs on multiple platforms, including Linux, Windows, and Mac OS X. By
the end of this tutorial, attendees will understand the concepts behind
the Model-View- Controller (MVC) design pattern and will have built a
complex wxPython application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intended Audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python programmers (of any level; familiarity with Python is assumed)
with some wxPython experience. Attending the &amp;quot;wxPython I&amp;quot; tutorial is
recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees are welcome to bring a laptop loaded with Python 2.4+ and
wxPython 2.6+ to follow along, but this is not required.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2010"></category><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="wxpython"></category></entry></feed>