<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_pyconza2014.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>A journey through the eyes of a newbie female developer</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/a-journey-through-the-eyes-of-a-newbie-female-dev.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ridhwana Khan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/a-journey-through-the-eyes-of-a-newbie-female-dev.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a developer, my goal is to provide inspiration to capable young
women, to fathers who have daughters, brothers who have sisters, and men
who have female colleagues. To convey that I have embraced the
development environment, and that we within the tech industry should
never shy away from the opportunity to increase our pool of passionate
developers. We are proudly South African and most definitely should be
known for our diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graduating from a 90% male computer science class, to an initially 100%
male software development team, finally allowed me to realise that there
is a dire lack of women in the computer science field. Entering this
industry in a minority invokes initial feelings of the need to
constantly prove oneself and one's capabilities – normally this puts one
at an immediate disadvantage. However, given the correct circumstances,
surrounding environments and attitudes, these adverse feelings can
quickly be replaced with self-confidence. I was fortunate enough in my
daily working environment to have my opinion given the weight that it
deserved. However, experience has also taught me that the sailing is not
always so smooth within every aspect of the development field. Certain
environments are a lot less welcoming to women because of the strange
misconception that they are going against the norms of society. As a
newbie, within the development industry, one has to be able to adapt and
have an open mind to gain unbounded knowledge and learning experiences.
The world of development is a polyglot environment and striving to build
an ambitious career involves lots of hard work and dedication. I would
like to take the audience on a journey to experience the obstacles,
growth and challenges that I’ve faced. I also aim to provide concrete
suggestions on increasing female willingness to join the tech industry,
and improving co-existence in the development environment. As a
developer, my goal is to provide inspiration to capable young women, to
fathers who have daughters, brothers who have sisters, and men who have
female colleagues. To convey that I have embraced the development
environment, and that we within the tech industry should never shy away
from the opportunity to increase our pool of passionate developers. We
are proudly South African and most definitely should be known for our
diversity….&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>An introduction to regular expressions in Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/an-introduction-to-regular-expressions-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adrianna Pińska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/an-introduction-to-regular-expressions-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular expressions are a mini-language used for pattern-matching in
text. They have been a staple of the computing world for decades: they
are implemented in most programming languages, form the core of several
utilities, and can be found lurking in the search-and-replace
functionality of any sufficiently advanced text editor. Despite their
usefulness, regular expressions have developed a reputation for
complexity and a steep learning curve. New programmers are often warned
to steer clear of them -- which is a pity, because there are some
problems for which they are a quick and elegant solution. In this talk I
aim to demystify regular expressions for the beginner programmer, and to
provide a brief guided tour of Python's re module. I hope to encourage
more programmers to get to know this useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Challenges and Prospects of the Python African Computational Science and Engineering Tour Project</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/challenges-and-prospects-of-the-python-african-co.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Godfrey Akpojotor</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/challenges-and-prospects-of-the-python-african-co.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer and computer based activities have pervaded our
teaching/learning process as well as research so much so that the 21st
century academic activities in science and engineering (S &amp;amp; E) cannot be
fully engaged without some level of computation. An important choice of
a programming language especially in a developing country is the ease to
learn it and its accessibility. Python's unique features and the
possibility that any user connected to the internet can download the
entire packages into any platform, install it and immediately begin to
use it makes it a preferred environment for introducing students and new
beginners to elegant and all purpose programming. Therefore in Africa,
the Python African Tour project has been launched and I am coordinating
its use in computational Science and Engineering (S &amp;amp; E) code-named
Python African Computational Science and Engineering Tour (PACSET).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>How I Became A Cookie Monster</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/how-i-became-a-cookie-monster.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Joseph</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/how-i-became-a-cookie-monster.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My journey from a user of the awesome cookiecutter, to a core member of
an awesome += 1 community. I've learned a lot from the modest and
multi-talented &amp;#64;audreyr about leading a community, writing clean
cross-platform Python code and putting the B in BFDL. My talk aims to
introduce cookiecutter to a wider audience (if you're at a PyCon and you
create new projects, you need to use it) and to chart my progress from
the outside to the inside of an open source project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>How Python helps writing documentation less painful</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/how-python-helps-writing-documentation-less-painf.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nickolas Grigoriadis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/how-python-helps-writing-documentation-less-painf.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all know writing documentation is an arduous exercise. We all know
how useless and frustrating out-of-date or just plain incorrect
documentation is. In this talk I'd like to demonstrate how Python can
help make writing documentation, keeping it up-to-date and verifying its
validity. It can be surprising what happens when other people discover
your little-but-well-documented API. Python has several built-in
concepts and standard tools to help making this easier, such as
docstrings, help(), Sphinx, Sphinx plugins, Doctests and generating
documentation off tests themselves. I'll focus on not only using Sphinx
as a tool, but also on how to structure your application/library/tool so
as to make writing accurate documentation as simple as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Inspired by Lisp to get Ruby to talk Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/inspired-by-lisp-to-get-ruby-to-talk-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Martin Pretorius</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/inspired-by-lisp-to-get-ruby-to-talk-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having pushed Ruby to the limits of what it can accomplish in terms of
number crunching and data analysis, we looked around for another
solution in the data analysis and modelling space. We quickly found that
with packages and tools like Numpy, Pandas, the iPython Notebook and new
packages like Blaze, Python looked to be a good language fit. Porting a
large existing codebase and accompanying infrastructure from a Ruby to
Python ecosystem simply wasn't an option, so we had to do something
clever (and fun!). This talk will be about how we managed to leverage
the power of Python while retaining our modelling code in Ruby (and
opening up opportunity for other languages), by embracing Lisp’s
code-is-data philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Monkeying around with Twisted</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/monkeying-around-with-twisted.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Richard Spiers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/monkeying-around-with-twisted.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twisted is an open source framework for writing network based services.
It utilises an asynchronous, event driven model which allows the rapid
development of custom network protocols. While Twisted makes
implementing network services much easier, it comes with its own set of
challenges. One of these challenges involves tracking the context of
multiple requests. In a traditional web server the thread ID could be
used to track a particular request and modify log entries appropriately.
However, this does not work in Twisted as it utilises a single thread
(generally speaking). We have chosen to tackle this issue, amongst
others, by monkey patching some of the Twisted subsystems. Through this
talk we will introduce Twisted as a viable option for programming
network based services. No previous Twisted knowledge is required, and
the concepts introduced will be explained through real world examples of
restful controllers implemented in Twisted. This primer will be followed
by a discussion on our solution to the context tracking problem as well
as some of the other areas in which we have found monkey patching to be
beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Practical testing</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/practical-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeremy Thurgood</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/practical-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automated tests are an important part of any software project, but
they're often hard to work with. Good test code should be written with
its own set of priorities and is sufficiently different from non-test
code that many standard programming practices are unsuitable. I have
spent many years writing (and reading) tests of varying quality and have
learned quite a lot from the experience. I hope to share some of that
experience and help to remove some of the pain usually associated with
writing and maintaining tests. This talk will cover some of the
practical aspects of writing good tests for real code, including: 1.
Properties of a good test case 2. How to manage setup and teardown 3.
Testing interactions between components 4. Some tools and techniques to
make testing easier 1. Helpers 2. Verified fakes 3. Recording doubles&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>PyConZA 2014: Closing Remarks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/pyconza-2014-closing-remarks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Simon Cross</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/pyconza-2014-closing-remarks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyConZA 2014 closing remarks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Python at the Observatory - Old telescopes, new instruments</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/python-at-the-observatory-old-telescopes-new-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Carel van Gend</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/python-at-the-observatory-old-telescopes-new-i.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'd like to show how we're using new instruments and the nimbleness of
Python to bring seventy-year-old telescopes into the 21st century. Our
long-term goal is to have the telescopes and associated instruments be
remotely operable, easy to use, and robust enough that valuable data is
reliably captured and stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astronomy in South Africa has a long and illustrious history. In
addition to the premier, 10-m Southern Africa Large Telescope (SALT) ,
there are a number of small- and medium-sized telescopes hosted at the
South African Astronomical Observatory that still produce a great deal
of valuable data. We'd like to show how we're using new instruments and
the nimbleness of Python to bring seventy-year-old telescopes into the
21st century. Our long-term goal is to have the telescopes and
associated instruments be remotely operable, easy to use, and robust
enough that valuable data is reliably captured and stored. In addition,
we want to make it as easy as possible to update and improve the
software which controls the instruments. We have developed a distributed
framework to control the instruments. Drivers for individual components
may be written in whichever language is most suitable (we've used C, C++
and Python where appropriate). These drivers communicate over a TCP/IP
socket with a Python controller process, and on top of that is a
Python/Flask driven web interface. We plan to adapt the framework to new
instruments (such as a wide-field camera for the 1.9- and 1-m
telescopes), under-development instruments (such as an upgrade to the
Cassegrain spectrograph on the 1.9-m telescope), and retrofit to older
instruments as feasible. As a demonstration of the new framework, we
will present our work of migrating the control software for the
Sutherland High-speed Optical Camera (SHOC) from being a disparate
collection of proprietary, Windows-based software, to a unified, open,
web accessible system. SHOC is a high-speed, accurately-timed, imaging
instrument that can be mounted on the 1.9-, 1-, and 0.75-m telescopes in
Sutherland, control of which includes that for a camera, a global
positioning system (GPS), and a filter wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in Debian &amp; Ubuntu</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/python-in-debian-ubuntu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stefano Rivera</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/python-in-debian-ubuntu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at people who maintain Python libraries and also
users of Debian packaged libraries. (Wherever I say Debian in this
abstract, it applies to Ubuntu too). The talk should explain a bit about
how and why libraries are packaged in Debian, and how to help maintain
(or contribute) packages you care about. We'll cover a bit of history of
the Python stacks in Debian and how packaged modules are provided, and
who does the work. For context, we'll take a quick detour into Debian
packaging in general, and the Debian project's lifecycle. Debian
recently gained a new Python packaging tool, pybuild. This finally makes
it easy to package the same library for Python 2, 3, and even PyPy. So,
we'll have a look at what it does, and some example packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Python in the context of a Start-up: The Good, The Bad and the Ugly</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/python-in-the-context-of-a-start-up-the-good-th.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Adam Jorgensen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/python-in-the-context-of-a-start-up-the-good-th.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is great language for developing software that works well in a
short time-span. The ability to produce code quickly that is of a
reasonable quality is very important in a work environment where
productivity is of extreme importance. It would thus seem to be very
well suited for usage in a start-up environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is great language for developing software that works well in a
short time-span. The ability to produce code quickly that is of a
reasonable quality is very important in a work environment where
productivity is of extreme importance. It would thus seem to be very
well suited for usage in a start-up environment. Is this really the case
though? Here at Springlab we've been using Python to develop our
product, an online platform for locating and booking with medical
practitioners, since day one. Along the way we've written a lot of code,
used a variety of frameworks, libraries and toolkits while experimenting
with various approaches to solving the problems we've encountered. Of
key importance to us has been balancing the need to produce code that
works now against the desire to develop something that we won't become a
serious time-sink in the future. From our position it is thus possible
to go into a bit of detail about the pros, cons and extremely sharp
corners encountered using Python in the context of a small start-up
environment where time is of the essence and there is a lot of pressure
to produce a quality product as quickly AND as well as possibly. My aim
with this talk is to give the listener an idea of what kind of
experience to expect when using Python in an environment like ours and
also to hopefully share some tips that will help others avoid some of
the problems we've run into. I hope to cover issues on the subjects of
back-end development involving Django + Tastypie, front-end development
with Flask, client-side development involving JavaScript as well as
touching on the subject of integrating with other tools and pieces of
software.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Reaching Beyond the Web</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/reaching-beyond-the-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Vinod Kurup</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/reaching-beyond-the-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government of Libya recently implemented a voter registration system
and chose to use SMS as the implementation technology, In this talk, I
will explain how we used RapidSMS, a Django-based SMS framework, to
build this groundbreaking voter registration system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using RapidSMS to power democracy in Libya. As web developers, we often
think of the web as being a ubiquitous resource, available to everyone.
The truth is that there are still large groups of people who have either
limited or no web access. In addition, there are people who have
excellent web access, yet still prefer to use simpler tools to connect
to others. How can we reach these groups of people? While not perfectly
ubiquitous, SMS technology is much more widespread, especially in areas
that don't have great internet connectivity. It's also ubiquitous in the
sense that people who have excellent internet access still use SMS
frequently. The government of Libya recently implemented a voter
registration system and chose to use SMS as the implementation
technology, largely because of these reasons. In this talk, I will
explain how we used RapidSMS, a Django-based SMS framework, to build
this groundbreaking voter registration system. We will discuss the
basics of the RapidSMS framework, and show concrete examples from our
Libyan project. I will mostly describe concepts at a high level, though
familiarity with Python code may help you understand the details. If you
truly want your tools to reach everyone, adding SMS connectivity will
spread the power of your web apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>What I learned about Python – and about Guido's time machine – by reading the python-ideas mailing list</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/what-i-learned-about-python-and-about-guidos-t.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Mertz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-03:pycon-za-2014/what-i-learned-about-python-and-about-guidos-t.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that changes enter the Python language is via their
prior discussion on the python-ideas mailing list. Many core
contributors read and contribute to this list, some do not, and a large
number of other interested Python programmers also participate in the
discussion. A recurring element of these fascinating discussions is that
ideas which seem compelling at first blush, upon deeper discussion
reveal the greater wisdom of doing things just the way Python already
does. Not always, of course, but often. A wonderful case study of this
process is the innocuous seeming built-in 'sum()'. This function has an
intricate history, with a great deal of dispute over just what its
semantics and performance characteristics can or should be. A particular
thread on python-ideas, rich with discussions of use cases and subtle
semantics, led both to the creation of the 'statistics' module in Python
3.4 (which contains a &amp;quot;private&amp;quot; version of the function,
'statistics._sum()') and to a rejection of performance &amp;quot;optimizations&amp;quot;
when operating over collections of collections (which may or may not
seem obvious to &amp;quot;sum&amp;quot; in the first place).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Building the Internet of Things with Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/building-the-internet-of-things-with-raspberry-pi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Neil Broers</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/building-the-internet-of-things-with-raspberry-pi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the advent of the low cost Raspberry Pi computer, anyone with a
soldering iron and some basic Python skills can take everyday objects
and transform them into fully networked, smart devices. In this talk, I
will show you how I hacked a Raspberry Pi into my home alarm system,
turning my network of IP cameras into motion triggered sensors. I will
show you how to build basic input and output circuits and introduce you
to the RPi.GPIO Python module. We’ll talk about how you can build a
RESTful server on your Raspberry Pi to enable remote access. And
finally, more ideas for hacking everyday objects around the home! No
prior electronics knowledge required.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Enabling Science with the Southern African Large Telescope with Python</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/enabling-science-with-the-southern-african-large.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steve Crawford</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/enabling-science-with-the-southern-african-large.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Southern African Large Telescope is the premier optical astronomical
facility in South Africa. Since the start of science operations in
September 2011, it has produced a wide range of scientific results from
studies of near-Earth asteroids to galaxies at the edge of the Universe.
Once observations are obtained at the telescope, they are passed through
our science pipeline, which is built on Python. The pipeline rapidly
distributes the data, provides science quality reductions, and monitors
the performance of the telescope. In addition, developments made for
SALT have also contributed to astropy, a python library for astronomy.
In this talk, we highlight how these developments are helping to
contribute to our understanding of the Universe. We describe how we are
using python to provide rapid reductions of the observations, for
teaching new students, and for solving new problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Hand me the salt while I read my news</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/hand-me-the-salt-while-i-read-my-news.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Johann du Toit</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/hand-me-the-salt-while-i-read-my-news.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millions of people read news monthly, and news tend to happen in bursts.
The ideal infrastructure is able to scale up or down as soon as needed
and provide a way to let you proactively manage your servers rather than
reactively, which in the media game is a deal breaker. It gets even
worse when you're running most of the local publication sites, including
some big name players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the infrastructure we built, using Salt for management; give
insight into the news game and provide examples of challenges our team
are facing on a daily basis while servicing users. Expanding also on the
workflow put together using various solutions such for logging,
notifications with Python acting as the coordinator to keep all these
systems in line. Delving into various parts of the system from network
monitoring to deploying code. This talk is meant for anyone interested
in getting a glimpse of the systems and workflow put in place that allow
us to manage the required load and continue developing with the agility
to make the needed quick decisions daily.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>IPython as a tool for teaching and learning</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/ipython-as-a-tool-for-teaching-and-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Laura Richter</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/ipython-as-a-tool-for-teaching-and-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ipython environment lends itself to teaching and learning: immediate
feedback, flexible visualisation, easy access to docstrings and ability
to explore modules. With development of the ipython notebook, this is
taken a step further, by providing browser-based access to an ipython
environment with the ability to share notebooks with others, embed
output products and annotate code. I will present some experience of
using ipython as a teaching tool in a tertiary teaching environment in
Radio Astronomy courses in Windhoek, Nairobi and Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>IPython Notebook</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/ipython-notebook.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tobie Nortje</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/ipython-notebook.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IPython Notebook is a browser-based interactive computational
environment in which you can combine code execution, text, mathematics,
plots and rich media into a single document. Notebooks are text files
that can be shared with colleagues, converted to other formats such as
HTML, PDF, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Large Scale Data Processing with Python and Apache Spark</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/large-scale-data-processing-with-python-and-apach.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nick Pentreath</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/large-scale-data-processing-with-python-and-apach.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apache Spark is a fast and general engine for large-scale, distributed
data processing. It offers high-level APIs in Java, Scala and Python as
well as a rich set of libraries including stream processing, machine
learning, and graph analytics. Spark is currently one of the most
exciting and fastest-growing Apache open source projects. This talk will
give an overview of the Apache Spark project and introduce the basics of
PySpark, the Python API for Spark. It will then dive a little deeper
into PySpark internals, and finally show some examples and a live demo
covering PySpark, Spark's SQL engine, and machine learning with Spark's
built-in libraries as well as other Python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/lightning-talks-17.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mike Jones</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/lightning-talks-17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Talks are fun, short, five-minute (or less) talks. Ideally
each talk should make a single point, often in a fun, quirky or
over-the-top way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch to Borderline Zombie in a Year by Mike Jones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why you're dumb if you are doing a Python GUI in anything other than
Kivy by Richard Larkin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyPy by Adam Jorgensen (slides)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sonic Pi by Simon de Haan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The challenge of mathematical formula markup for African feature
phones by Jonathan Endersby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="lightning talks"></category><category term="kivy"></category><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>The Earth is not Flat (and other Heresies)</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/the-earth-is-not-flat-and-other-heresies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Allison Randal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/the-earth-is-not-flat-and-other-heresies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any decent textbook on astrophysics starts with a historical prologue
running something like this: &amp;quot;Once upon a time, we believed the earth
was flat. We were wrong. Once upon a time, we believed the sun rotated
around the earth. We were wrong.&amp;quot; It's a shame that computer science
textbooks don't start the same way: &amp;quot;Once upon a time, we believed that
all computer languages would be statically compiled. We were wrong. Once
upon a time, we believed that execution would always be single-threaded,
on a single processor, on a single machine. We were wrong.&amp;quot; The world of
technology is marching on toward ever more concurrent architectures,
also called &amp;quot;Cloud&amp;quot;, and various other buzzwords. The transition is at
once so mundane as to go unnoticed, and so fundamental as to shake the
very foundations of computer science. This talk explores the past,
present, and future of the &amp;quot;Cloud&amp;quot;, and the implications for Python and
other open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>The elephant in the web application</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/the-elephant-in-the-web-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Iwan Vosloo</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/the-elephant-in-the-web-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing a web application today is an unnecessarily cumbersome and
error prone task. It is time for web frameworks to evolve and become
more like graphical user interface (GUI) frameworks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'd like to convince you that developing a web application
today is an unnecessarily cumbersome and error prone task. It is time
for web frameworks to evolve and become more like graphical user
interface (GUI) frameworks: these provide abstractions called &amp;quot;windows&amp;quot;
or &amp;quot;widgets&amp;quot; that let a programmer write an application using terms that
describe what is being built, with less (if any) focus on the underlying
technologies needed to accomplish drawing these items on a screen. A web
application programmer (in contrast to a GUI programmer) needs to know
quite a few different technologies and a fair bit of effort is required
to orchestrate these tools into achieving an end result: a template
language, HTML, HTTP, CSS, JavaScript, etc. Reusing something
substantial is especially difficult, which means in a sizeable web
application the same dragons need to be fought several times over. If a
programmer has to constantly deal with all this subject matter, it takes
focus away from what actually needs to be built: the application itself.
Why are we putting up with having to know HTML and similar low-level
technologies? Is it an elephant in the room? Something we pretend not to
see, yet we accept the burden of having to work around it? I will show
you what it takes to build a web application; what repetitive tasks
there are and what a programmer needs to be aware of. I hope to convince
you that there's a better way, and that what was perhaps an idealistic
dream a decade ago can now be done - not only by our own fully-featured
Python web framework (Reahl), but also by a small number of others
beyond the realm of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Python in Blender</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/using-python-in-blender.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Albert Nel</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/using-python-in-blender.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is such a beautiful language, and is used as a scripting language
in many open source graphical applications. By using the power of Python
within Blender, we can easily automate so many things, and make long
tedious tasks seem like child's play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python is such a beautiful language, and is used as a scripting language
in many open source graphical applications. By using the power of Python
within Blender, we can easily automate so many things, and make long
tedious tasks seem like child's play. In this talk I wanted to share a
few real world examples where I used Python to do something that would
otherwise be impossible (Or just take too long!) At first, we will take
a quick look at the API, and how to get started. Here we will look at
where you can find what you are looking for, and how it all comes
together. This wont be too in-depth, but just enough to give you a
taste. We will play with the console a bit and see how to wield the
mighty sword that is Python. And then, we will look at some scripts.
These are a few of the scripts that I wrote while I was working on some
random things. This will cover some things such as: Adding new mesh
objects, updating object coordinates, changing special properties (such
as modifers), and setting keyframes all from the console. This talk is
for anyone interested in seeing just how to leverage the power of Python
in Blender. You need not have any experience with Blender since this
will be mostly focussed on the Python side of things, so I wont be
covering parts of Blender such as rendering, modeling etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing Python Code to Decide an Election</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2014/writing-python-code-to-decide-an-election.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peter Lubell-Doughtie</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-02:pycon-za-2014/writing-python-code-to-decide-an-election.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year Ona was given three weeks to write the software that
will tally votes in the Libyan elections and decide who wins and who
loses. This is not something we could get wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not something we could get wrong. We combined agile development
with best practices in testing and QA to build an open source tally
system that was well tested, accurate, and easy to use. We will describe
a success story of iterative behavior/test-driven-development under
extreme conditions. Did the structure of the data change the day before
the election? Yes. Did we have the tests to ensure that our
implementation changes would not compromise the system's integrity? Yes,
and they didn't. This talk provides a narrative to both Software
Engineers and Tech/Product Managers describing why best practices are
essential for any organization and any project of any size. We will
provide the audience with: 1. Real world examples they can implement in
their own workflow and organizations, 2. Insight into what succeeded
(quick iteration with prioritization) and what was challenging (nothing
being static), 3. Anecdotes and coherent arguments they can take back to
their organization to advocate for best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyconza"></category><category term="pyconza2014"></category></entry></feed>