<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_all-other-programming-languages.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Teaching Programming to the Next Generation</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/teaching-programming-to-the-next-generation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lilian Nandi anonymous</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-10:europython-2019/teaching-programming-to-the-next-generation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our generation of young people in school (aged 5-18) have noticed the
connection between Computer pRogramming, Technology &amp;amp; Success and
Billionaires.On mass they are clamoring to master the skill of Computer
pRogramming. We describe a successful working model for the teaching of
Computer pRogamming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Science is now regarded as one of the leading disciplines in
the 21st century. Computers are ubiquitous and prevalent in most, if not
all, sectors of our modern society – applications include using them in
weather forecasting, robotic surgery, space exploration, e-commerce,
smart cities, driverless cars, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, coding or computer programming is now regarded by many as an
essential skill for the young person, and it has been dubbed the ‘4th’
R’ (computer pRogramming) along with Reading, wRiting and aRithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recognition of the new status of computer programming, governments
worldwide have launched initiatives to have it taught in schools from
Kindergarten through to junior school and all the way through secondary
school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the question emerges is how do we best teach and motivate the next
generation in acquiring this skill? Given the fact that this field is
very much in its infancy, there are insufficient number of skilled
Computer Science teachers and very little pedagogy to guide the
educator. Therefore, the whole world is learning how best to teach this
subject by trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will describe a case study whereby coding/computer programming,
in the form of Python programming, was introduced to a group of 110
young people from the ages of 11 to 18 (Years 7-13 in a U.K secondary
school). The talk will include descriptions of the various teaching
methodologies introduced to the young people for this purpose and the
outcomes; the talk will also address various challenges and questions
about how to teach coding to young people. The talk will conclude with
helpful suggestions, based on the findings of the case study, on how to
proceed with the teaching of computer programming to these people.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="All Other Programming Languages"></category><category term="Education"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Teaching"></category></entry></feed>