<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_graphs.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Treehugging</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--treehugging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Luft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-09:djangocon-us-2010/djangocon-2010--treehugging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hierarchical data sprouts up almost everywhere, but not all trees look
alike. Learn to how tell them apart and love them all in Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk would cover some common examples of hierarchical data in web
applications and then review solutions like django-mptt and
django-treebeard. Rather than trying to cover tree algorithms in-depth,
the focus would be on best practices for querying and rendering trees in
your Django apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is not geared for the smart kids; they already know this
stuff. It is intended to help less experienced developers take advantage
of patterns without needing to worry about the deeper concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2010"></category><category term="django-mptt"></category><category term="django-treebeard"></category><category term="graphs"></category><category term="structureddata"></category></entry><entry><title>Refactoring PyChart</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/refactoring-pychart.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jacob Hallén</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/refactoring-pychart.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Jacob Hallen - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyChart is a very nice program for producing print quality graphs.
However, it came equipped with a rather strange API, where every class
was called T. It was also using the global namespace in strange and
disturbing ways. Furthermore, it mixed multiple distinct tasks in some
classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will show how I went about refactoring the package in order to make a
nice and clean API. This talk is focused on teaching refactoring
methodology to beginner and intermediate level programmers. It will also
give a brief introduction to how to make beautiful graphs with PyChart.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graphs"></category><category term="teaching"></category></entry><entry><title>Pricing products using Python graphs and sets</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/pricing-products-using-python-graphs-and-sets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Collins</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/pricing-products-using-python-graphs-and-sets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Rob Collins - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will look at the limitations of available rule engines when it comes
to complex pricing rules. Rob has been part of a Python team writing a
pricing engine based on network graphs. We will show:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why pricing is not easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rule engine anti-patterns, e.g. to change one price requires a week's
development time, and has to be fitted into a release cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make pricing rules data driven, usable by the business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the use of graphs and sets reduces the complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob is joined by David Layton of Grey Squirrel Consulting, who is a
fellow contractor working with Rob on the pricing project. He is an
American expatriate and Python developer, currently living and working
in London. His background is in scientific computing, CRMs and Business
Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="business"></category><category term="graphs"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="scientific"></category></entry></feed>