<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_python-skills.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>And now for something completely different.</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/and-now-for-something-completely-different.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Danny Engelbarts</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/and-now-for-something-completely-different.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this talk is to show the audience a different way of
thinking about and developing regex statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working with UNIX for decades now and, although i always
managed to avoid Perl, i have been intrigued with Regex constructs ever
since my first encounter. These weird unreadable things that can
transform text like nothing else or can find what i’m looking for in
massive files, in no time at all. I’ve created regexes that only appeal
to the most nerdiest of nerds and i’ve stunned colleagues by fixing
their futile regex attempts in just a few keystrokes. But when Damian
Conway showed me how regexes really work i was awestruck. And now i want
to share this knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at pythonistas that have some experience with the re
module. I will take some easy examples and explain in plain english how
a regex engine searches for a match. This will show that a regex is not
some mysterious incomprehensible pattern description or declarative
blueprint. Instead it is a small program that is very good at comparing
single characters. Like any programming language it turns out that once
you understand the rules and structure it suddenly becomes so much
easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new found knowledge we will up the ante and try some more
difficult stuff, adding other semantics and some tips and tricks. We’ll
look at some pitfalls, maybe compare regex to python solutions and have
a look at some regexes found in the wild (either on my drive or on
github).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Compiler and Interpreters"></category><category term="Mind Bending"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category><category term="Tooling"></category></entry><entry><title>Don't do this at work</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/dont-do-this-at-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tiago Montes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/dont-do-this-at-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk I reframe a computer programming workshop for kids I
delivered earlier this year, exploring and sharing my experience
throughout that journey, from preparation to delivery, by recreating a
simple yet engaging enough game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that I'll both demonstrate several Python related techniques and
tools many may not be aware of, on one hand, and, on the other, extract
provocative questions about general learning processes, especially when
targeted at professional developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise zero slides and a somewhat fast-paced live (re)coding session,
intertwined with comments on good/bad techniques, along with a
surprising exploration of the turtle module in the Standard Library --
it is more capable than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrap up with a self-code review and with thoughts on how such a game
could be improved, what implications that could have for both beginners
and seasoned professionals: should you do this at work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeting 10 minute Q&amp;amp;A / discussion by the end!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Education"></category><category term="Learning"></category><category term="Life"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category></entry><entry><title>PEP yourself: 10 PEPs you should pay attention to</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/pep-yourself-10-peps-you-should-pay-attention-to.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Juan Santos</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-12:europython-2019/pep-yourself-10-peps-you-should-pay-attention-to.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading standards documents can be a dull task. But like in other
fields, standards in Python play a big part. Python Enhancement
Proposals (PEPs) are defined, improved, and eventually implemented by
the community. They apply to mostly anything related to Python, from the
more abstract and general to the more concrete and specific. Paying
attention to them, and knowing which ones to read beforehand is a vital
task that should take place prior to writing the first lines of code in
a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will go over a condensed list of the most important PEPs
to this date and see how they influence everyday coding. From style
guides and docstring conventions to data classes and assignment
expressions, we will see how these PEPs affect (or can affect) the code
we write, and how can we use them to improve our code and make
developing easier and more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this talk, attendees will have a better grasp on why PEPs are
important to Python, which are a must read, and which ones they should
use as a guide in the future, both for coding and refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Clean Code"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category><category term="Python general"></category></entry><entry><title>Exceptional Exceptions</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/exceptional-exceptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mario Corchero</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/exceptional-exceptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Did you know there are multiple ways to raise and capture exceptions?
Have you ever wondered if you should raise a built-in exception or
create your own hierarchy? Did you ever find it hard to understand
what an exception meant?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;This talk will go through the decisions needed to raise and capture
exceptions when creating a library. We will look at how to translate
and handle errors, create your own exceptions, and make exceptions
clear and easy to troubleshoot, while also understanding how they
actually work, common pitfalls.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will enable intermediate developers to leave the room with a
solid understanding of how to work effectively with exceptions. As the
exception flow usually goes untested, this will help prevent frustrating
situations when errors occur that are not easy to understand or when an
unexpected result is produced. The talk will delve into the different
ways of working with exceptions. We will illustrate this with a
real-world example to which many developers will be able to relate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the talk, intermediate developers will leave the room more
informed and better prepared to create and handle exceptions, having
learned about many utilities that were already available to them, but
were never used or were used improperly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The not-so-advanced Pythonistas will get an in-depth dive into
exceptions. Even if they might not be able to grasp all of the content,
they will get a sense of the features that most programmers are unaware
of and learn to use them when the proper situation arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced programmers will find this to be a humorous talk that will
certainly teach them at least one new thing, as I will dive into parts
of the grammar of Python that even many advanced programmers are not
used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk is also full of niche information like why the variable that
catches exceptions doesn’t like outside of the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;except&lt;/tt&gt; scope.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The talk is comprised of four main sections preceded by an
introduction to the problem and a conclusion with time for questions
at the end. We will look at how to raise, capture, create and design
exceptions, offering tips and pitfalls in each section.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Best Practice"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="General"></category><category term="Python 3"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category></entry><entry><title>Practical decorators</title><link href="https://pyvideo.org/europython-2019/practical-decorators.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Reuven Lerner</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2019-07-11:europython-2019/practical-decorators.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decorators are one of Python's most powerful features. But even if you
understand what they do, it's not always obvious what you can do with
them. Sure, from a practical perspective, they let you remove repeated
code from your callables. And semantically, they let you think at a
higher level of abstraction, applying the same treatment to functions
and classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can you actually do with them? For many Python developers I've
encountered, decorators sometimes appear to be a solution looking for a
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show you some practical uses for decorators, and how
you can use them to make your code more readable and maintainable, while
also providing more semantic power. Moreover, you'll see examples of
things would be hard to do without decorators. I hope that after this
talk, you'll have a good sense of how to use decorators in your own
Python projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Compiler and Interpreters"></category><category term="Data Structures"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Python Skills"></category><category term="Python general"></category></entry></feed>